<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cross-input signature aggregation (CISA) on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/cisa/</link><description>Recent content in Cross-input signature aggregation (CISA) on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/cisa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Making Bitcoin More Private with CISA</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-magazine/bitcoin-2024/making-bitcoin-more-private-with-cisa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-magazine/bitcoin-2024/making-bitcoin-more-private-with-cisa/</guid><description>Delve into the world of Cross-Input Signature Aggregation (CISA) with our expert panel from Sparrow Wallet, Bitcoin Core, and Casa. This discussion illuminates how CISA could revolutionize Bitcoin transactions by enhancing privacy and reducing fees. Uncover the technical aspects of half and full signature aggregation and understand their potential impact on the Bitcoin network.</description></item><item><title>Cross Input Signature Aggregation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2024-04/cross-input-signature-aggregation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2024-04/cross-input-signature-aggregation/</guid><description>cisaresearch.org, put together by fjahr Documents progress of half and full agg (theory, implementation and deployment) Provides collection of CISA-related resources (ML posts, papers, videos/podcasts, etc.) Should provide guidance for further development/open todos for contributors to grab HRF announces CISA Research Fellowship Seeks to answer questions how CISA will affect privacy, cost-savings, and much more during a four-month period for a total of .5BTC More: https://nostr.com/note1h4fdw5ttqmjwf3eqr0s5lqzjhdvwcayl0hrfnv726cw4eeag6phs9xszpw Will coordinate with them to align cisaresearch.</description></item><item><title>Schnorr, MuSig, FROST and more</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/schnorr-musig-frost-and-more/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/schnorr-musig-frost-and-more/</guid><description>Pieter Wuille and Tim Ruffing treat us to a conversation about Schnorr, multisignatures, MuSig, and more. We covered a lot so this is part one of a two part conversation.</description></item></channel></rss>