<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mark Erhardt on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/mark-erhardt/</link><description>Recent content in Mark Erhardt on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/mark-erhardt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Privacy Metrics for Coin Selection</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2023-09/privacy-metrics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2023-09/privacy-metrics/</guid><description>Goal: Get privacy consciousness into coin selection Configurability Privacy vs cost (waste) Privacy: weighted on a 0-5 scale Cost: weighted on a 0-5 scale Convert privacy preference (0-5) into satoshis to make it compatible with the waste score Combined score = PrivacyScoreWeight x PrivacyScore + CostWeight x WasteMetric 20-30 sats per privacy point as a gut feeling Privacy score example: sending to different script type than inputs of transaction We already match the change type to the recipient type, but that can still mean that we have differently typed inputs than outputs If we have two input sets, where one has the same type and the other has a different type, the one with the same type inputs should be preferred by the privacy metric Privacy score example: Preferring spending UTXOs of similar age E.</description></item><item><title>Misconceptions about segwit vbytes</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-15-segwit-vbytes-misconceptions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-15-segwit-vbytes-misconceptions/</guid><description>Weighing transactions: The witness discount You&amp;rsquo;ve already heard from someone that this presentation will be more interactive. I probably won&amp;rsquo;t get through all of my material. If you have questions during the talk, please feel free to raise your hand and we can cover it right away. I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to walk you through a transaction serialization for both a non-segwit transaction and a segwit transaction. By the end of the talk, I hope you understand how the transaction weight is calculated and how the witness discount works.</description></item><item><title>Weighing Transactions, The Witness Discount</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/weighing-transactions-the-witness-discount/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/weighing-transactions-the-witness-discount/</guid><description>In this talk Mark Erhardt: 0:00:25
I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to walk with you through a transaction serialization, the Bitcoin transaction serialization. And we&amp;rsquo;ll try to understand a non-SegWit transaction and then a SegWit transaction to compare it to. And I hope by the end of this talk, you understand how the transaction weight is calculated and how the witness discount works. And if we get to it, we may take a look at a few different output types in the end as well.</description></item><item><title>SLP321 On-chain scaling with Bitcoin Core Developers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2021-11-16-pieter-wuille-andrew-poelstra-andrew-chow-mark-erhardt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2021-11-16-pieter-wuille-andrew-poelstra-andrew-chow-mark-erhardt/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/321/
Emcee:
All right. I’m really excited for this next panel. I’ve heard some of them speak in different rooms and I can’t wait to hear what they all have to say today. Next up, I’m going to bring up our moderator. He has a podcast. It is a self-titled podcast and he’s also the managing director of Swan Bitcoin International. Please everybody, welcome to the stage Stephan Livera, everyone.</description></item><item><title>Enterprise Wallets/UTXO Management</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2020-11-09-enterprise-walletsutxo-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2020-11-09-enterprise-walletsutxo-management/</guid><description>Mark Erhardt: 00:00:00
Just to throw out a few numbers there, non-SegWit inputs cost almost 300 bytes, and native SegWit inputs cost slightly more than 100 bytes. There&amp;rsquo;s almost a reduction by two-thirds in fees if you switch from non-SegWit to native SegWit.
Introduction Caralie Chrisco: 00:00:29
Hi, everyone, welcome to the Chaincode podcast. My name is Caralie.
Adam Jonas: 00:00:32
And it&amp;rsquo;s Jonas.
Caralie Chrisco: 00:00:33
And we&amp;rsquo;re back!</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Coin Selection - Managing Large Wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-05-27-bitcoin-coin-selection/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-05-27-bitcoin-coin-selection/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/177/
Stephan Livera:
Welcome, Murch.
Murch:
Hey, Stephan, thanks for having me.
Stephan Livera:
Well, yeah, thanks for joining me, man. I am a fan. I’ve read some of your work on coin selection. And I know you’ve, you’re you’re the man to talk to about this topic. So look, let’s start with how you got into Bitcoin and Bitcoin contribution and also just some of your work at BitGo.</description></item><item><title>Coin Selection</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/coin-selection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/coin-selection/</guid><description>Simulation-based evaluation of coin selection strategies
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785061222316113920
Introduction Thank you. ((applause))
Hi. Okay. I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about coin selection. I have been doing this for my master thesis. To take you through what I will be talking about, I will be shortly outlining my work, then talking about coin selection in general. And then the design space of coin selection. I will also be introducing the framework I have been using for simulating coin selection.</description></item></channel></rss>