<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Misc on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/</link><description>Recent content in Misc on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>FROST</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2022-08-07-komlo-crites-frost/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2022-08-07-komlo-crites-frost/</guid><description>Topic: FROST
Location: Zcon 3
FROST paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/852.pdf
Sydney Socratic on FROST: https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2022-03-29-socratic-seminar/
Introduction Elizabeth Crites (EC): My name is Elizabeth Crites, I’m a postdoc at the University of Edinburgh.
Chelsea Komlo (CK): I’m Chelsea Komlo, I’m at the University of Waterloo and I’m also a Principal Researcher at the Zcash Foundation. Today we will be giving you research updates on FROST.
What is FROST? (Chelsea Komlo) You might not know what FROST is and that’s totally ok.</description></item><item><title>ROAST</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2022-07-14-tim-ruffing-roast/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2022-07-14-tim-ruffing-roast/</guid><description>Topic: ROAST
Location: Monash Cybersecurity Seminars
ROAST paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2022/550.pdf
ROAST blog post: https://medium.com/blockstream/roast-robust-asynchronous-schnorr-threshold-signatures-ddda55a07d1b
ROAST in Python: https://github.com/robot-dreams/roast
Introduction (Amin Sakzad) Welcome everyone to Monash Cybersecurity Seminars. Today we will be having Tim Ruffing. Tim is an applied cryptographer in the research team of Blockstream, a Bitcoin and blockchain technology company. He obtained his PhD from Saarland University researching cryptographic aspects of cryptocurrencies. His current research focus on advanced applications of Schnorr signatures, for example multi and threshold signatures.</description></item><item><title>What Am I Working On</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2020-07-10-what-am-i-working-on/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2020-07-10-what-am-i-working-on/</guid><description>Topic: What am I working on?
Location: Reddit (r/bitcoin)
Reddit link: https://www.reddit.com/r/Bitcoin/comments/ho0t1a/what_are_bitcoin_developers_currently_working_on/fxhwqli/?context=3
What am I working on? I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on essentially rewriting the Bitcoin Core wallet, one piece at a time. Now when I say &amp;ldquo;the wallet&amp;rdquo;, a lot of people think of the GUI. That&amp;rsquo;s not what I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on. Rather I&amp;rsquo;ve been changing the internals; how keys are managed, how transactions are tracked, how inputs are selected for spending.</description></item><item><title>Structured Fuzzing</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2019-08-07-jonathan-metzman-structured-fuzzing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2019-08-07-jonathan-metzman-structured-fuzzing/</guid><description>Topic: Going Beyond Coverage Guided Fuzzing with Structured Fuzzing
Location: Black Hat USA 2019
Blackhat: https://www.blackhat.com/us-19/briefings/schedule/#going-beyond-coverage-guided-fuzzing-with-structured-fuzzing-16110
Slides: https://i.blackhat.com/USA-19/Wednesday/us-19-Metzman-Going-Beyond-Coverage-Guided-Fuzzing-With-Structured-Fuzzing.pdf
Transcript completed by: Michael Folkson
Intro Hi everyone. Thanks for coming to my talk. As I was introduced I’m Jonathan Metzman. I’m here to talk about how you can get more bugs with coverage guided fuzzing by adding structure awareness to your fuzzers.
Unstructured Fuzzing = Magic I first got into fuzzing while I was in college through AFL.</description></item><item><title>Chain Defense In Depth</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2019-02-09-mcelrath-on-chain-defense-in-depth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2019-02-09-mcelrath-on-chain-defense-in-depth/</guid><description>On-chain defense in depth (UCL CBT seminar)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1159542209584218113
Introduction It seems strange to come to a university and put PhD on my slides because in the finance world that&amp;rsquo;s weird. I put it up there.
Okay, so. I work for Fidelity Digital Assets. Just a couple words about this. Our lawyers make us say this: &amp;ldquo;This presentation is intended to be educational in nature and is not representative of existing products and services from Fidelity Investments or Fidelity Digital Assets.</description></item><item><title>Unchained Capital Socratic Seminar</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2019-01-05-unchained-capital-socratic-seminar/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2019-01-05-unchained-capital-socratic-seminar/</guid><description>Unchained Capital Bitcoin Socratic Seminar
Socratic Seminar 87 at BitDevs NYC has all of the links on meetup.com available.
https://www.meetup.com/BitDevsNYC/events/256924041/
https://www.meetup.com/Austin-Bitcoin-Developers/events/257718282/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1081674259880120323
Last time Last time Andrew Poelstra gave a talk about research at Blockstream. He also talked about scriptless scripts and using the properties of Schnorr signatures to do all of your scripting. There was also talk about taproot and graftroot.
J: The chaincode labs guys in NYC .. we had a lot of participation, it was very cool.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network BOLT by BOLT</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2018-07-24-la-blockchain-jim-posen-lightning-bolt-by-bolt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2018-07-24-la-blockchain-jim-posen-lightning-bolt-by-bolt/</guid><description>Topic: Lightning Network BOLT by BOLT
Location: LA Blockchain Meetup
Transcript by: glozow
Introduction I&amp;rsquo;m Jim from the protocol team at Coinbase. We work on open source stuff in the crypto space. We just contribute to projects like Bitcoin core. The reason I&amp;rsquo;m talking about this is I&amp;rsquo;ve been contributing on and off to one of the major lightning implementations lnd for the past eight months or so.
This is gonna be a fairly technical talk.</description></item><item><title>Bulletproofs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2018-02-02-andrew-poelstra-bulletproofs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2018-02-02-andrew-poelstra-bulletproofs/</guid><description>49th Milan Bitcoin meetup
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/962326126969442304
https://www.reddit.com/r/Bitcoin/comments/7w72pq/bulletproofs_presentation_at_feb_2_milan_meetup/
Introduction Alright. Thank you for that introduction, Giacamo. I am here to talk about bulletproofs. This is different from proof-of-bullets, which is what fiat currencies use. In bulletproofs, we use a zero-knowledge proof which has nothing to do with consensus at all, but it has a lot of exciting applications. The original motivation to create bulletproofs was for range proofs which are used in confidential transactions.</description></item><item><title>Future Bitcoin Tech Directions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2018-01-24-rusty-russell-future-bitcoin-tech-directions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2018-01-24-rusty-russell-future-bitcoin-tech-directions/</guid><description>Future technological directions in bitcoin: An unreliable guide
notes: https://docs.google.com/document/d/1iNzJtJRq9-0vdILQAe9Bcj7r1a7xYVf8CSY0_oFrH9c/edit or http://diyhpl.us/~bryan/papers2/bitcoin/Future%20technological%20directions%20in%20bitcoin%20-%202018-01-24.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/957318453181939712
Introduction Thank you very much for that introduction. Alright, well polished machine right there. Let&amp;rsquo;s try that again. Thank you for that introduction. My talk today is all about this. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to be talking about this. If you see me reaching for the red hat, please stop me. Before I begin, I want to apologize in advance: this talk is a summary of things coming up in bitcoin that some people are workin on, which means first I need to apologize to the people whose work I am about to compress into about 85 second segments each, because I am going to gloss over a lot of things.</description></item><item><title>Whalepool</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2016-12-14-whalepool/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2016-12-14-whalepool/</guid><description>Whalepool segwit transcript
https://soundcloud.com/elux-2/the-great-stakehodler-debate-lombroso-petrov-potter-ver
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/809174512105295872
Host: Mr. Ver, can you hear this?
RV: Yes, I can.
Host: Welcome to Whalepool.
Gavin: Hey Roger, it&amp;rsquo;s Gavin. I heard about this.
RV: Hey Eric. I see lots of familiar names in here.
RV: Who was that? I don&amp;rsquo;t know whose voice that was.
Hodl: Mr. Hodl
RV: Thanks for organizing this. Hello Mr. Hodl.
Host: Okay, ready to go. Here we have Eric Lombrozo who is a developer who has committed code to Bitcoin Core.</description></item><item><title>Implications of Blockchain</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2016-adam-back/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2016-adam-back/</guid><description>New Context Conference 2016 http://dg717.com/ncc/en/
We are using a hashtag to organize the information today. The hashtag we&amp;rsquo;re using is nccblockchain. Ncc stands for new conference context. That&amp;rsquo;s where we are. Blockchain is what we&amp;rsquo;re talkin gabout. Can I ask the people in the back to take a seat? We&amp;rsquo;re about to get ready. Meet the neighbor near your seat. Switch your cellphone off. I am going to demonstrate. The toilets squirt you.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Scaling Tradeoffs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/adam3us-bitcoin-scaling-tradeoffs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/adam3us-bitcoin-scaling-tradeoffs/</guid><description>Bitcoin scaling tradeoffs with Adam Back (adam3us) at Paralelni Polis
Institute of Cryptoanarchy http://www.paralelnipolis.cz/
slides: http://www.slideshare.net/paralelnipolis/bitcoin-scaling-tradeoffs-with-adam-back
description: &amp;ldquo;In this talk, Adam Back overviews the Bitcoin scaling and discuses his personal view about its tradeoffs and future development.&amp;rdquo;
Intro fluff And now I would like to introduce you to a great guest from the U.K. or Malta, Adam Back. Adam is long-time professional cryptologist and also he&amp;rsquo;s a Bitcoin expert. He&amp;rsquo;s the inventor of hashcash, which was used for example by Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Epicenter Bitcoin - Scalability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2015-09-07-epicenter-bitcoin-adam3us-scalability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2015-09-07-epicenter-bitcoin-adam3us-scalability/</guid><description>Why bitcoin needs a measured approach to scaling
Name: Adam Back (adam3us) Epicenter (EC)
Sebastien Couture (SC) Brian Fabian Crain (BC)
BC: Adam Back is here for the second time on this show. Some of you will be familiar that Adam Back is the inventor of proof-of-work or hashcash as it was then. He was one of the few people cited in the original Bitcoin whitepaper. More recently he has been involved in sidechains and Blockstream where he is a founder.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Sidechains - Unchained Epicenter</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/bitcoin-sidechains-unchained-epicenter-adam3us-gmaxwell/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/bitcoin-sidechains-unchained-epicenter-adam3us-gmaxwell/</guid><description>EB65 – Adam Back &amp;amp; Greg Maxwell: Sidechains Unchained
people:
Sebastien Couture Brian Fabian Crain Adam Back (adam3us) Greg Maxwell (gmaxwell) Brian: We are here today we have Adam Back and Greg Maxwell, to anyone who is following bitcoin and bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s development, you will have probably heard of these two gentlemen. I was fortunate enough that the first time that I went to a bitcoin conference at the beginning of my involvement in this space, it was in Amsterdam 2013 and I somehow randomly ended up having dinner twice with Adam which really was super fascinating talking to him about bitcoin, and so I&amp;rsquo;m really exciting to have them on today, especially since we are going to have a chance to talk about a project we have talked about many times on this show before, with different people, which is sidechains, because sidechains I think that everyone is in agreement that it is one of the more interesting projects in the space, and a lot of people have many questions about it.</description></item><item><title>NY DFS Bitlicense Lawsky Update</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/nydfs-bitlicense-lawsky-update/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/nydfs-bitlicense-lawsky-update/</guid><description>NY DFS BitLicense update 2014-12-18
http://web.archive.org/web/20150511110453/http://bipartisanpolicy.org/events/payment-policy-in-the-21st-century-the-promise-of-innovation-and-the-challenge-of-regulation/
And that&amp;rsquo;s a serious problem that we all need to address with a hightened sense of urgency and focus. Let me start with the BitLicense and virtual currencies. These came on our radar screen last year at DFS because like all of the other states we regulate money transmitters like Moneygram and Western Union. We were worried that virtual currency firms were transmitting currency. Our regulatory rules were written before the internet and before virtual currencies.</description></item><item><title>CFTC Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/cftc-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/cftc-bitcoin/</guid><description>Commodity Futures Trading Commission
http://www.onlinevideoservice.com/clients/cftc/video.htm?eventid=cftclive
# NDFs description Panel I: CFTC Clearing for Non-Deliverable Forwards (NDF)
The first panel will discuss whether mandatory clearing should be required of NDF swaps contracts. Each panelist will present and then there will be opportunity for broader discussion and questions. Representatives from the CFTC, the Bank of England, and the European Securities and Markets Authority will also be joined by a subcommittee of experts on the foreign exchange markets who, although not presenting at the meeting, will participate in the broader discussion following the presentations.</description></item><item><title>CTV BIP Review Workshop</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/ctv-bip-review-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/ctv-bip-review-workshop/</guid><description>OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY workshop notes
Reference materials transcript tweet https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1223708325960798208
tweet https://twitter.com/JeremyRubin/status/1223664128381734912 or https://twitter.com/JeremyRubin/status/1223672458516938752 and https://twitter.com/JeremyRubin/status/1223729378946715648
IRC logs: http://gnusha.org/ctv-bip-review/
bip119 proposal: https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/tree/master/bip-0119.mediawiki
proposal site: https://utxos.org/
branch comparison: https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/compare/master...JeremyRubin:checktemplateverify
workshop scripts: https://github.com/JeremyRubin/ctv-workshop
slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1XDiZOz52XyJc4LDSbiD9_JAaJobyF5QDGtR3O9qD7yg/edit?usp=sharing
Introduction Howdy livestreamers. Can someone just tweet that the livestream has actually started? https://twitter.com/JeremyRubin/status/1223672458516938752 Okay thanks.
Welcome to the OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY workshop. In the email I mentioned that we do have a code of conduct. It boils down to &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t be a jerk&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Discreet Log Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/discreet-log-contracts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/discreet-log-contracts/</guid><description>paper: https://adiabat.github.io/dlc.pdf
slides: http://bit.ly/2uSqkV6 or https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1QXZBtELcVMoCq6wx-rJr31KvtsqxxcWIewMvuSTpsa4
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/902201044297555970
We are going to have next month on September 13 when Ethan Heilman will be talking about something controversial but he hasn&amp;rsquo;t told me what it is yet. But it&amp;rsquo;s controversial. I am Amy. I organize the meetup with some help from other people in the MIT Bitcoin Club. I write about blockchain technologies and stuff. I have written for coindesk and bitcoin magazine and now I&amp;rsquo;m writing for Forbes.</description></item><item><title>Failures Of Secret Key Cryptography (2013)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/failures-of-secret-key-cryptography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/failures-of-secret-key-cryptography/</guid><description>FSE 2013
Welcome to the second invited talk, to be given by Dan Bernstein. Dan is one of the few members of our community who does not need an introduction. It&amp;rsquo;s a great honor and pleasure that he has agreed to give a talk here. Dan comes from UC Berkeley and from Chicago. Just a few things you might know Dan from&amp;ndash; he sued the U.S. government about export controls. In 2004, .</description></item><item><title>Fungibility and Privacy</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/bitcoin-adam3us-fungibility-privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/bitcoin-adam3us-fungibility-privacy/</guid><description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3dAdI3Gzodo
First of all I was going to explain what we mean by fungibility before bitcoin and ecash. It&amp;rsquo;s an old legal concept in fact, about paper currency. It&amp;rsquo;s the idea that a one ten dollar note is the same as any other ten dollar note. If you receive a note that was involved in a theft, 10 transactions ago, and the police investigate the theft, they have no right to remove the ten dollar note from your pocket.</description></item><item><title>Mimblewimble Podcast</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/mimblewimble-podcast/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/mimblewimble-podcast/</guid><description>https://soundcloud.com/heryptohow/mimblewimble-andrew-poelstra-peter-wuille-brian-deery-and-chris-odom
Andrew Poelstra (andytoshi) Pieter Wuille (sipa) Brian Deery Chris Odom Starts at 26min.
I am going to introduce our guests here in just a minute.
Launch of zcash might be delayed in order to allow the code to be analyzed by multiple third-party auditors. Zooko stated, &amp;ldquo;I feel bad that we didn&amp;rsquo;t do a better job of making TheDAO disaster-like problems harder for people&amp;rdquo;.
Our guests on the line are Andrew Poelstra and Pieter Wuille.</description></item><item><title>Safecurves - Choosing Safe Curves For Elliptic Curve Cryptography (2014)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/safecurves-choosing-safe-curves-for-elliptic-curve-cryptography-2014/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/safecurves-choosing-safe-curves-for-elliptic-curve-cryptography-2014/</guid><description>Daniel J. Bernstein (djb) and Tanja Lange
SchmooCon 2014
video 2 (same?): https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=maBOorEfOOk&amp;amp;list=PLgO7JBj821uGZTXEXBLckChu70kl7Celh&amp;amp;index=91
Video intro text There are several different standards covering selection of curves for use in elliptic-curve cryptography (ECC). Each of these standards tries to ensure that the elliptic-curve discrete-logarithm problem (ECDLP) is difficult. ECDLP is the problem of finding an ECC user&amp;rsquo;s secret key, given the user&amp;rsquo;s public key.
Unfortunately, there is a gap between ECDLP difficulty and ECC security.</description></item></channel></rss>