<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Andrew Miller on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/andrew-miller/</link><description>Recent content in Andrew Miller on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/andrew-miller/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Coinscope</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/coinscope-andrew-miller/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/coinscope-andrew-miller/</guid><description>http://cs.umd.edu/projects/coinscope/
I am going to talk about a pair of tools, one is a simulator and another one is a measurement station for the bitcoin network. So let me start with the bitcoin simulator framework. The easiest approach is to create a customized model that is a simplified abstraction of what you care about- which is like simbit, to show off how selfish-mining works. What you put in is what you get, so the model is actually different from the actual behavior of the bitcoin network means that you don&amp;rsquo;t learn anything really.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/introduction/</guid><description>&amp;ndash; Disclaimer &amp;ndash;
These are unpaid transcriptions, performed in real-time and in-person during the actual source presentation. Due to personal time constraints they are usually not reviewed against the source material once published. Errors are possible. If the original author/speaker or anyone else finds errors of substance, please email me at kanzure@gmail.com for corrections.
I sometimes add annotations to the transcription text. These will always be denoted by a standard editor&amp;rsquo;s note in parenthesis brackets ((like this)), or in a numbered footnote.</description></item><item><title>Snarks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/snarks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/snarks/</guid><description>some setup motivating topics:
practicality pcp theorem trustless setup magic away the trusted setup schemes without trusted setup pcp theorem is the existent proof that the spherical cow exists. people:
Andrew Miller (AM) Madars Virza (MV) Andrew Poelstra (AP) Bryan Bishop (BB) Nathan Wilcox ZZZZZ: zooko gmaxwell&amp;rsquo;s ghost (only in spirit) SNARKs always require some sort of setup. PCP-based SNARKs can use random oracle assumption instantiated by hash function, sha256 acts as the random oracle.</description></item><item><title>Step by Step Towards Writing a Safe Contract - Insights from an Undergraduate Ethereum Lab</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/andrew-miller/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/andrew-miller/</guid><description>Next up I want to introduce Elaine Shi and Andrew Miller from University of Maryland. Andrew is also on the zerocash team.
Okay. I am an assistant professor at the University of Maryland. We all believe that cryptocurrency is the way of the future and smart contracts. So students in the future have to program smart contracts.
So that&amp;rsquo;s what I did. I asked some students to program some smart contracts.</description></item></channel></rss>