<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nicolas Dorier on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/nicolas-dorier/</link><description>Recent content in Nicolas Dorier on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/nicolas-dorier/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nicolas Dorier and BTCPayServer – self hosted Bitcoin and Lightning payments</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2019-01-20-nicolas-dorier-and-btcpayserver/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2019-01-20-nicolas-dorier-and-btcpayserver/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/48/
Stephan Livera: You’re listening to the Stephan Livera podcast focused on Bitcoin and Austrian economics. This is episode 48 with Nicolas Dorier, who started a great project. I wanted to discuss BTCPayServer. Nicolas is also the creator of NBitcoin, a Bitcoin library for the .Net platform in C#. Here’s my conversation with Nicolas. Nicolas, thanks for coming on the show.
Nicolas Dorier: Yeah, thank you for inviting me.</description></item><item><title>Cross-Chain Swaps</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/cross-chain-swaps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/cross-chain-swaps/</guid><description>Ethan and Nicolas describe atomic cross-chain swaps - a protocol where two parties can exchange coins as a single operation. The exchange does not require any trusted third party and neither of the parties involved can cheat each other. They describe how this can be used on a single blockchain as a privacy protocol or “cross-chain” as a trading protocol.</description></item><item><title>How to make everyone run their own full node</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/btcpay/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/btcpay/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014166857958461440
I am the maintainer of Nbitcoin and btcpay. I am a dot net fanboy. I am happy that the number of people working on bitcoin in C# has spread from one about four years ago to about ten in this room toay. That&amp;rsquo;s great. I work at DG Lab in Japan.
The goal of my talk is to continue what Jonas Schnelli was talking about. He was speaking about how to get the best wallet and get the three components of security, privacy and trust.</description></item><item><title>Tooling</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/tooling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/tooling/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014167542422822913
What kind of tools do we need to create, in order to facilitate building on bitcoin? We are going to open questions to the floor. The guys will be there to get your questions. The panel will be about 20 minutes long, and then we will go for food.
LN: I work at Blockstream. I work on low-level wallets and tooling for wallets.
ND: I am working on a library called Nbitcoin for programming bitcoin in C#.</description></item><item><title>Reproducible Lightning Benchmark</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/reproducible-lightning-benchmark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/reproducible-lightning-benchmark/</guid><description>Reproducible lightning benchmark
https://github.com/dgarage/LightningBenchmarks
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048760545699016705
Introduction Thanks for the introduction, Jameson. I feel like a rock star now. So yeah, I won&amp;rsquo;t introduce myself. I call myself a code monkey the reason is that a lot of the talks in scaling bitcoin can surprise people but I understood very few of them. The reason is that I am more of an application developer. Basically, I try to understand a lot of the talks but if it&amp;rsquo;s too complex then I just wait until some crypto guy makes a proof-of-concept, then I just make something in C# that other people can use.</description></item></channel></rss>