<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nicolas Dorier on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/nicolas-dorier/</link><description>Recent content in Nicolas Dorier on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/nicolas-dorier/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nicolas Dorier and BTCPayServer – self hosted Bitcoin and Lightning payments</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2019-01-20-nicolas-dorier-and-btcpayserver/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2019-01-20-nicolas-dorier-and-btcpayserver/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/48/
Stephan Livera: You’re listening to the Stephan Livera podcast focused on Bitcoin and Austrian economics. This is episode 48 with Nicolas Dorier, who started a great project. I wanted to discuss BTCPayServer. Nicolas is also the creator of NBitcoin, a Bitcoin library for the .Net platform in C#. Here’s my conversation with Nicolas. Nicolas, thanks for coming on the show.
Nicolas Dorier: Yeah, thank you for inviting me.</description></item><item><title>Btcpay</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/btcpay/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/btcpay/</guid><description>How to make everyone run their own full node
Building on Bitcoin, 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014166857958461440
I am the maintainer of Nbitcoin and btcpay. I am a dot net fanboy. I am happy that the number of people working on bitcoin in C# has spread from one about four years ago to about ten in this room toay. That&amp;rsquo;s great. I work at DG Lab in Japan.
The goal of my talk is to continue what Jonas Schnelli was talking about.</description></item><item><title>Tooling</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/tooling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/tooling/</guid><description>Building on Bitcoin 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014167542422822913
What kind of tools do we need to create, in order to facilitate building on bitcoin? We are going to open questions to the floor. The guys will be there to get your questions. The panel will be about 20 minutes long, and then we will go for food.
eric voskuil nicolasdorier kevin loaec lawrence nahum
LN: I work at Blockstream. I work on low-level wallets and tooling for wallets.</description></item><item><title>Cross Chain Swaps</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/edgedevplusplus/cross-chain-swaps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/edgedevplusplus/cross-chain-swaps/</guid><description>Cross-chain swaps: Atomically swapping coins for privacy or cross-blockchain trades
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048017311431413760
Introduction We are Ethan Heilman and Nicolas Dorier. Ethan is from Boston University. Nicolas is from DG Lab and working on NBitcoin. Today we&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking with you about atomic swaps for privacy and for cross-blockchain swaps. When we say atomic swaps, what do we mean? At a very high level, the idea is that it enables Alice and Bob to trade some cryptocurrency.</description></item><item><title>Reproducible Lightning Benchmark</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/reproducible-lightning-benchmark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/reproducible-lightning-benchmark/</guid><description>Reproducible lightning benchmark
https://github.com/dgarage/LightningBenchmarks
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048760545699016705
Introduction Thanks for the introduction, Jameson. I feel like a rock star now. So yeah, I won&amp;rsquo;t introduce myself. I call myself a code monkey the reason is that a lot of the talks in scaling bitcoin can surprise people but I understood very few of them. The reason is that I am more of an application developer. Basically, I try to understand a lot of the talks but if it&amp;rsquo;s too complex then I just wait until some crypto guy makes a proof-of-concept, then I just make something in C# that other people can use.</description></item></channel></rss>