<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>security on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/security/</link><description>Recent content in security on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Stepan Snigirev - Hardware wallet attacks (2019-05-01)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2019-05-01-stepan-snigirev-hardware-wallet-attacks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2019-05-01-stepan-snigirev-hardware-wallet-attacks/</guid><description>Name: Stepan Snigirev
Topic: Hardware Wallets (History of attacks)
Location: London Bitcoin Devs
Date: May 1st 2019
Video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P5PI5MZ_2yo
Slides: https://www.dropbox.com/s/64s3mtmt3efijxo/Stepan%20Snigirev%20on%20hardware%20wallet%20attacks.pdf
Pieter Wuille on anti covert channel signing techniques: https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2020-March/017667.html
Introduction This talk is the second in the series after my previous talk in London a few months ago at the Advancing Bitcoin conference. There I was talking mostly about general attacks on hardware, more from the theoretical perspective. I didn’t say anything bad hardware wallets that exist and I didn’t specify anything on the bad side.</description></item><item><title>Amiko Pay</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/amiko-pay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/amiko-pay/</guid><description>Amiko Pay
Come Plooy
Amiko Pay aims to become an implementation of the lightning network. So that previous presentation was a great setup. There&amp;rsquo;s a little bit more to Amiko Pay. If you look through the basic design of the lightning network, there&amp;rsquo;s a network of payment channels. There have been several variations of this idea. Lightning Network happens to be the best so far. What Amiko Pay aims to do is to focus on the nodes, and do the routing between nodes.</description></item><item><title>Andreas Antonopolous Canada Senate Bitcoin (2014-10-08)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/andreas-antonopoulos/2014-10-08-andreas-antonopolous-canada-senate-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/andreas-antonopoulos/2014-10-08-andreas-antonopolous-canada-senate-bitcoin/</guid><description>This is a transcript of submitted evidence to the Parliament of Canada&amp;rsquo;s Senate Committee on Banking, Trade and Commerce. Here is a video. The opening remarks can be found here.
Another transcript may appear here but who knows.
An additional transcript can be found here.
final report: http://www.parl.gc.ca/Content/SEN/Committee/412/banc/rep/rep12jun15-e.pdf
Prepared remarks. My experience is primarily in information security and network architecture. I have a Master’s degree in networks and distributed systems and have worked in this field since 1992.</description></item><item><title>Andreas Antonopoulos - Seed Splitting (2020-04-08)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/andreas-antonopoulos/2020-04-08-andreas-antonopoulos-seed-splitting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/andreas-antonopoulos/2020-04-08-andreas-antonopoulos-seed-splitting/</guid><description>Name: Andreas Antonopoulos
Topic: Why is seed splitting a bad idea?
Location: Andreas Antonopoulos YouTube channel
Date: April 8th 2020
Video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=p5nSibpfHYE
Why is seed splitting a bad idea? This is something that is being discussed all the time especially on newbie forums. It really needs to be careful very carefully. A friend had the idea to achieve 2 out of 3 protection from my wallet seed by storing the seed in the following way:</description></item><item><title>Armory Proof Of Payment</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/armory-proof-of-payment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/armory-proof-of-payment/</guid><description>Armory proof of payment
Andy Ofiesh
I am going to talk about proof of payment. This is simple. You can do this. That you couldn&amp;rsquo;t do before 2008. We&amp;rsquo;ll see if this works. I hear it might work. That&amp;rsquo;s okay, I&amp;rsquo;ll pull this up here. I have ruined everything. Just jam that in there. Here we go.
So uh, I said who I am. Bitcoin Armory. I am here to talk about proof of payment.</description></item><item><title>Arvind Narayanan</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/arvind-narayanan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/arvind-narayanan/</guid><description>Arvind Narayanan
Threshold signatures
I want to tell you what threshold signatures are and I want to convince you that threshold signatures are a technology you need. This is collaborative work.
There are three things I want to tell you today. The first is that the banking security model has been very very refined and has sophisticated techniques and process and controls for ensuring security. It does not translate to Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Assumeutxo (2019-06-07)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06-07-assumeutxo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06-07-assumeutxo/</guid><description>Assumeutxo
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137008648620838912
Why assumeutxo assumeutxo is a spiritual continuation of assumevalid. Why do we want to do this in the first place? At the moment, it takes hours and days to do initial block download. Various projects in the community have been implementing meassures to speed this up. Casa I think bundles datadir with their nodes. Other projects like btcpay have various ways of bundling this up and signing things with gpg keys and these solutions are not quite half-baked but they are probably not desirable either.</description></item><item><title>Banks As Bitcoin Custodians</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/banks-as-bitcoin-custodians/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/banks-as-bitcoin-custodians/</guid><description>Traditional banks as bitcoin custodians: Security challenges and implications
Giacomo Zucco
video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eCE2OzKIab8&amp;amp;t=4h8m
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005545022559866880
Our next speaker is Giacomo Zucco. Yeah, have fun.
categories: [&amp;lsquo;conference&amp;rsquo;] tags: [&amp;lsquo;security&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;research&amp;rsquo;] As you can hear, there are a lot of italians here. Okay. So, good afternoon everyone. I am Giacomo Zucco.
I am a theoretical physicist. I worked at Accenture as a technology consultant and now I work at BHB Network which is a bridge between free open-source development and research on the bitcoin protocol, and the world of the incumbents.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Build System</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/bitcoin-build-system/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/bitcoin-build-system/</guid><description>Bitcoin build systems and bitcoin build system security
Carl Dong, Chaincode Labs
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137347937426661376
video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I2iShmUTEl8
I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it to Amsterdam this year, but I hope the graphics I have prepared for this talk can make up for my absence. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you want to be a good bitcoin citizen and start to run your own bitcoin node. Say you go to bitcoincore.org, you click the download button, and you open the disk image and you double click on Bitcoin Core.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Mining And Trustlessness</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/bitcoin-mining-and-trustlessness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/bitcoin-mining-and-trustlessness/</guid><description>Bitcoin mining and security models
Matt Corallo
2017-03-04
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0mVOq1jaR1U&amp;amp;t=2h22m11s
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/838500313212518404
Yes, something like that. As mentioned, I&amp;rsquo;ve been contributing to Bitcoin Core since 2011 and I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on various parts of bitcoin, such as the early payment channel work, some wallet stuff, and now I work for Chaincode Lab one of the sponsors&amp;ndash; we&amp;rsquo;re a bitcoin research lab. We all kind of hang out and work on various bitcoin projects we find interesting.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Security</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/dallas-bitcoin-symposium/bitcoin-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/dallas-bitcoin-symposium/bitcoin-security/</guid><description>Dhruv Bansal
Bitcoin security
Introduction Hi everyone, my name is Dhruv Bansal. I am the CTO of Unchained Capital. Thank you for the history lesson, Tuur. That&amp;rsquo;s a hard act to follow. I keep thinking about how it must have been like to transact large amounts of money back then. It was a fascinating time period. There was a lot of foundations laid for how the global financial system will work later in the future, like fractional reserve lending, loans, and so on.</description></item><item><title>Bitml</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/bitml/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/bitml/</guid><description>Developing secure bitcoin contracts using BitML
Stefano Lande
paper: https://arxiv.org/abs/1905.07639
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171695588116746240
This is shared work with my collaborators and coauthors.
Smart contracts I am sure everyone here knows what a smart contract is. It&amp;rsquo;s a program that can move cryptoassets. It&amp;rsquo;s executed in a decentralized environment. Generally speaking, we can say there&amp;rsquo;s two classes of smart contracts. A smart contract is a program. While in blockchain like bitcoin, smart contracts are cryptographic protocols.</description></item><item><title>Blind Signatures And Scriptless Scripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/blind-signatures-and-scriptless-scripts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/blind-signatures-and-scriptless-scripts/</guid><description>Blind signatures in scriptless scripts
Jonas Nick
Building on Bitcoin 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014197255593603072
My name is Jonas. I work at Blockstream as an engineer. I am going to talk about some primitives about blind signatures, scriptless scripts, and blind coin swap, and I will explain how to trustlessly exchange ecash tokens using bitcoin.
I want to introduce the blind Schnorr signature in a few moments.
Schnorr signature My assumption is not that you will completely understand Schnorr signatures, but maybe you will at least agree that if you can understand Schnorr signatures then the step to blind Schnorr signatures is not a big step.</description></item><item><title>Block Synchronization Time</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/block-synchronization-time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/block-synchronization-time/</guid><description>Initial Block Synchronization Time Complexity
slides: http://strateman.ninja/initial_block_synchronization.pdf
video: http://youtube.com/watch?v=TgjrS-BPWDQ&amp;amp;t=2h02m06s
Block synchronization is how nodes join the market. New nodes download the blockchain and validate everything. This is how the security of the network works. Who is responsible for doing this? Everyone must be doing a full block synchronization. If you are not doing this, you&amp;rsquo;re not on the bitcoin network. As a simple hypothesis, the block size growth is related to initial block synchronization as a simple function of the integral.</description></item><item><title>Blockchain Testbed</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/blockchain-testbed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/blockchain-testbed/</guid><description>Ittay Eyal
Emin Gun Sirer
A testbed for bitcoin scaling
I want to talk today about how to scale bitcoin. We want lower latency, we want higher throughput, more bandwidth and more transactions per second, and we want security. We can try to tune the parameters. In all of the plots, I have time going from left to right and these are blocks in rectangles. We have larger blocks which might give us more throughput.</description></item><item><title>Breaking The Chain</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/breaking-the-chain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/breaking-the-chain/</guid><description>Breaking the chain
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785144266683195392
http://dpaste.com/1ZYW028
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/milan/client-side-validation/
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong/braiding-the-blockchain/
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/milan/jute-braiding/
Inclusivitiy So it seems like we have two big topics here, one is braiding and one is proof-of-publication. I had a talk in Hong Kong about braiding. The major difference is the inclusive nature. The notion that every block gets a block reward as a way to solve selfish-mining. It&amp;rsquo;s a competition between the orphans that get a reward and the ones that don&amp;rsquo;t that causes a loss of security.</description></item><item><title>Btcpay</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/btcpay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/btcpay/</guid><description>How to make everyone run their own full node
Nicolas Dorier
Building on Bitcoin, 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014166857958461440
I am the maintainer of Nbitcoin and btcpay. I am a dot net fanboy. I am happy that the number of people working on bitcoin in C# has spread from one about four years ago to about ten in this room toay. That&amp;rsquo;s great. I work at DG Lab in Japan.
The goal of my talk is to continue what Jonas Schnelli was talking about.</description></item><item><title>Collective Signing</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/collective-signing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/collective-signing/</guid><description>Enhancing bitcoin security and performance with strong consistency via collective signing
Lefteris Kokoris-Kogias (LefKok), Philipp Jovanovic, Nicoas Gailly, Ismail Khoffi, Linus Gasser, Bryan Ford
EPFL
Eleftherios Kokoris Kogias
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785102844839985153
We are starting the session called &amp;ldquo;breaking the chain&amp;rdquo;. We will first have collective signing presentation. Thank you.
This is joint work with some collaborators.
What we have now is that real-time verification is not safe. What we managed to get is that we get transaction commitment in about 20-90 seconds at close to 1,000 transactions/second.</description></item><item><title>Competitive Fee Market Urgency</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/competitive-fee-market-urgency/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/competitive-fee-market-urgency/</guid><description>Marshall Long
The urgency of a competitive fee market to ensure a scalable future
I am Marshall. I run Firehash. CTO Cryptsy also. Some people have higher cost, some people have lower cost. I think those were some good estimates for true costs. I am going to be talking about why fees are going to be very important very soon. We&amp;rsquo;ll talk about what happens without fees, talk about why bitcoin really isn&amp;rsquo;t free but how we can do things like microtransactions, real microtransactions, talk about the cost and talk about solutions.</description></item><item><title>Crypto Castles</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/crypto-castles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/crypto-castles/</guid><description>Building your own bank and constructing crypto castles
Jameson Lopp
Building on Bitcoin 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014483571946508288
I am going to do a brain dump of basically anything that people who are building systems protecting private keys are thinking about. Hopefully you can ingest this for when you decide to build one of these systems.
If you have been in this space for long at all, you should be well aware that there are risks for trusting third-parties.</description></item><item><title>Crypto In Cryptocurrency</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/crypto-in-cryptocurrency/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/crypto-in-cryptocurrency/</guid><description>The &amp;ldquo;crypto&amp;rdquo; in cryptocurrency: Why everything is weird and hard
Andrew Poelstra
Video: https://youtu.be/mRl3c9ppO78
I do not have any slides for you. This is my attempt to keep this non-technical, by depriving myself of any ability to write equations on screen. The topic of my talk is why everything is weird and hard in cryptocurrency. What is cryptography as a mathematics and field of science? And how does this work in practice?</description></item><item><title>Cryptography Audit</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/cryptography-audit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/cryptography-audit/</guid><description>libsecp256k1-zkp audit
John Woeltz
It&amp;rsquo;s a real treat to be able to be a part of this.
Why bother? Just a high-level, why are we taking community resources to spend time on audits? There are some perspectives&amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s good for the community and it&amp;rsquo;s what you do.
Bitcoin had on professional security audits and did just fine. But it launched in a very different environment, and it did get audits eventually.</description></item><item><title>Current And Future State Of Wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/current-and-future-state-of-wallets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/current-and-future-state-of-wallets/</guid><description>Current and future state of wallets
jonasschnelli
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014127893495021568
Introduction I started to contribute to Bitcoin Core about 5 years ago. Since then, I have managed to get 450 commits merged. I am also the co-founder of a wallet hardware company based in Switzerland called Shift+ Cryptocurrency.
Wallets is not rocket science. It&amp;rsquo;s mostly about pointing the figure to things that we can do better. I prepared a lot of content.</description></item><item><title>Dan Boneh</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/verifiable-delay-functions/vdf-day-2019/dan-boneh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/verifiable-delay-functions/vdf-day-2019/dan-boneh/</guid><description>Verifiable delay functions
Dan Boneh
video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dN-1q8c50q0
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1152586087912673280
Introduction I&amp;rsquo;ll give an overview of VDFs and make sure that we&amp;rsquo;re on the same page. I want to make sure everyone knows what it is that we&amp;rsquo;re talking about.
The goal of a VDF is to slow things down. The question is, how do we slow things down in a verifiable way?
What is a VDF? I won&amp;rsquo;t give a precise definition, look at the manuscripts.</description></item><item><title>Day 2 Group Summaries</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/day-2-group-summaries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/day-2-group-summaries/</guid><description>Day 2 group summaries
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785151245883412480
Our epic journey in Milan is coming to an end. Let&amp;rsquo;s get seated. Each group is going to have a maximum of 3 minutes to report back. First let&amp;rsquo;s have collaboration between bitcoin community and academia.
Collaboration between bitcoin community and academia In the first half the workshop, 6 universities gave introductions of their activities and relationship to engineering and companies. We share the fact that most universities have joint research work with companies.</description></item><item><title>Exchange Security</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/exchange-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/exchange-security/</guid><description>Exchange security
Mitchell Dong
2017-03-04
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0mVOq1jaR1U&amp;amp;t=3h15m
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/838517545783148545
How often do you check your wallets? Have you ever looked in your wallet and found all your bitcoin gone or missing? Last summer, somebody, a friend of mine checked his wallet and found that 100,000 bitcoin was gone. What the hell, right? But that&amp;rsquo;s what happened at Bitfinex last summer. Some hacker got into their hot wallet and stole 100,000 bitcoin. This was $70 million bucks.</description></item><item><title>Extensibility</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/extensibility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/extensibility/</guid><description>Eric Lombrozo (CodeShark)
Extensibility, fraud proofs, and security models
slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY2/4_extensibility_lombrozo.pdf
Transcript pending, please email link to video to kanzure@gmail.com for transcribing&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Extracting Seeds From Hardware Wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/extracting-seeds-from-hardware-wallets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/extracting-seeds-from-hardware-wallets/</guid><description>Extracting seeds from hardware wallets
Charles Guillemet (P3b7_)
7DC5A359D0D5B5AB6728&amp;hellip;
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137672946435198976
Introduction My talk is about extracting seeds from hardware wallets. I am chief security officer at Ledger. I joined Ledger a bit more than one year ago. I built the Ledger Donjon which is an independent red team. Our mission is to help secure Ledger&amp;rsquo;s products. So what we do day to do is try to break all the hardware wallets.</description></item><item><title>Formal Verification</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/formal-verification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/formal-verification/</guid><description>Formal verification: The road to complete security of smart contracts
Martin Lundfall (MakerDAO)
slides: https://twitter.com/MartinLundfall/status/1091119463276064769
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1091103595016085504
Introduction Thank you everyone. It&amp;rsquo;s exciting to be here speaking about formal verification. The road to complete security of smart contracts is a sensationalist title. I&amp;rsquo;ll be spending a few moments making a huge disclaimer.
Disclaimer This can only be interpreted as a very long road or a very narrow sense in which complete security is actually cheap.</description></item><item><title>Fractal</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/fractal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/fractal/</guid><description>Fractal: Post-Quantum and Transparent Recursive Proofs from Holography
Nick Spooner
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230295372909514752
https://eprint.iacr.org/2019/1076.pdf
Introduction One of the most powerful things that you can do with SNARKs is something called recursive proofs where you actually prove that another SNARK was correct. I can give you a proof of a proof of a proof and this is amazing because you can prove an ever-expanding computation like a blockchain is always correct. I can always give you a proof that you have the latest block and you know the entire blockchain and all the transactions in it are correct.</description></item><item><title>Fraud Proofs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/fraud-proofs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/fraud-proofs/</guid><description>Improving SPV client validation and security with fraud proofs
Mustafa Al-Bassam (University College London)
paper: https://arxiv.org/pdf/1809.09044.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048446183004233731
Introduction I am going to be talking about fraud proofs. It allows lite clients to have a leve lof security of almost the level of a full node. Before I describe fraud proofs, how about we talk about motivations.
Motivations There&amp;rsquo;s a large tradeoff between blockchain decentralization and how much on-chain throughput you can get.</description></item><item><title>Ghostdag</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/ghostdag/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/ghostdag/</guid><description>The GHOSTDAG protocol
Yonatan Sompolinsky and Aviv Zohar (The Hebrew University of Jerusalem)
paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/104.pdf
Introduction This is joint work with Yonatan. I am going to talk about a DAG-based protocol to scale on-chain. The reason why I like this protocol is because it&amp;rsquo;s a very simple generalization of the longest-chain protocol that we all know and love. It gives some insight into what the role of proof-of-work is in these protocols.</description></item><item><title>Greg Maxwell - 51 percent mining attack (2019–10-04)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2019-10-04-majority-miner-attack/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2019-10-04-majority-miner-attack/</guid><description>Name: Greg Maxwell
Topic: Should we be more concerned by the prospect of a 51 percent mining attack?
Location: Reddit
Date: October 4th 2019
https://www.reddit.com/r/Bitcoin/comments/ddddfl/comment/f2g9e7b/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3
Should we be more concerned by the prospect of a 51 percent mining attack? I think questions like this are ultimately the result of a fundamental lack of understanding about what Bitcoin is doing.
The problem Bitcoin is attempting to solve is getting everyone everywhere to agree on the same stable history of transactions.</description></item><item><title>Greg Maxwell - Yubikey Security (2020-11-05)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2020-11-05-greg-maxwell-yubikey-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2020-11-05-greg-maxwell-yubikey-security/</guid><description>Name: Greg Maxwell
Topic: Yubikey security
Location: Reddit
Date: November 7th 2020
https://www.reddit.com/r/Bitcoin/comments/jp2fp3/opinion_regarding_security/gbhojor?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web2x&amp;amp;context=3
Yubikey Security By this logic, a yubikey would also be a great targeting vector.
They would be, and if US intelligence services have not compromised yubis or at least have a perfect targeted substitution solutions for them then they should all be fired for gross incompetence and mismanagement of their funding.
Likewise, if parties which things of significant value to secure who might be targeted by state level attackers are securing those things with just yubs instead of using yubis as a second factor in an otherwise secure setup then those parties ought to be fired too.</description></item><item><title>Groups</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/rebooting-web-of-trust/2019-prague/groups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/rebooting-web-of-trust/2019-prague/groups/</guid><description>Group 1: Agents We talked about minimal requirements for &amp;hellip; a different set of protocols and other implementations, and we asked the question, what&amp;rsquo;s out there for being able to create a minimal requirement for&amp;hellip; Are we able to map this and pull it all down into a minimal requirement architecture for an agent without having to buy into the whole stack? What about building an agent for a smartphone or a feature phone, and then move on from there?</description></item><item><title>Hardening Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/hardening-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/hardening-lightning/</guid><description>Hardening lightning network
Olaoluwa Osuntokun (roasbeef), Lightning Labs
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/959155562134102016
video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V3f4yYVCxpk
slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/14NuX5LTDSmmfYbAn0NupuXnXpfoZE0nXsG7CjzPXdlA/edit
previous talk (2017): http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/lightning-network-security-analysis/
previous slides (2017): https://cyber.stanford.edu/sites/default/files/olaoluwaosuntokun.pdf
Introduction I am basically going to go over some ways that I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about basically hardening lightning network, in terms of making security better and making the client more scalable itself, and then I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about some issues and pain points that come up when you&amp;rsquo;re doing fees on mainnet.</description></item><item><title>In Adversarial Environments Blockchains Dont Scale</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/in-adversarial-environments-blockchains-dont-scale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/in-adversarial-environments-blockchains-dont-scale/</guid><description>petertodd
slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY1/2_security_and_incentives_2_todd.pdf
video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ivgxcEOyWNs&amp;amp;t=30m35s
That was a very useful talk (on security assumptions), thank you Andrew.
I am going to start by talking about nitty-gritty applications where adversarial thinking is useful for incentives for decentralization. In an environment where everyone has the data, we are kind of limited as to what we can do. When we talk about scale, I am talking about 5 or 10 orders of magnitude. Do we have a system that has fundamentally different scaling characteristics?</description></item><item><title>Introduction (2019)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/introduction/</guid><description>Introduction to DFA Workshop We are an international conference that focuses on the latest development in software and its scalability in the bitcoin ecosystem. We have come here to Israel. We are running 5 days of events, including this current workshop. Over the next 4 days following today, we&amp;rsquo;re running Bitcoin Edge Dev++ workshop at Tel Aviv University for 2 days, and then Scaling Bitcoin for 2 days which is compromised of over 44 high tech sessions on complex scalability and security related topics in the bitcoin ecosystem, mainly for developers.</description></item><item><title>Investing In Bitcoin Businesses</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/investing-in-bitcoin-businesses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/investing-in-bitcoin-businesses/</guid><description>1 on 1: Investing in bitcoin businesses
Nic Carter (nic__carter)
Florian Maier (Marsmensch)
Matthew Mezinskis (crypto_voices) (moderator)
MM: I run a podcast based here in Latvia on bitcoin economics and money. It&amp;rsquo;s American-Latvian. I do it with my partner who is based in Brazil. Today we&amp;rsquo;re going to focus on investing in businesses focused on bitcoin and crypto.
NC: My name is Nic Carter. I work for a venture fund. We&amp;rsquo;re one of the few venture funds that focus on bitcoin and bitcoin-related startups.</description></item><item><title>John Newbery Security Models (2019-06-17)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-17-john-newbery-security-models/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-17-john-newbery-security-models/</guid><description>Name: John Newbery
Topic: Security Models
Location: Chaincode Labs 2019 Residency
Video: https://youtu.be/6gGcS4N5Rg4
Slides: https://residency.chaincode.com/presentations/bitcoin/security_models.pdf
John Newbery: Alright, Security Models. This is going to be like a quick whistle-stop tour of various things, very high-level view. I&amp;rsquo;m going to start by giving you some kind of framework to think about things. So in cryptography, we often talk about security proofs in terms of existing schemes, we talk about assumptions.
So, for example&amp;hellip; If you can break new scheme B, then you&amp;rsquo;ll also be able to break old scheme A.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Routing Security</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-routing-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-routing-security/</guid><description>Security aspects of LN routing
Joost Jager, Lightning Labs
D146 D0F6 8939 4362 68FA 9A13 0E26 BB61 B76C 4D3A
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137740282139676672
Introduction Together with my colleagues I am building lnd. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the implementations of lightning. In routing, there&amp;rsquo;s the sender of the payment, the intermediate routing nodes that forward payments, and a receiver. I would like to scope this down to looking at security just from the perspective of the sender.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Security Analysis</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/lightning-network-security-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/lightning-network-security-analysis/</guid><description>Security analysis of the lightning network (2017)
Olaoluwa Osuntokun (roasbeef), Lightning Labs
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/957978915515092992
video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Eq_eY8iWrKI
slides: https://cyber.stanford.edu/sites/default/files/olaoluwaosuntokun.pdf
Introduction My name is Laolu Osuntokun and I work on lightning stuff. I go by roasbeef on the internet. I work at Lightning Labs. I am going to be giving an overview of some security properties and privacy properties of lightning.
State of the hash-lock Before I start, I want to go over the state of the hash-lock which is the current progress to completion and design of lightning.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Security Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-security-panel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-security-panel/</guid><description>Lightning network security panel
Olaoluwa Osuntokun, Justin Camarena, Matt Corallo, Michael Folkson
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137758233865703424
Introduction MF: I will start by thanking Kevin and Lea and the organizers. It&amp;rsquo;s been an awesome event. Thanks also to the sponsors. Without their assistance we couldn&amp;rsquo;t have had the event. I&amp;rsquo;d also like to make some plugs before we start the conversation. One, I run the London Bitcoin developers group. If you&amp;rsquo;re ever in London or interested in speaking, please look up London Bitcoin Devs on Twitter or Meetup.</description></item><item><title>Matsuo</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/matsuo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/matsuo/</guid><description>Shinichiro Matsuo
bsafe.network
Giving trust by security evaluation and bsafe.network
This is a severe problem. How can we trust the output of blockchain technology? We have several security issues. There was the huge DAO attack from two weeks ago. We also have other problems, such as protocol specification, key management, implementation, operation, and vulnerability handling. Also key renewal and key revocation issues.
ISO/IEC 27000 ISO/IEC 15408 ISO/IEC 29128 ISO/IEC 29128 ISO/IEC, NIST IETF We already have several international standards on each layer.</description></item><item><title>Matt Corallo Sidechains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/matt-corallo-sidechains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/matt-corallo-sidechains/</guid><description>Matt Corallo (BlueMatt)
Sidechains, Blockstream
One second. Technical difficulties. Okay, sorry about that. Okay. Hi. I am Matt or BlueMatt for those of you know me. I swear it&amp;rsquo;s not related to my hair. Nobody believes me.
I got into Bitcoin three or four years ago because I was interested in the programming and computer science aspects and as well as my interest in large-scale economic incentive structures and macroeconomics and how we create incentive structures that create actions on a low level by rational actors.</description></item><item><title>Michael Flaxman - Security Guide (2020-09-28)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-09-28-michael-flaxman-security-guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-09-28-michael-flaxman-security-guide/</guid><description>Name: Michael Flaxman
Topic: 10x your Bitcoin security with Multisig
Location: Stephan Livera Podcast
Date: September 28th 2020
Audio: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/215/
Previous SLP episode with Michael Flaxman: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/stephan-livera-podcast/2019-08-08-michael-flaxman/
10x Security Bitcoin Guide: https://btcguide.github.io/
Transcript completed by: Stephan Livera Edited by: Michael Folkson
10x Security Bitcoin Guide Stephan Livera (SL): Michael, welcome back to the show.
Michael Flaxman (MF): It’s great to be here. I’m a big fan of the podcast so I love to be on it.</description></item><item><title>Microchains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/microchains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/microchains/</guid><description>Microchains
David Vorick
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/927257690685939712
I would like to see a blockchain ecosystem with 1000s of transactions/second at layer 1 with full security. And so, we have to look at blockchain differently if we are going to achieve this.
A brief introduction&amp;hellip; my name is David Vorick. I have been studying bitcoin since 2011. My primary gig is Sia. I have been spending a lot of time on consensus algorithms and proof-of-work.</description></item><item><title>Mining Firmware Security</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/edgedevplusplus/mining-firmware-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/edgedevplusplus/mining-firmware-security/</guid><description>Mining firmware security
James Hilliard
slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1apJRD1BwskElWP0Yb1C_tXmGYA_vkx9rjS8VTDW_Z3A/edit?usp=sharing</description></item><item><title>Multi Hop Locks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-hop-locks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-hop-locks/</guid><description>Multi-hop locks for secure, privacy-preserving and interoperable payment-channel networks
Giulio Malavolta (Friedrich-Alexander-University Erlangen-Nuernberg), Pedro Moreno-Sanchez (Purdue University), Clara Schneidewind (Vienna University of Technology), Aniket Kate (Purdue University) and Matteo Maffei (Vienna University of Technology)
https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/472.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048476273259900928
This is joint work with my colleagues. I promise I will talk slower than the last talk. In a multi-hop network, the security tool is a hash-time lock contract (HTLC) where the payment is conditioned on revealing the pre-image of a hash function.</description></item><item><title>Near Misses</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/near-misses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/near-misses/</guid><description>Near misses: What could have gone wrong
Ethan Heilman
Introduction Thank you. I am Ethan Heilman. I am a research whose has done a bunch of work in security of cryptocurrencies. I am also CTO of Arwen which does secure atomic swaps. I am a little sick today so please excuse my coughing, wheezing and drinking lots of water.
Bitcoin scary stories The general outline of this talk is going to be &amp;ldquo;scary stories in bitcoin&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Neutrino</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/neutrino/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/neutrino/</guid><description>Neutrino bip158
Jimmy Song
&amp;hellip; 228C D70C FAA6 17E3 2679 E455
bip157 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; bip158
Introduction I want to start this talk with a question for the audience. How many of you have a mobile wallet on your phone right now? How many know the security model that the wallets are using? Okay, how many of you trust those security assumptions? Okay, less of you. I am going to talk about Neutrino.</description></item><item><title>Nix Bitcoin (2020-07-26)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-07-26-nix-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-07-26-nix-bitcoin/</guid><description>Name: nixbitcoindev
Topic: nix-bitcoin
Location: Stephan Livera Podcast
Date: July 26th 2020
Audio: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/195/
nix-bitcoin on GitHub: https://github.com/fort-nix/nix-bitcoin
Transcript completed by: Stephan Livera Edited by: Michael Folkson
Intro Stephan Livera (SL): nixbitcoindev welcome to the show.
nixbitcoindev (NBD): Hello. Thank you for having me.
SL: Obviously as you’re under a pseudonym don’t dox anything about yourself but can you just tell us what you’re interested in about Bitcoin and is it the computer science aspects or what aspects of it interest you?</description></item><item><title>On The Security And Performance Of Proof Of Work Blockchains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/on-the-security-and-performance-of-proof-of-work-blockchains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/on-the-security-and-performance-of-proof-of-work-blockchains/</guid><description>On the security and performance of proof-of-work blockchains
Arthur Gervais
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785066988532068352
As most of you might know, in bitcoin and blockchains, the information is very important. Every node should receive the blocks in the network. Increase latency and risk network partition. If individual peers do not get the information, they could be victims of selfish mining and so on. Multiple blockchains has been proposed, multiple reparameterizations like litecoin, dogecoin, ethereum and others.</description></item><item><title>Overview Of Bips Necessary For Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/overview-of-bips-necessary-for-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/overview-of-bips-necessary-for-lightning/</guid><description>Tadge Dryja
Scalability of Lightning with different BIPs and some back-of-the-envelope calculations.
slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY2/1_layer2_2_dryja.pdf
video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fst1IK_mrng&amp;amp;t=1h5m50s
I don&amp;rsquo;t have time to introduce the idea of zero-confirmation transactions and lightning. We have given talks about this. There&amp;rsquo;s some documentation available. There&amp;rsquo;s an implementation being worked on. I think it helps a lot with scalability by keeping some transactions off the blockchain. Ideally, many or most transactions. Instead, you would open and close channels.</description></item><item><title>Overview Of Security Concerns</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/overview-of-security-concerns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/overview-of-security-concerns/</guid><description>petertodd
Overview of Security Concerns
I am going to talk about scale-related security issues. Scale-related security issues. I said scale, not scalability. We are not talking about scalability. We&amp;rsquo;re talking about changing numbers, and what are the implications, what attacks are easier or harder by changing the block size number. What are we trying to accomplish? What is the system meant to be? Nobody really agrees of course. What&amp;rsquo;s interesting is that as much as we disagree about what was meant to be, there are a lot of key things about what bitcoin could be, these visions share some details.</description></item><item><title>Prism</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/prism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/prism/</guid><description>Prism: Scaling bitcoin to physical limits
Vivek Bagaria
Introduction Prism is a consensus protocol which is a one-stop solution to all of bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s scaling problems. The title is 7 to 70000 transactions per second. We have a full stack implementation of prism running and we were able to obtain 70,000 transactions/second. Before we get started, here are my collaborators.
This workshop is on scaling bitcoin so I won&amp;rsquo;t spend any time justifying why we would want to scale bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Prism</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/prism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/prism/</guid><description>Prism: Scaling bitcoin by 10,000x
Lei Yang
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230634530110730241
https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/prism/
Introduction Hello everyone. I am excited to be here to talk about our implementation and evaluation of the Prism consensus protocol which achieves 10,000x better performance than bitcoin. This is a multi-university collaboration between MIT, Stanford and a few others. I&amp;rsquo;d like to thank my collaborators, including my advisor, and other people.
Bitcoin performance We all know that bitcoin has good security, but in terms of performance it is not so good.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Anonymity And Identity Group</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/privacy-anonymity-and-identity-group/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/privacy-anonymity-and-identity-group/</guid><description>Anonymous identity
Another part of it is that all of those IoT things have firmware that can update. The moment that someone gets a key to update this, you can hack the grid by making rapid changes on power usage which actually destroys the &amp;hellip;. do the standards make things less secure? It should be illegal to design broken cryptosystems. Engineers should go to jail. It&amp;rsquo;s too dangerous. Do you think there should be smart grids at all?</description></item><item><title>Proof Of Stake</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/proof-of-stake/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/proof-of-stake/</guid><description>Proof-of-stake longest chain protocols revisited
David Tse
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230646529230163968
Introduction Thanks. I am the last talk of the session so I better make it interesting, and if not interesting then short at least. I am going to talk about proof-of-stake. This is collaboration with a few people. Vivek Bagaria, &amp;hellip; et al.
Proof-of-stake prism The starting point of this project was to come up with a proof-of-stake version of prism, which we just saw in the last talk.</description></item><item><title>Protecting Yourself And Your Business</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/edgedevplusplus/protecting-yourself-and-your-business/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/edgedevplusplus/protecting-yourself-and-your-business/</guid><description>Exchange security: Protecting yourself and your business
Warren Togami
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048087226742071296
Introduction Hello. My name is Warren Togami and I will be talking about exchange security. Not only protecting the people but also the business. This has been a topic of interest recently.
Warren&amp;rsquo;s security background I have some credibility when it comes to security due to my previous career in open-source software. I have been working on the Linux operating system first with Fedora then with Red Hat for many years.</description></item><item><title>Relay Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/relay-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/relay-network/</guid><description>It was indicative of two issues. A lot of people were reducing their security model by not validating their bitcoin. It was potentially less secure. That&amp;rsquo;s not something that relay networks try to address. The big issue with the decreasing number of nodes, which the relay network doesn&amp;rsquo;t address, is that it reduces the resilience against attack. If there&amp;rsquo;s only 100 nodes, there&amp;rsquo;s really only some 100 VPses that you have to knock offline before the bitcoin network stops working.</description></item><item><title>Rodolfo Novak Coldcard Mk3 (2019-09-14)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2019/2019-09-14-rodolfo-novak-coldcard-mk3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2019/2019-09-14-rodolfo-novak-coldcard-mk3/</guid><description>Name: Rodolfo Novak
Topic: Coldcard Mk3 - Security in Depth
Location: Baltic Honeybadger 2019
Date: September 14th 2019
Audio: https://youtu.be/2IpZWSWUIVE?t=23739
Intro My name is Rodolfo, I have been around Bitcoin for a little while. We make hardware. Today I wanted to get a little bit into how do you make a hardware wallet secure in a little bit more layman’s terms. Go through the process of getting that done.
What were the options When I closed my last company and decided to find a place to store my coins I couldn’t really find a wallet that satisfied two things that I needed.</description></item><item><title>Rootstock</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/rootstock/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/rootstock/</guid><description>Rootstock
Sergio Lerner
Sergio is co-founder and chief scientist at RSK Labs. The whitepaper was pretty good. I am happy that he is here. Thank you. Just give me a minute.
Alicia Bendhan Lous Parker BitDevsNYC
Yes, I use powerpoint. Please don&amp;rsquo;t read my emails.
Thanks everyone for staying here and not going to the next room. Thanks for the organizers for inviting me. Today I am going to talk about Rootstock.</description></item><item><title>Safecurves - Choosing Safe Curves For Elliptic Curve Cryptography (2014)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/safecurves-choosing-safe-curves-for-elliptic-curve-cryptography-2014/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/safecurves-choosing-safe-curves-for-elliptic-curve-cryptography-2014/</guid><description>SafeCurves: Choosing Safe Curves for Elliptic Curve Cryptography
Daniel J. Bernstein (djb) and Tanja Lange
SchmooCon 2014
video 1: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dFUJmzcj0iw&amp;amp;list=PLgO7JBj821uGZTXEXBLckChu70kl7Celh&amp;amp;index=15
video 2 (same?): https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=maBOorEfOOk&amp;amp;list=PLgO7JBj821uGZTXEXBLckChu70kl7Celh&amp;amp;index=91
Video intro text There are several different standards covering selection of curves for use in elliptic-curve cryptography (ECC). Each of these standards tries to ensure that the elliptic-curve discrete-logarithm problem (ECDLP) is difficult. ECDLP is the problem of finding an ECC user&amp;rsquo;s secret key, given the user&amp;rsquo;s public key.</description></item><item><title>Schnorr Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/schnorr-signatures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/schnorr-signatures/</guid><description>Name: Pieter Wuille
Topic: Schnorr signatures for Bitcoin
Location: Scaling Bitcoin (Milan)
Date: October 10th 2016
Video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_Z0ID-0DOnc&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;amp;t=2297
Slides: URL expired
Pieter Wuille presentation on Schnorr at BPASE 2018: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/schnorr-signatures-for-bitcoin-challenges-opportunities/
Transcript completed by: Bryan Bishop Edited by: Michael Folkson
Intro Today I will be talking about Schnorr signatures for Bitcoin. I want to say a few things in advance. One is even though this is a talk about cryptography and in particular new cryptography I don&amp;rsquo;t consider myself to be a cryptographer.</description></item><item><title>Secure Fountain Architecture</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/secure-fountain-architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/secure-fountain-architecture/</guid><description>A secure fountain architecture for slashing storage costs in blockchains
Swanand Kadhe (UC Berkeley)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1172158545577594880
paper: https://arxiv.org/abs/1906.12140
Introduction I know this is the last formal talk of the day so thank you so much for being here. This is joint work with my collaborators.
Is storage really an issue for bitcoin? Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s blockchain size is only 238 GB. So why is storage important? But blockchain size is a growing problem. It&amp;rsquo;s always going to go up.</description></item><item><title>Security And Usability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/security-and-usability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/security-and-usability/</guid><description>Melanie Shapiro Alan Reiner Kristov Atlas Elizabeth Stark (moderator) and maybe Melanie Shapiro? malani? Security and usability.
Elizabeth: I think this is a highly relevant discussion. I talked a bit about regulation. Regulation might be the number threat, but security might be the number two threat. I am excited to have a panel of leaders in this space who are actively building in this ecosystem. I am going to ask each to do a quick intro.</description></item><item><title>Security Assumptions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/security-assumptions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/security-assumptions/</guid><description>Andrew Poelstra (andytoshi)
Security Assumptions
video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ivgxcEOyWNs&amp;amp;t=9m20s
Hi, welcome back.
I am a developer for libsecp256k1. It&amp;rsquo;s a library that does the underlying traditional cryptography used in Bitcoin. I am going to talk about security assumptions, security models and trust models. I am going to give a high-level overview of how we should be thinking about these issues for scaling and efficiency and decentralization. Bitcoin is a crypto system. Everything about it is a crypto system.</description></item><item><title>Security Attacks Decentralized Mining Pools</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/security-attacks-decentralized-mining-pools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/security-attacks-decentralized-mining-pools/</guid><description>Security and attacks on decentralized mining pools
Alexei Zamyatin
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137373752038240262
Introduction Hi, I am Alexei. I am a research student at Imperial College London and I will be talking about the security of decentralized mining pools.
Motivation The motivation behind this talk is straightforward. I think we can all agree that to some extent the hashrate in bitcoin has seen some centralization around large mining pools, which undermines the base properties of censorship resistance in bitcoin which I think bitcoin solves in a nice matter.</description></item><item><title>Segwit Lessons Learned</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/segwit-lessons-learned/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/segwit-lessons-learned/</guid><description>Lessons learned with segwit in Bitcoin
Greg Sanders (instagibbs)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785034301272420353
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_Z0ID-0DOnc
Hi. My name is Greg Sanders. I will be giving a talk about segwit in bitcoin lessons learned. I will also give some takeaways that I think are important. A little bit about myself. I work on Elements Project at Blockstream. I was a reviewer on segwit for Bitcoin Core. How do we scale protocol development? How do we scale review and keep things safe?</description></item><item><title>Sergei Tikhomirov - Lightning Privacy (2020-05-09)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2020-05-09-sergei-tikhomirov-lightning-privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2020-05-09-sergei-tikhomirov-lightning-privacy/</guid><description>Name: Sergei Tikhomirov
Topic: Quantitative Analysis of Lightning Network Privacy
Location: Lightning Hacksprint (Fulmo)
Date: May 9th 2020
Video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8lUTbfO94mM
Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1H9EdrhjQ9x3q0qfsei7iFYINVf2lwPyjUKHd3CScy4k/edit#slide=id.g7774542944_0_0
Paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/303
Intro Hello everyone. I am Sergei, I am a PhD student at the University of Luxembourg. I am going to present our joint work with Pedro Moreno-Sanchez and Matteo Maffei from TU Wien on certain aspects of the privacy and scalability of the Lightning Network. The full paper can be found here.</description></item><item><title>Smart Contract Bug Hunting</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/smart-contract-bug-hunting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/smart-contract-bug-hunting/</guid><description>Finding Bugs Automatically in Smart Contracts with Parameterized Specifications
Mooly Sagiv
https://www.certora.com/pubs/sbc2020.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230906600140918784
Introduction I am from Tel Aviv University and now we have a 1-year old company called Cotera which is located in Berlin, Seattle and Tel Aviv. Our mission is to bring formal methods into code security and I will talk to you today about how we use this method to find bugs. And actually, I try to make this talk as informal as possible but there is actually a paper just download it from the certora website.</description></item><item><title>Socratic Seminar - AssumeUTXO (2021-11-02)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2021-11-02-socratic-seminar-assumeutxo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2021-11-02-socratic-seminar-assumeutxo/</guid><description>Name: Socratic Seminar
Topic: AssumeUTXO
Location: London BitDevs (online)
Date: November 2nd 2021
Video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JottwT-kEdg
Reading list: https://gist.github.com/michaelfolkson/f46a7085af59b2e7b9a79047155c3993
Intros Michael Folkson (MF): This is a discussion on AssumeUTXO. We are lucky to have James O’Beirne on the call. There is a reading list that I will share in a second with a bunch of links going right from concept, some of the podcasts James has done, a couple of presentations James has done.</description></item><item><title>State Of Multisig</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/state-of-multisig/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/state-of-multisig/</guid><description>State of multisig for bitcoin hodlers: Better wallets with PSBT
Justin Moon
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1162769521993834496
Introduction I am going to be talking about the state of multisig. It&amp;rsquo;s a way of creating a transaction output that requires multiple keys to sign. This is a focus for people holding bitcoin. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about some of the benefits and some of the issues. I am not a security expert, though.
Perspective Multisig is an emphasis on saving and not spending a lot.</description></item><item><title>Statechains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/statechains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/statechains/</guid><description>Statechains: Off-chain transfer of UTXOs
Ruben Somsen
I am the education director of readingbitcoin.org, and I am going to be talking about statechains for off-chain transfer of UTXOs.
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048799338703376385
Statechains This is another layer 2 scaling solution, by avoiding on-chain transactions. It&amp;rsquo;s similar to lightning network. The difference is that coin movement is not restricted. You deon&amp;rsquo;t have these channels where you have to have a path and send an exact amount.</description></item><item><title>Tadge Dryja - How much Security is too much Security? Defending against a 99.999% Attack (2021-04-03)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2021/2021-04-03-defending-against-99-attack/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2021/2021-04-03-defending-against-99-attack/</guid><description>Name: Tadge Dryja
Topic: How much Security is too much Security? Defending Against a 99.999% Attack
Date: 2021-04-03
Location: Online
Video: https://mitbitcoinexpo.org/ - Day 1, Part 1 @ 38:15
Introduction Hi everyone, it&amp;rsquo;s too bad that we can&amp;rsquo;t be in person but I think by next year we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to do this in person. It&amp;rsquo;s been a long year without conferences. And I guess for maybe many people watching the MIT Bitcoin Expo last March, was the last time I saw a bunch of people in person before this whole thing.</description></item><item><title>The Bitcoin Standard</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/the-bitcoin-standard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/the-bitcoin-standard/</guid><description>The bitcoin standard as a layered scaling solution
Saifedean Ammous (via skype) (saifedean)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043425514801844224
Hello, everyone. Can everyone hear me? Okay, wonderful. You can&amp;rsquo;t see my slides, can you. You have to share the screen if you want them to see your slides. How do I do that? Where is that? This is new skype, I&amp;rsquo;m sorry. Thank you everyone for inviting me to speak today. It would be great to join you, but unforutnately I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it.</description></item><item><title>Topics</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/rebooting-web-of-trust/2019-prague/topics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/rebooting-web-of-trust/2019-prague/topics/</guid><description>Rebooting Web of Trust topic selection
Dictionary terms: we have a glossary that I wrote 6 months ago which by definition glosses everything. A dictionary would give an opportunity to go into more depth, to look at disagreements without getting lost in the weeds, and also talk about some foundational assumptions.
Verifiable secret sharing: this is a modification for Shamir secret sharing that also incorporates multisignatures as well. We&amp;rsquo;re interested in solidifying that into an actual proposal and talk about the pro&amp;rsquo;s of con&amp;rsquo;s of traditional secret sharing and this scheme and whether you should be using multisig as opposed to Shamir secret sharing in your application and provide some guidance there.</description></item><item><title>Trustlessness Scalability And Directions In Security Models</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/trustlessness-scalability-and-directions-in-security-models/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/trustlessness-scalability-and-directions-in-security-models/</guid><description>Trustlessness, scalability and directions in security models
Matt Corallo (bluematt)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043397023846883329
&amp;hellip; Is everyone awake? Sure. Jumping jacks. Wow, that&amp;rsquo;s bright. I am more idealistic than Eric. I am going to talk about utility and why people use bitcoin and let&amp;rsquo;s see how that goes.
Trustlessness is much better than decentralization. I want to talk about trustlessness. People use the word decentralization a lot and I find that to be kind of useless because decentralization is a means to an end.</description></item><item><title>Wallet Security, Key Management &amp; HSMs (2018-10-04)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/edgedevplusplus/wallet-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/edgedevplusplus/wallet-security/</guid><description>Bryan Bishop
Wallet Security, Key Management &amp;amp; Hardware Security Modules (HSMs)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1049813559750746112
Dev++ / BC2 - October 4th-5th 2018 - Keio University, Tokyo, Japan https://bitcoinedge.org/event/keio-devplusplus-2018
schedule: https://keio-devplusplus-2018.bitcoinedge.org/#schedule
video: https://youtu.be/WcOIXsOLJ3w?t=3550
Intro Alright, I’m now going to talk about bitcoin wallet security. And I was asked to talk about key management and hardware security modules and a bunch of other topics all in one talk. This will be a bit broader than some of the other talks because this is an important subject about how do you actually store bitcoin and then some of the developments around the actual storage of bitcoin in a secure way.</description></item><item><title>Why Miners Will Not Voluntarily Individually Produce Smaller Blocks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/why-miners-will-not-voluntarily-individually-produce-smaller-blocks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/why-miners-will-not-voluntarily-individually-produce-smaller-blocks/</guid><description>Jonathan Bier
slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY1/2_security_and_incentives_3_bier.pdf
video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ivgxcEOyWNs&amp;amp;t=1h30s
Marginal cost is very low.
In about 2011, people started discussing the idea of needing an artificial cap for a block size limit to kind of kick up the transaction fees. The orphan risk is a marginal cost the larger the block, the higher the chance of an orphan.
Now I&amp;rsquo;ve got some issues why orphan risk may not be so great. As technology improves, over time the technology cost of orphaning gets lower and lower, so you are relying on driving miner revenue or fees, would become less relevant.</description></item></channel></rss>