<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Schnorr signatures on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/schnorr-signatures/</link><description>Recent content in Schnorr signatures on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/schnorr-signatures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Libsec Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/libsec-panel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/libsec-panel/</guid><description>Intros NVK: I have an absolute rock star team here. So why don&amp;rsquo;t I start introducing the panel? Tim, hello! Do you want to tell a very brief what do you do?
Tim: Yes, so my name is Tim Ruffing. I am a maintainer of the libsecp256k1 library. I do work for Blockstream, who pay me to do this and also who pay me to do research on cryptography and all kinds of aspects related to Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>ROAST: Robust asynchronous Schnorr threshold signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-14-roast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-14-roast/</guid><description>paper: https://ia.cr/2022/550
slides: https://slides.com/real-or-random/roast-tabconf22/
Hey. Hello. My name is Tim and I work at Blockstream. This is some academic work in joint with some of my coworkers.
Schnorr signatures in Bitcoin We recently got support for Schnorr signatures in bitcoin, introduced as part of bip340 which was activated as part of the taproot soft-fork. There are three main reasons why we want Schnorr signatures and prefer them over ECDSA bitcoin signatures which can still be used: one is that Schnorr signatures have provable security and give the theory guys more confidence; Schnorr signatures are more efficient; and the main thing is that we can get easier constructions of advanced signing protocols.</description></item><item><title>How to Design Schnorr Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinology/how-to-design-schnorr-signatures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinology/how-to-design-schnorr-signatures/</guid><description>Passwords So, I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk to you today about passwords and about the problem with passwords and how we might be able to solve it, right? So we&amp;rsquo;re all familiar with using passwords on the internet and we&amp;rsquo;re all sort of sometimes annoyed about it. Maybe you use a password manager, maybe you don&amp;rsquo;t, but you have this problem, I think we all understand this problem that it&amp;rsquo;s not just about you losing the password, but it&amp;rsquo;s also about keeping it secret, right?</description></item><item><title>Schnorr Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/schnorr-signatures-jimmy-song/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/schnorr-signatures-jimmy-song/</guid><description>Introduction Anyway, like I said, this is a technical talk and we&amp;rsquo;re going to talk about Schnorr signatures and the benefits that it brings. So let&amp;rsquo;s get started.
Agenda So here&amp;rsquo;s the agenda. We&amp;rsquo;re going to talk about, we&amp;rsquo;re going to review the signature algorithm that&amp;rsquo;s currently on Bitcoin. This is Elliptic Curve Digital Signature Algorithm or ECDSA. Then we&amp;rsquo;re going to go describe what Schnorr signatures are. And then we&amp;rsquo;re going to go over all of the key and signature aggregation stuff that you can do or some of the benefits that you get out of Schnorr.</description></item><item><title>Taproot and Schnorr Multisignatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-17-tim-ruffing-schnorr-multisig/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-17-tim-ruffing-schnorr-multisig/</guid><description>Location: London Bitcoin Devs (online)
Slides: https://slides.com/real-or-random/taproot-and-schnorr-multisig
Transcript of the previous day’s Socratic Seminar on BIP-Schnorr: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-16-socratic-seminar-bip-schnorr/
Intro (Michael Folkson) We are now live. This is London Bitcoin Devs with Tim Ruffing. We had the Socratic Seminar yesterday, I think we have some people on the call that were at the Socratic Seminar. That was brilliant. Thanks to Tim, Pieter, Greg, waxwing and everyone for showing up and taking 2 and a half hours out of their day.</description></item><item><title>Socratic Seminar - BBIP Schnorr (BIP 340)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-16-socratic-seminar-bip-schnorr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-16-socratic-seminar-bip-schnorr/</guid><description>Pastebin of the resources discussed: https://pastebin.com/uyktht33
August 2020 update: Since this Socratic on BIP Schnorr there has been a proposed change to the BIP revisting the squaredness tiebreaker for the R point.
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have given permission for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.</description></item><item><title>Schnorr Taproot Tapscript BIPs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2019-12-27-aj-towns-schnorr-taproot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2019-12-27-aj-towns-schnorr-taproot/</guid><description>Stephan Livera: AJ, welcome to the show.
AJ Towns: Howdy.
Stephan Livera: Thanks for joining me AJ. I know you’re doing a lot of really cool work with the Schnorr and Taproot proposal and the review club. But let’s start with a bit of your background and I know you’re working at Xapo as well.
AJ Towns: Yeah so I’m working at Xapo on Bitcoin Core dev, which means that I get to do open source work full time and get paid for it and it’s pretty freaking awesome.</description></item><item><title>Schnorr and Taproot workshop</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinops/2019-09-27-schnorr-taproot-workshop/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinops/2019-09-27-schnorr-taproot-workshop/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs, NYC
https://github.com/bitcoinops/taproot-workshop
https://bitcoinops.slack.com
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1177697093462482949
Run: jupyter notebook
See also Schnorr signatures and taproot: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2018-07-09-taproot-schnorr-signatures-and-sighash-noinput-oh-my/
https://github.com/sipa/bips/blob/bip-schnorr/bip-schnorr.mediawiki
https://github.com/sipa/bips/blob/bip-schnorr/bip-taproot.mediawiki
https://github.com/sipa/bips/blob/bip-schnorr/bip-tapscript.mediawiki
Why Schnorr and why taproot? Who here already feels comfortbale with Schnorr/Taproot? This is a proposed consensus change to bitcoin. When we talk about consensus changes, we often talk about tradeoffs and compromises. It would be irresponsible to say taproot has no downsides, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s important to mention it&amp;rsquo;s a clear win for bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Tales from the Crypt with Andrew Poelstra</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tftc-podcast/2019-06-18-andrew-poelstra-tftc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tftc-podcast/2019-06-18-andrew-poelstra-tftc/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1160178010986876928
Podcast: https://talesfromthecrypt.libsyn.com/tales-from-the-crypt-80-andrew-poelstra
How the idea of Taproot was formed Andrew: There are some small off suit IRC channels of bitcoin-wizards where people discuss some specific topics such as Minisketch which is a set reconciliation protocol that was developed by Greg Maxwell, Pieter Wuille and Gleb Naumenko among a couple of others. It was mostly those three. They have a channel where they talk about things. There is one where there was a whole bunch of discussion leading up to the Taproot BIP proposal.</description></item><item><title>The Tools and The Work</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lets-talk-bitcoin-podcast/2019-06-09-ltb-pieter-wuille-jonas-nick/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lets-talk-bitcoin-podcast/2019-06-09-ltb-pieter-wuille-jonas-nick/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s Talk Bitcoin with Pieter Wuille and Jonas Nick - June 9th 2019
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1155851797568917504
Part 1: https://letstalkbitcoin.com/blog/post/lets-talk-bitcoin-400-the-tools-and-the-work
Part 2: https://letstalkbitcoin.com/blog/post/lets-talk-bitcoin-401-the-tools-and-the-work-part-2
Draft of BIP-Schnorr: https://github.com/sipa/bips/blob/bip-schnorr/bip-schnorr.mediawiki
Draft of BIP-Taproot: https://github.com/sipa/bips/blob/bip-schnorr/bip-taproot.mediawiki
Draft of BIP-Tapscript: https://github.com/sipa/bips/blob/bip-schnorr/bip-tapscript.mediawiki
Part 1 Adam: On this episode we&amp;rsquo;ll be digging deeply into some of the most important changes coming soon to the Bitcoin protocol in the form of BIPs or Bitcoin Improvement Proposals focused on Taproot, Tapscript and Schnorr signatures.</description></item><item><title>Secure Signatures: Harder Than You Think</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2019/signature-scheme-security-properties/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2019/signature-scheme-security-properties/</guid><description>Twitter announcement: https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1104399812147916800
Transcript completed by: Bryan Bishop Edited by: Michael Folkson
Introduction Hi everyone. Can you hear me alright? Is my mic? Okay, cool. I was scheduled to talk about the history of Schnorr signatures in Bitcoin. I wanted to do that but then I realized I’ve only got 20-30 minutes to talk here. Instead I am going to focus on one particular piece of that history, which is the security model surrounding not just Schnorr signatures but extensions to Schnorr signatures we really care about.</description></item><item><title>Threshold Signatures and Accountability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2019-02-04-threshold-signatures-and-accountability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2019-02-04-threshold-signatures-and-accountability/</guid><description>Slides: https://download.wpsoftware.net/bitcoin/wizardry/2019-02-sfdevs-threshold/slides.pdf
Transcript completed by: Bryan Bishop Edited by: Michael Folkson
Twitter announcement: https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1092665108960968704
Introduction (Mark Erhardt) Sorry for the delays. We&amp;rsquo;re finally ready to talk. Welcome to our talk. We&amp;rsquo;d like to thank our sponsors including Blockstream and Digital Garage. Today we have Andrew Poelstra to talk about threshold signatures and accountability. He is known for working on Mimblewimble, Bitcoin Core, libsecp256k1, and at Blockstream.
Introduction (Andrew Poelstra) Today I am here to talk about threshold signatures and accountable signatures and a whole bunch of signature work I’ve been doing with Pieter Wuille, Jonas Nick and Tim Ruffing and a few other people over the last year or so.</description></item><item><title>Schnorr Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/andreas-antonopoulos/2018-10-07-andreas-antonopoulos-schnorr-signatures/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/andreas-antonopoulos/2018-10-07-andreas-antonopoulos-schnorr-signatures/</guid><description>LTB Episode 378 - The Petro inside Venezuela &amp;amp; Schnorr Signatures
We’re currently using the elliptic curve digital signature algorithm (ECDSA) which is a specific way of doing digital signatures with elliptic curves but not the only way. Schnorr signatures have some unique characteristics that make them better in many ways than the ECDSA algorithm we use today in Bitcoin.
Schnorr signatures are better because they have certain quirks in the way the mathematics plays out.</description></item><item><title>Unfairly Linear Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2018-06-12-adam-gibson-unfairly-linear-signatures/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2018-06-12-adam-gibson-unfairly-linear-signatures/</guid><description>Slides: https://joinmarket.me/static/schnorrplus.pdf
Intro This is supposed to be a developer meetup but this talk is going to be a little more on the theoretical side. The title is “Unfairly Linear Signatures” that is just a joke. It is talking about Schnorr signatures. They are something that could in the near future have a big practical significance in Bitcoin. I am not going to explain all the practical significance.
Outline To give you an outline, I will explain what all these terms mean and how they fit in shortly.</description></item><item><title>Schnorr Signatures For Bitcoin: Challenges and Opportunities</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/schnorr-signatures-for-bitcoin-challenges-opportunities/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/schnorr-signatures-for-bitcoin-challenges-opportunities/</guid><description>slides: https://prezi.com/bihvorormznd/schnorr-signatures-for-bitcoin/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/958776403977220098
https://blockstream.com/2018/02/15/schnorr-signatures-bpase.html
Introduction My name is Pieter Wuille. I work at Blockstream. I contribute to Bitcoin Core and bitcoin research in general. I work on various proposals for the bitcoin system for some time now. Today I will be talking about Schnorr signatures for bitcoin, which is a project we&amp;rsquo;ve been working on, on-and-off, for a couple of years now. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the cool things that we can do that might be non-obvious, and also some non-obvious challenges that we ran into while doing this.</description></item><item><title>Schnorr Signatures for Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/schnorr-signatures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/schnorr-signatures/</guid><description>Slides: URL expired
Pieter Wuille presentation on Schnorr at BPASE 2018: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/schnorr-signatures-for-bitcoin-challenges-opportunities/
Transcript completed by: Bryan Bishop Edited by: Michael Folkson
Intro Today I will be talking about Schnorr signatures for Bitcoin. I want to say a few things in advance. One is even though this is a talk about cryptography and in particular new cryptography I don&amp;rsquo;t consider myself to be a cryptographer. Most of the work I will be talking about is a result of talking to a lot of smart people for a long time.</description></item><item><title>Taproot, Schnorr, and the next soft-fork</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/taproot-schnorr-soft-fork/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/taproot-schnorr-soft-fork/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1162839000811548672
Introduction I am going to speak about this potential next version of bitcoin. Who here has heard of these words? Taproot? Schnorr? Who has heard these buzzwords these days? Yeah, so, the proposed next soft-fork is going to involve both of these technologies sort of interplaying. We want to talk about what are these technologies and how do we use thse things and why is it important that a bitcoin user or holder understands these technologies?</description></item></channel></rss>