<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lightning Hack Day on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/</link><description>Recent content in Lightning Hack Day on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lightning Routing - Building a new economy</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2021-03-27-alex-bosworth-lightning-routing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2021-03-27-alex-bosworth-lightning-routing/</guid><description>Slides: https://www.dropbox.com/s/oo9o8ij62utvlfo/alex-bosworth-lightning-routing.pdf
Transcript of presentation on Channel Management (2018): https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-alex-bosworth-channel-management/
Intro With Lightning routing I think it is a very exciting topic because we’re doing something that no one has ever really done before, to build this peer-to-peer marketplace. It is a required component of the Lightning Network because the Lightning Network is dependent on this concept of liquidity. Capital needs to be placed in the right places, it is not a purely technical problem, it is also an economics problem.</description></item><item><title>A Quantitative Analysis of Security, Anonymity and Scalability for the Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2020-05-09-sergei-tikhomirov-lightning-privacy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2020-05-09-sergei-tikhomirov-lightning-privacy/</guid><description>Location: Lightning Hacksprint (Fulmo)
Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1H9EdrhjQ9x3q0qfsei7iFYINVf2lwPyjUKHd3CScy4k/edit#slide=id.g7774542944_0_0
Paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/303
Intro Hello everyone. I am Sergei, I am a PhD student at the University of Luxembourg. I am going to present our joint work with Pedro Moreno-Sanchez and Matteo Maffei from TU Wien on certain aspects of the privacy and scalability of the Lightning Network. The full paper can be found here.
LN intro (for completeness) Let me give some context on what Lightning Network is.</description></item><item><title>Zap Desktop: A look under the hood</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2018-12-01-tom-kirkpatrick-zap-wallet/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2018-12-01-tom-kirkpatrick-zap-wallet/</guid><description>Introduction I’m Tom. I’ve been working on the Zap desktop wallet for the last six months or so. If you’re not familiar, we’re trying to build consumer facing Lightning applications. We’ve currently got an iOS app and a desktop wallet. They’re pretty similar, the interface is pretty similar between them but they’ve got a slightly different focus. I’ve been working on the desktop wallet. Can I just get an idea of how many people here have used Zap?</description></item><item><title>Excel In Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2018-10-27-pierre-rochard-excel-in-lightning/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2018-10-27-pierre-rochard-excel-in-lightning/</guid><description>Excel in Lightning - Lightning Hack Day NYC
Demo I want to present a project I’ve been hacking on for the past month which is getting lnd inside of Excel. I’ll explain why someone would ever do that. I want to bring Lightning to the most popular business platform in existence today which is Microsoft Office Excel. It’s installed on hundreds of millions of computers around the world. It is used day-to-day by all sorts of business people who are doing adhoc data analysis.</description></item></channel></rss>