<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bob McElrath on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/bob-mcelrath/</link><description>Recent content in Bob McElrath on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/bob-mcelrath/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Braidpool</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-15-braidpool/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-15-braidpool/</guid><description>Introduction I am going to talk today about Braidpool which is a decentralized mining pool. I hope some of you were in the mining panel earlier today in particular p2pool which this is a successor to. I gave a talk a long time ago about a directed acyclic graph blockchain.
Braidpool Braidpool is a proposal for a decentralized mining pool which uses a merge-mined DAG with Nakamoto-like consensus to track shares.</description></item><item><title>Socratic Seminar - Coinswap</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-23-socratic-seminar-coinswap/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-23-socratic-seminar-coinswap/</guid><description>Pastebin of the resources discussed: https://pastebin.com/zbegGmb8
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have given permission for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Introductions Michael Folkson (MF): This is London BitDevs, this is a Socratic Seminar. We had two events last week so it is great to see so many people on the call.</description></item><item><title>On-Chain Defense in Depth</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2019-02-09-mcelrath-on-chain-defense-in-depth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2019-02-09-mcelrath-on-chain-defense-in-depth/</guid><description>On-chain defense in depth (UCL CBT seminar)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1159542209584218113
Introduction It seems strange to come to a university and put PhD on my slides because in the finance world that&amp;rsquo;s weird. I put it up there.
Okay, so. I work for Fidelity Digital Assets. Just a couple words about this. Our lawyers make us say this: &amp;ldquo;This presentation is intended to be educational in nature and is not representative of existing products and services from Fidelity Investments or Fidelity Digital Assets.</description></item><item><title>Braiding The Blockchain</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/braiding-the-blockchain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/braiding-the-blockchain/</guid><description>Bob McElrath (bsm117532)
slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY2/2_breaking_the_chain_1_mcelrath.pdf
I work for SolidX in New York. I am here to tell you about some modifications to the blockchain. All the things we heard yesterday about the block size, come down to the existence of orphans. The reason why we have these problems are orphans. These are consequences of physics and resources. This is not a fundamental property in Bitcoin. ((Transcripter&amp;rsquo;s note: basically, only sharding can make local bandwidth less of an issue.</description></item><item><title>Breaking The Chain</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/breaking-the-chain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/breaking-the-chain/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785144266683195392
http://dpaste.com/1ZYW028
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/milan/client-side-validation/
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong/braiding-the-blockchain/
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/milan/jute-braiding/
Inclusivitiy So it seems like we have two big topics here, one is braiding and one is proof-of-publication. I had a talk in Hong Kong about braiding. The major difference is the inclusive nature. The notion that every block gets a block reward as a way to solve selfish-mining. It&amp;rsquo;s a competition between the orphans that get a reward and the ones that don&amp;rsquo;t that causes a loss of security.</description></item></channel></rss>