<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mast on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/mast/</link><description>Recent content in mast on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/mast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Socratic Seminar - BIP Taproot (BIP 341)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-07-21-socratic-seminar-bip-taproot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-07-21-socratic-seminar-bip-taproot/</guid><description>Pastebin of the resources discussed: https://pastebin.com/vsT3DNqW
Transcript of Socratic Seminar on BIP-Schnorr: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-16-socratic-seminar-bip-schnorr/
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have given permission for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Introductions Michael Folkson (MF): This is a Socratic Seminar on BIP-Taproot. Sorry for the delay for the people on the YouTube livestream.</description></item><item><title>Taproot and Graftroot</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/taproot-and-graftroot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/taproot-and-graftroot/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1047764770265284608
Introduction Taproot and graftroot are recent proposals in the bitcoin world. Every script type looks different and they are distinct. From a privacy perspective, that&amp;rsquo;s pretty bad. You watermark or fingerprint yourself all the time by showing unique scripts on the blockchain or in your transactions. This causes censorship risks and other problems for fungibility. Often you are paying for contigencies that are never used, like the whoopsies branches in your scripts.</description></item><item><title>Merkleized Abstract Syntax Trees - MAST</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-03/2018-03-06-merkleized-abstract-syntax-trees-mast/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-03/2018-03-06-merkleized-abstract-syntax-trees-mast/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/972120890279432192
See also http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2017-09-07-merkleized-abstract-syntax-trees/
MAST stuff You could directly merkleize scripts if you switch from IF, IFNOT, ELSE with IFJUMP that has the number of bytes.
With graftroot and taproot, you never to do any scripts (which were a hack to get things started). But we&amp;rsquo;re doing validation and computation.
You take every single path it has; so instead, it becomes &amp;hellip; certain condition, or certain not conditions&amp;hellip; You take every possible ifs, you use this, you say it&amp;rsquo;s one of these, then you specify which one, and you show it and everyone else can validate this.</description></item><item><title>Merkleized Abstract Syntax Trees</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2017-09/2017-09-07-merkleized-abstract-syntax-trees/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2017-09/2017-09-07-merkleized-abstract-syntax-trees/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/907075529534328832
https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2017-September/014932.html
I am going to talk about the scheme I posted to the mailing list yesterday which is to implement MAST (merkleized abstract syntax trees) in bitcoin in a minimally invasive way as possible. It&amp;rsquo;s broken into two major consensus features that together gives us MAST. I&amp;rsquo;ll start with the last BIP.
This is tail-call evaluation. Can we generalize P2SH to give us more general capabilities, than just a single redeem script.</description></item></channel></rss>