<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tadge Dryja on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/tadge-dryja/</link><description>Recent content in Tadge Dryja on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/tadge-dryja/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How much Security is too much Security? Defending against a 99.999% Attack</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2021/2021-04-03-defending-against-99-attack/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2021/2021-04-03-defending-against-99-attack/</guid><description>Topic: How much Security is too much Security? Defending Against a 99.999% Attack
Location: Online
Introduction Hi everyone, it&amp;rsquo;s too bad that we can&amp;rsquo;t be in person but I think by next year we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to do this in person. It&amp;rsquo;s been a long year without conferences. And I guess for maybe many people watching the MIT Bitcoin Expo last March, was the last time I saw a bunch of people in person before this whole thing.</description></item><item><title>Utreexo</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06-06-utreexo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06-06-utreexo/</guid><description>Utreexo: hash-based accumulator for bitcoin UTXOs
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-10-08-utxo-accumulators-and-utreexo/
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/mit-bitcoin-expo-2019/utreexo/
Utreexo paper https://eprint.iacr.org/2019/611.pdf
https://github.com/mit-dci/utreexo
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1136560700187447297
Introduction You still download everything; instead of writing to your UTXO database, you modify your accumulator. You accept a proof that it&amp;rsquo;s in the UTXO accumulator, you put it in there yourself, you just don&amp;rsquo;t remember it anymore. The end result is that you store less than a kilobyte instead of 4 GB or so. But the downside is that you need all these proofs.</description></item><item><title>Utxo Accumulators And Utreexo</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-10-08-utxo-accumulators-and-utreexo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-10-08-utxo-accumulators-and-utreexo/</guid><description>UTXO accumulators, UTXO commitments, and utreexo
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1049112390413897728
If people saw Benedikt&amp;rsquo;s talk, two days ago, it&amp;rsquo;s related. It&amp;rsquo;s a different construction but same goal. The basic idea is, and I think Cory kind of started to talk about this a few months ago on the mailing list&amp;hellip; instead of storing all UTXOs in leveldb, store the hash of each UTXO, and then it&amp;rsquo;s half the size, and then you could almost create it from the hash of the input, it&amp;rsquo;s like 10 bytes more.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network As A Directed Graph Single Funded Channel Network Topology</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-04-11-lightning-network-as-a-directed-graph-single-funded-channel-network-topology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-04-11-lightning-network-as-a-directed-graph-single-funded-channel-network-topology/</guid><description>http://lightning.network/
slides: http://diyhpl.us/~bryan/papers2/bitcoin/Lightning%20Network%20as%20Directed%20Graph%20Single-Funded%20Channel%20Topology%20-%20Tadge%20Dryja%20-%202016-04-11.pdf
Okay. Hello everyone. Yes, okay, great. Yes. Yeah, I&amp;rsquo;m working on Lightning Network. Bitcoin is great and fun to work on.
Basic super quick summary of Lightning I am going to re-cap lightning network real quick. The basic idea is to have channels between two nodes. A channel, from the perspective of the rest of the world, is just a 2-of-2 multisig output. You can&amp;rsquo;t even tell it&amp;rsquo;s multisig, you just see an address with a 3 in front of the address.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2015-05-26-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2015-05-26-lightning-network/</guid><description>Tadge Dryja Joseph Poon How Lightning Network can offer a solution for bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s scalability problems
http://lightning.network/
slides: https://lightning.network/lightning-network-presentation-sfbitcoinsocial-2015-05-26.pdf
Great to have you guys. They are going to talk about bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s scalability problems. There they are.
Okay, hi. So yeah, I titled it solutions because that sounds more positive than talking about problems. Joseph will go after that and talk about what needs to change and the economics and things like that.</description></item><item><title>Scaling Bitcoin To Billions Of Transactions Per Day</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2015-02-23-scaling-bitcoin-to-billions-of-transactions-per-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2015-02-23-scaling-bitcoin-to-billions-of-transactions-per-day/</guid><description>Scaling Bitcoin To Billions Of Transactions Per Day
http://lightning.network/
Joseph Poon joseph@lightning.network Thaddeus Dryja rx@awsomnet.org We&amp;rsquo;re doing a presentation on the lightning network and micropayments. Right now bitcoin faces some interesting problems, like transactions aren&amp;rsquo;t instant, and micropayments don&amp;rsquo;t work. The transaction fees are 1/10th of a cent or higher depending on the exchange rate. And, &amp;ldquo;bitcoin doesn&amp;rsquo;t scale&amp;rdquo; especially if you have a lot of micropayments. One megabyte blocks? Well, let&amp;rsquo;s increase them.</description></item><item><title>Accumulators</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/edgedevplusplus/accumulators/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/edgedevplusplus/accumulators/</guid><description>https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-10-08-utxo-accumulators-and-utreexo/
https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/mit-bitcoin-expo-2019/utreexo/
https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/accumulators/
https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/accumulators/
https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06-06-utreexo/
Note: the present presentation had more in depth information about RSA which might be interesting to the audience.
slides:
https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1OWhdB5P680FMHkoutd_YLP4hGFWI_aVaXRkkYdfoix8/edit?usp=sharing
https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1z_vAwA6hN-C1WEg89EFfZCwqfMRWDcYuW61aA7P84zM/edit?usp=sharing</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Failure Modes And The Role Of The Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/bitcoin-failure-modes-and-the-role-of-the-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/bitcoin-failure-modes-and-the-role-of-the-lightning-network/</guid><description>I am going to be talking about bitcoin failure modes, and Joseph will talk about how the lightning network can help. I&amp;rsquo;ll start. We&amp;rsquo;ll start off by saying that bitcoin is working, which is really cool. Blocks starts with lots of zeroes, coins stay put, they move when you tell them to. That&amp;rsquo;s really cool and it works. That&amp;rsquo;s great. This is a good starting place. We should acknowledge that bitcoin can fail.</description></item><item><title>Discreet Log Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/discreet-log-contracts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/discreet-log-contracts/</guid><description>paper: https://adiabat.github.io/dlc.pdf
slides: http://bit.ly/2uSqkV6 or https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1QXZBtELcVMoCq6wx-rJr31KvtsqxxcWIewMvuSTpsa4
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/902201044297555970
We are going to have next month on September 13 when Ethan Heilman will be talking about something controversial but he hasn&amp;rsquo;t told me what it is yet. But it&amp;rsquo;s controversial. I am Amy. I organize the meetup with some help from other people in the MIT Bitcoin Club. I write about blockchain technologies and stuff. I have written for coindesk and bitcoin magazine and now I&amp;rsquo;m writing for Forbes.</description></item><item><title>Discreet Log Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/discreet-log-contracts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/discreet-log-contracts/</guid><description>http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/discreet-log-contracts/
paper: https://adiabat.github.io/dlc.pdf
Hello everyone. I am going to give a talk about discreet log contracts. I am from MIT DCI. I work on lightning network software and discreet log contracts. A quick intro: these are pretty new. I am not sure if they work. This presentation is part of the peer review process. Maybe the math doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. Please let me know. It might also work, though.
It&amp;rsquo;s a system of smart contracts using bitcoin which is similar to lightning network.</description></item><item><title>Funding bitcoin development</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/funding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/funding/</guid><description>Funding bitcoin development
It&amp;rsquo;s basically open-source funding. It&amp;rsquo;s a subset of open-source funding. But these are similar problems with many open-source projects. As far as I can tell, all these digital currency cryptocurrency projects are licensed with open-source licenses. There may be some that are not, and some things are patented. I generally steer clear of the patented work. If it&amp;rsquo;s decentralized and open-source, then why are you just delivering a binary to me?</description></item><item><title>Improving Bitcoin Smart Contract Efficiency</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2018/improving-bitcoin-smart-contract-efficiency/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2018/improving-bitcoin-smart-contract-efficiency/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/980545280973201410
Introduction I will be talking about discreet log contracts, taproot, and graftroot. Not in that order, the order will actually be taproot, graftroot, and then discreet log contracts.
Quick intro: I&amp;rsquo;m Tadge Dryja. I work here at MIT down the street at Digital Currency Initiative. I was coauthor on the lightning network paper, and I worked on lightning. I also was the author of a paper introducing discreet log contracts.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/edgedevplusplus/lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/edgedevplusplus/lightning-network/</guid><description>Lightning network overview, lightning channel factories, discreet log contracts
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048039589837852672
Introduction I have quite a while to speak. I hope it&amp;rsquo;s not too boring. I&amp;rsquo;ll have an intermission half way through. It&amp;rsquo;s not going to be two hours. It will be more like 80 minutes or something. We are going to talk about payment channels, unidirectional payment channels, lightning channels, homomorphic keys, hash trees, watchtowers, discreet log contracts, oracles, anticipated signatures, DLCS within channels, etc.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/lightning-network/</guid><description>I am going to talk about blockchain scalability using payment channel networks. I am working on Lightning Network. It&amp;rsquo;s currently being built in bitcoin but it can support other things. One of the fundamental problems with blockchain is scalability. How can you have millions of users and rapid transactions?
Fundamentally, the blockchain is shared. You can call it a DLT but it&amp;rsquo;s really a copied ledger. Every user has a copy.</description></item><item><title>Overview Of Bips Necessary For Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/overview-of-bips-necessary-for-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/overview-of-bips-necessary-for-lightning/</guid><description>Scalability of Lightning with different BIPs and some back-of-the-envelope calculations.
slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY2/1_layer2_2_dryja.pdf
I don&amp;rsquo;t have time to introduce the idea of zero-confirmation transactions and lightning. We have given talks about this. There&amp;rsquo;s some documentation available. There&amp;rsquo;s an implementation being worked on. I think it helps a lot with scalability by keeping some transactions off the blockchain. Ideally, many or most transactions. Instead, you would open and close channels. That&amp;rsquo;s all that needs to be on the blockchain.</description></item><item><title>Unlinkable Outsourced Channel Monitoring</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/unlinkable-outsourced-channel-monitoring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/unlinkable-outsourced-channel-monitoring/</guid><description>http://lightning.network/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784752625074012160
Okay. Hi everyone. Check. Wow. Check one two. Okay it&amp;rsquo;s working. And I have 25 minutes. Great. So I am going to talk about unlinkable outsourced channel modeling. Everyone likes channels. You can update states. You can link them together to make a network. This is really great. There are risks. These are additional risks. The price of scalability is eternal vigilance. You have to keep watching your channels.</description></item><item><title>Utreexo - Reducing bitcoin nodes to 1 kilobyte</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2019/utreexo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2019/utreexo/</guid><description>Utreexo: Reducing bitcoin nodes to 1 kilobyte
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1104410958716387328
See also: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-10-08-utxo-accumulators-and-utreexo/
Introduction I am going to talk about another scaling solution and another strategy I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on for about 6-9 months, called Utreexo.
Bitcoin scalability Scalability has been a concern in bitcoin for the whole time. In fact, it&amp;rsquo;s the first thing that anyone said about bitcoin. In 2008, Satoshi Nakamoto said hey I made this thing called bitcoin. Some guy on the mailing list, James A.</description></item></channel></rss>