<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>package relay on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/package-relay/</link><description>Recent content in package relay on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/package-relay/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Package Relay Primer</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2023-04-25-package-relay-primer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2023-04-25-package-relay-primer/</guid><description>Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/12YPlmmaCiNNL83b3FDmYwa7FKHP7yD0krzkEzM-tkTM
Problems CPFP Doesn’t Work When Mempool Min Feerate Rises Bad for users who want to use CPFP and L2s, but also a glaring limitation in our ability to assess transaction incentive compatibility
Pinning being able to feebump transaction is a pinning concern counterpart can intentionally censor your transactions, and in L2 that can mean stealing your money because you didn’t meet the timelock Pinning examples ANYONECANPAY -&amp;gt; anyonecanpin: add input that comes from huge unconfirmed low-fee rate tx -&amp;gt; absolute feerate needs to increase, so you&amp;rsquo;re paying more fees for the tx to confirm slower shared descendant limit can be monopolized descendant limit is 25 txs, so someone else can fill up that limit we have a carve-out for CPFP already to try and mitigate that RBF Rule 3 is gameable replacement fees must &amp;gt; all descendants, and they may be large, low feerate -&amp;gt; expensive most L2s have pinning problems, so we need to fix that Get rid of txid-based relay we want to avoid txid based relay can&amp;rsquo;t deduplicate txid and wtxid that correspond to the same tx can&amp;rsquo;t deduplicate txs that only differ in witness we still require txid-based relay for orphans, because txs specify prevouts by txid -&amp;gt; so we don&amp;rsquo;t know which wtxid to request Definitions pinning attack: a censorship attack on relay/mempool level, abusing policy</description></item><item><title>Package Relay BIP, implementation, V3, and package RBF proposals</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2022-10-11-package-relay/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2022-10-11-package-relay/</guid><description>Notes on Package Relay BIP, implementation, V3, and package RBF proposals from Core Dev in Atlanta.
Also at https://gist.github.com/glozow/8469dc9c3a003c7046033a92dd504329.
Ancestor Package Relay BIP BIP updated to be receiver-initiated ancestor packages only. Sender-initiated vs receiver-initiated package relay. Receiver-intiated package relay enables a node to ask for more information when they suspect they are missing something (i.e. to resolve orphans). Sender-initiated package relay should, theoretically, save a round trip by notifying the receiver ahead of time that &amp;ldquo;hey, this is going to be a package, so make sure you download and submit these transactions together.</description></item></channel></rss>