<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Gloria Zhao on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/gloria-zhao/</link><description>Recent content in Gloria Zhao on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/gloria-zhao/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Package Relay Primer</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2023-04-25-package-relay-primer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2023-04-25-package-relay-primer/</guid><description>Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/12YPlmmaCiNNL83b3FDmYwa7FKHP7yD0krzkEzM-tkTM
Problems CPFP Doesn’t Work When Mempool Min Feerate Rises Bad for users who want to use CPFP and L2s, but also a glaring limitation in our ability to assess transaction incentive compatibility
Pinning being able to feebump transaction is a pinning concern counterpart can intentionally censor your transactions, and in L2 that can mean stealing your money because you didn’t meet the timelock Pinning examples ANYONECANPAY -&amp;gt; anyonecanpin: add input that comes from huge unconfirmed low-fee rate tx -&amp;gt; absolute feerate needs to increase, so you&amp;rsquo;re paying more fees for the tx to confirm slower shared descendant limit can be monopolized descendant limit is 25 txs, so someone else can fill up that limit we have a carve-out for CPFP already to try and mitigate that RBF Rule 3 is gameable replacement fees must &amp;gt; all descendants, and they may be large, low feerate -&amp;gt; expensive most L2s have pinning problems, so we need to fix that Get rid of txid-based relay we want to avoid txid based relay can&amp;rsquo;t deduplicate txid and wtxid that correspond to the same tx can&amp;rsquo;t deduplicate txs that only differ in witness we still require txid-based relay for orphans, because txs specify prevouts by txid -&amp;gt; so we don&amp;rsquo;t know which wtxid to request Definitions pinning attack: a censorship attack on relay/mempool level, abusing policy</description></item><item><title>What Do Bitcoin Core Maintainers Do?</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2022-08-11-gloria-zhao/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2022-08-11-gloria-zhao/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/404/
Stephan Livera: Gloria, welcome back to the show.
Gloria Zhao: Thank you for having me again.
Stephan Livera: Yeah, always great to chat with you, Gloria. I know you’ve got a lot of things you’re working on in the space and you recently took on a role as a maintainer as well, so we’ll obviously get into that as well as all your work around the mempool. So do you want to just start with — and we’re going to keep this accessible for beginners — so you’ve taken on this role as one of the maintainers of Bitcoin Core.</description></item><item><title>Transaction Relay Policy</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/adopting-bitcoin/2021/2021-11-16-gloria-zhao-transaction-relay-policy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/adopting-bitcoin/2021/2021-11-16-gloria-zhao-transaction-relay-policy/</guid><description>Topic: Transaction Relay Policy for L2 Developers
Location: Adopting Bitcoin
Slides: https://github.com/glozow/bitcoin-notes/blob/master/Tx%20Relay%20Policy%20for%20L2%20Devs%20-%20Adopting%20Bitcoin%202021.pdf
Intro Hi I’m Gloria, I work on Bitcoin Core at Brink. Today I am going to talk a bit about mempool policy and why you cannot always expect your transactions to propagate or your fee bumps to work. What we are doing to try to resolve stuff like that. This talk is for those of you who find the mempool a bit murky or unstable or unpredictable.</description></item><item><title>Learning Bitcoin Core Contribution &amp; Hosting PR Review Club</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-10-02-gloria-zhao-bitcoin-core/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-10-02-gloria-zhao-bitcoin-core/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/216/
Stephan Livera:
Gloria. Welcome to the show.
Gloria Zhao:
Thank you so much for having me.
Stephan Livera:
So Gloria I’ve heard a few things about you and I was looking up what you’ve been doing. You’ve been doing some really interesting things. Can we hear a little bit about you and how you got into Bitcoin?
Gloria Zhao:
Yeah, well, I didn’t get into Bitcoin by choice. Actually it was by accident.</description></item></channel></rss>