<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>routing on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/routing/</link><description>Recent content in routing on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/routing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lightning Routing</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2021-03-27-alex-bosworth-lightning-routing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2021-03-27-alex-bosworth-lightning-routing/</guid><description>Lightning Routing - Building a new economy
Location: Lightning Hack Day
media: No video posted online
Slides: https://www.dropbox.com/s/oo9o8ij62utvlfo/alex-bosworth-lightning-routing.pdf
Transcript of presentation on Channel Management (2018): https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-alex-bosworth-channel-management/
Transcript by: Michael Folkson
Intro With Lightning routing I think it is a very exciting topic because we’re doing something that no one has ever really done before, to build this peer-to-peer marketplace. It is a required component of the Lightning Network because the Lightning Network is dependent on this concept of liquidity.</description></item><item><title>Trampoline Routing</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-conference/2019/2019-10-20-bastien-teinturier-trampoline-routing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-conference/2019/2019-10-20-bastien-teinturier-trampoline-routing/</guid><description>The Lightning Conference Day 2 (Stage 2)
Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1bFu33_YFsRVUSEN-Vff5-wrxMabOFl2ck7ZTiVsp5ds/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1221100865328685057
Intro We will start with gory technical details about routing and pathfinding. I hope I will be able to keep you awake for the next twenty minutes. I’m working for ACINQ on the Lightning Network. If you don’t know ACINQ we are contributors to the specification. We run the biggest node on the network and we are also one of the leading mobile wallets, eclair-mobile.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Payment Pathfinding for Reliability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-conference/2019/lightning-payment-pathfinding-for-reliability/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-conference/2019/lightning-payment-pathfinding-for-reliability/</guid><description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;m Joost Jager. I work for Lightning Labs. At Lightning Labs, I&amp;rsquo;m a software engineer, and my main focus is on LND. Over the last month, I spent quite some time to improve pathfinding in LND. In this talk, I would like to explain how we optimize pathfinding for the reliability of paths.
Lightning payment pathfinding So we&amp;rsquo;re looking for a path. That&amp;rsquo;s clear. But what do we optimize the path for?</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Sphinx And Onion Routing</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/lightning-network-sphinx-and-onion-routing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/lightning-network-sphinx-and-onion-routing/</guid><description>Introduction Hi everyone. I am a developer of rust-lightning, it started in 2018 by BlueMatt. I started contributing about a year ago now. It&amp;rsquo;s a full featured, flexible, spec-compliant lightning library. It targets exchanges, wallet vendors, hardware, meshnet devices, and you can join us on Freenode IRC in the #rust-bitcoin channel which is a really nice one.
Privacy matters Privacy matters on the blockchain. This is the reason why lightning is taking so much time.</description></item><item><title>Lightning network topology, its creation and maintenance</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/lightning-network-topology/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/lightning-network-topology/</guid><description>Introduction Alright. Give me a second to test this. Alright. Antoine has taken you through the routing layer. I&amp;rsquo;m going to take you through what the lightning network looks like today. This is the current topology of the network and how this came about, and some approaches for maintaining the network and making the graph look like we want it to look.
Lightning brief overview There&amp;rsquo;s ideally only two transactions involved in any lightning channel, the commitment transaction and the closure transaction.</description></item><item><title>Routing Problems and Solutions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/2019-09-09-carla-kirk-cohen-routing-problems-and-solutions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/2019-09-09-carla-kirk-cohen-routing-problems-and-solutions/</guid><description>Topic: Routing Problems and Solutions
Location: Tel-Aviv 2019
Introduction I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking about routing in the Lightning Network now. So I&amp;rsquo;m going to touch on how it&amp;rsquo;s currently operating, some issues that you run into when you are routing, and then some potential expansions to the spec which are going to address some of these issues.
We ran through the Lightning Network graph: the nodes of vertices, the channels in this graph of edges.</description></item><item><title>Rendezvous Routing</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-28-christian-decker-rendezvous-routing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-28-christian-decker-rendezvous-routing/</guid><description>Rendezvous Routing (Lightning Network)
Location: Chaincode Residency 2019
Slides: https://residency.chaincode.com/presentations/lightning/Rendezvous_Routing.pdf
Transcript by: Caralie Chrisco and Davius Parvin
Introduction Okay, the second part is rendezvous routing. I basically already gave away the trick but I hope you all forgot. So what is rendezvous routing? Anybody have a good explanation of what we are trying to do here? So we have someplace where we meet in the middle, and I don&amp;rsquo;t have to know where you live, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to know where I live, we&amp;rsquo;re all really private.</description></item><item><title>Onion Routing Deep Dive</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-christian-decker-onion-routing-deep-dive/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-christian-decker-onion-routing-deep-dive/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Residency – Summer 2019
Onion Routing Deep Dive But we&amp;rsquo;ve not seen exactly why we are using an onion, or why we chose this construction of an onion and how this construction of an onion actually looks like. So my goal right now is to basically walk you through the iterations that onion routing packets have done so far, and why we chose this construction we have here.</description></item><item><title>Routing Failures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-fabrice-drouin-routing-failures/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-fabrice-drouin-routing-failures/</guid><description>Introduction So I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about routing failures in lightning. Basically lightning is a network of payment channels and you can pay anyone, you can find a route. In routing in lightning you have two completely different concepts: how to find a route (path finding) and once you have a route how to actually send a payment through the routes to the final destination. This is what Christian showed that&amp;rsquo;s the source routing.</description></item><item><title>Multihop of the Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-24-rene-pickhardt-multihop-in-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-24-rene-pickhardt-multihop-in-lightning/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs Lightning Residency 2019
Slides: https://residency.chaincode.com/presentations/lightning/Multihop_Layer.pdf
Introduction I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about Lightning Network payment channels and the update layer which is basically multihop payments and the outline of this talk is one slide myths about routing that are floating around and I just want to discuss them in the beginning very briefly. Then I will talk about the payment process on the Lightning Network and compare it a little bit with the payment process on Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Bootstrapping Lightning Node</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-elaine-ou-bootstrapping-lightning-node/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-elaine-ou-bootstrapping-lightning-node/</guid><description>Bootstrapping and maintaining a Lightning Node
Slides: https://lightningresidency.com/assets/presentations/Ou_Bootstrapping_and_Maintaining_a_Lightning_Node.pdf
Intro My name ie Elaine. I’ll talk about bootstrapping and maintaining a lightning node. Pretty much all of you have probably already set up a node so this should all be review. You guys will probably know more about this than I do.
Bootstrapping and Maintaining a Lightning Node We’ll start with an overview of how routing works just to understand what the nodes are trying to do and from there we’ll step back and look at ways of finding peers and getting incoming channels and maintaining capacity.</description></item><item><title>Channel Management</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-alex-bosworth-channel-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-alex-bosworth-channel-management/</guid><description>Slides: https://lightningresidency.com/assets/presentations/Bosworth_Channel_Management.pdf
Intro Today I’m going to talk about something a little bit different to building apps. I’m going to talk about becoming a great router. Managing your node so that your node can be routing payments and be a good citizen if you choose to have public channels.
Uptime So basically the big message overall is and I think I’ve said this before, if you have public channels you’re kind of like waving to everybody “please use these channels to do routing”.</description></item><item><title>Ant routing for the Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/lightning-routing-ants-pheromones/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/lightning-routing-ants-pheromones/</guid><description>Decentralized anonymous routing algorithm for LN
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014530761398145025
https://twitter.com/rperezmarco/status/1013938984718884866
Introduction I wanted to present some ideas for alternative ideas for routing on LN. This was published on arxiv: 1807.00151 (July 2018).
http://webusers.imj-prg.fr/~ricardo.perez-marco
Overview I am going to talk about what I understand to be decentralized network. Fabrice has already explained most of what is LN about and some history about it. I will just recall a few properties that I need in order to address the mathematical problem of routing.</description></item><item><title>Amiko Pay</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/amiko-pay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/amiko-pay/</guid><description>Amiko Pay aims to become an implementation of the lightning network. So that previous presentation was a great setup. There&amp;rsquo;s a little bit more to Amiko Pay. If you look through the basic design of the lightning network, there&amp;rsquo;s a network of payment channels. There have been several variations of this idea. Lightning Network happens to be the best so far. What Amiko Pay aims to do is to focus on the nodes, and do the routing between nodes.</description></item><item><title>Boomerang - Redundancy Improves Latency and Throughput in Payment-Channel Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/boomerang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/boomerang/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230936389300080640
Introduction Redundancy can be a useful tool for speeding up payment channel networks and improving throughput. We presented last week at Financial Crypto. You just received a nice introduction to payment channels and payment channel networks.
Payment channels Alice and Bob are connected through a payment channel. This is a channel and in that channel there are some coins that are escrowed. Some coins belong to Alice some belong to Bob and they want to transact them back and forth.</description></item><item><title>Day 1 Group Summaries</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/day-1-group-summaries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/day-1-group-summaries/</guid><description>Day 1 group summaries
We need two to three minute report backs from each session. Also, note takers. Please email your notes to contact@scalingbitcoin.org so that we can add notes to the wiki. Come join us. Okay, so.
Lightning We discussed routing and several aspects of routing algorithms in the lightning network. We talked about the tradeoff between privacy aspects and reliability in routing. We quickly discovered that after some of the things were already resolved by the papers&amp;ndash; the way how we deal with a general separation and channel transaction fees, is actually quite an interesting discussion topic.</description></item><item><title>Flare Routing In Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/flare-routing-in-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/flare-routing-in-lightning/</guid><description>Flare: An approach to routing in lightning network
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784745976170999810
I will not be as technical as Olaoluwa was. You have nodes that open up payment channels. This scheme is actually developed at the moment in great detail. So how do you find the channels through which to send payments? So we wanted to propose some initial solution to this.
Routing requirements It should be source routing because we need the privacy.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Routing</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/lightning-network-routing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/lightning-network-routing/</guid><description>Introduction Good afternoon everyone. My name is Carla. I am one of the chaincode residents this summer. This talk is going to walk through the protocol layer by layer and look at the different components that make up the network. Lightning is an off-chain scaling solution which consists of a p2p network of payment channels. It allows payments to be forwarded by nodes in exchange for fees.
Scaling with payment channels This involves a payment channel.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Routing Security</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-routing-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-routing-security/</guid><description>Security aspects of LN routing
Joost Jager, Lightning Labs
D146 D0F6 8939 4362 68FA 9A13 0E26 BB61 B76C 4D3A
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137740282139676672
Introduction Together with my colleagues I am building lnd. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the implementations of lightning. In routing, there&amp;rsquo;s the sender of the payment, the intermediate routing nodes that forward payments, and a receiver. I would like to scope this down to looking at security just from the perspective of the sender.</description></item><item><title>Onion Routing In Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/onion-routing-in-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/onion-routing-in-lightning/</guid><description>http://lightning.network/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784742298089299969
Privacy-preserving decentralized micropayments
We&amp;rsquo;re excited about lightning because the second layer could be an important opportunity to improve privacy and fungibility. Also, there might be timing information in the payments themselves.
Distributed set of onion routers (OR, cite OG onionrouting paper). Users create circuits with sub-set of nodes. Difficult for oion routers to gain more info than predecessor+successor in path. Low latency - usable within greater internet. Notable success is tor, notable success of routing nodes.</description></item><item><title>Rebalancing Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/rebalancing-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/rebalancing-lightning/</guid><description>Rebalancing in the lightning network: Analysis and implications
Sebastián Reca (Muun)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048753406628655105
Introduction This talk is going to be about rebalancing in the lightning network. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the implications and about running a lightning node.
Financial costs In the lightning network, routing nodes will incur in financial costs by having their money locked inside channels. They can&amp;rsquo;t use that money elsewhere. They incur a financial cost to doing this activity, at least an opportunity cost.</description></item></channel></rss>