<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tarun Chitra on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/tarun-chitra/</link><description>Recent content in Tarun Chitra on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/tarun-chitra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Stress Testing Decentralized Finance</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/stress-testing-decentralized-finance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/stress-testing-decentralized-finance/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229844754990370816
Introduction More quantitatively, I think coming up with stress tests is akin to Bryan&amp;rsquo;s question&amp;hellip;. stress testing is something that people in this space kind of do, and I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about what that looks like and what an actuarial analysis should look like.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to go through three examples of where an actuarial analysis shows certain weaknesses that need to be monitored and understood. They are going to be more on the scifi end of cryptocurrency.</description></item><item><title>Competitive Equilibria Staking Lending</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/competitive-equilibria-staking-lending/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/competitive-equilibria-staking-lending/</guid><description>Competitive equilibria between staking and on-chain lending
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230581977289379840
https://arxiv.org/pdf/2001.00919v1.pdf
See also &amp;ldquo;Stress testing decentralized finance&amp;rdquo; https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/stress-testing-decentralized-finance/
Introduction There have been some odd finanical attacks in the DeFi space and also on staking. This talk aims to show that the threat model for staking is definitively different from that of proof-of-work, and these financial attacks need to be part of the threat model.
Agenda I&amp;rsquo;ll go over some high level overview of intuitive market dynamics, then we will build up an agent-based model that correctly goes across multiple participants to stress test staking situations, then we go through the various assumptions, and at a high-level I&amp;rsquo;ll give some formal probability statements without proofs, and finally I have simulation results to discuss which can give you some idea about how to design a monetary policy.</description></item></channel></rss>