<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Covenants on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/covenants/</link><description>Recent content in Covenants on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/covenants/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Covenants</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2024-10/covenants/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2024-10/covenants/</guid><description>1) What are we solving? scaling? 10x, 20x, 100x? new use cases? giving users sovereignty? MEV concerns? 2) Different groups (some overlap with above): &amp;ldquo;ticking clock&amp;rdquo; for self-custody slow and steady buildoors ossification now 3) Various approaches: a. One weird trick (CAT? CTV?)
b. App-specific (APO), &amp;ldquo;LNHANCE&amp;rdquo;
c. minimal batched toolset: TXHASH(CTV), CSFS, CAT, TAPTWEAK, ???, Could keep going on this: OP_MUL, other general tools
d. overhaul: Great Script Restoration (GSR) - (overhaul of script engine sigops-&amp;gt; varops)</description></item><item><title>Covenants Part 2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/learning-bitcoin-and-design/covenants-part-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/learning-bitcoin-and-design/covenants-part-2/</guid><description>Introduction Christoph Ono: 00:00:01
All right, welcome to our second learning Bitcoin and Design call about covenants. Today, the idea was to go deeper into covenants use cases, right? Last time, the first call was more about just generally what it is and what it does. Now we wanted to go deeper. I think on the web, on the GitHub issue, there was one request about congestion control. But the other big one was scaling, I think.</description></item><item><title>Covenants</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/learning-bitcoin-and-design/covenants/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/learning-bitcoin-and-design/covenants/</guid><description>Introductions Christoph Ono: 00:00:01
Welcome to our first Learning Bitcoin and Design call of 2024. We haven&amp;rsquo;t had one of these in a while, but we&amp;rsquo;re picking them back up again. The first topic is a really tough one, I think at least, it&amp;rsquo;s covenants. The reason, one of the reasons why this came up is because on Bitcoin Design, we have this new design challenge. We have a page with design challenges that are meant to be kind of take home challenges.</description></item><item><title>Covenants, Introspection, CTV and Activation Impasse</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/covenants-introspection-ctv-and-activation-impasse/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/covenants-introspection-ctv-and-activation-impasse/</guid><description>Introduction NVK: 00:01:10
As usual, nothing is happening in Bitcoin and we figured, what a great day to put people to sleep in a one to three hour podcast. We don&amp;rsquo;t know yet how it&amp;rsquo;s going to be. We actually don&amp;rsquo;t know how this is going to play out at all. I have here with me Mr. Rijndael. Hello, sir. Welcome back.
Rijndael: 00:01:30
Hello. Good morning.
NVK: 00:01:32
Good morning.</description></item><item><title>#MPCbros vs #TeamScript Debate</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/mpcbros-vs-teamscript-debate/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/mpcbros-vs-teamscript-debate/</guid><description>In this episode of the Bitcoin Review, NVK moderates a debate between Rijndael and Rob Hamilton, representing Team MPC and Team Script respectively. The discussion explores the merits and challenges of multi-party computation (MPC) and Bitcoin Script in enhancing Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s functionality and security. Rijndael explains MPC&amp;rsquo;s ability to create shared key pairs and more efficient multi-signature transactions using Schnorr signatures and Taproot, improving privacy and space efficiency. Rob counters with Script’s simplicity, auditability, and established history in Bitcoin, highlighting the transparency of on-chain scripts. The debate covers various technical aspects including signature aggregation, nonce management, and the potential for covenants and transaction introspection to enhance Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s programmability. Both sides acknowledge the importance of advancing Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s scripting capabilities while ensuring security and usability. The episode concludes with insights on the future of Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s technical development, emphasizing the need for innovative solutions to drive adoption and enhance user experience</description></item><item><title>OP_VAULT for Bitcoin Covenants Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/op_vault-for-bitcoin-covenants-panel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/op_vault-for-bitcoin-covenants-panel/</guid><description>Speaker 0: 00:00:45
Today we have an absolute all-star panel here. We&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking about the Bitcoin Op Vault. It&amp;rsquo;s a new proposal by James. And you know, like any new proposals to Bitcoin, there is a lot to go over. And It&amp;rsquo;s a very big, interesting topic. So today we have Rindell.
Speaker 2: 00:01:05
Hey, good morning. Yeah, I&amp;rsquo;m here talking about vaults, Bitcoin developer, and I work a lot on multi-sig and vaults that don&amp;rsquo;t use covenants.</description></item><item><title>OP_Vault - A New Way to HODL?</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/opvault-a-new-way-to-hodl/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/opvault-a-new-way-to-hodl/</guid><description>Stephan:
James, welcome back to the show.
James 00:02:46:
Hey, Stephan, it&amp;rsquo;s great to be back. I think it&amp;rsquo;s been almost four years.
Stephan 00:02:50:
Damn. Yeah, well, in terms of on the show, yeah, actually in person, you know, a couple of times, some of the conferences and things. But I know you&amp;rsquo;ve got this awesome proposal out, and it looks pretty interesting to me, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure SLP listeners will be very interested to hear more about it.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin R&amp;D Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2022/bitcoin-randd-panel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2022/bitcoin-randd-panel/</guid><description>Ayush: 00:00:07
My name is Ayush Khandelwal. I am a software engineer at Google. I run a tech crypto-focused podcast on the side. And I have some amazing guests with me. So if you want to introduce yourself, what do you work on? And yeah, just get us started.
Jeremy: 00:00:31
I am Jeremy Rubin. I am a class of 2016 MIT alumni, so it&amp;rsquo;s good to be back on campus.</description></item><item><title>Covenants and BIP119</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2022-05-05-covenants-bip119/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2022-05-05-covenants-bip119/</guid><description>Location: Reddit
https://www.reddit.com/r/Bitcoin/comments/uim560/bip_119/i7dhfpb/
Covenants and BIP119 I was asked by an old colleague to respond to your post because I came up with the term covenant as applied Bitcoin many years ago back when I was still a Bitcoin developer.
does bip 119 completely mess the fungibility of bitcoin. If the idea of covenants is that you can create bitcoin that can only be sent to certain addresses, doesnt that make two classes of bitcoin?</description></item><item><title>Covenants</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/2021-11-05-jeremy-rubin-andrew-poelstra-covenants/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/2021-11-05-jeremy-rubin-andrew-poelstra-covenants/</guid><description>As per Socratic village rules names of all attendees (other than the advertised speakers) have been anonymized and audio will not be published to preserve anonymity of the question askers.
The covenant concept Shaun Apps (SA): I’ll kick things off with a bit of an introduction. Both Andrew and Jeremy will present. And then we will go through some questions and we&amp;rsquo;ll go to questions from the audience after that. So that&amp;rsquo;s the format for this.</description></item><item><title>Sydney Socratic Seminar</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-06-01-socratic-seminar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-06-01-socratic-seminar/</guid><description>Google Doc of the resources discussed: https://docs.google.com/document/d/1E9mzB7fmzPxZ74WZg0PsJfLwjpVZ7OClmRdGQQFlzoY/
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Bitcoin Problems (Lloyd Fournier) https://bitcoin-problems.github.io/
This is Bitcoin Problems, it is a Jekyll website I put on GitHub. I am very bad at making things look nice but it is functional at least.</description></item><item><title>Revault - A Multiparty Vault Architecture</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-05-26-kevin-loaec-antoine-poinsot-revault/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-05-26-kevin-loaec-antoine-poinsot-revault/</guid><description>Kevin slides: https://www.dropbox.com/s/rj45ebnic2m0q2m/kevin%20loaec%20revault%20slides.pdf?dl=0
Antoine slides: https://www.dropbox.com/s/xaoior0goo37247/Antoine%20Poinsot%20Revault%20slides.odp?dl=0
Intro (Michael Folkson) This is London Bitcoin Devs. This is on Zoom and live-streaming on YouTube. Last week we had a Socratic Seminar on vaults, covenants and CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY. There is a video up for that. There is also a transcript, @btctranscripts on Twitter. Regarding questions Kevin and Antoine are going to pause during the presentation for questions and comments. We are not going to have interruptions so we will let them speak until they pass.</description></item><item><title>Merkleized Abstract Syntax Trees - MAST</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-03/2018-03-06-merkleized-abstract-syntax-trees-mast/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-03/2018-03-06-merkleized-abstract-syntax-trees-mast/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/972120890279432192
See also http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2017-09-07-merkleized-abstract-syntax-trees/
MAST stuff You could directly merkleize scripts if you switch from IF, IFNOT, ELSE with IFJUMP that has the number of bytes.
With graftroot and taproot, you never to do any scripts (which were a hack to get things started). But we&amp;rsquo;re doing validation and computation.
You take every single path it has; so instead, it becomes &amp;hellip; certain condition, or certain not conditions&amp;hellip; You take every possible ifs, you use this, you say it&amp;rsquo;s one of these, then you specify which one, and you show it and everyone else can validate this.</description></item><item><title>Covenants - Structuring Multi Transaction Contracts in Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/2017-01-26-jeremy-rubin-covenants/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/2017-01-26-jeremy-rubin-covenants/</guid><description>Slides: https://rubin.io/public/pdfs/multi-txn-contracts.pdf
Intro Hey everyone. How is it going? Happy to be going last right now given that I had all these wonderful speakers before me to explain so much of what I am about to tell you. I’m going to talk to you today about structuring multi-transaction contracts in Bitcoin. I think there is a lot of great work that happens in Bitcoin at the script level, at the individual input and output.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Covenants: Opportunities and Challenges</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/covenants/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/covenants/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785071789705728000
We published this last February at an academic workshop. The work itself has interesting ramifications. My real goal here is to start a conversation and then do a follow-up blog post where we collate feedback from the community. We would like to add this to Bitcoin Core. Covenants.
This all started from a very basic and simple observation about the current status of our computing infrastructure. The observation is that the state of our computing infrastructure is no where near safe enough to store assets like bitcoin.</description></item></channel></rss>