<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>covenants on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/covenants/</link><description>Recent content in covenants on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/covenants/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bitcoin R&amp;D Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2022/bitcoin-randd-panel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2022/bitcoin-randd-panel/</guid><description>Ayush: 00:00:07
My name is Ayush Khandelwal. I am a software engineer at Google. I run a tech crypto-focused podcast on the side. And I have some amazing guests with me. So if you want to introduce yourself, what do you work on? And yeah, just get us started.
Jeremy: 00:00:31
I am Jeremy Rubin. I am a class of 2016 MIT alumni, so it&amp;rsquo;s good to be back on campus.</description></item><item><title>Covenants and BIP119</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2022-05-05-covenants-bip119/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2022-05-05-covenants-bip119/</guid><description>Location: Reddit
https://www.reddit.com/r/Bitcoin/comments/uim560/bip_119/i7dhfpb/
Covenants and BIP119 I was asked by an old colleague to respond to your post because I came up with the term covenant as applied Bitcoin many years ago back when I was still a Bitcoin developer.
does bip 119 completely mess the fungibility of bitcoin. If the idea of covenants is that you can create bitcoin that can only be sent to certain addresses, doesnt that make two classes of bitcoin?</description></item><item><title>Covenants</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/2021-11-05-jeremy-rubin-andrew-poelstra-covenants/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/2021-11-05-jeremy-rubin-andrew-poelstra-covenants/</guid><description>Topic: Covenants
Location: TABConf (The Atlanta Bitcoin Conference)
Video: No video was posted online
As per Socratic village rules names of all attendees (other than the advertised speakers) have been anonymized and audio will not be published to preserve anonymity of the question askers.
The covenant concept Shaun Apps (SA): I’ll kick things off with a bit of an introduction. Both Andrew and Jeremy will present. And then we will go through some questions and we&amp;rsquo;ll go to questions from the audience after that.</description></item><item><title>Revault - A Multiparty Vault Architecture</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-05-26-kevin-loaec-antoine-poinsot-revault/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-05-26-kevin-loaec-antoine-poinsot-revault/</guid><description>Location: London Bitcoin Devs (online)
Kevin slides: https://www.dropbox.com/s/rj45ebnic2m0q2m/kevin%20loaec%20revault%20slides.pdf?dl=0
Antoine slides: https://www.dropbox.com/s/xaoior0goo37247/Antoine%20Poinsot%20Revault%20slides.odp?dl=0
Intro (Michael Folkson) This is London Bitcoin Devs. This is on Zoom and live-streaming on YouTube. Last week we had a Socratic Seminar on vaults, covenants and CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY. There is a video up for that. There is also a transcript, @btctranscripts on Twitter. Regarding questions Kevin and Antoine are going to pause during the presentation for questions and comments. We are not going to have interruptions so we will let them speak until they pass.</description></item><item><title>Merkleized Abstract Syntax Trees - MAST</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-03/2018-03-06-merkleized-abstract-syntax-trees-mast/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-03/2018-03-06-merkleized-abstract-syntax-trees-mast/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/972120890279432192
See also http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2017-09-07-merkleized-abstract-syntax-trees/
MAST stuff You could directly merkleize scripts if you switch from IF, IFNOT, ELSE with IFJUMP that has the number of bytes.
With graftroot and taproot, you never to do any scripts (which were a hack to get things started). But we&amp;rsquo;re doing validation and computation.
You take every single path it has; so instead, it becomes &amp;hellip; certain condition, or certain not conditions&amp;hellip; You take every possible ifs, you use this, you say it&amp;rsquo;s one of these, then you specify which one, and you show it and everyone else can validate this.</description></item><item><title>Covenants - Structuring Multi Transaction Contracts in Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/2017-01-26-jeremy-rubin-covenants/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/2017-01-26-jeremy-rubin-covenants/</guid><description>Structuring Multi Transaction Contracts in Bitcoin
Location: BPASE 2017, Stanford University
Slides: https://rubin.io/public/pdfs/multi-txn-contracts.pdf
Intro Hey everyone. How is it going? Happy to be going last right now given that I had all these wonderful speakers before me to explain so much of what I am about to tell you. I’m going to talk to you today about structuring multi-transaction contracts in Bitcoin. I think there is a lot of great work that happens in Bitcoin at the script level, at the individual input and output.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Script</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/bitcoin-script/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/bitcoin-script/</guid><description>Featuring roasbeef
Agenda opcodes OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACK sighash flags keytree sigs MAST graftroot, taproot covenants, reverse covenants (input restrictions: this input has to be spent with tihs other input, or can only be spent if this other one doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist) stack manipulation script languages (simplicity) tx formats, serialization? what would we change with hard-fork changes to the transaction format? Segwit transaction encoding format sucks; the witnesses are at the end and inline with all the scriptsigs and that should be changed.</description></item><item><title>Covenants</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/covenants/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/covenants/</guid><description>Bitcoin covenants: Opportunities and challenges
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785071789705728000
We published this last February at an academic workshop. The work itself has interesting ramifications. My real goal here is to start a conversation and then do a follow-up blog post where we collate feedback from the community. We would like to add this to Bitcoin Core. Covenants.
This all started from a very basic and simple observation about the current status of our computing infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>Plasma Cash</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/plasma-cash/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/plasma-cash/</guid><description>Plasma Cash: Towards more efficient plasma constructions
Non-custodial sidechains for bitcoin utilizing plasma cash and covenants
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1172108023705284609
paper: https://github.com/loomnetwork/plasma-paper/blob/master/plasma_cash.pdf
slides: https://gakonst.com/scalingbitcoin2019.pdf
Introduction We have known how to do these things for at least a year, but the question is how can we find the minimum changes that we can figure out to do in bitcoin if any on how to explore the layer 2 space in a better sense rather than just accepting that lightning network is the dominant solution?</description></item></channel></rss>