<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Breaking Bitcoin 2019 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/</link><description>Recent content in Breaking Bitcoin 2019 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HODL Invoices</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/2019-06-09-joost-jager-hodl-invoices/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/2019-06-09-joost-jager-hodl-invoices/</guid><description>Hodl Invoices (Breaking Bitcoin training session)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1146124260324384768
Intro My name is Joost, Michael introduced me already. I’ve been working with Lightning Labs since the middle of last year and during that time I’ve worked on several subprojects within lnd. lnd is the Lightning implementation developed by Lightning Labs. I’m not sure really what the background knowledge is at this point in this three day course. One of those subprojects within lnd is called hodl invoices and this is the topic that I would like to talk about today.</description></item><item><title>Mempool Analysis &amp; Simulation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/2019-06-08-mempool-analysis-simulation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/2019-06-08-mempool-analysis-simulation/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137342023063744512
slides: https://breaking-bitcoin.com/docs/slides/2019/mempoolAnalysis.pdf
Introduction Fun fact: I don&amp;rsquo;t think anyone knows this fact, but antpool is a miner and antpool is not mining replace-by-fee transactions. What I mean by that is that if you do a replace-by-fee transaction, they will ignore the second high fee transaction. There are cases where transactions are RBF-bumped to increase the fee to make it mined faster, so you RBF bump it, and then you have people spending the unconfirmed RBF version and then have a chain of transactions but then the original transaction is mined and not the other chained transactions.</description></item><item><title>P2P Encryption</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/p2p-encryption/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/p2p-encryption/</guid><description>bip324: v2 message transport protocol
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137312478373851136
slides: https://twitter.com/_jonasschnelli_/status/1137389541512351749
Previous talks https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/bip151-peer-encryption/
https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-09-04-jonas-schenlli-bip150-bip151/
https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06-07-p2p-encryption/
Introduction This will be a technical talk. I hope you&amp;rsquo;re prepared for some cryptography. By the way, this now has a bip number as of this morning. This is bip324. I call it v2 message transport protocol. It&amp;rsquo;s not a consensus change, it&amp;rsquo;s purely a p2p network layer change. It&amp;rsquo;s not all about encryption, but mainly about encryption.</description></item><item><title>Secure Protocols Bip Taproot</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/secure-protocols-bip-taproot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/secure-protocols-bip-taproot/</guid><description>36C7 1A37 C9D9 88BD E825 08D9 B1A7 0E4F 8DCD 0366
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137358557584793600
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06-06-taproot/
slides: https://nickler.ninja/slides/2019-breaking.pdf
Introduction I am going to tlak about something that is a collaboration of many people in the bitcoin community including my colleagues at Blockstream. The bip-taproot proposal was recently posted to the bitcoin-dev mailing list which proposes an improvement for bitcoin.
Disclaimer It&amp;rsquo;s not at all certain that a bip-taproot soft-fork will activate in its current form or at all.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Topological Analysis</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-topological-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-topological-analysis/</guid><description>Topological analysis of the lightning network
paper: https://arxiv.org/abs/1901.04972
https://github.com/seresistvanandras/LNTopology
Introduction Knowing the topology is not necessarily a vulnerability, but it gives you a lot of information. If I know Bryan&amp;rsquo;s full node is connected to some other nodes, I will have an easier time to cut Bryan out of the network or launch attacks against him. Knowing the topology is not necessarily a vulnerability, but it&amp;rsquo;s really strong information.
Recent research There were some recent papers published on this topic:</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Build System</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/bitcoin-build-system/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/bitcoin-build-system/</guid><description>Bitcoin build systems and bitcoin build system security
Carl Dong, Chaincode Labs
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137347937426661376
I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it to Amsterdam this year, but I hope the graphics I have prepared for this talk can make up for my absence. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you want to be a good bitcoin citizen and start to run your own bitcoin node. Say you go to bitcoincore.org, you click the download button, and you open the disk image and you double click on Bitcoin Core.</description></item><item><title>Breaking Bitcoin Privacy</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/breaking-bitcoin-privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/breaking-bitcoin-privacy/</guid><description>Breaking bitcoin privacy
0A8B 038F 5E10 CC27 89BF CFFF EF73 4EA6 77F3 1129
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137304437024862208
Introduction Hello everybody. I invented and created joinmarket, the first really popular coinjoin implementation. A couple months ago I wrote a big literature review on privacy. It has everything about anything in privacy in bitcoin, published on the bitcoin wiki. This talk is about privacy and what we can do to improve it.
Why privacy? Privacy is essential for fungibility, a necessary property of money where one unit is always equal to any other unit.</description></item><item><title>Breaking Wasabi</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/breaking-wasabi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/breaking-wasabi/</guid><description>Breaking wasabi and automated wallets
1127 96A8 DFCA 1A96 C8B8 0094 9211 687A D298 9B12
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137652130611978240
Trigger warnings Before I begin, some have told me that sometimes I tend to be toxic or provocative. So let&amp;rsquo;s start with some trigger warnings. This presentation might include bad jokes about bitcoin personalitites. It might have some multiplication. I might say &amp;ldquo;ethereum&amp;rdquo;. There&amp;rsquo;s also a coinjoin warning. If this is triggering to you, then it&amp;rsquo;s okay to leave.</description></item><item><title>Defense Of Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/defense-of-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/defense-of-bitcoin/</guid><description>Five insights into the defense of bitcoin
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137389045355614208
Introduction Today I work at Blockstream but I have a long long history working in open-source software first with the Linux operating system as an advocate then working on the operating system itself. This has led me to a few insights on the defense of bitcoin that has little to do with software but it needs a talk thrown together very quickly for today.</description></item><item><title>Extracting Seeds From Hardware Wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/extracting-seeds-from-hardware-wallets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/extracting-seeds-from-hardware-wallets/</guid><description>7DC5A359D0D5B5AB6728&amp;hellip;
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137672946435198976
Introduction My talk is about extracting seeds from hardware wallets. I am chief security officer at Ledger. I joined Ledger a bit more than one year ago. I built the Ledger Donjon which is an independent red team. Our mission is to help secure Ledger&amp;rsquo;s products. So what we do day to do is try to break all the hardware wallets. We continuously challenge the security of our products.</description></item><item><title>Fud Perceived Vs Real Bitcoin Risks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/fud-perceived-vs-real-bitcoin-risks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/fud-perceived-vs-real-bitcoin-risks/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137285873534492672
Eric Voskuil 3CD8 C07F 0B5C E14E
Jimmy FAA6 17E3 2679 E455
Rodolfo 1C9E 033C 6C65 8606
Introduction AW: Some topics might have more agreement between the three of you, and some maybe less. It&amp;rsquo;s up to you guys to say smart things.
JS: Can&amp;rsquo;t guarantee anything there.
FUD: bitcoin too volatile to be used as money AW: What about, bitcoin is too volatile to be used as money?
EV: It is used as money, so.</description></item><item><title>Future Of Hardware Wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/future-of-hardware-wallets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/future-of-hardware-wallets/</guid><description>The future of hardware wallets
D419 C410 1E24 5B09 0D2C 46BF 8C3D 2C48 560E 81AC
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137663515957837826
Introduction We are making a secure hardware platform for developers so that they can build their own hardware wallets. Today I want to talk about certain challenges for hardware wallets, what we&amp;rsquo;re missing, and how we can get better.
Current capabilities of hardware wallets Normally, hardware wallets keep keys reasonably secret and are able to spend coins or sign transactions.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Routing Security</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-routing-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-routing-security/</guid><description>Security aspects of LN routing
Joost Jager, Lightning Labs
D146 D0F6 8939 4362 68FA 9A13 0E26 BB61 B76C 4D3A
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137740282139676672
Introduction Together with my colleagues I am building lnd. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the implementations of lightning. In routing, there&amp;rsquo;s the sender of the payment, the intermediate routing nodes that forward payments, and a receiver. I would like to scope this down to looking at security just from the perspective of the sender.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Security Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-security-panel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-security-panel/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137758233865703424
Introduction MF: I will start by thanking Kevin and Lea and the organizers. It&amp;rsquo;s been an awesome event. Thanks also to the sponsors. Without their assistance we couldn&amp;rsquo;t have had the event. I&amp;rsquo;d also like to make some plugs before we start the conversation. One, I run the London Bitcoin developers group. If you&amp;rsquo;re ever in London or interested in speaking, please look up London Bitcoin Devs on Twitter or Meetup.</description></item><item><title>Neutrino</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/neutrino/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/neutrino/</guid><description>Neutrino bip158
&amp;hellip; 228C D70C FAA6 17E3 2679 E455
bip157 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; bip158
Introduction I want to start this talk with a question for the audience. How many of you have a mobile wallet on your phone right now? How many know the security model that the wallets are using? Okay, how many of you trust those security assumptions? Okay, less of you. I am going to talk about Neutrino. In order to talk about it, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about before Neutrino.</description></item><item><title>Opening Remarks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/opening-remarks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/opening-remarks/</guid><description>Opening remarks
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137273436332576768
We have a nice six second intro video. There we go. Woo. Alright. I think I can display my notes here. Yay. Good morning. First thing I need to tell you is the wifi password if you want to use the venue wifi. So, outside of that, thank you all for coming. This year we have a little fewer people than usual, but that&amp;rsquo;s bear market and all.</description></item><item><title>Security Attacks Decentralized Mining Pools</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/security-attacks-decentralized-mining-pools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/security-attacks-decentralized-mining-pools/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137373752038240262
Introduction Hi, I am Alexei. I am a research student at Imperial College London and I will be talking about the security of decentralized mining pools.
Motivation The motivation behind this talk is straightforward. I think we can all agree that to some extent the hashrate in bitcoin has seen some centralization around large mining pools, which undermines the base properties of censorship resistance in bitcoin which I think bitcoin solves in a nice matter.</description></item><item><title>Selfish mining and Dyck words</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/selfish-mining/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/selfish-mining/</guid><description>Introduction I am going to talk about our recent work on selfish mining. I am going to explain the profitability model, the different mathematical models that are used to analyze selfish mining with their properties.
Bibliography On profitability of selfish mining On profitability of stubborn mining On profitability of trailing mining Bitcoin selfish mining and Dyck words Selfish mining and Dyck words in bitcoin and ethereum networks Selfish mining in ethereum The paper on selfish mining in ethereum is even more complex.</description></item></channel></rss>