<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bram Cohen on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/bram-cohen/</link><description>Recent content in Bram Cohen on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/bram-cohen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Consensus Protocol Risks And Vulnerabilities</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/consensus-protocol-risks-and-vulnerabilities/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/consensus-protocol-risks-and-vulnerabilities/</guid><description>Consensus protocol risks and vulnerabilities
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229906447808360450
Introduction I am going to talk about why cryptocurrencies matter. I am going to take the skeptics side. I am going to start from a banker&amp;rsquo;s standpoint why a lot of the things that cryptocurrency people land say don&amp;rsquo;t make any sense.
Where are the engineers coming from? An engineer will look at something like Visa and say this is horrible. These are systems from 50-100 years ago.</description></item><item><title>Proofs Of Space</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/proofs-of-space/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/proofs-of-space/</guid><description>Beyond Hellman&amp;rsquo;s time-memory trade-offs with applications to proofs of space
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/962378701278208000
Introductions Hi everyone. This presentation is based off of a paper called &amp;ldquo;Beyond Hellman&amp;rsquo;s time-memory trade-offs&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;ll get to why it&amp;rsquo;s called that. These slides and the proofs are by Hamza Abusalah.
Outline I am going to describe what proofs of space are. I&amp;rsquo;ll give some previous constructions and information about them. I&amp;rsquo;ll give a simple new construction which has lots of advantages to it.</description></item><item><title>Merkle Sets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-07-08-bram-cohen-merkle-sets/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-07-08-bram-cohen-merkle-sets/</guid><description>Merkle set data structures for scaling bitcoin
code: https://github.com/bramcohen/MerkleSet
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/888836850529558531
Introduction There&amp;rsquo;s been a fair amount of talk about putting UTXO commitments in bitcoin blocks. Whether this is a good idea or not, but on the off-chance that it might be a good idea, I spent a fair amount of time thinking and actually good merkle set implementation whic his what you you need to put utxo set commitments in bitcoin blocks.</description></item><item><title>Roundgroup Roundup 1</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/roundgroup-roundup-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/roundgroup-roundup-1/</guid><description>Roundtable roundup review 1
Future of SPV Technology So hopefully I summarized this reasonably. There were a number of things that came up in our discussion. It would help SPV a lot if there were UTXO commitments in blocks. This can be done with a soft-fork. It has implementation cost difficulties. There are some ugly things you could do about how the trees are formed, so that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to repopulate the whole thing every single block.</description></item><item><title>Transaction Fee Estimation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/transaction-fee-estimation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/transaction-fee-estimation/</guid><description>How wallets can handle real transaction fees
You should have a market at this point, where some number of transactions never happen because they aren&amp;rsquo;t willing to pay a fee. So you get some equilibrium of price going on. I proactively want to see this happen because we don&amp;rsquo;t know what fees should be until we run the experiment and see what prices end up being. For this to happen, wallets have to do price setting in some way.</description></item></channel></rss>