<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Boltathon on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/boltathon/</link><description>Recent content in Boltathon on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/boltathon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>JSON Interface</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/boltathon/2019-04-06-rusty-russell-json-interface/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/boltathon/2019-04-06-rusty-russell-json-interface/</guid><description>JSON Interface with c-lightning and Writing Extensions
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230892247345852416
Intro Ok I have top running. We have a plan and we’re going to start from zero. We’re going to clone c-lightning, we’re going to compile it, we’re going to set up a test node. I’m assuming Bitcoin is already installed. We’re going to talk a little about configuring it and stuff like that. All this stuff is useful to see somebody else do.</description></item><item><title>Major Limitations of Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/boltathon/2019-04-06-alex-bosworth-major-limitations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/boltathon/2019-04-06-alex-bosworth-major-limitations/</guid><description>Slides: https://drive.google.com/open?id=1UIHfYdnAWGMvsLhljTgcneCxQAHcWjxg
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1116824776952229890
Intro So I had a Twitter poll to decide what to talk about. People seem pretty interested in the limitations. Where is the line of what Lightning can do and what Lightning can’t do. That’s what I want to talk about. To make it more clear what can be done and what can’t be done.
Every Transaction A Lightning Transaction When I first started really focusing on Lightning I thought what is the goal of Lightning, what is the goal of the Lightning Network?</description></item><item><title>Watchtowers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/boltathon/2019-04-06-conner-fromknecht-watchtowers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/boltathon/2019-04-06-conner-fromknecht-watchtowers/</guid><description>Architecture of LND Watchtowers
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1117427512081100800
discussion: https://www.reddit.com/r/lightningdevs/comments/bd33cp/architecture_of_lnd_watchtowers_presentation_from/
Intro Pretty excited today to speak on the topic of watchtowers. It is something that we at Lightning Labs have been working on for almost a year now. Conceptual proof of concept code to really flushing it out into what would be today more of a full on protocol. Hopefully today we’re going to summarize a year of research into this presentation. I’m looking forward to getting into it with you guys so let’s dive right in.</description></item></channel></rss>