<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>James O'Beirne on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/james-obeirne/</link><description>Recent content in James O'Beirne on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/james-obeirne/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AssumeUTXO update</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2023-04-27-assumeutxo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2023-04-27-assumeutxo/</guid><description>Goals allow nodes to get a utxo set quickly (1h) at the same time, no major security concessions Approach Provide serialized utxo snapshot get headers chain first, load snapshot and deserialize, sync to tip from that then start background verification with a 2nd snapshot finally, compare hashes when background IBD hits snapshot base Progress update lots of refactoring has been done; ChainStateManager was introduced, globals removed, mempool / blockstorage refactored init / shutdown logic changes have been merged wallet changes done p2p changes still under review (i.</description></item><item><title>A New Way to HODL?</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2023-01-14-james-obeirne-a-new-way-to-hodl/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2023-01-14-james-obeirne-a-new-way-to-hodl/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/449/
James, welcome back to the show.
James – 00:02:46:
Hey, Stephan, it’s great to be back. I think it’s been almost four years.
Stephan – 00:02:50:
Damn. Yeah, well, in terms of on the show, yeah, actually in person, you know, a couple of times, some of the conferences and things. But I know you’ve got this awesome proposal out, and it looks pretty interesting to me, and I’m sure SLP listeners will be very interested to hear more about it.</description></item><item><title>Advanced Segwit</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-18-james-obeirne-advanced-segwit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-18-james-obeirne-advanced-segwit/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs 2019 Residency
Slides: https://residency.chaincode.com/presentations/bitcoin/Advanced_segwit.pdf
James O&amp;rsquo;Beirne: To sort of vamp off of Jonas&amp;rsquo;s preamble, I&amp;rsquo;m not that smart. I&amp;rsquo;m a decent programmer, but compared to a lot of people who work on Bitcoin, I barely know what I&amp;rsquo;m doing. I kind of consider myself like a carpenter, a digital carpenter equivalent. I&amp;rsquo;m a steady hand. I can get things done. I&amp;rsquo;m fairly patient, which i s key when it comes to Bitcoin Core development because, trust me, you&amp;rsquo;re gonna be doing a lot of waiting around and a lot of rebasing.</description></item><item><title>Assumeutxo</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06-07-assumeutxo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06-07-assumeutxo/</guid><description>Assumeutxo
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137008648620838912
Why assumeutxo assumeutxo is a spiritual continuation of assumevalid. Why do we want to do this in the first place? At the moment, it takes hours and days to do initial block download. Various projects in the community have been implementing meassures to speed this up. Casa I think bundles datadir with their nodes. Other projects like btcpay have various ways of bundling this up and signing things with gpg keys and these solutions are not quite half-baked but they are probably not desirable either.</description></item><item><title>The Truth About 'Power' in Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2019-04-11-james-obeirne/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2019-04-11-james-obeirne/</guid><description>Stephan Livera Podcast with James O’Beirne - April 11th 2019
Podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/66/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1198289594069983237
Stephan Livera: Hello and welcome to the Stephan Livera podcast focused on Bitcoin and Austrian economics. Today my guest is James O’Beirne, Bitcoin Core engineer working at Chaincode Labs. Here’s the interview. James, I’m a fan of what you are working on over at Chaincode Labs and welcome to the show.
James O’Beirne: Thanks Stephan. It’s good to be here.</description></item><item><title>Overview Bitcoin Core Architecture</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/edgedevplusplus/overview-bitcoin-core-architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/edgedevplusplus/overview-bitcoin-core-architecture/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048098034234445824
slides: http://jameso.be/dev++2018/
Introduction Alright guys, how are you guys doing? You guys look tired. Given your brains are probably fried, I am delighted to tell you that this talk will be pretty high level. I am James O&amp;rsquo;Beirne, I work at Chaincode Labs. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on Bitcoin Core since 2015. I am in New York most of the time.
Agenda Today we are going to talk about Bitcoin Core.</description></item></channel></rss>