<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>miniscript on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/miniscript/</link><description>Recent content in miniscript on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/miniscript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Simplicity: Going Beyond Miniscript</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2023/simplicity-going-beyond-miniscript/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2023/simplicity-going-beyond-miniscript/</guid><description>Can we welcome Christian to the stage? I think I don&amp;rsquo;t have any computer yet. Oh.. It&amp;rsquo;s just okay. All right, I just, I just just read. There&amp;rsquo;s a pointer, okay, great great. I was a bit confused for a second. Can I start? great, so welcome, I&amp;rsquo;m Christian Lewe. I work for Blockstream to research where I mainly work on Simplicity and Miniscript and it&amp;rsquo;s great that we just had a talk on Miniscript so you all know why Miniscript is great, why you should use Miniscript, and in my talk I want to go beyond that.</description></item><item><title>Timelock-enabled safety and recovery use cases for Bitcoin users</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2023/timelock-enabled-safety-and-recovery-use-cases-for-bitcoin-users/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2023/timelock-enabled-safety-and-recovery-use-cases-for-bitcoin-users/</guid><description>Introduction Can we give a round of applause for Kevin, and welcome him to the stage. Thank you. Alright, yeah, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to do a talk around Timelocks in Bitcoin. I&amp;rsquo;m going to start with a pretty quick introduction on the different types of Timelocks over time in Bitcoin, and where we&amp;rsquo;re at today. Also, a little bit, very, very quickly talking about what we&amp;rsquo;re using Timelocks for in Bitcoin today.</description></item><item><title>Miniscript</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2022/2022-03-03-sanket-kanjalkar-miniscript/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2022/2022-03-03-sanket-kanjalkar-miniscript/</guid><description>Topic: Miniscript: Composable, Analyzable and Smarter Bitcoin Script
Andrew Poelstra on Miniscript: https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-02-04-andrew-poelstra-miniscript/
Intro (Jeff Gallas) The next speaker is Sanket. He is working at Blockstream and is mostly working on Simplicity and Miniscript and that is also what he is going to talk about, Miniscript. Please welcome Sanket.
Intro (Sanket Kanjalkar) Good morning everyone. Today I will be discussing Miniscript which is a work of Pieter Wuille, Andrew Poelstra and me with input from many Bitcoiners.</description></item><item><title>Miniscript</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/2021-11-06-andrew-poelstra-miniscript/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/2021-11-06-andrew-poelstra-miniscript/</guid><description>Topic: Miniscript - Custody, Computable, Composable
Location: TABConf (The Atlanta Bitcoin Conference)
Slides: https://download.wpsoftware.net/bitcoin/wizardry/2021-11-tabconf/slides.pdf
Intro I am here to talk about Miniscript. This is something that I have talked about a few times before but usually in a much more technical way where we get into the weeds of Bitcoin Script and what Miniscript is and how to use it and stuff. I want to talk today about Miniscript from the perspective of someone actually trying to use Bitcoin and how this solves problems that I think are very important in the space regarding how to custody your coins, how to keep track of your keys, stuff like that.</description></item><item><title>Magical Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/la-bitdevs/2020-05-21-alekos-filini-magical-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/la-bitdevs/2020-05-21-alekos-filini-magical-bitcoin/</guid><description>Location: LA BitDevs (online)
Magical Bitcoin site: https://magicalbitcoin.org/
Magical Bitcoin wallet GitHub: https://github.com/MagicalBitcoin/magical-bitcoin-wallet
sipa’s Miniscript site: http://bitcoin.sipa.be/miniscript/
Andrew Poelstra Miniscript presentation at London Bitcoin Devs: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-02-04-andrew-poelstra-miniscript/
Andrew Poelstra Miniscript workshop at Advancing Bitcoin: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-07-andrew-poelstra-miniscript/
Intro I am a developer, I work on Bitcoin. I came to Bitcoin pretty late compared to the people I work with. I started a couple of years ago working with Giacomo Zucco at BHB Network. I worked for a while at Blockstream and then I left.</description></item><item><title>Miniscript</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-07-andrew-poelstra-miniscript/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-07-andrew-poelstra-miniscript/</guid><description>Advancing Bitcoin workshop
Miniscript
Website: https://bitcoin.sipa.be/miniscript/
Workshop repo: https://github.com/apoelstra/miniscript-workshop
Transcript of London Bitcoin Devs Miniscript presentation: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-02-04-andrew-poelstra-miniscript/
Part 1 So what we’re going to do, there is a couple of things. We are going to go through the Miniscript website and learn about how Miniscript is constructed, how the type system works, some of the anti-malleability rules. Then we’re going to go to a repo that I created last night, a Git repo with some example programs.</description></item><item><title>Miniscript Intro</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-06-andrew-poelstra-miniscript-intro/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-06-andrew-poelstra-miniscript-intro/</guid><description>Topic: Introduction to Miniscript
Location: Advancing Bitcoin
Slides: https://www.dropbox.com/s/vgh5vaooqqbgg1v/andrew-poelstra.pdf
Intro Hi everyone. Some of you were at my Bitcoin dev presentation about Miniscript a couple of days where I managed to spend over 2 hours giving a presentation about this. I think I got this one down to 20 minutes but no promises. I will keep an eye on the clock.
Descriptors It is very nice having this scheduled immediately after Andrew Chow’s talk about output descriptors because there is a good transition here.</description></item><item><title>Socratic Seminar 3</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/austin-bitcoin-developers/2019-10-14-socratic-seminar-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/austin-bitcoin-developers/2019-10-14-socratic-seminar-3/</guid><description>https://www.meetup.com/Austin-Bitcoin-Developers/events/265295570/
https://bitdevs.org/2019-09-16-socratic-seminar-96
We have sort of done two meetups in this format. The idea here is that in NY there&amp;rsquo;s BitDevs which is one of the oldest meetups. This has been going on for five years. They have a format called socratic where they have a talented guy named J who leads them through some topics and they try to get some discussion going on and pull from expertise in the audience.</description></item><item><title>Tales from the Crypt with Andrew Poelstra</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tftc-podcast/2019-06-18-andrew-poelstra-tftc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tftc-podcast/2019-06-18-andrew-poelstra-tftc/</guid><description>TFTC podcast with Andrew Poelstra - June 18th 2019 (Abridged)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1160178010986876928
Podcast: https://talesfromthecrypt.libsyn.com/tales-from-the-crypt-80-andrew-poelstra
How the idea of Taproot was formed Andrew: There are some small off suit IRC channels of bitcoin-wizards where people discuss some specific topics such as Minisketch which is a set reconciliation protocol that was developed by Greg Maxwell, Pieter Wuille and Gleb Naumenko among a couple of others. It was mostly those three. They have a channel where they talk about things.</description></item><item><title>Miniscript</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/noded-podcast/2019-05-11-andrew-poelstra-miniscript/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/noded-podcast/2019-05-11-andrew-poelstra-miniscript/</guid><description>Noded podcast May 10th 2019
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1135217746059415552
Intros Pierre: Welcome to the Noded Bitcoin podcast. I’m your co-host Pierre Rochard with my other co-host Michael Goldstein aka bitstein. How’s it going Michael?
bitstein: It’s going well, I just hope they don’t ban Bitcoin
Pierre: Any day now. We have a very special guest on today, Andrew Poelstra from Blockstream. Andrew, how are you?
Andrew: I’m good. How are you?
Pierre: Great. Did you hear today’s news about the representative in Congress who wanted to ban cryptocurrencies?</description></item><item><title>Miniscript</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/miniscript/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/miniscript/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1091116834219151360
Jeremy: Our next speaker really needs no introduction. However, I am obligated to deliver an introduction anyway. I&amp;rsquo;m not just trying to avoid pronouncing his name which is known to be unpronounceable. I am pleased to welcome Pieter Wuille to stage to present on miniscript.
Introduction Thanks, Jeremy. I am Pieter Wuille. I work at Blockstream. I do various things. Today I will be talking about miniscript, which is a joint effort between myself and some colleagues at Blockstream particularly Andrew Poelstra.</description></item></channel></rss>