<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Matt Corallo on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/matt-corallo/</link><description>Recent content in Matt Corallo on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/matt-corallo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What Bitcoin Specialises in</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2023-02-23-matt-corallo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2023-02-23-matt-corallo/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/461/
Stephan:
Welcome back to the show, Matt.
Matt :
Yeah, thanks for having me.
Stephan :
So lots of things going on. I know there’s always some topic of the day or whatever that’s happening, whether it’s Ordinals and inscriptions, which is the latest kind of craze. Maybe the Mempool is clearing out a little bit now, but yeah, I thought it would be good to chat with you again.</description></item><item><title>Lightning is Broken AF (But We Can Fix It)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/lightning-is-broken-af-but-we-can-fix-it/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/lightning-is-broken-af-but-we-can-fix-it/</guid><description>Introduction Thank you. Yeah, so, as the title says, for those of you who work in lightning or have been around lightning for a long time, hopefully you will recognize basically all the issues I&amp;rsquo;ll go through today. I&amp;rsquo;m going to go through a very long list of things. But I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to go through most of the kind of, at least my understanding of the current thinking of solutions for a lot of these issues.</description></item><item><title>SLP324 Scaling Bitcoin off-chain with Matt Corallo, Alex Bosworth, Lisa Neigut, and Graham Krizek</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2021-11-27-lisa-neigut-alex-bosworth-graham-krizek-and-matt-corallo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2021-11-27-lisa-neigut-alex-bosworth-graham-krizek-and-matt-corallo/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/324/
Stephan Livera:
So guys, thanks for joining us. We’re talking about off-chain scaling. And so obviously Lightning is the first thing that comes to our mind, but maybe we could start with this idea of What is off-chain scaling? I think Lisa, you had something to add on this, didn’t you?
Matt Corallo:
We had a meeting in the back and we decided we were moving Lightning to TRON.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Dev Kit - Making Lightning More Accessible to Developers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/lightning-dev-kit-making-lightning-more-accessible-to-developers-matt-corallo-tabconf-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/lightning-dev-kit-making-lightning-more-accessible-to-developers-matt-corallo-tabconf-2021/</guid><description>Introduction So, I worked on Bitcoin Core for many many years, but I am not here to talk about that! I now spend my time, full time at Square Crypto working on a project we call the Lightning Dev Kit (LDK). So, working to enable Lightning to be more accessible to developers and I&amp;rsquo;m here to talk about that and give the lay of the land for why it exists, what the state of the Lightning ecosystem is broadly, and why we think it&amp;rsquo;s an important project and why Square is funding us, to work on it.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Development Kit</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2021-05-12-matt-corallo-ldk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2021-05-12-matt-corallo-ldk/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs Podcast (Episode 13)
Matt Corallo presentation at Advancing Bitcoin 2019: https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2019/2019-02-07-matt-corallo-rust-lightning/
rust-lightning repo: https://github.com/rust-bitcoin/rust-lightning
Intro Adam Jonas (AJ): Welcome back to the office Matt, glad to have you back on the podcast.
Matt Corallo (MC): Thank you.
Update on LDK AJ: We are going to start with LDK. Where are we at? What is going on?
MC: If listeners are aware LDK kind of grew out of a project that I started a few years ago when I was working at Chaincode called rust-lightning.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Soft Fork Activation, Taproot, and Playing Chicken</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2021-03-04-matt-corallo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2021-03-04-matt-corallo/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/257/
Stephan Livera:
Matt, welcome to the show.
Matt Corallo:
Hey yeah, thanks for having me.
Stephan Livera:
So guys, obviously, listeners, you know, we’re just having to re-record this. We had basically a screw up the first time around, but we wanted to chat about Taproot and soft fork activation. So perhaps Matt, if we could just start from your side, let’s try to keep this accessible for listeners who maybe they are new.</description></item><item><title>UASFs, BIP 148, BIP 91 and Taproot Activation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tftc-podcast/2021-02-11-matt-corallo-taproot-activation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tftc-podcast/2021-02-11-matt-corallo-taproot-activation/</guid><description>Topic: UASFs, BIP 148, BIP 91 and Taproot Activation
Location: Tales from the Crypt podcast
Intro Marty Bent (MB): Sitting down with a man who needs no introduction on this podcast. I think you have been on four times already. I think this is number five Matt. You are worried about the future of Bitcoin. What the hell is going on? You reached out to me last week, you scaring the s*** out of me.</description></item><item><title>Compact Blocks and Fibre</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2020-03-12-matt-corallo-compact-blocks-fibre/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2020-03-12-matt-corallo-compact-blocks-fibre/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs Podcast (Episode 6)
Intro Adam Jonas (AJ): Welcome Matt
Matt Corallo (MC): Hi
John Newbery (JN): Hi Matt
AJ: Today we are going to do a little bit of a “This is your life Bitcoin”.
MC: I am not dead yet.
AJ: You have a lot of contributions over the years so there is lots to talk about but we’ll start with three. Let’s start with compact blocks.</description></item><item><title>Great Consensus Cleanup</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06/2019-06-06-great-consensus-cleanup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06/2019-06-06-great-consensus-cleanup/</guid><description>https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2019-March/016714.html
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1136591286012698626
Introduction There&amp;rsquo;s not much new to talk about. Unclear about CODESEPARATOR. You want to make it a consensus rule that transactions can&amp;rsquo;t be larger than 100 kb. No reactions to that? Alright. Fine, we&amp;rsquo;re doing it. Let&amp;rsquo;s do it. Does everyone know what this proposal is?
Validation time for any block&amp;ndash; we were lazy about fixing this. Segwit was a first step to fixing this, by giving people a way to do this in a more efficient way.</description></item><item><title>The State of Bitcoin Mining</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/the-state-of-bitcoin-mining/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/the-state-of-bitcoin-mining/</guid><description>Topic: The State of Bitcoin Mining: No Good, The Bad, and The Ugly
So I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk a little bit about kind of the state of mining and the set of protocols that are used for mining today, a tiny bit about the history. And then I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk very briefly about some of the solutions that are being proposed, whether it&amp;rsquo;s BetterHash, whether it&amp;rsquo;s Braidpool design, rebooting P2Pool, and some of the other stuff, only kind of briefly at the end.</description></item><item><title>Rust Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2019/2019-02-07-matt-corallo-rust-lightning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2019/2019-02-07-matt-corallo-rust-lightning/</guid><description>Flexible Lightning in Rust
Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/154bMWdcMCFUco4ZXQ3lWfF51U5dad8pQ23rKVkncnns/edit#slide=id.p
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1144256392490029057
Introduction Thanks for having me. I want to talk a little bit about a project I’ve been working on for about a year called rust-lightning. I started it in December so a year and a few months ago. This is my first presentation on it so I’m excited to finally get to talk about it a little bit.
Goals It is yet another Lightning implementation because somehow we needed another one I guess or really not.</description></item><item><title>Betterhash</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2019-02-05-matt-corallo-betterhash/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2019-02-05-matt-corallo-betterhash/</guid><description>Topic: Better Hashing through BetterHash
Location: London Bitcoin Devs
Announcement of BetterHash on the mailing list: https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2018-June/016077.html
Draft BIP: https://github.com/TheBlueMatt/bips/blob/betterhash/bip-XXXX.mediawiki
Intro I am going to talk about BetterHash this evening. If you are coming to Advancing Bitcoin don’t worry I am talking about something completely different. You are not going to get duplicated content. That talk should be interesting as well though admittedly I haven’t written it yet. We’ll find out.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Mining And Trustlessness</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/bitcoin-mining-and-trustlessness/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/bitcoin-mining-and-trustlessness/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/838500313212518404
Yes, something like that. As mentioned, I&amp;rsquo;ve been contributing to Bitcoin Core since 2011 and I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on various parts of bitcoin, such as the early payment channel work, some wallet stuff, and now I work for Chaincode Lab one of the sponsors&amp;ndash; we&amp;rsquo;re a bitcoin research lab. We all kind of hang out and work on various bitcoin projects we find interesting. I want to talk about reflections on trusting trust.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Protocol Development Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/bitcoin-protocol-development-panel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/bitcoin-protocol-development-panel/</guid><description>Bitcoin protocol development panel
KW: We have some wonderful panelists today. Let&amp;rsquo;s kick it off. Let&amp;rsquo;s start with Eric. Who are you and what role do you play in bitcoin development?
EL: I got into bitcoin in 2011. I had my own network stack. I almost had a full node implementation but I stopped short because it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as well tested or reviewed as Bitcoin Core. So I started to look into the community a little bit.</description></item><item><title>Fungibility Overview</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/fungibility-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/fungibility-overview/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784676022318952448
Introduction Alright. So let&amp;rsquo;s get started. Okay. Why fungibility? Let&amp;rsquo;s start. What does fungibility mean? Bitcoin is like cash. The hope is that it&amp;rsquo;s for immediate and final payments. To add some nuiance there, you might have to wait for some confirmations. Once you receive a bitcoin, you have a bitcoin and that&amp;rsquo;s final. So even with banks and PayPal, who sometimes shutdown accounts for trivial reasons or sometimes no reason at all, it&amp;rsquo;s typically not the case that it&amp;rsquo;s someone who sent you money&amp;hellip; if you were selling something on ebay, and someone bought an item from you, and that person had an account shutdown, the money you received will not be removed from your account.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Security Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-security-panel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-security-panel/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137758233865703424
Introduction MF: I will start by thanking Kevin and Lea and the organizers. It&amp;rsquo;s been an awesome event. Thanks also to the sponsors. Without their assistance we couldn&amp;rsquo;t have had the event. I&amp;rsquo;d also like to make some plugs before we start the conversation. One, I run the London Bitcoin developers group. If you&amp;rsquo;re ever in London or interested in speaking, please look up London Bitcoin Devs on Twitter or Meetup.</description></item><item><title>Sidechains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/matt-corallo-sidechains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/matt-corallo-sidechains/</guid><description>Sidechains, Blockstream
One second. Technical difficulties. Okay, sorry about that. Okay. Hi. I am Matt or BlueMatt for those of you know me. I swear it&amp;rsquo;s not related to my hair. Nobody believes me.
I got into Bitcoin three or four years ago because I was interested in the programming and computer science aspects and as well as my interest in large-scale economic incentive structures and macroeconomics and how we create incentive structures that create actions on a low level by rational actors.</description></item><item><title>Trustlessness Scalability And Directions In Security Models</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/trustlessness-scalability-and-directions-in-security-models/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/trustlessness-scalability-and-directions-in-security-models/</guid><description>Trustlessness, scalability and directions in security models
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043397023846883329
&amp;hellip; Is everyone awake? Sure. Jumping jacks. Wow, that&amp;rsquo;s bright. I am more idealistic than Eric. I am going to talk about utility and why people use bitcoin and let&amp;rsquo;s see how that goes.
Trustlessness is much better than decentralization. I want to talk about trustlessness. People use the word decentralization a lot and I find that to be kind of useless because decentralization is a means to an end.</description></item></channel></rss>