<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>multisig on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/multisig/</link><description>Recent content in multisig on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/multisig/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What is splicing?</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/what-is-splicing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/what-is-splicing/</guid><description>Stephan Livera 00:02:14
Dusty welcome to the show hey thanks for having me yeah I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of what you got what you&amp;rsquo;re doing with splicing and obviously it&amp;rsquo;s been great to see you over the years kind of or in and around the Bitcoin and Lightning circles and yeah I love what you&amp;rsquo;re doing with flashing so let&amp;rsquo;s hear a little bit about you just for people who don&amp;rsquo;t know you just a little bit on you</description></item><item><title>Timelock-enabled safety and recovery use cases for Bitcoin users</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2023/timelock-enabled-safety-and-recovery-use-cases-for-bitcoin-users/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2023/timelock-enabled-safety-and-recovery-use-cases-for-bitcoin-users/</guid><description>Introduction Can we give a round of applause for Kevin, and welcome him to the stage. Thank you. Alright, yeah, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to do a talk around Timelocks in Bitcoin. I&amp;rsquo;m going to start with a pretty quick introduction on the different types of Timelocks over time in Bitcoin, and where we&amp;rsquo;re at today. Also, a little bit, very, very quickly talking about what we&amp;rsquo;re using Timelocks for in Bitcoin today.</description></item><item><title>SLP455 Anant Tapadia - Single Sig or Multi Sig?</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/slp455-anant-tapadia-single-sig-or-multi-sig/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/slp455-anant-tapadia-single-sig-or-multi-sig/</guid><description>Stephan 00:00:00:
Anant, welcome back to the show.
Anant 00:02:38:
Hey Stephan, thanks for having me again.
Stephan 00:02:40:
So there&amp;rsquo;s been a lot going on. I think the conversation around learning to self custody is always an important one. It&amp;rsquo;s always one that&amp;rsquo;s very fresh on my mind as well. And so we&amp;rsquo;re seeing a lot of discussion. And I think recently, of course, there was the news about Luke Dash-jr losing his coins, I think, I don&amp;rsquo;t know exactly how many, but probably something in the range of 200 bitcoins, so a serious amount of coin.</description></item><item><title>MuSig2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2022-08-11-tim-ruffing-musig2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2022-08-11-tim-ruffing-musig2/</guid><description>Topic: MuSig2
Location: London Bitcoin Devs
Date: August 11th 2022
Reading list: https://gist.github.com/michaelfolkson/5bfffa71a93426b57d518b09ebd0998c
Introduction Michael Folkson (MF): This is a Socratic Seminar, we are going to be discussing MuSig2 and we’ll move onto adjacent topics such as FROST and libsecp256k1 later. We have a few people on the call including Tim (Ruffing). If you want to do short intros, you don’t have to, for the people on the call.
Tim Ruffing (TR): Hi.</description></item><item><title>Taproot multisig</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2022/2022-03-03-jimmy-song-taproot-multisig/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2022/2022-03-03-jimmy-song-taproot-multisig/</guid><description>Slides: https://jimmysong.github.io/taproot-multisig
Pull request adding multisig Taproot support to buidl-python: https://github.com/buidl-bitcoin/buidl-python/pull/109
Intro (Jeff Gallas) The next speaker is Jimmy Song who doesn’t really need an introduction but in any case, he has been, which is important for this conference, running the Programming Blockchain workshops for 5 years now. Leon is one of his alumni so there is a direct connection to this conference. He has also just released a new book which is a bit more political than technical, it is called “Bitcoin and the American Dream”.</description></item><item><title>MuSig2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/iacr/2021-08-16-jonas-nick-musig2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/iacr/2021-08-16-jonas-nick-musig2/</guid><description>MuSig2: Simple Two-Round Schnorr Multi-Signatures
Location: IACR Crypto
MuSig2 paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/1261.pdf
Introduction This is a talk about MuSig2, simple two round Schnorr multisignatures. I am Jonas Nick and this work is a collaboration with my colleague Tim Ruffing at Blockstream and Yannick Seurin.
Multi-Signatures Multisignatures allow n signers to produce a single signature on a single message. The signing protocol can be interactive and require multiple communication rounds. We distinguish between multisignatures where n-of-n signers can produce a signature and threshold signatures where any subset of size t out of n signers can produce a signature.</description></item><item><title>MuSig2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/realworldcrypto/2021/2021-01-12-tim-ruffing-musig2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/realworldcrypto/2021/2021-01-12-tim-ruffing-musig2/</guid><description>Topic: MuSig2: Simple Two-Round Schnorr Multi-Signatures
Location: Real World Crypto
MuSig2 paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/1261.pdf
Introduction This is about MuSig2, simple two round Schnorr multisignatures. This is joint work with Jonas Nick and Yannick Seurin. Jonas will be available to answer questions as I will be of course.
Multi-Signatures The idea that with multisignatures is that n signers can get together and produce a single signature on a single message. To be clear for this talk when I talk about multisignatures what I mean is n-of-n signatures and not the more general setting of threshold signatures where you can have a threshold t that is smaller than n and have something like a t-of-n signatures.</description></item><item><title>MuSig, MuSig-DN and MuSig2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-10-27-jonas-nick-tim-ruffing-musig2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-10-27-jonas-nick-tim-ruffing-musig2/</guid><description>Topic: MuSig, MuSig-DN and MuSig2
Location: Stephan Livera Podcast
Tim Ruffing on Schnorr multisig at London Bitcoin Devs: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-17-tim-ruffing-schnorr-multisig/
MuSig paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/068.pdf
MuSig blog post: https://blockstream.com/2019/02/18/en-musig-a-new-multisignature-standard/
Insecure shortcuts in MuSig: https://medium.com/blockstream/insecure-shortcuts-in-musig-2ad0d38a97da
MuSig-DN paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/1057.pdf
MuSig-DN blog post: https://medium.com/blockstream/musig-dn-schnorr-multisignatures-with-verifiably-deterministic-nonces-27424b5df9d6
MuSig2 paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/1261.pdf
MuSig2 blog post: https://medium.com/blockstream/musig2-simple-two-round-schnorr-multisignatures-bf9582e99295
Transcript completed by: Stephan Livera Edited by: Michael Folkson
Intro Stephan Livera (SL): Jonas and Tim, welcome to the show.
Jonas Nick (JN): Hello.
Tim Ruffing (TR): Hey.</description></item><item><title>Checkmultisig Bug</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2020-08-27-greg-maxwell-checkmultisig-bug/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2020-08-27-greg-maxwell-checkmultisig-bug/</guid><description>What is stopping the OP_CHECKMULTISIG extra pop bug from being fixed?
Location: Bitcointalk
https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?topic=5271566.msg55079521#msg55079521
What is stopping the OP_CHECKMULTISIG extra pop bug from being fixed? I think it is probably wrong to describe it as a bug. I think it was intended to indicate which signatures were present to fix the otherwise terrible performance of CHECKMULTISIG.
Regardless, there is no real point to fixing it: Any &amp;lsquo;fix&amp;rsquo; would require that all software using CHECKMULTISIG get an incompatible change (as part of a highly disruptive hard fork).</description></item><item><title>Schnorr and Multisig</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-17-tim-ruffing-schnorr-multisig/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-17-tim-ruffing-schnorr-multisig/</guid><description>Taproot and Schnorr Multisignatures
Location: London Bitcoin Devs (online)
Slides: https://slides.com/real-or-random/taproot-and-schnorr-multisig
Transcript of the previous day’s Socratic Seminar on BIP-Schnorr: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-16-socratic-seminar-bip-schnorr/
Intro (Michael Folkson) We are now live. This is London Bitcoin Devs with Tim Ruffing. We had the Socratic Seminar yesterday, I think we have some people on the call that were at the Socratic Seminar. That was brilliant. Thanks to Tim, Pieter, Greg, waxwing and everyone for showing up and taking 2 and a half hours out of their day.</description></item><item><title>Socratic Seminar</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2020-05-19-socratic-seminar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2020-05-19-socratic-seminar/</guid><description>Name: Socratic Seminar
Topic: Agenda in Google Doc below
Location: Bitcoin Sydney (online)
Video: No video posted online
Google Doc of the resources discussed: https://docs.google.com/document/d/1hCTlQdt_dK6HerKNt0kl6X8HAeRh16VSAaEtrqcBvlw/
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.</description></item><item><title>Custody Group</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/custody-group/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/custody-group/</guid><description>Custody working group
One of the problems in the ecosystem was nomenclature. We started working on a report about what features a nomenclature would have. Airgaps, constant-time software, sidechannel resistance, Faraday cage, deterministic software, entropy, blind signatures, proof-of-reserve, multi-vendor hardware to minimize compromise. Multi-location and multi-sig. Insurance guarantee scheme. Canaries, dead man switches, tripwires, heartbeat mechanisms. Shamir&amp;rsquo;s secret sharing vs multisig. The second part of this report was going to be market analysis.</description></item><item><title>Socratic Seminar 2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/austin-bitcoin-developers/2019-08-22-socratic-seminar-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/austin-bitcoin-developers/2019-08-22-socratic-seminar-2/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1164710800910692353
Introduction Hello. The idea was to do a more socratic style meetup. This was popularized by Bitdevs NYC and spread to SF. We tried this a few months ago with Jay. The idea is we run through research news, newsletters, podcasters, talk about what happened in the technical bitcoin community. We&amp;rsquo;re going to have different presenters.
Mike Schmidt is going to talk about some optech newsletters that he has been contributing to.</description></item><item><title>Secure Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2019/signature-scheme-security-properties/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2019/signature-scheme-security-properties/</guid><description>Topic: Secure Signatures - Harder Than You Think
Location: MIT Bitcoin Expo 2019
Twitter announcement: https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1104399812147916800
Transcript completed by: Bryan Bishop Edited by: Michael Folkson
Introduction Hi everyone. Can you hear me alright? Is my mic? Okay, cool. I was scheduled to talk about the history of Schnorr signatures in Bitcoin. I wanted to do that but then I realized I’ve only got 20-30 minutes to talk here. Instead I am going to focus on one particular piece of that history, which is the security model surrounding not just Schnorr signatures but extensions to Schnorr signatures we really care about.</description></item><item><title>Scripts (general &amp; simple)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/scripts-general-and-simple/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/scripts-general-and-simple/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1047679223115083777
Introduction I am going to talk about why we have scripts in bitcoin. I&amp;rsquo;ll give some examples and the design philosophy. I am not going to talk about the semantics of bitcoin script, though. Why do we have bitcoin script? I&amp;rsquo;ll show how to lock and unlock coins. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about pay-to-pubkey, multisig, and computing vs verification in the blockchain.
Why have script at all? In my first talk, I talked about digital signatures to transfer coins from one person to another.</description></item><item><title>Bellare Neven</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-03/2018-03-05-bellare-neven/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-03/2018-03-05-bellare-neven/</guid><description>See also http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2017-09-06-signature-aggregation/
Bellare-Neven It&amp;rsquo;s been published, it&amp;rsquo;s been around for a decade, and it&amp;rsquo;s widely cited. In Bellare-Neven, it&amp;rsquo;s itself, it&amp;rsquo;s a multi-signature scheme which means multiple pubkeys and one message. You should treat the individual authorizations to spend inputs, as individual messages. What we need is an interactive aggregate signature scheme. Bellare-Neven&amp;rsquo;s paper suggests a trivial way of building an aggregate signature scheme out of a multisig scheme where interactively everyone signs everyone&amp;rsquo;s message.</description></item><item><title>Signature Aggregation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2017-09/2017-09-06-signature-aggregation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2017-09/2017-09-06-signature-aggregation/</guid><description>﻿https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/907065194463072258
Signature aggregation Sipa, can you sign and verify ECDSA signatures by hand? No. Over GF(43), maybe. Inverses could take a little bit to compute. Over GF(2).
I think the first thing we should talk about is some definitions. I&amp;rsquo;d like to start by distinguishing between three things: Key aggregation, signature aggregation, and batch validation. Multi-signature later.
There are three different problems. Key aggregation is where there are a number of people with each their own key, they want to produce a combined key that can only sign when they come together.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network As A Directed Graph Single Funded Channel Network Topology</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-04-11-lightning-network-as-a-directed-graph-single-funded-channel-network-topology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-04-11-lightning-network-as-a-directed-graph-single-funded-channel-network-topology/</guid><description>http://lightning.network/
slides: http://diyhpl.us/~bryan/papers2/bitcoin/Lightning%20Network%20as%20Directed%20Graph%20Single-Funded%20Channel%20Topology%20-%20Tadge%20Dryja%20-%202016-04-11.pdf
Okay. Hello everyone. Yes, okay, great. Yes. Yeah, I&amp;rsquo;m working on Lightning Network. Bitcoin is great and fun to work on.
Basic super quick summary of Lightning I am going to re-cap lightning network real quick. The basic idea is to have channels between two nodes. A channel, from the perspective of the rest of the world, is just a 2-of-2 multisig output. You can&amp;rsquo;t even tell it&amp;rsquo;s multisig, you just see an address with a 3 in front of the address.</description></item><item><title>Key Tree Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2015-08-24-pieter-wuille-key-tree-signatures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2015-08-24-pieter-wuille-key-tree-signatures/</guid><description>Topic: Key Tree Signatures
Location: SF Bitcoin Devs
Slides: https://prezi.com/vsj95ns4ucu3/key-tree-signatures/
Blog post: https://blockstream.com/2015/08/24/en-treesignatures/
Intro For those who don’t know me I’m Pieter Wuille. I have been working on Bitcoin Core for a while but this is work I have been doing at Blockstream. Today I will be talking about Key Tree Signatures which is what I have been working on these past few weeks. It is an improvement to the multisig schemes that we want to support.</description></item><item><title>Armory Proof Of Payment</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/armory-proof-of-payment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/armory-proof-of-payment/</guid><description>I am going to talk about proof of payment. This is simple. You can do this. That you couldn&amp;rsquo;t do before 2008. We&amp;rsquo;ll see if this works. I hear it might work. That&amp;rsquo;s okay, I&amp;rsquo;ll pull this up here. I have ruined everything. Just jam that in there. Here we go.
So uh, I said who I am. Bitcoin Armory. I am here to talk about proof of payment. Basically, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about Armory first real quick.</description></item><item><title>Future Of Hardware Wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/future-of-hardware-wallets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/future-of-hardware-wallets/</guid><description>The future of hardware wallets
D419 C410 1E24 5B09 0D2C 46BF 8C3D 2C48 560E 81AC
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137663515957837826
Introduction We are making a secure hardware platform for developers so that they can build their own hardware wallets. Today I want to talk about certain challenges for hardware wallets, what we&amp;rsquo;re missing, and how we can get better.
Current capabilities of hardware wallets Normally, hardware wallets keep keys reasonably secret and are able to spend coins or sign transactions.</description></item><item><title>Gavinandresen</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2015-02/gavinandresen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2015-02/gavinandresen/</guid><description>http://blog.circle.com/2015/02/10/devcore-livestream/
The instant transaction time.. you know I walk up to a cash register, I put my phone there, and in a second or two the transaction is confirmed and I walk away with my coffee. Anything beyond that, 10 minutes versus 1 minute doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. So the problem you want to solve is how do we get instant confirmation.. there&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of ideas about this, like a trusted third party that promises to not double spend, have some coins locked up in a multisig wallet like Green Address.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Routing</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/lightning-network-routing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/lightning-network-routing/</guid><description>Introduction Good afternoon everyone. My name is Carla. I am one of the chaincode residents this summer. This talk is going to walk through the protocol layer by layer and look at the different components that make up the network. Lightning is an off-chain scaling solution which consists of a p2p network of payment channels. It allows payments to be forwarded by nodes in exchange for fees.
Scaling with payment channels This involves a payment channel.</description></item><item><title>Petertodd Dex</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/petertodd-dex/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/petertodd-dex/</guid><description>I have been working on deterministic expressions language called DEX. It looks like lambda calculus. But really we&amp;rsquo;re trying to create a way to specify expressions that would return true if a signature is valid. Something like this, which is really just check a signature against a pubkey for a message, is essentially something that would be baked into your software anyway. We&amp;rsquo;re trying to move into a layer of abstraction where you can specify the conditions you need for your particular use case.</description></item><item><title>Scriptless Ecdsa</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/scriptless-ecdsa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/scriptless-ecdsa/</guid><description>Instantiating scriptless 2p-ECDSA: fungible 2-of-2 multisigs for bitcoin today
Conner Fromknecht (Lightning Labs)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048483254087573504
maybe https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/472.pdf and https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/lightning-dev/2018-April/001221.html
Introduction Alright. Thank you very much. Thank you Pedro, that was a great segue into what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about. He has been doing work on formalizing multi-hop locks. I want to also talk about what changes might be necessary to deploy this on the lightning network.
History For what it&amp;rsquo;s worth, these dates are rough.</description></item><item><title>Scriptless Scripts With Mimblewimble</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/scriptless-scripts-with-mimblewimble/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/scriptless-scripts-with-mimblewimble/</guid><description>Scriptless scripts with mimblewimble
Andrew Poelstra (andytoshi)
Introduction Hi everyone. I am Andrew Poelstra. I am the research director at Blockstream. I want to talk about deploying scriptless scripts, wihch is something I haven&amp;rsquo;t talked much about over the past year or two.
History Let me give a bit of history about mimblewimble. As many of you know, this was dead-dropped anonymously in the middle of 2016 by someone named Tom Elvis Jedusor which is the French name for Voldemort.</description></item><item><title>Smart Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/smart-signatures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/smart-signatures/</guid><description>Christopher Allen
Smart signatures and smarter signatures
Signatures are a 50+ year old technology. I am talking about the digital signature. It&amp;rsquo;s a hash of an object that has been encrypted by private key and verified by a public key against the hash of the object. All of our systems are using this in a varity of complex ways at high level to either do identity, sign a block, or do a variety of different things.</description></item><item><title>State Of Multisig</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/state-of-multisig/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/state-of-multisig/</guid><description>State of multisig for bitcoin hodlers: Better wallets with PSBT
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1162769521993834496
Introduction I am going to be talking about the state of multisig. It&amp;rsquo;s a way of creating a transaction output that requires multiple keys to sign. This is a focus for people holding bitcoin. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about some of the benefits and some of the issues. I am not a security expert, though.
Perspective Multisig is an emphasis on saving and not spending a lot.</description></item><item><title>Threshold Scriptless Scripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/threshold-scriptless-scripts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/threshold-scriptless-scripts/</guid><description>Omer Shlomovits (KZen Research) (omershlomovits, zengo)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171690582445580288
Scriptless scripts We can write smart contracts in bitcoin today, but there&amp;rsquo;s some limitations. We can do a lot of great things. We can do atomic swaps, multisig, payment channels, etc. There&amp;rsquo;s a cost, though. Transactions become bigger with bigger scripts. Also, it&amp;rsquo;s kind of heavy on the verifiers. The verifiers now need to verify more things. There&amp;rsquo;s also privacy issues because you put your contract publicly on chain.</description></item><item><title>Threshold signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/arvind-narayanan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/arvind-narayanan/</guid><description>I want to tell you what threshold signatures are and I want to convince you that threshold signatures are a technology you need. This is collaborative work.
There are three things I want to tell you today. The first is that the banking security model has been very very refined and has sophisticated techniques and process and controls for ensuring security. It does not translate to Bitcoin. This may seem surprising.</description></item><item><title>Topics</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/rebooting-web-of-trust/2019-prague/topics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/rebooting-web-of-trust/2019-prague/topics/</guid><description>Rebooting Web of Trust topic selection
Dictionary terms: we have a glossary that I wrote 6 months ago which by definition glosses everything. A dictionary would give an opportunity to go into more depth, to look at disagreements without getting lost in the weeds, and also talk about some foundational assumptions.
Verifiable secret sharing: this is a modification for Shamir secret sharing that also incorporates multisignatures as well. We&amp;rsquo;re interested in solidifying that into an actual proposal and talk about the pro&amp;rsquo;s of con&amp;rsquo;s of traditional secret sharing and this scheme and whether you should be using multisig as opposed to Shamir secret sharing in your application and provide some guidance there.</description></item></channel></rss>