<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>privacy-problems on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/privacy-problems/</link><description>Recent content in privacy-problems on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/privacy-problems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Monero and the Privacy Doom Principle</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/monero-and-the-privacy-doom-principle/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/monero-and-the-privacy-doom-principle/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a blockchain researcher and developer. I&amp;rsquo;ve built the Sia blockchain ecosystem and I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the space for a while and today I&amp;rsquo;m talking about Monero and privacy models that ended up being explained in analytical techniques that we can use to beat error in privacy.
The Concept of Privacy in Cryptocurrencies So my name is David Vork. I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the blockchain space for about a decade. I&amp;rsquo;ve been between researching and launching blockchains, doing a lot of engineering, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the space for a while and studying things.</description></item><item><title>Privacy On Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/adopting-bitcoin/2021/2021-11-17-bastien-teinturier-privacy-on-lightning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/adopting-bitcoin/2021/2021-11-17-bastien-teinturier-privacy-on-lightning/</guid><description>Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1llk70vI2Mo5uQ7vnpfbl1qlr0qe0NLpySIelChIKhH4/edit
Introduction Buenos Dias San Salvador, I&amp;rsquo;m Bastien. Hopefully my slides are going to come up. Oh yay, perfect. So I&amp;rsquo;m working on the Lightning Protocol Specification and one of its main implementation at Acinq.
I&amp;rsquo;m here to talk to you about privacy. This is a big topic. It&amp;rsquo;s not a black and white thing. There are various degrees of gray when you talk about what your threat model is, who you want to protect against.</description></item><item><title>Sydney Socratic Seminar</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-02-23-socratic-seminar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-02-23-socratic-seminar/</guid><description>Topic: Agenda in Google Doc below
Video: No video posted online
Google Doc of the resources discussed: https://docs.google.com/document/d/1VAP4LNjHHVLy9RJwpQ8LqXEUw79z5TTZxr9du_Z0-9A/
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
PoDLEs revisited (Lloyd Fournier) https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/lightning-dev/2021-January/002929.html
We’ll start with me talking about my research into UTXO probing attacks on Lightning in the dual funding proposal.</description></item><item><title>ANYPREVOUT, MPP, Mitigating Lightning Attacks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-08-13-christian-decker-lightning-topics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-08-13-christian-decker-lightning-topics/</guid><description>Transcript completed by: Stephan Livera Edited by: Michael Folkson
Latest ANYPREVOUT update ANYPREVOUT BIP (BIP 118): https://github.com/ajtowns/bips/blob/bip-anyprevout/bip-0118.mediawiki
Stephan Livera (SL): Christian welcome back to the show.
Christian Decker (CD): Hey Stephan, thanks for having me.
SL: I wanted to chat with you about a bunch of stuff that you’ve been doing. We’ve got a couple of things that I was really interested to chat with you about: ANYPREVOUT, MPP, Lightning attacks, the latest with Lightning Network.</description></item><item><title>A Quantitative Analysis of Security, Anonymity and Scalability for the Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2020-05-09-sergei-tikhomirov-lightning-privacy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2020-05-09-sergei-tikhomirov-lightning-privacy/</guid><description>Location: Lightning Hacksprint (Fulmo)
Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1H9EdrhjQ9x3q0qfsei7iFYINVf2lwPyjUKHd3CScy4k/edit#slide=id.g7774542944_0_0
Paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/303
Intro Hello everyone. I am Sergei, I am a PhD student at the University of Luxembourg. I am going to present our joint work with Pedro Moreno-Sanchez and Matteo Maffei from TU Wien on certain aspects of the privacy and scalability of the Lightning Network. The full paper can be found here.
LN intro (for completeness) Let me give some context on what Lightning Network is.</description></item><item><title>Linking Anonymous Transactions via Remote Side-Channel Attacks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/linking-anonymous-transactions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/linking-anonymous-transactions/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230214874908655617
paper: https://crypto.stanford.edu/timings/paper.pdf
Introduction This is going to be talking about linking anonymous transactions in zcash and monero. Thanks for the introduction. I am going to be talking about remote side-channel attacks on anonymous transactions. This will be with respect to zcash and monero. Full disclosure, we disclosed all of the things I am talking about here today and everything has been fixed. No need to worry.
This is joint work with Dan Boneh and Kenny Paterson.</description></item><item><title>P2P Privacy Attacks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-10-09-giulia-fanti-p2p-privacy-attacks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-10-09-giulia-fanti-p2p-privacy-attacks/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs 2019 Residency
Slides: https://residency.chaincode.com/presentations/bitcoin/giulia_fanti_bitcoin_p2p.pdf
Giulia: So today I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk to you about some work that my collaborators and I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on for the last three years now. So this was joint work with a bunch of people who are now spread across a few different universities but it started at the University of Illinois: Shaileshh Bojja Venkatakrishnan, Surya Bakshi, Brad Denby, Shruti Bhargava, Andrew Miller, Pramod Viswanath.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Concepts for Bitcoin application developers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/privacy-concepts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/privacy-concepts/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171036497044267008
Introduction You&amp;rsquo;re not going to walk out of here as a privacy protocol developer. I am going to mention and talk about some ideas in some protocols that exist. What I find myself is that of really smart people working on a lot of pretty cool stuff that can make privacy easier and better to use. A lot of times, application developers or exchanges aren&amp;rsquo;t even aware of those things and as a result the end result is that people just sometimes use bitcoin in very non-private ways because they&amp;rsquo;re not aware of how to do privacy.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin network partitioning &amp; network-level privacy attacks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-12-ethan-heilman-network-partitioning-attacks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-12-ethan-heilman-network-partitioning-attacks/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs 2019 Residency
Slides: https://residency.chaincode.com/presentations/bitcoin/ethan_heilman_p2p.pdf
Eclipse attack paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2015/263.pdf
Bitcoin’s P2P Network Please interrupt me. I&amp;rsquo;m going to go through this stuff a little bit quickly because I hear that you&amp;rsquo;ve already read Eclipse attack paper and you&amp;rsquo;ve already looked at some of the peer to peer stuff.
Bitcoin uses a peer-to-peer network to announce transactions and blocks. It makes 8 outgoing connections. These are TCP connections initiated by the node.</description></item><item><title>How Much Privacy is Enough? Threats, Scaling, and Trade-offs in Blockchain Privacy Protocols</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/how-much-privacy-is-enough/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/how-much-privacy-is-enough/</guid><description>unrelated, https://arxiv.org/pdf/1706.00916.pdf
Introductions Hi everybody. This is a talk on how much privacy is enough, evaluating trade-offs in privacy and scalability. This is going to be unusual for this conference because I will not be presenting new technical content. I am going to be talking about evaluating the tradeoffs between these scalability and privacy. As context, my name is Ian Miers. I am a postdoc at Cornell Tech. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on privacy tech since 2011.</description></item><item><title>Fungibility Overview</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/fungibility-overview/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/fungibility-overview/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784676022318952448
Introduction Alright. So let&amp;rsquo;s get started. Okay. Why fungibility? Let&amp;rsquo;s start. What does fungibility mean? Bitcoin is like cash. The hope is that it&amp;rsquo;s for immediate and final payments. To add some nuiance there, you might have to wait for some confirmations. Once you receive a bitcoin, you have a bitcoin and that&amp;rsquo;s final. So even with banks and PayPal, who sometimes shutdown accounts for trivial reasons or sometimes no reason at all, it&amp;rsquo;s typically not the case that it&amp;rsquo;s someone who sent you money&amp;hellip; if you were selling something on ebay, and someone bought an item from you, and that person had an account shutdown, the money you received will not be removed from your account.</description></item><item><title>Fungibility and Privacy</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/bitcoin-adam3us-fungibility-privacy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/bitcoin-adam3us-fungibility-privacy/</guid><description>First of all I was going to explain what we mean by fungibility before bitcoin and ecash. It&amp;rsquo;s an old legal concept in fact, about paper currency. It&amp;rsquo;s the idea that a one ten dollar note is the same as any other ten dollar note. If you receive a note that was involved in a theft, 10 transactions ago, and the police investigate the theft, they have no right to remove the ten dollar note from your pocket.</description></item><item><title>Breaking Bitcoin Privacy</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/breaking-bitcoin-privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/breaking-bitcoin-privacy/</guid><description>0A8B 038F 5E10 CC27 89BF CFFF EF73 4EA6 77F3 1129
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137304437024862208
Introduction Hello everybody. I invented and created joinmarket, the first really popular coinjoin implementation. A couple months ago I wrote a big literature review on privacy. It has everything about anything in privacy in bitcoin, published on the bitcoin wiki. This talk is about privacy and what we can do to improve it.
Why privacy? Privacy is essential for fungibility, a necessary property of money where one unit is always equal to any other unit.</description></item><item><title>Breaking Wasabi (and Automated Wallets)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/breaking-wasabi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/breaking-wasabi/</guid><description>1127 96A8 DFCA 1A96 C8B8 0094 9211 687A D298 9B12
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137652130611978240
Trigger warnings Before I begin, some have told me that sometimes I tend to be toxic or provocative. So let&amp;rsquo;s start with some trigger warnings. This presentation might include bad jokes about bitcoin personalitites. It might have some multiplication. I might say &amp;ldquo;ethereum&amp;rdquo;. There&amp;rsquo;s also a coinjoin warning. If this is triggering to you, then it&amp;rsquo;s okay to leave. The bad jokes are really objectively bad.</description></item><item><title>Privacy and Scalability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/privacy-and-fungibility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/privacy-and-fungibility/</guid><description>Even though Bitcoin is the worst privacy system ever, everyone in the community very strongly values privacy.
There are at least three things: privacy censorship resistance fungibility
The easiest way to censor things is to punish communication, not prevent communication. Privacy is the weakest link in censorship resistance. Fungibility is an absolute necessity for any medium of exchange. The properties of money include fungibility. Without privacy you may not be able to have fungibility.</description></item></channel></rss>