<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rob Hamilton on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/rob-hamilton/</link><description>Recent content in Rob Hamilton on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/rob-hamilton/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>#MPCbros vs #TeamScript Debate</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/mpcbros-vs-teamscript-debate/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/mpcbros-vs-teamscript-debate/</guid><description>In this episode of the Bitcoin Review, NVK moderates a debate between Rijndael and Rob Hamilton, representing Team MPC and Team Script respectively. The discussion explores the merits and challenges of multi-party computation (MPC) and Bitcoin Script in enhancing Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s functionality and security. Rijndael explains MPC&amp;rsquo;s ability to create shared key pairs and more efficient multi-signature transactions using Schnorr signatures and Taproot, improving privacy and space efficiency. Rob counters with Script’s simplicity, auditability, and established history in Bitcoin, highlighting the transparency of on-chain scripts. The debate covers various technical aspects including signature aggregation, nonce management, and the potential for covenants and transaction introspection to enhance Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s programmability. Both sides acknowledge the importance of advancing Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s scripting capabilities while ensuring security and usability. The episode concludes with insights on the future of Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s technical development, emphasizing the need for innovative solutions to drive adoption and enhance user experience</description></item></channel></rss>