<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pedro Moreno-Sanchez on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/pedro-moreno-sanchez/</link><description>Recent content in Pedro Moreno-Sanchez on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/pedro-moreno-sanchez/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Anonymous Atomic Locks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/anonymous-atomic-locks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/anonymous-atomic-locks/</guid><description>A2L: Anonymous atomic locks for scalability and interoperability in payment-channel hubs
paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2019/589.pdf
https://github.com/etairi/A2L
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1172116189742546945
Introduction I am going ot talk about anonymous atomic locks for scalability and interoperability in payment-channel hubs. This is joint work with my colleagues.
Scalability I will try to keep this section as short as possible. This talk is also about scalability in bitcoin. You&amp;rsquo;re probably aware of the scalability issues. There is decentralized data structure recording each transaction in order to provide public verifiability.</description></item><item><title>Atomic Multi Channel Updates</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/atomic-multi-channel-updates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/atomic-multi-channel-updates/</guid><description>Atomic multi-channel updates with constant collateral in bitcoin-compatible payment-channel networks
paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2019/583
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1172102203995283456
Introduction Thank you for coming to my talk after lunch. This talk today is about atomic multi-channel updates with constant collateral in bitcoin-compatible payment-channel networks. It&amp;rsquo;s a long title, but I hope you will understand. This is collaborative work with my colleagues.
Scalability We&amp;rsquo;re at Scaling Bitcoin so you&amp;rsquo;re probably not suprised that I think bitcoin has scaling issues.</description></item><item><title>Concurrency And Privacy With Payment Channel Networks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/concurrency-and-privacy-with-payment-channel-networks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/concurrency-and-privacy-with-payment-channel-networks/</guid><description>paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2017/820.pdf
Introduction I am going to talk about concurrency and privacy. This was joint work with my collaborators.
Bitcoin has scalability issues. That&amp;rsquo;s the main reason why we are here today. Currently the bitcoin network allows for less than 10 transactions/second. Today we have more than 135 gigabytes of memory requirement. And there are some high fees and micropayments are not really possible. One of the proposals to fix this is payment channels.</description></item><item><title>Multi Hop Locks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-hop-locks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-hop-locks/</guid><description>Multi-hop locks for secure, privacy-preserving and interoperable payment-channel networks
Giulio Malavolta (Friedrich-Alexander-University Erlangen-Nuernberg), Pedro Moreno-Sanchez (Purdue University), Clara Schneidewind (Vienna University of Technology), Aniket Kate (Purdue University) and Matteo Maffei (Vienna University of Technology)
https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/472.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048476273259900928
This is joint work with my colleagues. I promise I will talk slower than the last talk. In a multi-hop network, the security tool is a hash-time lock contract (HTLC) where the payment is conditioned on revealing the pre-image of a hash function.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Preserving Multi Hop Locks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/privacy-preserving-multi-hop-locks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/privacy-preserving-multi-hop-locks/</guid><description>Privacy preserving multi-hop locks for blockchain scalability and interoperability
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1091026195032924160
paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/472.pdf
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-hop-locks/
Introduction This is joint work with my collaborators. Permissionless blockchains have some issues. The permissionless nature leads to the transaction rate that they have. This limits widespread adoption of blockchain technology like bitcoin or ethereum. Scalability approaches can be roughly grouped into two groups, one is on-chain layer 1 solutions. The other group is off-chain layer 2, which is the focus of this talk today.</description></item></channel></rss>