<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tim Ruffing on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/tim-ruffing/</link><description>Recent content in Tim Ruffing on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/tim-ruffing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Libsec Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/libsec-panel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/libsec-panel/</guid><description>Intros NVK: I have an absolute rock star team here. So why don&amp;rsquo;t I start introducing the panel? Tim, hello! Do you want to tell a very brief what do you do?
Tim: Yes, so my name is Tim Ruffing. I am a maintainer of the libsecp256k1 library. I do work for Blockstream, who pay me to do this and also who pay me to do research on cryptography and all kinds of aspects related to Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>v2 P2P Transport Protocol for Bitcoin (BIP324)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2022-11-13-dhruv-pieter-wuille-and-tim-ruffing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2022-11-13-dhruv-pieter-wuille-and-tim-ruffing/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/433/
Stephan Livera – 00:03:20:
Gentlemen, welcome to the show.
Dhruv – 00:03:22:
Hello.
Tim Ruffing – 00:03:23:
Hi.
Stephan Livera – 00:03:24:
Yeah, so thanks, guys, for joining me and interested to chat about what you’re working on and especially what’s going on with P2P transport, a v2 P2P transport protocol for bitcoin core.
Dhruv – 00:03:36:
Bitcoin?
Stephan Livera – 00:03:37:
Yeah, for a course for bitcoin. So I think, Pieter and Tim, I think listeners probably know you, Dhruv, if you want to just give a quick intro for yourself, just for listeners to know who you are.</description></item><item><title>ROAST - Robust asynchronous Schnorr threshold signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-14-roast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-14-roast/</guid><description>paper: https://ia.cr/2022/550
slides: https://slides.com/real-or-random/roast-tabconf22/
Hey. Hello. My name is Tim and I work at Blockstream. This is some academic work in joint with some of my coworkers.
Schnorr signatures in Bitcoin We recently got support for Schnorr signatures in bitcoin, introduced as part of bip340 which was activated as part of the taproot soft-fork. There are three main reasons why we want Schnorr signatures and prefer them over ECDSA bitcoin signatures which can still be used: one is that Schnorr signatures have provable security and give the theory guys more confidence; Schnorr signatures are more efficient; and the main thing is that we can get easier constructions of advanced signing protocols.</description></item><item><title>MuSig2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2022-08-11-tim-ruffing-musig2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2022-08-11-tim-ruffing-musig2/</guid><description>Topic: MuSig2
Location: London Bitcoin Devs
Date: August 11th 2022
Reading list: https://gist.github.com/michaelfolkson/5bfffa71a93426b57d518b09ebd0998c
Introduction Michael Folkson (MF): This is a Socratic Seminar, we are going to be discussing MuSig2 and we’ll move onto adjacent topics such as FROST and libsecp256k1 later. We have a few people on the call including Tim (Ruffing). If you want to do short intros, you don’t have to, for the people on the call.
Tim Ruffing (TR): Hi.</description></item><item><title>Half Signature Aggregation-What is it and how does it help scale Bitcoin?</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2022-08-02-jonas-nick-tim-ruffing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2022-08-02-jonas-nick-tim-ruffing/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/400/
Stephan Livera: Jonas and Tim, welcome back to the show. Great to chat with you guys again. And so we’re gonna chat about half signature aggregation and hear a little bit from you guys about what you’re working on and just get into what that means for Bitcoin. So Jonas, I know you probably will be best to give some background on some of this — I know you did a talk at Adopting Bitcoin in November of last year, so call it 7–8 months ago, talking about some of this at a high level.</description></item><item><title>ROAST</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2022-07-14-tim-ruffing-roast/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2022-07-14-tim-ruffing-roast/</guid><description>Topic: ROAST
Location: Monash Cybersecurity Seminars
ROAST paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2022/550.pdf
ROAST blog post: https://medium.com/blockstream/roast-robust-asynchronous-schnorr-threshold-signatures-ddda55a07d1b
ROAST in Python: https://github.com/robot-dreams/roast
Introduction (Amin Sakzad) Welcome everyone to Monash Cybersecurity Seminars. Today we will be having Tim Ruffing. Tim is an applied cryptographer in the research team of Blockstream, a Bitcoin and blockchain technology company. He obtained his PhD from Saarland University researching cryptographic aspects of cryptocurrencies. His current research focus on advanced applications of Schnorr signatures, for example multi and threshold signatures.</description></item><item><title>MuSig2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/realworldcrypto/2021/2021-01-12-tim-ruffing-musig2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/realworldcrypto/2021/2021-01-12-tim-ruffing-musig2/</guid><description>Topic: MuSig2: Simple Two-Round Schnorr Multi-Signatures
Location: Real World Crypto
MuSig2 paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/1261.pdf
Introduction This is about MuSig2, simple two round Schnorr multisignatures. This is joint work with Jonas Nick and Yannick Seurin. Jonas will be available to answer questions as I will be of course.
Multi-Signatures The idea that with multisignatures is that n signers can get together and produce a single signature on a single message. To be clear for this talk when I talk about multisignatures what I mean is n-of-n signatures and not the more general setting of threshold signatures where you can have a threshold t that is smaller than n and have something like a t-of-n signatures.</description></item><item><title>MuSig, MuSig-DN and MuSig2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-10-27-jonas-nick-tim-ruffing-musig2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-10-27-jonas-nick-tim-ruffing-musig2/</guid><description>Topic: MuSig, MuSig-DN and MuSig2
Location: Stephan Livera Podcast
Tim Ruffing on Schnorr multisig at London Bitcoin Devs: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-17-tim-ruffing-schnorr-multisig/
MuSig paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/068.pdf
MuSig blog post: https://blockstream.com/2019/02/18/en-musig-a-new-multisignature-standard/
Insecure shortcuts in MuSig: https://medium.com/blockstream/insecure-shortcuts-in-musig-2ad0d38a97da
MuSig-DN paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/1057.pdf
MuSig-DN blog post: https://medium.com/blockstream/musig-dn-schnorr-multisignatures-with-verifiably-deterministic-nonces-27424b5df9d6
MuSig2 paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/1261.pdf
MuSig2 blog post: https://medium.com/blockstream/musig2-simple-two-round-schnorr-multisignatures-bf9582e99295
Transcript completed by: Stephan Livera Edited by: Michael Folkson
Intro Stephan Livera (SL): Jonas and Tim, welcome to the show.
Jonas Nick (JN): Hello.
Tim Ruffing (TR): Hey.</description></item><item><title>Schnorr and Multisig</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-17-tim-ruffing-schnorr-multisig/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-17-tim-ruffing-schnorr-multisig/</guid><description>Taproot and Schnorr Multisignatures
Location: London Bitcoin Devs (online)
Slides: https://slides.com/real-or-random/taproot-and-schnorr-multisig
Transcript of the previous day’s Socratic Seminar on BIP-Schnorr: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-16-socratic-seminar-bip-schnorr/
Intro (Michael Folkson) We are now live. This is London Bitcoin Devs with Tim Ruffing. We had the Socratic Seminar yesterday, I think we have some people on the call that were at the Socratic Seminar. That was brilliant. Thanks to Tim, Pieter, Greg, waxwing and everyone for showing up and taking 2 and a half hours out of their day.</description></item><item><title>Threshold Schnorr Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/threshold-schnorr-signatures/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/threshold-schnorr-signatures/</guid><description>Topic: The Quest for Practical Threshold Schnorr Signatures
Location: Cryptoeconomic Systems Summit 2019
Slides: https://slides.com/real-or-random/schnorr-threshold-sigs-ces-summit-2019
Transcript completed by: Bryan Bishop Edited by: Michael Folkson
Introduction It&amp;rsquo;s great to be here. My name is Tim Ruffing and I work for the research team at Blockstream. This is a talk about practical threshold Schnorr signatures and our quest for constructing them.
Disclaimer First of all, this is work in progress. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty early work in progress, mostly based on discussions with people at Blockstream.</description></item><item><title>Valueshuffle Mixing Confidential Transactions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/valueshuffle-mixing-confidential-transactions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/valueshuffle-mixing-confidential-transactions/</guid><description>paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2017/238.pdf
Thank you.
We have seen two talks now about putting privacy in layer two. But let&amp;rsquo;s talk about layer one. We still don&amp;rsquo;t have great privacy there. So the title of this talk is valueshuffle - mixing confidential transactions. I don&amp;rsquo;t have to convince you that bitcoin at the moment is not really private. There are a lot of possibilities to link&amp;hellip; to deal them as, to link addresses together.</description></item></channel></rss>