<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Andrew Poelstra on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/andrew-poelstra/</link><description>Recent content in Andrew Poelstra on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/andrew-poelstra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bitcoin R&amp;D Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2022/bitcoin-randd-panel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2022/bitcoin-randd-panel/</guid><description>Ayush: 00:00:07
My name is Ayush Khandelwal. I am a software engineer at Google. I run a tech crypto-focused podcast on the side. And I have some amazing guests with me. So if you want to introduce yourself, what do you work on? And yeah, just get us started.
Jeremy: 00:00:31
I am Jeremy Rubin. I am a class of 2016 MIT alumni, so it&amp;rsquo;s good to be back on campus.</description></item><item><title>Long-Term Trust and Analog Computers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2022/long-term-trust-and-analog-computers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2022/long-term-trust-and-analog-computers/</guid><description>What I am here to talk to you about are analog computers and long-term trust. And what I mean by long-term trust is how can you have assurance that your Bitcoin secrets, your seed words or your seed phrase or whatever have you, how can you be assured that that is stored correctly, that the data has integrity and so on, and how can you be assured of that for a long time?</description></item><item><title>SLP321 On-chain scaling with Bitcoin Core Developers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2021-11-16-pieter-wuille-andrew-poelstra-andrew-chow-mark-erhardt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2021-11-16-pieter-wuille-andrew-poelstra-andrew-chow-mark-erhardt/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/321/
Emcee:
All right. I’m really excited for this next panel. I’ve heard some of them speak in different rooms and I can’t wait to hear what they all have to say today. Next up, I’m going to bring up our moderator. He has a podcast. It is a self-titled podcast and he’s also the managing director of Swan Bitcoin International. Please everybody, welcome to the stage Stephan Livera, everyone.</description></item><item><title>Miniscript</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/2021-11-06-andrew-poelstra-miniscript/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/2021-11-06-andrew-poelstra-miniscript/</guid><description>Topic: Miniscript - Custody, Computable, Composable
Location: TABConf (The Atlanta Bitcoin Conference)
Slides: https://download.wpsoftware.net/bitcoin/wizardry/2021-11-tabconf/slides.pdf
Intro I am here to talk about Miniscript. This is something that I have talked about a few times before but usually in a much more technical way where we get into the weeds of Bitcoin Script and what Miniscript is and how to use it and stuff. I want to talk today about Miniscript from the perspective of someone actually trying to use Bitcoin and how this solves problems that I think are very important in the space regarding how to custody your coins, how to keep track of your keys, stuff like that.</description></item><item><title>Covenants</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/2021-11-05-jeremy-rubin-andrew-poelstra-covenants/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/2021-11-05-jeremy-rubin-andrew-poelstra-covenants/</guid><description>Topic: Covenants
Location: TABConf (The Atlanta Bitcoin Conference)
Video: No video was posted online
As per Socratic village rules names of all attendees (other than the advertised speakers) have been anonymized and audio will not be published to preserve anonymity of the question askers.
The covenant concept Shaun Apps (SA): I’ll kick things off with a bit of an introduction. Both Andrew and Jeremy will present. And then we will go through some questions and we&amp;rsquo;ll go to questions from the audience after that.</description></item><item><title>Taproot</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2020/2020-03-07-andrew-poelstra-taproot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2020/2020-03-07-andrew-poelstra-taproot/</guid><description>Topic: Taproot - Who, How, Why
Location: MIT Bitcoin Expo 2020
BIP 341: https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/master/bip-0341.mediawiki
Intro (Hugo Uvegi) I am excited to introduce our first speaker, Andrew Poelstra. He is coming to us from Blockstream where he is Director of Research. He is going to be talking about Taproot which I think is on everybody’s mind these days.
Intro (Andrew Poelstra) Thanks for waking up so early for the first day of the conference and making the trek from the registration room over here.</description></item><item><title>Miniscript</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-07-andrew-poelstra-miniscript/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-07-andrew-poelstra-miniscript/</guid><description>Advancing Bitcoin workshop
Miniscript
Website: https://bitcoin.sipa.be/miniscript/
Workshop repo: https://github.com/apoelstra/miniscript-workshop
Transcript of London Bitcoin Devs Miniscript presentation: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-02-04-andrew-poelstra-miniscript/
Part 1 So what we’re going to do, there is a couple of things. We are going to go through the Miniscript website and learn about how Miniscript is constructed, how the type system works, some of the anti-malleability rules. Then we’re going to go to a repo that I created last night, a Git repo with some example programs.</description></item><item><title>Miniscript Intro</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-06-andrew-poelstra-miniscript-intro/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-06-andrew-poelstra-miniscript-intro/</guid><description>Topic: Introduction to Miniscript
Location: Advancing Bitcoin
Slides: https://www.dropbox.com/s/vgh5vaooqqbgg1v/andrew-poelstra.pdf
Intro Hi everyone. Some of you were at my Bitcoin dev presentation about Miniscript a couple of days where I managed to spend over 2 hours giving a presentation about this. I think I got this one down to 20 minutes but no promises. I will keep an eye on the clock.
Descriptors It is very nice having this scheduled immediately after Andrew Chow’s talk about output descriptors because there is a good transition here.</description></item><item><title>Miniscript</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-02-04-andrew-poelstra-miniscript/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-02-04-andrew-poelstra-miniscript/</guid><description>Bitcoin Script to Miniscript
London Bitcoin Devs
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1237071807699718146
Slides: https://www.dropbox.com/s/au6u6rczljdc86y/Andrew%20Poelstra%20-%20Miniscript.pdf?dl=0
Introduction As Michael mentioned I’ve got like two hours. Hopefully I won’t get close to that but you guys are welcome to interrupt and ask questions. I’ve given a couple of talks about Miniscript usually in like 20 or 30 minute time slots where I try to give a high level overview of what this project is, why should you use it and why it makes Bitcoin script accessible in ways that it hasn’t been.</description></item><item><title>Blockchain Design Patterns: Layers and scaling approaches</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/blockchain-design-patterns/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/blockchain-design-patterns/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171400374336536576
Introduction Alright. Are we ready to get going? Thumbs up? Alright. Cool. I am Andrew and this is David. We&amp;rsquo;re here to talk about blockchain design patterns: layers and scaling approaches. This will be a tour of a bunch of different scaling approaches in bitcoin in particular but it&amp;rsquo;s probably applicable to other blockchains out there. Our talk is in 3 parts. We&amp;rsquo;ll talk about some existing scaling tech and related things like caching transactions and mempool propagation.</description></item><item><title>Tales from the Crypt with Andrew Poelstra</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tftc-podcast/2019-06-18-andrew-poelstra-tftc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tftc-podcast/2019-06-18-andrew-poelstra-tftc/</guid><description>TFTC podcast with Andrew Poelstra - June 18th 2019 (Abridged)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1160178010986876928
Podcast: https://talesfromthecrypt.libsyn.com/tales-from-the-crypt-80-andrew-poelstra
How the idea of Taproot was formed Andrew: There are some small off suit IRC channels of bitcoin-wizards where people discuss some specific topics such as Minisketch which is a set reconciliation protocol that was developed by Greg Maxwell, Pieter Wuille and Gleb Naumenko among a couple of others. It was mostly those three. They have a channel where they talk about things.</description></item><item><title>Crypto In Cryptocurrency</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/crypto-in-cryptocurrency/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/crypto-in-cryptocurrency/</guid><description>The &amp;ldquo;crypto&amp;rdquo; in cryptocurrency: Why everything is weird and hard
I do not have any slides for you. This is my attempt to keep this non-technical, by depriving myself of any ability to write equations on screen. The topic of my talk is why everything is weird and hard in cryptocurrency. What is cryptography as a mathematics and field of science? And how does this work in practice?
Encryption Historically the purvue of cryptography is encryption, like trying to come up with something random looking.</description></item><item><title>Miniscript</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/noded-podcast/2019-05-11-andrew-poelstra-miniscript/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/noded-podcast/2019-05-11-andrew-poelstra-miniscript/</guid><description>Noded podcast May 10th 2019
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1135217746059415552
Intros Pierre: Welcome to the Noded Bitcoin podcast. I’m your co-host Pierre Rochard with my other co-host Michael Goldstein aka bitstein. How’s it going Michael?
bitstein: It’s going well, I just hope they don’t ban Bitcoin
Pierre: Any day now. We have a very special guest on today, Andrew Poelstra from Blockstream. Andrew, how are you?
Andrew: I’m good. How are you?
Pierre: Great. Did you hear today’s news about the representative in Congress who wanted to ban cryptocurrencies?</description></item><item><title>Secure Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2019/signature-scheme-security-properties/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2019/signature-scheme-security-properties/</guid><description>Topic: Secure Signatures - Harder Than You Think
Location: MIT Bitcoin Expo 2019
Twitter announcement: https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1104399812147916800
Transcript completed by: Bryan Bishop Edited by: Michael Folkson
Introduction Hi everyone. Can you hear me alright? Is my mic? Okay, cool. I was scheduled to talk about the history of Schnorr signatures in Bitcoin. I wanted to do that but then I realized I’ve only got 20-30 minutes to talk here. Instead I am going to focus on one particular piece of that history, which is the security model surrounding not just Schnorr signatures but extensions to Schnorr signatures we really care about.</description></item><item><title>Threshold Signatures And Accountability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2019-02-04-threshold-signatures-and-accountability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2019-02-04-threshold-signatures-and-accountability/</guid><description>Topic: Threshold Signatures and Accountability
Location: SF Bitcoin Devs
Slides: https://download.wpsoftware.net/bitcoin/wizardry/2019-02-sfdevs-threshold/slides.pdf
Transcript completed by: Bryan Bishop Edited by: Michael Folkson
Twitter announcement: https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1092665108960968704
Introduction (Mark Erhardt) Sorry for the delays. We&amp;rsquo;re finally ready to talk. Welcome to our talk. We&amp;rsquo;d like to thank our sponsors including Blockstream and Digital Garage. Today we have Andrew Poelstra to talk about threshold signatures and accountability. He is known for working on Mimblewimble, Bitcoin Core, libsecp256k1, and at Blockstream.</description></item><item><title>Scriptless Scripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/layer2-summit/2018/scriptless-scripts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/layer2-summit/2018/scriptless-scripts/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1017881177355640833
Introduction I am here to talk about scriptless scripts today. Scriptless scripts are related to mimblewimble, which is the other thing I was going to talk about. For time constraints, I will only talk about scriptles scripts. I&amp;rsquo;ll give a brief historical background, and then I will say what scriptless scripts are, what we can do with them, and give some examples.
History In 2016, there was a mysterious paper dead-dropped on an IRC channel that I frequent called #bitcoin-wizards.</description></item><item><title>Bulletproofs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2018-02-02-andrew-poelstra-bulletproofs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2018-02-02-andrew-poelstra-bulletproofs/</guid><description>49th Milan Bitcoin meetup
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/962326126969442304
https://www.reddit.com/r/Bitcoin/comments/7w72pq/bulletproofs_presentation_at_feb_2_milan_meetup/
Introduction Alright. Thank you for that introduction, Giacamo. I am here to talk about bulletproofs. This is different from proof-of-bullets, which is what fiat currencies use. In bulletproofs, we use a zero-knowledge proof which has nothing to do with consensus at all, but it has a lot of exciting applications. The original motivation to create bulletproofs was for range proofs which are used in confidential transactions.</description></item><item><title>Mimblewimble And Scriptless Scripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/realworldcrypto/2018/mimblewimble-and-scriptless-scripts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/realworldcrypto/2018/mimblewimble-and-scriptless-scripts/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/954531580848082944
We&amp;rsquo;re about ready for the second session of RWC. We are going to move on to cryptocurrencies. So we have 3 talks lined up in this session. The first one is on mimblewimble and scriptless scripts, delivered by Andrew Poelstra from Blockstream.
Introduction Thank you. Cool. Hello. My name is Andrew Poelstra. I am the research director at Blockstream and I&amp;rsquo;m here to talk about a couple of things that I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about over the past year, called mimblewimble, and also scriptless scripts.</description></item><item><title>Mimblewimble And Scriptless Scripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/mimblewimble-and-scriptless-scripts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/mimblewimble-and-scriptless-scripts/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/838480912396533760
Up next we have Andrew Poelstra and he is going to be talking about a really interesting new concept for a cryptocurrency. It&amp;rsquo;s called mimblewimble, after a spell from Harry Potter, because it prevents characters from speaking. Try speaking? Hello, test. We also have a&amp;hellip; hello? hello? Can you guys hear me?
I am going to talk about the concept of scriptless scripts. It&amp;rsquo;s a way of describing what mimblewimble does, in a way that shows the conceptual details, and maybe give the ability to take the lessons we learned from mimblewimble and apply to other projects.</description></item><item><title>Mimblewimble</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-11-21-mimblewimble/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-11-21-mimblewimble/</guid><description>Mimblewimble
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aHTRlbCaUyM
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/801990263543648256
History As Denise said, I gave a talk in Milan about mimblewimble about a month ago (slides). This is more or less the same talk, but rebalanced a bit to try to emphasize what I think is important and add some history that has happened in the intervening time. I&amp;rsquo;ll get started.
Many of you have heard of mimblewimble. It&amp;rsquo;s been in the news. It has a catchy name.</description></item><item><title>Future Of Privacy Coins</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/future-of-privacy-coins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/future-of-privacy-coins/</guid><description>Future of privacy coins
AM: That&amp;rsquo;s not good. Hi everyone. Thanks for coming to the future of privacy coins panel. I want to spend a minute talking ablout backgrounds and interest in this area.
BG: I have a PhD in something. I got into monero a couple of years ago. I needed to pay rent, so I did some work in math in exchange for money.
AP: I work on confidential transactions and scriptless scripts and I do not have a PhD.</description></item><item><title>Improvements to Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/maaku-panel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/maaku-panel/</guid><description>This can be a broad range of topics for improvements. I am Mark Friedenbach, I have worked on Bitcoin protocol research, but I also do Core tech engineering at Blockstream. We also have Jonas, an independent Bitcoin Core developer. We also have Andrew Poelstra, who has been core to the crypto work which has been incoporated into Bitcoin, such as libsecp256k1 which we recently integrated in the 0.12 release. It speeds up Bitcoin validation by 7-8x.</description></item><item><title>Mimblewimble</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/mimblewimble/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/mimblewimble/</guid><description>Mimblewimble: private, massively-prunable public blockchains
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784696648597405696
slides: http://diyhpl.us/~bryan/papers2/bitcoin/mimblewimble-2016-scaling-bitcoin-slides.pdf
Hi, I am from Blockstream. I am here to talk about Mimblewimble. Mimblewimble is not mine. It&amp;rsquo;s from the dark lord. I am going to start with the history of the paper. It has been in the news a little bit. I will talk about the transaction structure, the block structure, try to explain the trust model and argue that it&amp;rsquo;s almost as strong as bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Mimblewimble Podcast</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/mimblewimble-podcast/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/mimblewimble-podcast/</guid><description>https://soundcloud.com/heryptohow/mimblewimble-andrew-poelstra-peter-wuille-brian-deery-and-chris-odom
Andrew Poelstra (andytoshi) Pieter Wuille (sipa) Brian Deery Chris Odom Starts at 26min.
I am going to introduce our guests here in just a minute.
Launch of zcash might be delayed in order to allow the code to be analyzed by multiple third-party auditors. Zooko stated, &amp;ldquo;I feel bad that we didn&amp;rsquo;t do a better job of making TheDAO disaster-like problems harder for people&amp;rdquo;.
Our guests on the line are Andrew Poelstra and Pieter Wuille.</description></item><item><title>Scriptless Scripts With Mimblewimble</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/scriptless-scripts-with-mimblewimble/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/scriptless-scripts-with-mimblewimble/</guid><description>Scriptless scripts with mimblewimble
Andrew Poelstra (andytoshi)
Introduction Hi everyone. I am Andrew Poelstra. I am the research director at Blockstream. I want to talk about deploying scriptless scripts, wihch is something I haven&amp;rsquo;t talked much about over the past year or two.
History Let me give a bit of history about mimblewimble. As many of you know, this was dead-dropped anonymously in the middle of 2016 by someone named Tom Elvis Jedusor which is the French name for Voldemort.</description></item><item><title>Security Assumptions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/security-assumptions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/security-assumptions/</guid><description>Hi, welcome back.
I am a developer for libsecp256k1. It&amp;rsquo;s a library that does the underlying traditional cryptography used in Bitcoin. I am going to talk about security assumptions, security models and trust models. I am going to give a high-level overview of how we should be thinking about these issues for scaling and efficiency and decentralization. Bitcoin is a crypto system. Everything about it is a crypto system. It needs to be designed with an adversarial mindset, even in an adversarial setting.</description></item><item><title>Snarks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/snarks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/snarks/</guid><description>some setup motivating topics:
practicality pcp theorem trustless setup magic away the trusted setup schemes without trusted setup pcp theorem is the existent proof that the spherical cow exists. people:
Andrew Miller (AM) Madars Virza (MV) Andrew Poelstra (AP) Bryan Bishop (BB) Nathan Wilcox ZZZZZ: zooko gmaxwell&amp;rsquo;s ghost (only in spirit) SNARKs always require some sort of setup. PCP-based SNARKs can use random oracle assumption instantiated by hash function, sha256 acts as the random oracle.</description></item><item><title>Using The Chain For What Chains Are Good For</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/using-the-chain-for-what-chains-are-good-for/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/using-the-chain-for-what-chains-are-good-for/</guid><description>I am Andrew Poelstra, a cryptographer at Blockstream. I am going to talk about scriptless scripts. But this is a specific example of a more general theme, which is using the blockchain as a trust anchor or commitment layer for smart contracts whose real contents don&amp;rsquo;t really hit the blockchain. I&amp;rsquo;ll elaborate on what I mean by that, and I&amp;rsquo;ll show what the benefits are for that.
To give some context, in Bitcoin script, the scripting language which is used to encode smart contracts, which go on to the blockchain and everyone verifies the chain and downloads and executes all of this contract code.</description></item></channel></rss>