<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>TABConf 2021 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/</link><description>Recent content in TABConf 2021 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Schnorr Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/schnorr-signatures-jimmy-song/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/schnorr-signatures-jimmy-song/</guid><description>Introduction Anyway, like I said, this is a technical talk and we&amp;rsquo;re going to talk about Schnorr signatures and the benefits that it brings. So let&amp;rsquo;s get started.
Agenda So here&amp;rsquo;s the agenda. We&amp;rsquo;re going to talk about, we&amp;rsquo;re going to review the signature algorithm that&amp;rsquo;s currently on Bitcoin. This is Elliptic Curve Digital Signature Algorithm or ECDSA. Then we&amp;rsquo;re going to go describe what Schnorr signatures are. And then we&amp;rsquo;re going to go over all of the key and signature aggregation stuff that you can do or some of the benefits that you get out of Schnorr.</description></item><item><title>Liquidity Advertisements - niftynei - TABConf 2021</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/liquidity-advertisements-niftynei-tabconf-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/liquidity-advertisements-niftynei-tabconf-2021/</guid><description>Introduction Again, my name is Lisa Neigut. I work at Blockstream. I&amp;rsquo;m here today to talk to you about the spec proposal that we&amp;rsquo;ve added to c-lightning and hoping to get into more Lightning implementation soon to make it standard. This is about liquidity advertisements. So today I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking to you about what a liquidity ad is, how they work, kind of explain how data gets passed around Lightning Network just in general, and maybe get some of you excited about using them.</description></item><item><title>Miniscript</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/2021-11-06-andrew-poelstra-miniscript/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/2021-11-06-andrew-poelstra-miniscript/</guid><description>Topic: Miniscript - Custody, Computable, Composable
Location: TABConf (The Atlanta Bitcoin Conference)
Slides: https://download.wpsoftware.net/bitcoin/wizardry/2021-11-tabconf/slides.pdf
Intro I am here to talk about Miniscript. This is something that I have talked about a few times before but usually in a much more technical way where we get into the weeds of Bitcoin Script and what Miniscript is and how to use it and stuff. I want to talk today about Miniscript from the perspective of someone actually trying to use Bitcoin and how this solves problems that I think are very important in the space regarding how to custody your coins, how to keep track of your keys, stuff like that.</description></item><item><title>Coin Selection Algorithms</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/coin-selection-algorithms/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/coin-selection-algorithms/</guid><description>Introduction Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Andrew Chow. I&amp;rsquo;m an engineer at Blockstream and I work on Bitcoin Core in the wallet and on various things in the wallet. So, today I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking about coin selection and generally how you can pick your inputs better for when you&amp;rsquo;re making a transaction. To start off, what happens when you make a transaction? Well, first, you type in, you copy and paste in your address, you type in the amount that you want to send and you click the send button and your wallet does some stuff in the background and out comes a transaction, right?</description></item><item><title>Covenants</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/2021-11-05-jeremy-rubin-andrew-poelstra-covenants/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/2021-11-05-jeremy-rubin-andrew-poelstra-covenants/</guid><description>Topic: Covenants
Location: TABConf (The Atlanta Bitcoin Conference)
Video: No video was posted online
As per Socratic village rules names of all attendees (other than the advertised speakers) have been anonymized and audio will not be published to preserve anonymity of the question askers.
The covenant concept Shaun Apps (SA): I’ll kick things off with a bit of an introduction. Both Andrew and Jeremy will present. And then we will go through some questions and we&amp;rsquo;ll go to questions from the audience after that.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Dev Kit - Making Lightning More Accessible to Developers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/lightning-dev-kit-making-lightning-more-accessible-to-developers-matt-corallo-tabconf-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/lightning-dev-kit-making-lightning-more-accessible-to-developers-matt-corallo-tabconf-2021/</guid><description>Introduction So, I worked on Bitcoin Core for many many years, but I am not here to talk about that! I now spend my time, full time at Square Crypto working on a project we call the Lightning Dev Kit (LDK). So, working to enable Lightning to be more accessible to developers and I&amp;rsquo;m here to talk about that and give the lay of the land for why it exists, what the state of the Lightning ecosystem is broadly, and why we think it&amp;rsquo;s an important project and why Square is funding us, to work on it.</description></item><item><title>Scaling with LND</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/scaling-with-lnd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/scaling-with-lnd/</guid><description>Intro I wanted to talk about scaling lightning using LND. I started working at Lightning Labs three years ago and come really a long way. I started working with LND before that when I worked at BitGo. That was the barest, almost didn&amp;rsquo;t work, it was crashing everyday type of scenario. Now, three years later, we&amp;rsquo;re trying to scale this to millions of people. We&amp;rsquo;re trying to scale this to millions of payments.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Mining Firmware and Stratum v2 - Rachel Rybarczyk - TABConf 2021</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/bitcoin-mining-firmware-and-stratum-v2-rachel-rybarczyk-tabconf-2021/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/bitcoin-mining-firmware-and-stratum-v2-rachel-rybarczyk-tabconf-2021/</guid><description>Introduction Coming to the stage next, she is the VP of Mining at Galaxy Digital. Everybody please welcome to the stage Rachel Rybarczyk, everyone. My name is Rachel, I&amp;rsquo;m VP of Mining at Galaxy Digital. I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the space for a few years now and I recently started developing on Stratum V2, which is a new mining protocol. So I want to talk today about Stratum V2, how it compares to Stratum V1, the adoption efforts, some adoption hurdles, and how it all fits in together.</description></item></channel></rss>