<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mit Bitcoin Expo 2015 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/</link><description>Recent content in Mit Bitcoin Expo 2015 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Andrew Miller</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/andrew-miller/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/andrew-miller/</guid><description>Step by Step Towards Writing a Safe Contract: Insights from an Undergraduate Ethereum Lab
Andrew Miller Elaine Shi Next up I want to introduce Elaine Shi and Andrew Miller from University of Maryland. Andrew is also on the zerocash team.
Okay. I am an assistant professor at the University of Maryland. We all believe that cryptocurrency is the way of the future and smart contracts. So students in the future have to program smart contracts.</description></item><item><title>Armory Proof Of Payment</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/armory-proof-of-payment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/armory-proof-of-payment/</guid><description>Armory proof of payment
Andy Ofiesh
I am going to talk about proof of payment. This is simple. You can do this. That you couldn&amp;rsquo;t do before 2008. We&amp;rsquo;ll see if this works. I hear it might work. That&amp;rsquo;s okay, I&amp;rsquo;ll pull this up here. I have ruined everything. Just jam that in there. Here we go.
So uh, I said who I am. Bitcoin Armory. I am here to talk about proof of payment.</description></item><item><title>Arvind Narayanan</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/arvind-narayanan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/arvind-narayanan/</guid><description>Arvind Narayanan
Threshold signatures
I want to tell you what threshold signatures are and I want to convince you that threshold signatures are a technology you need. This is collaborative work.
There are three things I want to tell you today. The first is that the banking security model has been very very refined and has sophisticated techniques and process and controls for ensuring security. It does not translate to Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Financing And Trading</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/bitcoin-financing-and-trading/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/bitcoin-financing-and-trading/</guid><description>Joshua Lim (Circle, ex Goldman Sachs) Juthica Chou (LedgerX) (Goldman Sachs) Bobby Cho (ItBit) (VP of trading at SecondMarket) Harry Yeh (moderator) (Binary Financial) Today we will hear from some people who are traders and also infrastructure providers. Good morning everybody. It took me 18 hours to get here. The Uber dropped me off at the wrong building. They need better signs.
So usually I am the one that sits on the panel.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Regulation Landscape</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/bitcoin-regulation-landscape/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/bitcoin-regulation-landscape/</guid><description>Elizabeth Stark Jerry Brito Constance Choi Christian Catalini (moderator) MIT Compton Labs - Building 26, room 100
http://mitbitcoinexpo.org/
Okay guys, we are getting close to the time for the next panel. Head back to your seats. You may bring food in with you. We also started 15 minutes late. People have 15 minutes .. we ended lunch on time. One of our speakers literally only came for 30 minutes today, 2 to 230.</description></item><item><title>Decentralization Through Game Theory</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/decentralization-through-game-theory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/decentralization-through-game-theory/</guid><description>Andreas Antonopoulos
Thank you Charlie, let&amp;rsquo;s have another round of applause. Up next, we have Andreas Antonopoulos.
So I may make this a bit difficult for the camera because I hate standing behind the podium. Welcome everyone. How are you, thank you for coming. How many people in this audience own Bitcoin?
So I usually start my question with that. And most audiences that gives me an accurate representation. You gave Bitcoin to every undergraduate, so you ruined my polling ability.</description></item><item><title>Eric Martindale</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/eric-martindale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/eric-martindale/</guid><description>Open source: Beyond Bitcoin Core
Eric Martindale
He is at Bitpay, working on copay, bitcore, foxtrot, and their blockchain explorer.
First of all, a little bit about Bitpay. We were actually founded in May 2011. We have been around for some time. At the time, MtGox was actually still a viable exchange. The Bitcoin price was down at about $1 or a little more. And we had a grand total of two merchants.</description></item><item><title>Human Side Trust Workshop</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/human-side-trust-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/human-side-trust-workshop/</guid><description>Human side of trust
Matt Weiss Joe Gerber We would like to start with a brief activity. In you rprograms, this says design workshop. If that scares you, then we will not be doing trust falls. We will not be forming teams. But we would like to start with an activity. Identify someone around you who you do not know. Keep a mental image of that person in your mind.</description></item><item><title>Internet Of Value</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/internet-of-value/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/internet-of-value/</guid><description>Jeremy Allaire
What are the lessons from the development of the internet that we can learn from? Why is there an inevitability as to what Bitcoin is doing?
At a high level, I like to explain that we are experiencing a fundamental transformation in how the world economy stores and verifies value. Bitcoin and these other projects that are being built are part of that arc. We have talked not just about payments.</description></item><item><title>Keynote</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/keynote/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/keynote/</guid><description>Charlie Lee
It has been a while since I have been back to MIT. So. So um. Yeah, it&amp;rsquo;s. I got extremely excited that the expo is at 26100. This was one of my favorite classrooms. Almost 20 years ago, I took 1802 with Professor Rogers. Yeah. I hope I am not as boring as he was back then.
Another thing I remember about this classroom is that we watched a lot of LS movies.</description></item><item><title>Keynote Gavin Andresen</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/keynote-gavin-andresen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/keynote-gavin-andresen/</guid><description>Gavin Andresen
His fame precedes him. He&amp;rsquo;s going to talk about chain sizes and all that.
Cool, I&amp;rsquo;ll have to follow you guys. Thank you, it&amp;rsquo;s great to be here. I was here last time and had a great time. I&amp;rsquo;m really happy that it&amp;rsquo;s not snowing because we&amp;rsquo;ve had too much snow. I&amp;rsquo;m also happy that you all decided to listen to me on a Sunday morning. I don&amp;rsquo;t usually give talks on Sunday.</description></item><item><title>Matt Corallo Sidechains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/matt-corallo-sidechains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/matt-corallo-sidechains/</guid><description>Matt Corallo (BlueMatt)
Sidechains, Blockstream
One second. Technical difficulties. Okay, sorry about that. Okay. Hi. I am Matt or BlueMatt for those of you know me. I swear it&amp;rsquo;s not related to my hair. Nobody believes me.
I got into Bitcoin three or four years ago because I was interested in the programming and computer science aspects and as well as my interest in large-scale economic incentive structures and macroeconomics and how we create incentive structures that create actions on a low level by rational actors.</description></item><item><title>Peter Todd Scalability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/peter-todd-scalability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/peter-todd-scalability/</guid><description>Peter Todd
Scalability
There we go. Yeah. Looks good. Thank you.
So I wanted to talk about scalability and I wanted to give two opposing views of it. The first is really, scaling Bitcoin up is really really easy. The underlying architecture of Bitcoin is designed in a way that makes it easy to scale. You have your blockchain, and you have your blocks at the top which are 80 bytes data structures.</description></item><item><title>Security And Usability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/security-and-usability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/security-and-usability/</guid><description>Melanie Shapiro Alan Reiner Kristov Atlas Elizabeth Stark (moderator) and maybe Melanie Shapiro? malani? Security and usability.
Elizabeth: I think this is a highly relevant discussion. I talked a bit about regulation. Regulation might be the number threat, but security might be the number two threat. I am excited to have a panel of leaders in this space who are actively building in this ecosystem. I am going to ask each to do a quick intro.</description></item><item><title>Some Questions For Bitcoiners</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/some-questions-for-bitcoiners/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/some-questions-for-bitcoiners/</guid><description>Joi Ito
He is the director of the MIT Media Lab. He served as the chairman of the Creative Commons and is on the board of the Mozilla Foundation.
Just so that I can get a sense of the room, how many people here would say that you are technical? Most of you. How many of you were on the cypherpunks mailing list? How many of you have been threatened by Timothy May?</description></item><item><title>Welcome</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/welcome/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/welcome/</guid><description>Welcome session
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lIgjogLipvk
Jonathan Harvey Buschel Jinglan Wang We are going to get started in about two minutes, so please take your seats. We are also testing the mic for the live stream. If you have friends who are not here, feel free to tweet them, email them or post their facebook page or instagram whatever.
(buzzing/feedback continues)
Hey. All y&amp;rsquo;all ready? Alright, awesome. My name is Jing, I am president of the Wossley Bitcoin Club.</description></item><item><title>Zerocash And Zero Knowledge Succint Arguments Of Knowledge Libsnark</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/zerocash-and-zero-knowledge-succint-arguments-of-knowledge-libsnark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/zerocash-and-zero-knowledge-succint-arguments-of-knowledge-libsnark/</guid><description>Zero knowledge proofs and SNARKs and libsnark
Madars Virza
I am going to tell you about zerocash and our approach of addressing Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s privacy problem. All of this is joint work with Techion, ETCH Zurich, and MIT, and Matt Green, .. and .. and..
So first to get us going, I want to talk a little bit about two of my ideas around Bitcoin. There are two questions that every decentralized cryptocurrency must answer.</description></item></channel></rss>