<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Offers on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/offers/</link><description>Recent content in Offers on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/offers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lightning Privacy &amp; Splice Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/lightning-privacy-splice-panel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/lightning-privacy-splice-panel/</guid><description>Housekeeping Speaker 0: 00:01:17
Today we&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking about Lightning privacy, splicing and other very cool things with an absolute amazing panel here. Just before that, I have a couple of things that I want to set out some updates. So OpenSats is now taking grants for a Bitcoin application, sorry, taking grant applications for Bitcoin projects and Nostra projects and Lightning projects. And there is about five mil for an OSTER, five mil for Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Basis of Lightning Technology 12</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/basis-of-lightning-technology-12/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/basis-of-lightning-technology-12/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this episode of The Van Wirdum Sjorsnado, hosts Aaron van Wirdum and Sjors Provoost discuss BOLT 12 (Basis of Lightning Technology 12), a newly proposed Lightning Network specification for “offers”, a type of “meta invoices” designed by c-lightning developer Rusty Russell.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Where coins on Bitcoin’s base layer are sent to addresses, the Lightning network uses invoices. Invoices communicate the requested amount, node destination, and the hash of a secret which is used for payment routing. This works, but has a number of limitations, Sjors explains, notably that the amount must be bitcoin-denominated (as opposed for fiat denominated), and the invoice can only be used once.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>BOLT 12, which has been implemented in c-ligtning, is a way to essentially refer a payer to the node that is to be paid, in order to request a new invoice. While the BOLT 12 offer can be static and reusable — it always refers to the same node — the payee can generate new invoices on the fly when requested, allowing for much more flexibility, Sjors explains.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, Aaron and Sjors discuss how the new BOLT 12 messages are communicated over the Lightning Network through an update to the BOLT 7 specification for message relay.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>