<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Greg Sanders on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/greg-sanders/</link><description>Recent content in Greg Sanders on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/greg-sanders/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bitcoin Transaction Pinning, ANYPREVOUT &amp; eltoo</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2023-03-06-greg-sanders/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2023-03-06-greg-sanders/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/463/
Stephan Livera – 00:02:02: So on to the discussion with Greg. Greg, also known as instagibbs. Welcome to the show.
Greg Sanders :
Hi, glad to be here.
Stephan Livera :
So, Greg, I know you’re doing a lot of work on some interesting Lightning stuff and transaction fee pinning things. I know you’ve been around for a while in terms of Bitcoin development and Lightning stuff, so yeah, interested to chat and hear a little bit more from your perspective, and want to learn a little bit about what you’re up to.</description></item><item><title>Federated Chains, Sidechains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/sidechains-and-federation-models/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/sidechains-and-federation-models/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048008467871666178
Introduction The name &amp;ldquo;sidechain&amp;rdquo; is overloaded. My favorite private sidechain is my coach. That&amp;rsquo;s my private sidechain. Hopefully I can explain the high-level concepts of a sidechain, at a 10,000 foot view. What are these? What do they give you?
Sidechain components First you need a blockchain. It has to be something that builds a consensus history. The state of the ledger has to be recorded, or the account model, or whatever you&amp;rsquo;re doing.</description></item><item><title>P2PKH, P2WPKH, P2SH, P2WSH</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/p2pkh-p2wpkh-p2h-p2wsh/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/p2pkh-p2wpkh-p2h-p2wsh/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1047697572444270592
Introduction This is going to be a bit of a re-tread I think. I am going to be talking about common bitcoin script templates used in bitcoin today.
Addresses do not exist on the blockchain. But scripts do. You&amp;rsquo;ve heard about p2pk, p2pkh, p2sh, and others. I&amp;rsquo;m going to go over these anyway.
Pay-to-pubkey (p2pk) This was the first type. It had no address format actually. Nodes connected to each other over IP address, with no authentication.</description></item><item><title>Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions (BIP174)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/partially-signed-bitcoin-transactions-bip174/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/partially-signed-bitcoin-transactions-bip174/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1047730297242935296
Introduction Bryan briefly mentioned partially-signed bitcoin transactions (PSBT). I can give more depth on this. There&amp;rsquo;s history and motivation, a background of why this is important, what these things are doing. What is the software doing?
History and motivation Historically, there was no standard for this. Armory had its own format. Bitcoin Core had network-serialized transactions. This ensures fragmentation and it&amp;rsquo;s incomplete and bad that there was no standard. For segwit, a transaction to a legacy node looks like a zero-input transaction, which is a way to flag it as a segwit transaction.</description></item><item><title>Taproot and Graftroot</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/taproot-and-graftroot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/taproot-and-graftroot/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1047764770265284608
Introduction Taproot and graftroot are recent proposals in the bitcoin world. Every script type looks different and they are distinct. From a privacy perspective, that&amp;rsquo;s pretty bad. You watermark or fingerprint yourself all the time by showing unique scripts on the blockchain or in your transactions. This causes censorship risks and other problems for fungibility. Often you are paying for contigencies that are never used, like the whoopsies branches in your scripts.</description></item><item><title>Segwit Lessons Learned</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/segwit-lessons-learned/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/segwit-lessons-learned/</guid><description>Lessons learned with segwit in Bitcoin
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785034301272420353
Hi. My name is Greg Sanders. I will be giving a talk about segwit in bitcoin lessons learned. I will also give some takeaways that I think are important. A little bit about myself. I work on Elements Project at Blockstream. I was a reviewer on segwit for Bitcoin Core. How do we scale protocol development? How do we scale review and keep things safe?</description></item></channel></rss>