<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Stanford (2017) on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/</link><description>Recent content in Stanford (2017) on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Atomically Trading With Roger Gambling On The Success Of A Hard Fork</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/atomically-trading-with-roger-gambling-on-the-success-of-a-hard-fork/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/atomically-trading-with-roger-gambling-on-the-success-of-a-hard-fork/</guid><description>Atomically Trading with Roger: Gambling on the success of a hard-fork
paper: http://homepages.cs.ncl.ac.uk/patrick.mc-corry/atomically-trading-roger.pdf
This is joint work with Patrick McCorry, Andrew Miller and myslef. Patrick was originally going to give this talk but he was unable to make it. I&amp;rsquo;ll give the talk with his slides. I want to acknowledge Roger Ver for permission to use his name in the title of the talk. We asked permission.
I will only be talking about some of the information in the paper.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Script V2.0 And Strengthened Payment Channels</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/bitcoin-script-v2.0-and-strengthened-payment-channels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/bitcoin-script-v2.0-and-strengthened-payment-channels/</guid><description>This is a brief history of bitcoin script evolution. Since bitcoin was active in 2009, there was a lot of emergency fixes for the first 2 years done by Satoshi. He found that people could skpi the signature check using OP_RETURN and malformed scriptSigs. So those functions were removed. OP_VER and OP_VERIF were intended for script upgrades but it was found that after every release of bitcoin, it would become a hard-fork because of the design.</description></item><item><title>Blocksci Platform</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/blocksci-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/blocksci-platform/</guid><description>BlockSci: a Platform for Blockchain Science and Exploration
Harry Kalodner, Princeton University (Arvind Narayanan etc.)
Alright well, my name is Harry Kalodner, I am a student at Princeton University and I am here to tell you about a tool I built alon with some colleagues at Princeton which could be used for analyzing the blockchain in different ways. So far most of the talks today have been constructive about new ways to use the blockchain and protocols to slightly modify bitcoin in roder to improve privacy or scaling.</description></item><item><title>Bolt Anonymous Payment Channels For Decentralized Currencies</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/bolt-anonymous-payment-channels-for-decentralized-currencies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/bolt-anonymous-payment-channels-for-decentralized-currencies/</guid><description>paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2016/701.pdf
To make questions easier, we are going to have a mic on the isle. Please line up so that we can have questions quickly. Okay, now we have Ian Miers.
My name is Ian Miers. Just got my PhD at Hpkins&amp;hellip; authors of zcash, zerocash, &amp;hellip; My interest in bitcoin was, first getting involved, was dealing wit hthe privacy aspect. There is also a scaling problem. I assume you are aware of that.</description></item><item><title>Changes Without Unanimous Consent</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/changes-without-unanimous-consent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/changes-without-unanimous-consent/</guid><description>I want to talk about dealing with consensus changes without so-called consensus. I am using consensus in terms of the social aspect, not in terms of the software algorithm consensus for databases. &amp;ldquo;Consensus changes without consensus&amp;rdquo;. If you don&amp;rsquo;t consensus on consensus, then some people are going to follow one chain and another another chain.
If you have unanimous consensus, then new upgrades work just fine. Developers write software, miners run the same stuff, and then there are no splits because PoW builds on other blocks and we&amp;rsquo;re all happy and the economy is all in agreement as well and everyone wins.</description></item><item><title>Concurrency And Privacy With Payment Channel Networks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/concurrency-and-privacy-with-payment-channel-networks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/concurrency-and-privacy-with-payment-channel-networks/</guid><description>paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2017/820.pdf
Introduction I am going to talk about concurrency and privacy. This was joint work with my collaborators.
Bitcoin has scalability issues. That&amp;rsquo;s the main reason why we are here today. Currently the bitcoin network allows for less than 10 transactions/second. Today we have more than 135 gigabytes of memory requirement. And there are some high fees and micropayments are not really possible. One of the proposals to fix this is payment channels.</description></item><item><title>Discreet Log Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/discreet-log-contracts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/discreet-log-contracts/</guid><description>http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/discreet-log-contracts/
paper: https://adiabat.github.io/dlc.pdf
Hello everyone. I am going to give a talk about discreet log contracts. I am from MIT DCI. I work on lightning network software and discreet log contracts. A quick intro: these are pretty new. I am not sure if they work. This presentation is part of the peer review process. Maybe the math doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. Please let me know. It might also work, though.
It&amp;rsquo;s a system of smart contracts using bitcoin which is similar to lightning network.</description></item><item><title>Flyclient Super Light Clients For Cryptocurrencies</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/flyclient-super-light-clients-for-cryptocurrencies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/flyclient-super-light-clients-for-cryptocurrencies/</guid><description>As you know, the blockchain is a chain because each block connects to the previous block through these hashes. In the header of each block is a commitment to all the transactions. It&amp;rsquo;s using this merkle hash tree where at each level the parent node hashes to the children and this gives you some nice properties which I will talk about later. I need to check consistency though. The first thing I need to check is that the transactions don&amp;rsquo;t spend more than they have&amp;hellip; then I need to check that the tree was onstructed correctly.</description></item><item><title>Graphene Set Reconciliation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/graphene-set-reconciliation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/graphene-set-reconciliation/</guid><description>Brian N. Levine, College of Information and Computer Sciences, UMass Amherst
This is joint work with some people I work with at UMass, including Gavin Andresen.
The problem I am going to focus on in this presentation is how to relay information to a new block, to a neighbor, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t know about next. This would be on the fast relay network or on the regular p2p network. It&amp;rsquo;s about avoiding a situation where, the naieve situation is to send the entire block data.</description></item><item><title>How To Charge Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/how-to-charge-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/how-to-charge-lightning/</guid><description>Our next talk is getting into layer 2. Leaving hwat needs to done at th&amp;hellip;
I am going to start with maybe a simple beginning talking about a single channel between Alice and Bob. We heard about channels yesterday so I am not going to go into details. Alice is not going to cheat Bob in my scenario. Everything is going to run as if everyone honest and doing their best effort, for my example.</description></item><item><title>Incentives Tradeoffs Transaction Selection In Dag Based Protocols</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/incentives-tradeoffs-transaction-selection-in-dag-based-protocols/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/incentives-tradeoffs-transaction-selection-in-dag-based-protocols/</guid><description>Yonatan Sompolinsky (The Hebrew University)
Commercial effort to implement DAG-based protocols. No ICO, it&amp;rsquo;s a regular company.
A little bit background of DAG-based protocols. The background to this work is something we have been working at Hebrew University and Yoad. This idea of blockDAG is about layer 1 of bitcoin. And so it&amp;rsquo;s a generalization of the chain structure of blockchain. As such, there are two solutions- lightning network and payment channels, and were scaling up layer 1, and you&amp;rsquo;re scaling up in layer 2, it&amp;rsquo;s complementary solutions.</description></item><item><title>Intro</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/intro/</guid><description>Introduction Stanford 2017
https://scalingbitcoin.org/
https://scalingbitcoin.org/event/stanford2017
Sorry that we&amp;rsquo;re running a little bit late. My name is Anton Yemelyanov. I am one of the organizers running this event. Welcome everybody. It&amp;rsquo;s great to have a lot of familiar faces here. First of all, as you may know, we have ran over the last 2 days, Bitcoin Edge Dev++ where we have trained over 80 new developers that have joined our ecosystem. They have covered a number of topics including ECDSA and discreet log contracts.</description></item><item><title>Joi Ito</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/joi-ito/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/joi-ito/</guid><description>Welcome back to Scaling Bitcoin day 2. I am sure everyone went home and tried Ethan&amp;rsquo;s wagering setup yesterday. Today we are going to be covering topics like layer 2, fees, and consensus. To get us started today, we have a very special guest, Joi Ito, director of the MIT Media Lab, and he will be talking about parallels to the internet and ICOs and he will cover a lot of ground.</description></item><item><title>Measuring Network Maximum Sustained Transaction Throughput</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/measuring-network-maximum-sustained-transaction-throughput/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/measuring-network-maximum-sustained-transaction-throughput/</guid><description>Measuring maximum sustained transaction throughput on a global network of Bitcoin nodes
Andrew Stone, Bitcoin Unlimited
We are 25 minutes behind schedule.
We have the rest of the team wathcing remotely. I think the motivation for this project is clear. Transaction volume on the bitcoin network could be growing exponentially except that there is a limit on the number of confirmed transactions. Transaction fees have increased and confirmation times are not reliable, and bitcoin is unusable for some applications.</description></item><item><title>Microchains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/microchains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/microchains/</guid><description>Microchains
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/927257690685939712
I would like to see a blockchain ecosystem with 1000s of transactions/second at layer 1 with full security. And so, we have to look at blockchain differently if we are going to achieve this.
A brief introduction&amp;hellip; my name is David Vorick. I have been studying bitcoin since 2011. My primary gig is Sia. I have been spending a lot of time on consensus algorithms and proof-of-work. If we could start over what sorts of things could we do today that we didnt know about in 2008?</description></item><item><title>Optimizing Fee Estimation Via Mempool State</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/optimizing-fee-estimation-via-mempool-state/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/optimizing-fee-estimation-via-mempool-state/</guid><description>I am a Bitcoin Core developer and I work at DG Lab. Today I would like to talk about fees. There&amp;rsquo;s this weird gap between&amp;ndash; there are two things going on. People complain about high fees. But people are confused about why Bitcoin Core is giving high fees but if you set fees manually you can get a much lower fee and get a transaction mined pretty fast. I started to look into this in detail and did simulations and a bunch of stuff.</description></item><item><title>Redesigning Bitcoin Fee Market</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/redesigning-bitcoin-fee-market/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/redesigning-bitcoin-fee-market/</guid><description>Or Sattath (The Hebrew University)
https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2017-September/015093.html
https://www.reddit.com/r/Bitcoin/comments/72qi2r/redesigning_bitcoins_fee_market_a_new_paper_by/
paper: https://arxiv.org/abs/1709.08881
He will be exploring alternative auction markets.
Hello. This is joint work with Aviv Zohar and I have just moved. And Ron Lavi. And I am going to be talking about tehcniques from&amp;hellip; auction theory.. to rethink how fees in bitcoin are done.
Just a fast recap of how the current mechanism works. Each block has a size. Users are asked to specify the fee they will even pay.</description></item><item><title>State Of Cryptography</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/state-of-cryptography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/state-of-cryptography/</guid><description>State of cryptography for blockchains beyond ECDSA and sha256
Signatures and zero-knowledge proofs
Benedikt Bunz, Stanford University
Am going to talk about cryptography relevant to blockchains. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about signatures and zero-knowledge proofs. It has a lot of applications to bitcoin. It turns out that bitcoin is pretty simple in terms of cryptography. It just uses a hash function (sha256) and,s eparately, ECDSA for signatures. I will be mentioning some other cryptography that bitcoin could use.</description></item><item><title>Using The Chain For What Chains Are Good For</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/using-the-chain-for-what-chains-are-good-for/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/using-the-chain-for-what-chains-are-good-for/</guid><description>I am Andrew Poelstra, a cryptographer at Blockstream. I am going to talk about scriptless scripts. But this is a specific example of a more general theme, which is using the blockchain as a trust anchor or commitment layer for smart contracts whose real contents don&amp;rsquo;t really hit the blockchain. I&amp;rsquo;ll elaborate on what I mean by that, and I&amp;rsquo;ll show what the benefits are for that.
To give some context, in Bitcoin script, the scripting language which is used to encode smart contracts, which go on to the blockchain and everyone verifies the chain and downloads and executes all of this contract code.</description></item><item><title>Valueshuffle Mixing Confidential Transactions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/valueshuffle-mixing-confidential-transactions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/valueshuffle-mixing-confidential-transactions/</guid><description>paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2017/238.pdf
Thank you.
We have seen two talks now about putting privacy in layer two. But let&amp;rsquo;s talk about layer one. We still don&amp;rsquo;t have great privacy there. So the title of this talk is valueshuffle - mixing confidential transactions. I don&amp;rsquo;t have to convince you that bitcoin at the moment is not really private. There are a lot of possibilities to link&amp;hellip; to deal them as, to link addresses together.</description></item><item><title>Weak Signal Radio Communications For Bitcoin Network Resilience</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/weak-signal-radio-communications-for-bitcoin-network-resilience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/weak-signal-radio-communications-for-bitcoin-network-resilience/</guid><description>Weak signal radio communications for bitcoin network resilience
What is weak-signal HF radio? These are called high frequency. That&amp;rsquo;s the official name for these frequencies. Short wave is for historical reasons is longer waves and much higher frequency compared to our wireless internet frequencies. The terminology is backwards. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the ionosphere and how we&amp;rsquo;re bouncing signals off of it. This is really long-range stuff. This is an old Voice of America broadcast station that broadcasted radio programs across the pacific.</description></item></channel></rss>