<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jonas Nick on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/jonas-nick/</link><description>Recent content in Jonas Nick on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/jonas-nick/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Libsec Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/libsec-panel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/libsec-panel/</guid><description>Intros NVK: I have an absolute rock star team here. So why don&amp;rsquo;t I start introducing the panel? Tim, hello! Do you want to tell a very brief what do you do?
Tim: Yes, so my name is Tim Ruffing. I am a maintainer of the libsecp256k1 library. I do work for Blockstream, who pay me to do this and also who pay me to do research on cryptography and all kinds of aspects related to Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Provably bug-free BIPs and implementations using hac-spec</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-14-hac-spec/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-14-hac-spec/</guid><description>https://nickler.ninja/
Alright. Strong crowd here, I can see. That&amp;rsquo;s very nice.
Introduction I am Jonas and I will talk about provably bug-free BIPs and implementations. I don&amp;rsquo;t have such a BIP nor such an implementation but if you lower your time-preference enough this could eventually be true at some point. This presentation is only 15 minutes so raise your hand if you have questions.
Just to set the stage. Specifications should be free of bugs, we want them easy to implement and hard to misinterpret.</description></item><item><title>Half Signature Aggregation-What is it and how does it help scale Bitcoin?</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2022-08-02-jonas-nick-tim-ruffing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2022-08-02-jonas-nick-tim-ruffing/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/400/
Stephan Livera: Jonas and Tim, welcome back to the show. Great to chat with you guys again. And so we’re gonna chat about half signature aggregation and hear a little bit from you guys about what you’re working on and just get into what that means for Bitcoin. So Jonas, I know you probably will be best to give some background on some of this — I know you did a talk at Adopting Bitcoin in November of last year, so call it 7–8 months ago, talking about some of this at a high level.</description></item><item><title>MuSig2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/iacr/2021-08-16-jonas-nick-musig2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/iacr/2021-08-16-jonas-nick-musig2/</guid><description>MuSig2: Simple Two-Round Schnorr Multi-Signatures
Location: IACR Crypto
MuSig2 paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/1261.pdf
Introduction This is a talk about MuSig2, simple two round Schnorr multisignatures. I am Jonas Nick and this work is a collaboration with my colleague Tim Ruffing at Blockstream and Yannick Seurin.
Multi-Signatures Multisignatures allow n signers to produce a single signature on a single message. The signing protocol can be interactive and require multiple communication rounds. We distinguish between multisignatures where n-of-n signers can produce a signature and threshold signatures where any subset of size t out of n signers can produce a signature.</description></item><item><title>MuSig, MuSig-DN and MuSig2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-10-27-jonas-nick-tim-ruffing-musig2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-10-27-jonas-nick-tim-ruffing-musig2/</guid><description>Topic: MuSig, MuSig-DN and MuSig2
Location: Stephan Livera Podcast
Tim Ruffing on Schnorr multisig at London Bitcoin Devs: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-17-tim-ruffing-schnorr-multisig/
MuSig paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/068.pdf
MuSig blog post: https://blockstream.com/2019/02/18/en-musig-a-new-multisignature-standard/
Insecure shortcuts in MuSig: https://medium.com/blockstream/insecure-shortcuts-in-musig-2ad0d38a97da
MuSig-DN paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/1057.pdf
MuSig-DN blog post: https://medium.com/blockstream/musig-dn-schnorr-multisignatures-with-verifiably-deterministic-nonces-27424b5df9d6
MuSig2 paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/1261.pdf
MuSig2 blog post: https://medium.com/blockstream/musig2-simple-two-round-schnorr-multisignatures-bf9582e99295
Transcript completed by: Stephan Livera Edited by: Michael Folkson
Intro Stephan Livera (SL): Jonas and Tim, welcome to the show.
Jonas Nick (JN): Hello.
Tim Ruffing (TR): Hey.</description></item><item><title>The Tools and The Work</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lets-talk-bitcoin-podcast/2019-06-09-ltb-pieter-wuille-jonas-nick/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lets-talk-bitcoin-podcast/2019-06-09-ltb-pieter-wuille-jonas-nick/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s Talk Bitcoin with Pieter Wuille and Jonas Nick - June 9th 2019
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1155851797568917504
Part 1: https://letstalkbitcoin.com/blog/post/lets-talk-bitcoin-400-the-tools-and-the-work
Part 2: https://letstalkbitcoin.com/blog/post/lets-talk-bitcoin-401-the-tools-and-the-work-part-2
Draft of BIP-Schnorr: https://github.com/sipa/bips/blob/bip-schnorr/bip-schnorr.mediawiki
Draft of BIP-Taproot: https://github.com/sipa/bips/blob/bip-schnorr/bip-taproot.mediawiki
Draft of BIP-Tapscript: https://github.com/sipa/bips/blob/bip-schnorr/bip-tapscript.mediawiki
Part 1 Adam: On this episode we&amp;rsquo;ll be digging deeply into some of the most important changes coming soon to the Bitcoin protocol in the form of BIPs or Bitcoin Improvement Proposals focused on Taproot, Tapscript and Schnorr signatures.</description></item><item><title>Secure Protocols Bip Taproot</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/secure-protocols-bip-taproot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/secure-protocols-bip-taproot/</guid><description>36C7 1A37 C9D9 88BD E825 08D9 B1A7 0E4F 8DCD 0366
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137358557584793600
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06-06-taproot/
slides: https://nickler.ninja/slides/2019-breaking.pdf
Introduction I am going to tlak about something that is a collaboration of many people in the bitcoin community including my colleagues at Blockstream. The bip-taproot proposal was recently posted to the bitcoin-dev mailing list which proposes an improvement for bitcoin.
Disclaimer It&amp;rsquo;s not at all certain that a bip-taproot soft-fork will activate in its current form or at all.</description></item><item><title>Blind Signatures in Scriptless Scripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/blind-signatures-and-scriptless-scripts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/blind-signatures-and-scriptless-scripts/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014197255593603072
My name is Jonas. I work at Blockstream as an engineer. I am going to talk about some primitives about blind signatures, scriptless scripts, and blind coin swap, and I will explain how to trustlessly exchange ecash tokens using bitcoin.
I want to introduce the blind Schnorr signature in a few moments.
Schnorr signature My assumption is not that you will completely understand Schnorr signatures, but maybe you will at least agree that if you can understand Schnorr signatures then the step to blind Schnorr signatures is not a big step.</description></item><item><title>Validation Cost Metric</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/validation-cost-metric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/validation-cost-metric/</guid><description>slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY2/3_tweaking_the_chain_3_nick.pdf
Motivation As we&amp;rsquo;ve seen over the last two days scalability is a multidimensional problem. One of the main topics of research is increasing the blocksize to increase transaction throughput. The assumption is that as technological progress is continuing and transaction throughput is increased accordingly, the cost for runnning a fully validating node stays constant.
However, blocksize proposals usually only directly change one aspect of full node costs - the blocksize.</description></item></channel></rss>