<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Coinjoin on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/coinjoin/</link><description>Recent content in Coinjoin on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/coinjoin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vortex: ZeroLink for Lightning Opens</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/vortex-zerolink-for-lightning-opens/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/vortex-zerolink-for-lightning-opens/</guid><description>(The start of the talk is missing from the source media)
What is a blind signature All these people could come, and they all can then present their signatures. And Bob will know, &amp;ldquo;okay, all of these signatures are correct, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know who gave me which one. You&amp;rsquo;ll see how we use this in the protocol to get some privacy. This is kind of the structure (referring to slide#2).</description></item><item><title>Challenges in implementing coinjoin in hardware wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2022/challenges-in-implementing-coinjoin-in-hardware-wallets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2022/challenges-in-implementing-coinjoin-in-hardware-wallets/</guid><description>Introduction Hi everyone. I&amp;rsquo;m Pavel Rusnak, known as Stik in the Bitcoin community. I&amp;rsquo;m the co-founder of Satoshi Labs, the company that brought Trezor. Today I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking about the challenges of implementing CoinJoin in hardware wallets.
Why Privacy Let&amp;rsquo;s summarize why privacy matters. Among all reasons I consider these reasons as most important.
Autonomy: Privacy allows individuals to have control over their personal information, enabling them to make independent choices and decisions.</description></item><item><title>Coinjoin Done Right: the onchain offchain mix (and anti-Sybil with RIDDLE)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/coinjoin-done-right-the-onchain-offchain-mix-and-anti-sybil-with-riddles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/coinjoin-done-right-the-onchain-offchain-mix-and-anti-sybil-with-riddles/</guid><description>NOTE: Slides of the talk can be found here
Introduction My name&amp;rsquo;s Adam Gibson, also known as waxwing on the internet. Though the title might suggest that I have the solution to the problem of implementing CoinJoin, it&amp;rsquo;s not exactly true. It&amp;rsquo;s a clickbait. I haven&amp;rsquo;t, but I suppose what I can say in a more serious way is that I&amp;rsquo;m proposing what I consider to be a meaningfully different alternative way of looking at the concept of CoinJoin and therefore at the concept of on-chain privacy because the conversation nowadays about on-chain privacy tends to be dominated by CoinJoin.</description></item><item><title>Cross-Chain Swaps: Atomically Swapping Coins for Privacy or Cross-Blockchain Trades</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/cross-chain-swaps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/cross-chain-swaps/</guid><description>Ethan and Nicolas describe atomic cross-chain swaps - a protocol where two parties can exchange coins as a single operation. The exchange does not require any trusted third party and neither of the parties involved can cheat each other. They describe how this can be used on a single blockchain as a privacy protocol or “cross-chain” as a trading protocol.</description></item><item><title>CoinjoinXT and other techniques for deniable transfers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/coinjoinxt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/coinjoinxt/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014197088979226625
https://joinmarket.me/blog/blog/coinjoinxt/
Introduction My talk today is about what I&amp;rsquo;m calling CoinjoinXT which is kind of a new proposal. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t say it&amp;rsquo;s a new technology, but perhaps a new combination of technologies. My name is Adam Gibson. Yes, another Adam, sorry about that. I have been working on privacy tech for the last number of years, mostly on joinmarket. Today&amp;rsquo;s talk is not about joinmarket, but it is about coinjoin.</description></item><item><title>ValueShuffle: Mixing Confidential Transactions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/valueshuffle-mixing-confidential-transactions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/valueshuffle-mixing-confidential-transactions/</guid><description>paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2017/238.pdf
Thank you.
We have seen two talks now about putting privacy in layer two. But let&amp;rsquo;s talk about layer one. We still don&amp;rsquo;t have great privacy there. So the title of this talk is valueshuffle - mixing confidential transactions. I don&amp;rsquo;t have to convince you that bitcoin at the moment is not really private. There are a lot of possibilities to link&amp;hellip; to deal them as, to link addresses together.</description></item><item><title>Joinmarket</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/joinmarket/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/joinmarket/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784681036504522752
slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/milan2016/presentations/D1%20-%202%20-%20Adlai%20Chandrasekhar.pdf
Finding a risk-free rate for Bitcoin
Joinmarket, just to clear up a misconception&amp;hellip; Joinmarket, like bitcoin, it is a protocol. Not a company. The protocol is defined by an open-source reference implementation. There are other versions of the code out there. It&amp;rsquo;s entirely, I guess you could say it&amp;rsquo;s voluntary like bitcoin. Those of you who might have less of a finance background might not be familiar with the term risk-free rate.</description></item></channel></rss>