<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>privacy on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/privacy/</link><description>Recent content in privacy on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Silent Payments and Alternatives</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-15-silent-payments/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-15-silent-payments/</guid><description>Introduction I will talk about silent payments but also in general the design space around what kind of constructs you can have to pay people in a non-interactive way. In the bitcoin world, there are a couple common ways of paying someone. Making a payment is such a basic thing. &amp;hellip; The alternative we have is that you can generate a single address and put it in your twitter profile and everyone can pay you, but that&amp;rsquo;s not private.</description></item><item><title>Privacy On Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/adopting-bitcoin/2021/2021-11-17-bastien-teinturier-privacy-on-lightning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/adopting-bitcoin/2021/2021-11-17-bastien-teinturier-privacy-on-lightning/</guid><description>Topic: Privacy On Lightning
Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1llk70vI2Mo5uQ7vnpfbl1qlr0qe0NLpySIelChIKhH4/edit
Introduction Buenos Dias San Salvador, I&amp;rsquo;m Bastien. Hopefully my slides are going to come up. Oh yay, perfect. So I&amp;rsquo;m working on the Lightning Protocol Specification and one of its main implementation at Acinq.
I&amp;rsquo;m here to talk to you about privacy. This is a big topic. It&amp;rsquo;s not a black and white thing. There are various degrees of gray when you talk about what your threat model is, who you want to protect against.</description></item><item><title>Nix Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-07-26-nix-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-07-26-nix-bitcoin/</guid><description>Topic: nix-bitcoin
Location: Stephan Livera Podcast
Date: July 26th 2020
nix-bitcoin on GitHub: https://github.com/fort-nix/nix-bitcoin
Transcript completed by: Stephan Livera Edited by: Michael Folkson
Intro Stephan Livera (SL): nixbitcoindev welcome to the show.
nixbitcoindev (NBD): Hello. Thank you for having me.
SL: Obviously as you’re under a pseudonym don’t dox anything about yourself but can you just tell us what you’re interested in about Bitcoin and is it the computer science aspects or what aspects of it interest you?</description></item><item><title>Socratic Seminar - Coinswap</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-23-socratic-seminar-coinswap/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-23-socratic-seminar-coinswap/</guid><description>Location: London BitDevs (online)
Pastebin of the resources discussed: https://pastebin.com/zbegGmb8
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have given permission for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Introductions Michael Folkson (MF): This is London BitDevs, this is a Socratic Seminar. We had two events last week so it is great to see so many people on the call.</description></item><item><title>Coinswap</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi-research-club/2020-06-15-coinswap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi-research-club/2020-06-15-coinswap/</guid><description>Name: Wasabi Research Club
Topic: CoinSwaps
Location: Wasabi Research Club (online)
Wasabi Research Club: https://github.com/zkSNACKs/WasabiResearchClub
Intro (Aviv Milner) Today we are talking about CoinSwaps, massively improving Bitcoin privacy and fungibility. A lot of excitement about CoinSwaps so hopefully we can touch on some interesting things.
CoinSwaps (Belcher 2020) https://gist.github.com/chris-belcher/9144bd57a91c194e332fb5ca371d0964
This is a 2020 ongoing GitHub research paper that Chris Belcher has been working on. You can view the original file here.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Privacy</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2020-05-09-sergei-tikhomirov-lightning-privacy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2020-05-09-sergei-tikhomirov-lightning-privacy/</guid><description>Quantitative Analysis of Lightning Network Privacy
Location: Lightning Hacksprint (Fulmo)
Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1H9EdrhjQ9x3q0qfsei7iFYINVf2lwPyjUKHd3CScy4k/edit#slide=id.g7774542944_0_0
Paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/303
Intro Hello everyone. I am Sergei, I am a PhD student at the University of Luxembourg. I am going to present our joint work with Pedro Moreno-Sanchez and Matteo Maffei from TU Wien on certain aspects of the privacy and scalability of the Lightning Network. The full paper can be found here.
LN intro (for completeness) Let me give some context on what Lightning Network is.</description></item><item><title>Socratic Seminar Payjoins - Bitcoin privacy (Payjoin/P2EP)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-05-05-socratic-seminar-payjoins/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-05-05-socratic-seminar-payjoins/</guid><description>Location: London BitDevs (online)
Adam Gibson Pastebin on Payjoin resources: https://pastebin.com/rgWVuNrC
6102bitcoin resources on Payjoin/P2EP: https://github.com/6102bitcoin/CoinJoin-Research/blob/master/CoinJoin_Research/CoinJoin_Theory/P2EP/summary.md
Transaction fingerprinting discussion: https://github.com/zkSNACKs/WalletWasabi/issues/3625
BitDevs resources on Coinjoin: https://bitdevs.org/2020-02-19-whitepaper-series-11-coinjoin
The conversation has been anonymized to protect the identities of the participants.
Intro (Michael Folkson) We are live, London BitDevs Socratic Seminar on Bitcoin privacy with Adam Gibson. This is a live call on Jitsi. We are streaming on YouTube so bear that in mind. Thanks to Jeff from Fulmo for helping us set this up.</description></item><item><title>Technological Stability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/technological-stability/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/technological-stability/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229891596688052226
Controversial thesis: the primary source of economic instability is unreasonable demands (from regulators, but really from the general public) for violating certain cryptocurrency tech design principles, like on sound money- privacy and confidentiality (like confidential transactions and confidential assets), monetary policy (like scarcity economics), identity vs anonymity, AML/KYC requirements, censorship, sanctions requirements and discrimination (e.g. denying money to certain parties), and issues of fungibility (like mixing and history-indistinguishability).
Financial stability goals- like avoiding global economic crashes- might be at odds with goals like producing sound money and privacy for everyone.</description></item><item><title>P2P Privacy Attacks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-10-09-giulia-fanti-p2p-privacy-attacks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-10-09-giulia-fanti-p2p-privacy-attacks/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs 2019 Residency
Slides: https://residency.chaincode.com/presentations/bitcoin/giulia_fanti_bitcoin_p2p.pdf
Giulia: So today I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk to you about some work that my collaborators and I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on for the last three years now. So this was joint work with a bunch of people who are now spread across a few different universities but it started at the University of Illinois: Shaileshh Bojja Venkatakrishnan, Surya Bakshi, Brad Denby, Shruti Bhargava, Andrew Miller, Pramod Viswanath.</description></item><item><title>Network Partitioning Attacks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-12-ethan-heilman-network-partitioning-attacks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-12-ethan-heilman-network-partitioning-attacks/</guid><description>Bitcoin network partitioning &amp;amp; network-level privacy attacks
Location: Chaincode Labs 2019 Residency
Slides: https://residency.chaincode.com/presentations/bitcoin/ethan_heilman_p2p.pdf
Eclipse attack paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2015/263.pdf
Bitcoin’s P2P Network Please interrupt me. I&amp;rsquo;m going to go through this stuff a little bit quickly because I hear that you&amp;rsquo;ve already read Eclipse attack paper and you&amp;rsquo;ve already looked at some of the peer to peer stuff.
Bitcoin uses a peer-to-peer network to announce transactions and blocks. It makes 8 outgoing connections.</description></item><item><title>Btcpay</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/btcpay/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/btcpay/</guid><description>How to make everyone run their own full node
Building on Bitcoin, 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014166857958461440
I am the maintainer of Nbitcoin and btcpay. I am a dot net fanboy. I am happy that the number of people working on bitcoin in C# has spread from one about four years ago to about ten in this room toay. That&amp;rsquo;s great. I work at DG Lab in Japan.
The goal of my talk is to continue what Jonas Schnelli was talking about.</description></item><item><title>Coinjoinxt</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/coinjoinxt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/coinjoinxt/</guid><description>CoinjoinXT and other techniques for deniable transfers.
Building on Bitcoin 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014197088979226625
https://joinmarket.me/blog/blog/coinjoinxt/
Introduction My talk today is about what I&amp;rsquo;m calling CoinjoinXT which is kind of a new proposal. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t say it&amp;rsquo;s a new technology, but perhaps a new combination of technologies. My name is Adam Gibson. Yes, another Adam, sorry about that. I have been working on privacy tech for the last number of years, mostly on joinmarket.</description></item><item><title>Current And Future State Of Wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/current-and-future-state-of-wallets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/current-and-future-state-of-wallets/</guid><description>Current and future state of wallets
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014127893495021568
Introduction I started to contribute to Bitcoin Core about 5 years ago. Since then, I have managed to get 450 commits merged. I am also the co-founder of a wallet hardware company based in Switzerland called Shift+ Cryptocurrency.
Wallets is not rocket science. It&amp;rsquo;s mostly about pointing the figure to things that we can do better. I prepared a lot of content.
Privacy, security and trust When I look at existing wallets, I see the triangle of privacy, security and trust.</description></item><item><title>Dandelion</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/dandelion/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/dandelion/</guid><description>Dandelion: Privacy-preserving transaction propagation in bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s p2p network
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014196927062249472
Today I will be talking to you about privacy in bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s p2p layer. This was joint work with some talented colleagues.
Bitcoin p2p layer I want to give a brief overview of the p2p layer. Users in bitcoin are connected over a p2p network with tcp links. Users are identified by ip address and port number. Users have a second identity, which is their address or public key or however you want to think about it.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Notes</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2017-09-05-meeting-notes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2017-09-05-meeting-notes/</guid><description>coredev.tech september 2017
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/907233490919464960
((As always, any errors are most likely my own. etc.))
# Introduction There is significant concern regarding whether BlueMatt has become a misnomer.
Monday night presentation: https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-09-04-jonas-schnelli-bip150-bip151/
I think we should continue to use #bitcoin-core-dev for anything about changing Bitcoin Core and try to keep things open even though we&amp;rsquo;re together here today and tomorrow and the next.
# Wallets and block pruning and rescans Nobody produces P2SH change when they have a native output.</description></item><item><title>Confidential Transactions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2017-04-28-gmaxwell-confidential-transactions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2017-04-28-gmaxwell-confidential-transactions/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/859604355917414400
Introduction Thank you.
So as mentioned, I am going to be talking about confidential transactions today. And I look at confidential transactions as a building block fundamental piece of technology, it&amp;rsquo;s not like altcoin or something like that. It&amp;rsquo;s not a turnkey system, it&amp;rsquo;s some fundamental tech, and there are many different ways to use it and deploy it.
My interest in this technology is primarily driven by bitcoin, but the technology here could be applied to many other things, including things outside of the cryptocurrency space.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Security Analysis</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/lightning-network-security-analysis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/lightning-network-security-analysis/</guid><description>Security analysis of the lightning network
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/957978915515092992
slides: https://cyber.stanford.edu/sites/default/files/olaoluwaosuntokun.pdf
Introduction My name is Laolu Osuntokun and I work on lightning stuff. I go by roasbeef on the internet. I work at Lightning Labs. I am going to be giving an overview of some security properties and privacy properties of lightning.
State of the hash-lock Before I start, I want to go over the state of the hash-lock which is the current progress to completion and design of lightning.</description></item><item><title>Scalable Smart Contracts Via Proofs And Single Use Seals</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/scalable-smart-contracts-via-proofs-and-single-use-seals/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/scalable-smart-contracts-via-proofs-and-single-use-seals/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/957660108137418752
slides: https://cyber.stanford.edu/sites/default/files/petertodd.pdf
https://petertodd.org/2016/commitments-and-single-use-seals
https://petertodd.org/2016/closed-seal-sets-and-truth-lists-for-privacy
Introduction I am petertodd and I am here to break your blockchain. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of interesting following a talk like that, in some ways I&amp;rsquo;m going in a more extreme direcion for consensus. Do we actually need consensus at all? Can we make a more robust system by eliminating it to the maximum extent possible? I think for some use case at least I have some techniques that will let you go do this.</description></item><item><title>Mimblewimble</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-11-21-mimblewimble/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-11-21-mimblewimble/</guid><description>Mimblewimble
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aHTRlbCaUyM
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/801990263543648256
History As Denise said, I gave a talk in Milan about mimblewimble about a month ago (slides). This is more or less the same talk, but rebalanced a bit to try to emphasize what I think is important and add some history that has happened in the intervening time. I&amp;rsquo;ll get started.
Many of you have heard of mimblewimble. It&amp;rsquo;s been in the news. It has a catchy name.</description></item><item><title>Aurora Transparent Succinct Arguments R1Cs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/aurora-transparent-succinct-arguments-r1cs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/aurora-transparent-succinct-arguments-r1cs/</guid><description>Aurora: Transparent succinct arguments for R1CS
Alessandro Chiesa
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1090741190100545536
Introduction Hi. I am Alessandro Chiesa, a faculty member at UC Berkeley. I work on cryptography. I&amp;rsquo;m also a chief scientist at Starkware. I was a founder of zcash. Today I will like to tell you about recent work in cryptographic proof systems. This is joint work with people at Starkware, UC Berkeley, MIT Media Lab, and others. In the prior talk, we talked about scalability.</description></item><item><title>Bip Securethebag</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/bip-securethebag/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/bip-securethebag/</guid><description>BIP: OP_SECURETHEBAG
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171750965478854656
Introduction Thank you for the introduction. Today I am going to talk to you about OP_SECURETHEBAG. It&amp;rsquo;s research that I have been working on for the last couple years. I think it&amp;rsquo;s very exciting and hopefully it will have a big compact. I have a lot of slides.
Why are we here? We are here for scaling bitcoin. The goal we have is to scale bitcoin. What is scaling, though?</description></item><item><title>Blind Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/edgedevplusplus/blind-signatures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/edgedevplusplus/blind-signatures/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1047648050234060800
See also http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/building-on-bitcoin/2018/blind-signatures-and-scriptless-scripts/
Introduction Hi everyone. I work at Commonwealth Crypto. Today I am going to be talking to you about blind signatures. I&amp;rsquo;d like to encourage people to ask questions. Please think of questions. I&amp;rsquo;ll give time and pause for people to ask questions.
What are blind signatures? A very informal definition of blind signatures is that they are a signature scheme that allows one party to sign a message without learning the message they signed.</description></item><item><title>Blocksci Platform</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/blocksci-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/blocksci-platform/</guid><description>BlockSci: a Platform for Blockchain Science and Exploration
Harry Kalodner, Princeton University (Arvind Narayanan etc.)
Alright well, my name is Harry Kalodner, I am a student at Princeton University and I am here to tell you about a tool I built alon with some colleagues at Princeton which could be used for analyzing the blockchain in different ways. So far most of the talks today have been constructive about new ways to use the blockchain and protocols to slightly modify bitcoin in roder to improve privacy or scaling.</description></item><item><title>Bolt Anonymous Payment Channels For Decentralized Currencies</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/bolt-anonymous-payment-channels-for-decentralized-currencies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/bolt-anonymous-payment-channels-for-decentralized-currencies/</guid><description>paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2016/701.pdf
To make questions easier, we are going to have a mic on the isle. Please line up so that we can have questions quickly. Okay, now we have Ian Miers.
My name is Ian Miers. Just got my PhD at Hpkins&amp;hellip; authors of zcash, zerocash, &amp;hellip; My interest in bitcoin was, first getting involved, was dealing wit hthe privacy aspect. There is also a scaling problem. I assume you are aware of that.</description></item><item><title>Breaking Bitcoin Privacy</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/breaking-bitcoin-privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/breaking-bitcoin-privacy/</guid><description>Breaking bitcoin privacy
0A8B 038F 5E10 CC27 89BF CFFF EF73 4EA6 77F3 1129
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137304437024862208
Introduction Hello everybody. I invented and created joinmarket, the first really popular coinjoin implementation. A couple months ago I wrote a big literature review on privacy. It has everything about anything in privacy in bitcoin, published on the bitcoin wiki. This talk is about privacy and what we can do to improve it.
Why privacy? Privacy is essential for fungibility, a necessary property of money where one unit is always equal to any other unit.</description></item><item><title>Breaking Wasabi</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/breaking-wasabi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/breaking-wasabi/</guid><description>Breaking wasabi and automated wallets
1127 96A8 DFCA 1A96 C8B8 0094 9211 687A D298 9B12
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137652130611978240
Trigger warnings Before I begin, some have told me that sometimes I tend to be toxic or provocative. So let&amp;rsquo;s start with some trigger warnings. This presentation might include bad jokes about bitcoin personalitites. It might have some multiplication. I might say &amp;ldquo;ethereum&amp;rdquo;. There&amp;rsquo;s also a coinjoin warning. If this is triggering to you, then it&amp;rsquo;s okay to leave.</description></item><item><title>Building Mimblewimble And Grin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/building-mimblewimble-and-grin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/building-mimblewimble-and-grin/</guid><description>Building mimblewimble and green
Quentin Le Sceller (Grin Dev Team), Ignotus Peverell (Grin Dev Team), Yeastplume (Grin Dev Team), Antioch Peverell (Grin Dev Team), HashMap (Grin Dev Team), John Tromp (Grin Dev Team), Daniel Lehnberg (Grin Dev Team)
Quentin Le Sceller
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1090662484275384320
Our first talk is from the Grin project. It was just launched a few weeks ago. Okay, let&amp;rsquo;s get started.
Introduction Hi everyone. My name is Quentin Le Sceller.</description></item><item><title>Concurrency And Privacy With Payment Channel Networks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/concurrency-and-privacy-with-payment-channel-networks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/concurrency-and-privacy-with-payment-channel-networks/</guid><description>paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2017/820.pdf
Introduction I am going to talk about concurrency and privacy. This was joint work with my collaborators.
Bitcoin has scalability issues. That&amp;rsquo;s the main reason why we are here today. Currently the bitcoin network allows for less than 10 transactions/second. Today we have more than 135 gigabytes of memory requirement. And there are some high fees and micropayments are not really possible. One of the proposals to fix this is payment channels.</description></item><item><title>Cross Chain Swaps</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/edgedevplusplus/cross-chain-swaps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/edgedevplusplus/cross-chain-swaps/</guid><description>Cross-chain swaps: Atomically swapping coins for privacy or cross-blockchain trades
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048017311431413760
Introduction We are Ethan Heilman and Nicolas Dorier. Ethan is from Boston University. Nicolas is from DG Lab and working on NBitcoin. Today we&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking with you about atomic swaps for privacy and for cross-blockchain swaps. When we say atomic swaps, what do we mean? At a very high level, the idea is that it enables Alice and Bob to trade some cryptocurrency.</description></item><item><title>Cryptographic Hocus Pocus</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/cryptographic-hocus-pocus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/cryptographic-hocus-pocus/</guid><description>Cryptographic hocus-pocus meaning nothing: The zcash trusted setup MPC
or: &amp;ldquo;Peter Todd&amp;rsquo;s secret love letter to Zooko&amp;rdquo;
Background See http://web.archive.org/web/20170717025249/https://petertodd.org/2016/cypherpunk-desert-bus-zcash-trusted-setup-ceremony
and later it was then redacted: https://petertodd.org/2016/cypherpunk-desert-bus-zcash-trusted-setup-ceremony
Introduction Alright. Hopefully you guys are all awake ish or something. I am going to give a talk about the zcash trusted setup. As many of you know, I was involved in it. The way to start is to answer, what is it?</description></item><item><title>Cryptography Audit</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/cryptography-audit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/cryptography-audit/</guid><description>libsecp256k1-zkp audit
It&amp;rsquo;s a real treat to be able to be a part of this.
Why bother? Just a high-level, why are we taking community resources to spend time on audits? There are some perspectives&amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s good for the community and it&amp;rsquo;s what you do.
Bitcoin had on professional security audits and did just fine. But it launched in a very different environment, and it did get audits eventually.
Beyond just covering your ass, it&amp;rsquo;s good to have these audits because if there&amp;rsquo;s a vulnerability then you can have someone with liability.</description></item><item><title>Dan Boneh</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/dan-boneh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/dan-boneh/</guid><description>Dan Boneh fireside chat
Taariq Lewis
TL: I was one of the founders of SF Bitcoin Devs with aantonop. I am also the co-founder of a company called Promise. We sponsor protocols in privacy as well as mimblewimble. If you are mining or actively looking to mine in grin, please say hello to me because we&amp;rsquo;re connected with a lot of mining companies and hosting companies that are looking to host miners very cheaply.</description></item><item><title>Day 1 Group Summaries</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/day-1-group-summaries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/day-1-group-summaries/</guid><description>Day 1 group summaries
We need two to three minute report backs from each session. Also, note takers. Please email your notes to contact@scalingbitcoin.org so that we can add notes to the wiki. Come join us. Okay, so.
Lightning We discussed routing and several aspects of routing algorithms in the lightning network. We talked about the tradeoff between privacy aspects and reliability in routing. We quickly discovered that after some of the things were already resolved by the papers&amp;ndash; the way how we deal with a general separation and channel transaction fees, is actually quite an interesting discussion topic.</description></item><item><title>Decentralized Oracles Tls</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/decentralized-oracles-tls/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/decentralized-oracles-tls/</guid><description>DECO: Liberating Web Data Using Decentralized Oracles for TLS
Fan Zhang
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230657639740108806
Introduction I am Fan from Cornell. I am going to be talking about DECO, a privacy-preserving oracle for TLS. This is joint work with some other people.
Decentralized identity What is identity? To use any system, the first thing that the user needs to do is to prove her identity and that she is a user to the system.</description></item><item><title>Discreet Log Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/discreet-log-contracts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/discreet-log-contracts/</guid><description>http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/discreet-log-contracts/
paper: https://adiabat.github.io/dlc.pdf
Hello everyone. I am going to give a talk about discreet log contracts. I am from MIT DCI. I work on lightning network software and discreet log contracts. A quick intro: these are pretty new. I am not sure if they work. This presentation is part of the peer review process. Maybe the math doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. Please let me know. It might also work, though.
It&amp;rsquo;s a system of smart contracts using bitcoin which is similar to lightning network.</description></item><item><title>Extreme Opsec For The Modern Cypherpunk</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/extreme-opsec-for-the-modern-cypherpunk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/extreme-opsec-for-the-modern-cypherpunk/</guid><description>Extreme opsec for the modern cypherpunk
Jameson is the infrastructure engineer at Casa. Please welcome Jameson Lopp.
Introduction Hi fellow cypherpunks. We&amp;rsquo;re under attack. Corporations and nation states in their quest for omniscience have slowly stripped away our privacy. We are the frog being boiled in the pot called progress. We can&amp;rsquo;t trust that corporations will grant us privacy out of their beneficience. Our failures here are our own. After being swatted a year ago, I set out to restart my life with a new focus on privacy.</description></item><item><title>Flare Routing In Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/flare-routing-in-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/flare-routing-in-lightning/</guid><description>Flare: An approach to routing in lightning network
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784745976170999810
I will not be as technical as Olaoluwa was. You have nodes that open up payment channels. This scheme is actually developed at the moment in great detail. So how do you find the channels through which to send payments? So we wanted to propose some initial solution to this.
Routing requirements It should be source routing because we need the privacy.</description></item><item><title>Fungibility and Privacy</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/bitcoin-adam3us-fungibility-privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/bitcoin-adam3us-fungibility-privacy/</guid><description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3dAdI3Gzodo
First of all I was going to explain what we mean by fungibility before bitcoin and ecash. It&amp;rsquo;s an old legal concept in fact, about paper currency. It&amp;rsquo;s the idea that a one ten dollar note is the same as any other ten dollar note. If you receive a note that was involved in a theft, 10 transactions ago, and the police investigate the theft, they have no right to remove the ten dollar note from your pocket.</description></item><item><title>Fungibility And Scalability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/fungibility-and-scalability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/fungibility-and-scalability/</guid><description>slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY1/1_overviews_2_back.pdf
I think everyone knows what fungibility is, it&amp;rsquo;s when coins are equal and interchangeable. It&amp;rsquo;s an important property for an electronic cash system. All bitcoin users would have a problem if fungability goes away.
Bitcoin has fungibility without privacy. Previous electronic cash systems had fungibility and cryptographic blinding. In Bitcoin, there&amp;rsquo;s decentralized mining that somebody will process your transaction even if a given miner may not. But there is some privacy, because it&amp;rsquo;s based on pseudonyms.</description></item><item><title>Future Of Privacy Coins</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/future-of-privacy-coins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/future-of-privacy-coins/</guid><description>Future of privacy coins
AM: That&amp;rsquo;s not good. Hi everyone. Thanks for coming to the future of privacy coins panel. I want to spend a minute talking ablout backgrounds and interest in this area.
BG: I have a PhD in something. I got into monero a couple of years ago. I needed to pay rent, so I did some work in math in exchange for money.
AP: I work on confidential transactions and scriptless scripts and I do not have a PhD.</description></item><item><title>Future Of Spv Tech</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/future-of-spv-tech/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/future-of-spv-tech/</guid><description>https://docs.google.com/document/d/1t0bSZj5b66xBdW7xrjHlcvfqYAbTaQDB4-_T0Jvs3T4/edit#heading=h.5lm45oa6kuri
issues with current SPV wallets
Existing clients and their status
bitcoinj electrum ** they are doing SPV proofs ** bloom filters utxo commitments need to get in need to pick which type of utxo commitments
Number of nodes to connect to for more SPV clients
1 header from each peer to verify that we are all getting the same thing what block does each peer think is the best? very cheap to poll a huge number of peers</description></item><item><title>How Much Privacy Is Enough</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/how-much-privacy-is-enough/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/how-much-privacy-is-enough/</guid><description>How much privacy is enough? Threats, scaling, and trade-offs in blockchain privacy protocols
Ian Miers (secparam)
unrelated, https://arxiv.org/pdf/1706.00916.pdf
Introductions Hi everybody. This is a talk on how much privacy is enough, evaluating trade-offs in privacy and scalability. This is going to be unusual for this conference because I will not be presenting new technical content. I am going to be talking about evaluating the tradeoffs between these scalability and privacy. As context, my name is Ian Miers.</description></item><item><title>Invertible Bloom Lookup Tables And Weak Block Propagation Performance</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/invertible-bloom-lookup-tables-and-weak-block-propagation-performance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/invertible-bloom-lookup-tables-and-weak-block-propagation-performance/</guid><description>IBLT and weak block propagation performance
slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY1/3_block_propagation_1_rosenbaum.pdf
IBLT - invertible bloom lookup tables
Before we get started, for privacy reasons, and for reasons of zero attribution, please do not take pictures of attendees. Do not have pictures of attendees in the photographs. Taking pictures of the stage and slides are OK, since they are being broadcasted. No photographs of any attendees, please let them remain anonymous and private. For Chinese speakers, please ask in Chinese and I will use American English to translate.</description></item><item><title>Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/lightning/</guid><description>Lightning work group session
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784783992478466049
You have a network. Anyone can join the network. You have two points and you want to do route finding between those two points. To be clear, this is a network of channels. It is similar to the internet, but it is not the internet. How do you find such a route? It&amp;rsquo;s easy when you find all the implements of the network. Some of the information changes frequently.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Sphinx And Onion Routing</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/edgedevplusplus/lightning-network-sphinx-and-onion-routing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/edgedevplusplus/lightning-network-sphinx-and-onion-routing/</guid><description>Introduction Hi everyone. I am a developer of rust-lightning, it started in 2018 by BlueMatt. I started contributing about a year ago now. It&amp;rsquo;s a full featured, flexible, spec-compliant lightning library. It targets exchanges, wallet vendors, hardware, meshnet devices, and you can join us on Freenode IRC in the #rust-bitcoin channel which is a really nice one.
Privacy matters Privacy matters on the blockchain. This is the reason why lightning is taking so much time.</description></item><item><title>Mixicles</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/mixicles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/mixicles/</guid><description>Mixicles: Simple Private Decentralized Finance
Ari Juels
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230666545803563008
https://chain.link/mixicles.pdf
Introduction This work was done in my capacity as technical advisor to Chainlink, and not my Cornell or IC3 affiliation. Mixicle is a combination of the words mixers and oracles. You will see why in a moment.
DeFi and privacy As of a couple of weeks ago, DeFi passed the $1 billion mark which is to say there&amp;rsquo;s over $1 billion of cryptocurrency in DeFi smart contracts today.</description></item><item><title>Multi Hop Locks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-hop-locks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-hop-locks/</guid><description>Multi-hop locks for secure, privacy-preserving and interoperable payment-channel networks
Giulio Malavolta (Friedrich-Alexander-University Erlangen-Nuernberg), Pedro Moreno-Sanchez (Purdue University), Clara Schneidewind (Vienna University of Technology), Aniket Kate (Purdue University) and Matteo Maffei (Vienna University of Technology)
https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/472.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048476273259900928
This is joint work with my colleagues. I promise I will talk slower than the last talk. In a multi-hop network, the security tool is a hash-time lock contract (HTLC) where the payment is conditioned on revealing the pre-image of a hash function.</description></item><item><title>Onion Routing In Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/onion-routing-in-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/onion-routing-in-lightning/</guid><description>http://lightning.network/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784742298089299969
Privacy-preserving decentralized micropayments
We&amp;rsquo;re excited about lightning because the second layer could be an important opportunity to improve privacy and fungibility. Also, there might be timing information in the payments themselves.
Distributed set of onion routers (OR, cite OG onionrouting paper). Users create circuits with sub-set of nodes. Difficult for oion routers to gain more info than predecessor+successor in path. Low latency - usable within greater internet. Notable success is tor, notable success of routing nodes.</description></item><item><title>Perspective</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/perspective/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/perspective/</guid><description>Regulators should focus on consumer protection
Regulators should focus on operating (or overseeing) rating agencies, and formal review of proposed standards
Fungibility is important, and many regulatory goals are contrary to fungibility, indicating that their forms of money will be inferior and their economy will be left behind.
Anonymity should be a core value&amp;ndash; the society with the most privacy will have the most advantages.
The importance of regulatory sandboxes (which should be optional).</description></item><item><title>Privacy And Fungibility</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/privacy-and-fungibility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/privacy-and-fungibility/</guid><description>Privacy and scalability
Even though Bitcoin is the worst privacy system ever, everyone in the community very strongly values privacy.
There are at least three things: privacy censorship resistance fungibility
The easiest way to censor things is to punish communication, not prevent communication. Privacy is the weakest link in censorship resistance. Fungibility is an absolute necessity for any medium of exchange. The properties of money include fungibility. Without privacy you may not be able to have fungibility.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Concepts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/edgedevplusplus/privacy-concepts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/edgedevplusplus/privacy-concepts/</guid><description>Privacy concepts for bitcoin application developers
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171036497044267008
Introduction You&amp;rsquo;re not going to walk out of here as a privacy protocol developer. I am going to mention and talk about some ideas in some protocols that exist. What I find myself is that of really smart people working on a lot of pretty cool stuff that can make privacy easier and better to use. A lot of times, application developers or exchanges aren&amp;rsquo;t even aware of those things and as a result the end result is that people just sometimes use bitcoin in very non-private ways because they&amp;rsquo;re not aware of how to do privacy.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Preserving Smart Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/privacy-preserving-smart-contracts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/privacy-preserving-smart-contracts/</guid><description>ranjit@csail.mit.edu
http://people.csail.mit.edu/ranjit/
We have been looking at how much we can support or what limitations we might encounter. There are also efficiency issues and privacy guarantees. And then there are some potential relaxations that will help with removing the fundamental limitations and express the power and make smart contracts more useful.
The point of this talk is off-chain transactions and secure computation. I will also highlight the relationship of secure computation and bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Private Information Retrieval</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/private-information-retrieval/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/private-information-retrieval/</guid><description>Applying private information retrieval (PIR) to lightweight bitcoin clients
SPV overview I have to thank the prior speaker. This is basically the same, except this time we&amp;rsquo;re not using SGX. We&amp;rsquo;re looking at bitcoin lightweight clients. You have a lite client with not much space not much computing power, can&amp;rsquo;t store the bitcoin blockchain. All it knows about is the header information. We assume it has the blockheader history. In the header, we can find the merkle tree, and given the merkle tree we can make a merkle proof that a given transaction is included in a block.</description></item><item><title>Scaling Oblivious Read Write</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/scaling-oblivious-read-write/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/scaling-oblivious-read-write/</guid><description>A tale of two trees: One writes, and other reads, scaling oblivious accesses to large-scale blockchains
Introduction We are trying to get optimized oblivious accesses to large-scale blockchains. This is collaborative work with our colleagues.
Motivation As we all know, bitfcoin data has become too large to store in resource-constrained devices. It&amp;rsquo;s like 240 GB. The current solution today is bip37 + Nakamoto&amp;rsquo;s idea for simplified payment verification (SPV) clients which don&amp;rsquo;t run the bitcoin network rules.</description></item><item><title>Spork Probabilistic Bitcoin Soft Forks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/spork-probabilistic-bitcoin-soft-forks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/spork-probabilistic-bitcoin-soft-forks/</guid><description>Spork: Probabilistic bitcoin soft-forks
Introduction Thank you for the introduction. I have a secret. I am not an economist, so you&amp;rsquo;ll have to forgive me if I don&amp;rsquo;t have your favorite annotations today. I have my own annotations. I originally gave a predecessor to this talk in Japan. You might notice my title here is a haiku: these are protocols used for changing the bitcoin netwokr protocols. People do highly value staying together for a chain, we&amp;rsquo;re doing coordinated activation of a new upgrade.</description></item><item><title>Stark For Developers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/stark-for-developers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/stark-for-developers/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230279740570783744
Introduction It always seems like there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of different proof systems, but it turns out they really work well together and there&amp;rsquo;s great abstractions that are happening where we can take different tools and plug them together. We will see some of those in this session. I think STARKs were first announced 3 years ago back when this conference was BPASE, and now they are ready to use for developers and they are deployed in the wild and it&amp;rsquo;s exciting to see how far we&amp;rsquo;ve come in the past few years.</description></item><item><title>Taproot and Graftroot</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/edgedevplusplus/taproot-and-graftroot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/edgedevplusplus/taproot-and-graftroot/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1047764770265284608
Introduction Taproot and graftroot are recent proposals in the bitcoin world. Every script type looks different and they are distinct. From a privacy perspective, that&amp;rsquo;s pretty bad. You watermark or fingerprint yourself all the time by showing unique scripts on the blockchain or in your transactions. This causes censorship risks and other problems for fungibility. Often you are paying for contigencies that are never used, like the whoopsies branches in your scripts.</description></item><item><title>Threshold Scriptless Scripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/threshold-scriptless-scripts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/threshold-scriptless-scripts/</guid><description>Omer Shlomovits (KZen Research) (omershlomovits, zengo)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171690582445580288
Scriptless scripts We can write smart contracts in bitcoin today, but there&amp;rsquo;s some limitations. We can do a lot of great things. We can do atomic swaps, multisig, payment channels, etc. There&amp;rsquo;s a cost, though. Transactions become bigger with bigger scripts. Also, it&amp;rsquo;s kind of heavy on the verifiers. The verifiers now need to verify more things. There&amp;rsquo;s also privacy issues because you put your contract publicly on chain.</description></item><item><title>Tumblebit</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/tumblebit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/tumblebit/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784686167052709888
Hi. So I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking about tumblebit. It&amp;rsquo;s our untrusted private bitcoin payment system. Tumblebit provides payments which are private. They provide set anonymity when used as a classic tumbler. They are untrusted. The tumbler can&amp;rsquo;t violate your privacy, and can&amp;rsquo;t steal your coins. It&amp;rsquo;s also scalable. It&amp;rsquo;s compatible and works with today&amp;rsquo;s bitcoin. There are no malleability concerns. We&amp;rsquo;re going to rely on the constrained opcodes that currently exist in bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Valueshuffle Mixing Confidential Transactions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/valueshuffle-mixing-confidential-transactions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/valueshuffle-mixing-confidential-transactions/</guid><description>paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2017/238.pdf
Thank you.
We have seen two talks now about putting privacy in layer two. But let&amp;rsquo;s talk about layer one. We still don&amp;rsquo;t have great privacy there. So the title of this talk is valueshuffle - mixing confidential transactions. I don&amp;rsquo;t have to convince you that bitcoin at the moment is not really private. There are a lot of possibilities to link&amp;hellip; to deal them as, to link addresses together.</description></item><item><title>Zerocash And Zero Knowledge Succint Arguments Of Knowledge Libsnark</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/zerocash-and-zero-knowledge-succint-arguments-of-knowledge-libsnark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/zerocash-and-zero-knowledge-succint-arguments-of-knowledge-libsnark/</guid><description>Zero knowledge proofs and SNARKs and libsnark
I am going to tell you about zerocash and our approach of addressing Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s privacy problem. All of this is joint work with Techion, ETCH Zurich, and MIT, and Matt Green, .. and .. and..
So first to get us going, I want to talk a little bit about two of my ideas around Bitcoin. There are two questions that every decentralized cryptocurrency must answer.</description></item></channel></rss>