<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>proof-systems on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/proof-systems/</link><description>Recent content in proof-systems on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/proof-systems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Open Timestamps: Leveraging Bitcoin's Security For All Data</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/open-timestamps-leveraging-bitcoin-s-security-for-all-data/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/open-timestamps-leveraging-bitcoin-s-security-for-all-data/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this episode of The Van Wirdum Sjorsnado, Aaron and Sjors discuss Open Timestamps, a Bitcoin-based time stamping project from applied cryptography consultant and former Bitcoin Core contributor Peter Todd. Open Timestamps leverages the security of the Bitcoin blockchain to timestamp any type of data, allowing for irrefutable proof that that data existed at a particular point in time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aaron and Sjors explain that virtually any amount of data can, in fact, be timestamped in the Bitcoin blockchain at minimal cost because Open Timestamps leverages Merkle trees, the cryptographic trick to aggregate data into a single, compact hash. This hash is then included in a Bitcoin transaction, making all of the data aggregated into the hash as immutable as any other Bitcoin transaction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Todd offered an interesting showcase of Open Timestamps earlier this week, as he proved that the public key used by Google to sign “the email&amp;quot; to Hunter Biden indeed existed in 2016.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Aaron and Sjors also discuss some of the other possibilities that a time-stamping system like Open Timestamps offers, as well as its limitations. Finally, Aaron provides a little bit of context for the history of cryptographic time stamping, which was itself referenced in the Bitcoin white paper&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Plasma Cash: Towards more efficient Plasma Constructions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/plasma-cash/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/plasma-cash/</guid><description>Non-custodial sidechains for bitcoin utilizing plasma cash and covenants
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1172108023705284609
paper: https://github.com/loomnetwork/plasma-paper/blob/master/plasma_cash.pdf
slides: https://gakonst.com/scalingbitcoin2019.pdf
Introduction We have known how to do these things for at least a year, but the question is how can we find the minimum changes that we can figure out to do in bitcoin if any on how to explore the layer 2 space in a better sense rather than just accepting that lightning network is the dominant solution?</description></item><item><title>Proof-of-Verification for Proof-of-Work: Miners Must Verify the Signatures on Bitcoin Transactions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/proof-of-verification-for-proof-of-work/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/proof-of-verification-for-proof-of-work/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1172142603007143936
extended abstract: http://kmlab.iis.u-tokyo.ac.jp/papers/scaling19-matsuura-final.pdf
History lesson In the 90s, we had some timestamping schemes where things are aggregated into one hash and then it would be publicized later in the newspaper. This scheme was commercialized, in fact. However, the resolution of the trust anchor is very limited. It&amp;rsquo;s one day or half-day at best. When we want to verify, we need to visit the online-offline database maintained by a trusted party to get the merkle inclusion paths.</description></item><item><title>A Survey of Progress in Succinct Zero Knowledge Proofs: Towards Trustless SNARKs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/survey-of-progress-in-zero-knowledge-proofs-towards-trustless-snarks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/survey-of-progress-in-zero-knowledge-proofs-towards-trustless-snarks/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171683484382957568
Introduction I am going to be giving a survey of recent progress into succinct zero-knowledge proofs. I&amp;rsquo;ll survey recent developments, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to start with what zero-knowledge proofs are. This is towards SNARKs without trusted setup. I want to help you get up to date on what&amp;rsquo;s happening on with SNARKs. There&amp;rsquo;s an explosion of manuscripts and it&amp;rsquo;s hard to keep track.
One theme is the emergence of polynomial commitment schemes which is an efficient tool for building transparent SNARKs without trusted setup.</description></item><item><title>ZkVM: zero-knowledge virtual machine for fast confidential smart contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/zkvm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/zkvm/</guid><description>https://medium.com/stellar-developers-blog/zkvm-a-new-design-for-fast-confidential-smart-contracts-d1122890d9ae and https://twitter.com/oleganza/status/1126612382728372224
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171711553512583169
Introduction Okay, welcome. What is zkvm? It&amp;rsquo;s a multi-asset blockchain architecture that combines smart contracts and confidentiality features. It&amp;rsquo;s written in pure rust from top to bottom.
https://github.com/stellar/slingshot
Agenda I&amp;rsquo;ll explain the good parts, and then I&amp;rsquo;ll explain away the bad parts. Sounds like a good time.
What does this have to do with bitcoin? zkvm is a unique combination of the best ideas in the blockchain space.</description></item><item><title>Acumulator Based Cryptography &amp; UTreexo</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/accumulators/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/accumulators/</guid><description>https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-10-08-utxo-accumulators-and-utreexo/
https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/mit-bitcoin-expo-2019/utreexo/
https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/accumulators/
https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/accumulators/
https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06-06-utreexo/
Note: the present presentation had more in depth information about RSA which might be interesting to the audience.
slides:
https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1OWhdB5P680FMHkoutd_YLP4hGFWI_aVaXRkkYdfoix8/edit?usp=sharing
https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1z_vAwA6hN-C1WEg89EFfZCwqfMRWDcYuW61aA7P84zM/edit?usp=sharing</description></item><item><title>Future Of Privacy Coins</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/future-of-privacy-coins/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/future-of-privacy-coins/</guid><description>AM: That&amp;rsquo;s not good. Hi everyone. Thanks for coming to the future of privacy coins panel. I want to spend a minute talking ablout backgrounds and interest in this area.
BG: I have a PhD in something. I got into monero a couple of years ago. I needed to pay rent, so I did some work in math in exchange for money.
AP: I work on confidential transactions and scriptless scripts and I do not have a PhD.</description></item><item><title>UTXO accumulators, UTXO commitments, and Utreexo</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-10/2018-10-08-utxo-accumulators-and-utreexo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-10/2018-10-08-utxo-accumulators-and-utreexo/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1049112390413897728
If people saw Benedikt&amp;rsquo;s talk, two days ago, it&amp;rsquo;s related. It&amp;rsquo;s a different construction but same goal. The basic idea is, and I think Cory kind of started to talk about this a few months ago on the mailing list&amp;hellip; instead of storing all UTXOs in leveldb, store the hash of each UTXO, and then it&amp;rsquo;s half the size, and then you could almost create it from the hash of the input, it&amp;rsquo;s like 10 bytes more.</description></item><item><title>A Scalable Drop in Replacement for Merkle Trees</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/accumulators/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/accumulators/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048454406755168257
Introduction Hello. Test. Okay. I am going to talk about accumulators for UTXOs. The previous two talks were a great setup for this. This is joint work with Ben Fisch who is also here today and Dan Boneh. I first want to advertise the Stanford Blockchain Conference (formerly known as BPASE) happening at the end of January 2019 at Stanford. Whether you give a talk or not, you should try to attend.</description></item><item><title>Single Use Seals</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/single-use-seals/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/single-use-seals/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014168068447195136
I am going to talk about single use seals and ways to use them. They are a concept of building consensus applications and things that need consensus. I want to mention why that matters. What problem are we trying to solve? Imagine my cell phone and I open up my banking app or the banking app or lightning app&amp;hellip; I want to make sure that what I see on my screen is the same as what you see on your screen.</description></item><item><title>Bulletproofs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2018-02-02-andrew-poelstra-bulletproofs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2018-02-02-andrew-poelstra-bulletproofs/</guid><description>49th Milan Bitcoin meetup
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/962326126969442304
https://www.reddit.com/r/Bitcoin/comments/7w72pq/bulletproofs_presentation_at_feb_2_milan_meetup/
Introduction Alright. Thank you for that introduction, Giacamo. I am here to talk about bulletproofs. This is different from proof-of-bullets, which is what fiat currencies use. In bulletproofs, we use a zero-knowledge proof which has nothing to do with consensus at all, but it has a lot of exciting applications. The original motivation to create bulletproofs was for range proofs which are used in confidential transactions.</description></item><item><title>Sharding the Blockchain</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/sharding-the-blockchain/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/sharding-the-blockchain/</guid><description>I am going to talk about blockchain sharding. This is one of the scaling solutions that I like the most. I have done the most work on it. In case you don&amp;rsquo;t know who I am, I am a researcher mostly with the ethereum project. Basically the basics of sharding is that in non-sharding, every node does every validation. In a sharding solution, nodes hold a subset of the state, and a subset of the blockchain.</description></item><item><title>Zerocash: Zero knowledge proofs and SNARKs and libsnark</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/zerocash-and-zero-knowledge-succint-arguments-of-knowledge-libsnark/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/zerocash-and-zero-knowledge-succint-arguments-of-knowledge-libsnark/</guid><description>I am going to tell you about zerocash and our approach of addressing Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s privacy problem. All of this is joint work with Techion, ETCH Zurich, and MIT, and Matt Green, .. and .. and..
So first to get us going, I want to talk a little bit about two of my ideas around Bitcoin. There are two questions that every decentralized cryptocurrency must answer. First of them is where does the money come from.</description></item><item><title>Accumulators for blockchains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/accumulators/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/accumulators/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1090748293234094082
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1090741715059695617
https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/accumulators/
paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/1188
Introduction I am going to be talking about batching techniques for accumulators with applications to interactive oracle proofs and blockchains. I&amp;rsquo;ll maybe also talk about how to make these proofs even smaller. The main thing that we are going to focus on today is the bitcoin state and this application of accumulators to bitcoin and blockchain.
Bitcoin UTXO states The bitcoin state is the UTXO set.</description></item><item><title>Aurora: Transparent Succinct Arguments for R1CS</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/aurora-transparent-succinct-arguments-r1cs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/aurora-transparent-succinct-arguments-r1cs/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1090741190100545536
Introduction Hi. I am Alessandro Chiesa, a faculty member at UC Berkeley. I work on cryptography. I&amp;rsquo;m also a chief scientist at Starkware. I was a founder of zcash. Today I will like to tell you about recent work in cryptographic proof systems. This is joint work with people at Starkware, UC Berkeley, MIT Media Lab, and others. In the prior talk, we talked about scalability. But this current talk is more about privacy by using cryptographic proofs.</description></item><item><title>Breaking The Chain</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/breaking-the-chain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/breaking-the-chain/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785144266683195392
http://dpaste.com/1ZYW028
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/milan/client-side-validation/
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong/braiding-the-blockchain/
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/milan/jute-braiding/
Inclusivitiy So it seems like we have two big topics here, one is braiding and one is proof-of-publication. I had a talk in Hong Kong about braiding. The major difference is the inclusive nature. The notion that every block gets a block reward as a way to solve selfish-mining. It&amp;rsquo;s a competition between the orphans that get a reward and the ones that don&amp;rsquo;t that causes a loss of security.</description></item><item><title>Building Bulletproofs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/building-bulletproofs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/building-bulletproofs/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1090668746073563136
Introduction There are two parts to this talk. The first part of the talk will be building, like all the pieces we put into making the implementation of bulletproofs. We&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the group we used, the Ristretto group and ristretto255 group. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about parallel lelliptic curve arithmetic, and Merlin transcripts for zero-knowledge proofs, and how all these pieces fit together.
Cathie will talk in part two about constraint system proofs, cloak for a confidential assets protocol, ZkVM for zero-knowledge contracts, and aggregation multi-party computation with session types to aggregate proofs and have faster verification.</description></item><item><title>Bulletproofs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/bulletproofs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/bulletproofs/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/958881877896593410
http://web.stanford.edu/~buenz/pubs/bulletproofs.pdf
https://joinmarket.me/blog/blog/bulletpoints-on-bulletproofs/
https://crypto.stanford.edu/bulletproofs
Introduction Good morning everyone. I am Benedikt Bünz and I am going to talk about bulletproofs. This is joint work with myself, Jonathan Bootle, Dan Boneh, Andrew Poelstra, Pieter Wuille, and Greg Maxwell. Bulletproofs are short proofs that we designed originally with the goal of improving confidential transactions but I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about how they have many more applications and how they are short zero-knowledge proofs for arbitrary computations really.</description></item><item><title>Cryptography for Blockchains beyond ECDSA and sha256: Signatures and Zero-Knowledge Proofs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/state-of-cryptography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/state-of-cryptography/</guid><description>Am going to talk about cryptography relevant to blockchains. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about signatures and zero-knowledge proofs. It has a lot of applications to bitcoin. It turns out that bitcoin is pretty simple in terms of cryptography. It just uses a hash function (sha256) and,separately, ECDSA for signatures. I will be mentioning some other cryptography that bitcoin could use.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start with signatures. What do signatures do? If Bob wants to say, on every e-cash system, Bob says he is going to send 1 coin to Alice, but the problem is how does Alice know whether Bob said this or was this just from someone else or how does a third person verifyin miner check that actually Bob issued this transaction?</description></item><item><title>DECO: Liberating Web Data Using Decentralized Oracles for TLS</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/decentralized-oracles-tls/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/decentralized-oracles-tls/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230657639740108806
Introduction I am Fan from Cornell. I am going to be talking about DECO, a privacy-preserving oracle for TLS. This is joint work with some other people.
Decentralized identity What is identity? To use any system, the first thing that the user needs to do is to prove her identity and that she is a user to the system. The identity can be descriptive. You can think of digital identity as a set of descriptions about a user.</description></item><item><title>Hardware Accelerated RSA - VDFs, SNARKs, and Accumulators</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/hardware-accelerated-rsa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/hardware-accelerated-rsa/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230551345700069377
Introduction I am going to talk about accelerating RSA operations in hardware. So let&amp;rsquo;s just get into it.
Outline I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about what acceleration is and why we&amp;rsquo;re interested in it, then we&amp;rsquo;ll get into RSA primitives, then we&amp;rsquo;ll get into algorithms, and then various platforms for hardware. Hardware is anything you&amp;rsquo;re going to run software on. We&amp;rsquo;ll look at what the tradeoffs are, and then some performance numbers and measurements we&amp;rsquo;ve taken.</description></item><item><title>Proof of necessary work: Succinct state verification with fairness guarantees</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/proof-of-necessary-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/proof-of-necessary-work/</guid><description>Introduction I am going to show you proof of necessary work today. We use proof of work in a prototype. This is joint work with my collaborators.
Problems We wanted to tackle the problem of bitcoin blockchain size increases. Every 10 minutes, a block is added to the blockchain and the blockchain grows linearly in size over time. Initial block download increases over time.
Proof of necessary work We use proof-of-work to verify transactions.</description></item><item><title>Proof of Necessary Work: Succinct State Verification with Fairness Guarantees</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/proof-of-necessary-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/proof-of-necessary-work/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230199429849743360
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230192993786720256
See also https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/190
Previous talk: https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/proof-of-necessary-work/
Introduction Let&amp;rsquo;s start with something familiar. When you have a new lite client, or any client that wants to trustlessly connect to the network and joins the network for the first time&amp;hellip; they see this: they need to download a lot of data, initially, and then on an ongoing basis. They need to do a lot of verification and computation on top of this data.</description></item><item><title>Scalable and Accountable Timestamping</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/timestamping/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/timestamping/</guid><description>slides https://scalingbitcoin.org/milan2016/presentations/D1%20-%20A%20-%20Riccardo.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784773221610586112
Hi everybody. I attended Montreal and Hong Kong. It&amp;rsquo;s a pleasurable to be here in Milan giving a talk about scaling bitcoin. I am going to be talking about scalable and accountable timestamping. Why timestamping at this conference? Then I will talk about aggregating timestamps. Also there needs to be a timestamping proof format. I will describe two of the formats for this purpose, including opentimestamps and chainpoint.</description></item><item><title>Scalable RSA Modulus Generation with Dishonest Majority</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/scalable-rsa-modulus-generation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/scalable-rsa-modulus-generation/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230545603605585920
Introduction Groups of unknown order are interesting cryptographic primitives. You can commit to integers. If you commit to a very large integer, you have to do a lot of work to do the commitment so you have a sequentiality assumption useful for VDFs. But then you have this compression property where if you take a large integer with a lot of information in it, you can compress it down to something small.</description></item><item><title>SNARKs And Their Practical Applications</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/simons-institute/snarks-and-their-practical-applications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/simons-institute/snarks-and-their-practical-applications/</guid><description>Thank you very much. I would like to thank the organizers for giving this opportunity to learn so much from my peers and colleagues some of which are here. This is a wonderful survey of many of the works in this area. As I was sitting here, I was in real-time adjusting my slides to minimize the overlap. I will cut down on the amount of introduction because what we just saw (Mike Walfish) was wonderful.</description></item><item><title>STARK For Developers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/stark-for-developers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/stark-for-developers/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230279740570783744
Introduction It always seems like there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of different proof systems, but it turns out they really work well together and there&amp;rsquo;s great abstractions that are happening where we can take different tools and plug them together. We will see some of those in this session. I think STARKs were first announced 3 years ago back when this conference was BPASE, and now they are ready to use for developers and they are deployed in the wild and it&amp;rsquo;s exciting to see how far we&amp;rsquo;ve come in the past few years.</description></item><item><title>The STARK truth about DEXes</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/stark-dex/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/stark-dex/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1090731793395798016
Welcome to the first session after lunch. We call this the post-lunch session. The first part is on STARKs by Eli Ben-Sasson.
Introduction Thank you very much. Today I will be talking about STARK proofs of DEXes. I am chief scientist at Starkware. We&amp;rsquo;re a one-year startup in Israel that has raised $40m and we have a grant from the Ethereum Foundation. We have 20 team members. Most of them are engineers.</description></item><item><title>Tight Proofs of Space and Replication</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/proofs-of-space-and-replication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/proofs-of-space-and-replication/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1091064672831234048
paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/702.pdf
Introduction This talk is about proofs of space and tight proofs of space.
Proof of Space A proof-of-space is an alternative to proof-of-work. Applications have been proposed like spam prevention, DoS attack prevention, sybil resistance in consensus networks which is most relevant to this conference. In proof-of-space, it&amp;rsquo;s an interactive protocol between a miner and a prover who has some disk storage and claims that hey I am storing 1 gigabyte of data.</description></item><item><title>Transparent SNARKs from DARK compilers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/transparent-snarks-from-dark-compilers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/transparent-snarks-from-dark-compilers/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230561492254089224
paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2019/1229.pdf
Introduction Our next speaker is Ben Fisch, part of the Stanford Applied Crypto team and he has done a lot of work that is relevant to the blockchain space. Proofs of replication, proofs of space, he is also one of the coauthors of a paper that defined the notion of verifiable delay functions. He has also worked on accumulators, batching techniques, vector commitments, and one of his latest works is exciting which is DARKs which he is going to talk about today.</description></item><item><title>Zero Knowledge Proofs For Bitcoin Scalability And Beyond</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/zero-knowledge-proofs-for-bitcoin-scalability-and-beyond/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/zero-knowledge-proofs-for-bitcoin-scalability-and-beyond/</guid><description>I am going to tell you about zero-knowledge proofs for Bitcoin scalability. Even though this is an overview talk, many of the results I will be telling you about are based on work done by people in the slides and also here at the conference.
First I will give a brief introduction to zero knowledge proofs. Then I will try to convince you that if you care about Bitcoin scalability, then you should care about zero-knowledge proofs and you should keep them on your radar.</description></item><item><title>ZkSHARKS</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/zksharks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/zksharks/</guid><description>Introduction Indeed I am Madars Virza. I am going to talk about SHARKs. I am going to be talking about zero-knowledge SHARKs. It&amp;rsquo;s actually something serious and it&amp;rsquo;s related to non-interactive zero-knowledge proofs.
Non-interactive zero knowledge proofs zkproofs are protocols between two parties, a prover and a verifier. Both prover and verifier know a public input, but only the prover knows a secret input as a witness. The prover wants to convince the verifier that some relationship holds between the public input and the secret witness.</description></item></channel></rss>