<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Onchain Privacy on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/</link><description>Recent content in Onchain Privacy on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Monero and the Privacy Doom Principle</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/monero-and-the-privacy-doom-principle/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/monero-and-the-privacy-doom-principle/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a blockchain researcher and developer. I&amp;rsquo;ve built the Sia blockchain ecosystem and I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the space for a while and today I&amp;rsquo;m talking about Monero and privacy models that ended up being explained in analytical techniques that we can use to beat error in privacy.
The Concept of Privacy in Cryptocurrencies So my name is David Vork. I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the blockchain space for about a decade. I&amp;rsquo;ve been between researching and launching blockchains, doing a lot of engineering, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the space for a while and studying things.</description></item><item><title>Teach the Controversy: mempoolfullrbf</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/teach-the-controversy-mempoolfullrbf/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/teach-the-controversy-mempoolfullrbf/</guid><description>What is transaction replacement? (00:00)
So, let&amp;rsquo;s go start off. What is transaction replacement? And maybe not the best screen, but this is a screenshot of the Bitcoin wallet, Blue Wallet, and it shows off transaction replacement very nicely. I have a transaction, I got rid of $25 worth of Bitcoin, and I can do two things, I can go bump the fee or cancel the transaction, and if any of you guys played around with it, it does what it expects, it increases the fee or it cancels it.</description></item><item><title>Vortex: ZeroLink for Lightning Opens</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/vortex-zerolink-for-lightning-opens/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/vortex-zerolink-for-lightning-opens/</guid><description>(The start of the talk is missing from the source media)
What is a blind signature All these people could come, and they all can then present their signatures. And Bob will know, &amp;ldquo;okay, all of these signatures are correct, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know who gave me which one. You&amp;rsquo;ll see how we use this in the protocol to get some privacy. This is kind of the structure (referring to slide#2).</description></item><item><title>Coinjoin Done Right: the onchain offchain mix (and anti-Sybil with RIDDLE)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/coinjoin-done-right-the-onchain-offchain-mix-and-anti-sybil-with-riddles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/coinjoin-done-right-the-onchain-offchain-mix-and-anti-sybil-with-riddles/</guid><description>NOTE: Slides of the talk can be found here
Introduction My name&amp;rsquo;s Adam Gibson, also known as waxwing on the internet. Though the title might suggest that I have the solution to the problem of implementing CoinJoin, it&amp;rsquo;s not exactly true. It&amp;rsquo;s a clickbait. I haven&amp;rsquo;t, but I suppose what I can say in a more serious way is that I&amp;rsquo;m proposing what I consider to be a meaningfully different alternative way of looking at the concept of CoinJoin and therefore at the concept of on-chain privacy because the conversation nowadays about on-chain privacy tends to be dominated by CoinJoin.</description></item></channel></rss>