<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>op_checktemplateverify on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/op_checktemplateverify/</link><description>Recent content in op_checktemplateverify on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/op_checktemplateverify/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Covenants</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/learning-bitcoin-and-design/covenants/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/learning-bitcoin-and-design/covenants/</guid><description>Introductions Christoph Ono: 00:00:01
Welcome to our first Learning Bitcoin and Design call of 2024. We haven&amp;rsquo;t had one of these in a while, but we&amp;rsquo;re picking them back up again. The first topic is a really tough one, I think at least, it&amp;rsquo;s covenants. The reason, one of the reasons why this came up is because on Bitcoin Design, we have this new design challenge. We have a page with design challenges that are meant to be kind of take home challenges.</description></item><item><title>Sapio: Stateful Smart Contracts for Bitcoin with OP_CTV</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/vr-bitcoin/2020-07-11-jeremy-rubin-sapio-101/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/vr-bitcoin/2020-07-11-jeremy-rubin-sapio-101/</guid><description>Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1X4AGNXJ5yCeHRrf5sa9DarWfDyEkm6fFUlrcIRQtUw4/
utxos.org website: https://utxos.org/
Intro (Udi Wertheimer) Today we are joined by Jeremy Rubin who is a Bitcoin Core contributor and the co-founder of the MIT Bitcoin Project. He is involved in a tonne of other cool stuff. He is also championing BIP 119 which is OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY. He is going to tell us about that and how it allows for new types of smart contracts.
Intro Hey. Thanks for coming on your Saturday morning, I appreciate everyone making it out.</description></item><item><title>CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY (CTV)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-podcast/2020-02-11-jeremy-rubin-ctv/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-podcast/2020-02-11-jeremy-rubin-ctv/</guid><description>CTV BIP review workshop transcript: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/ctv-bip-review-workshop/
Intro Jonas: Welcome to the podcast Jeremy.
Jeremy: Thanks for having me on.
Jonas: I think to start us off tell us a bit about your background, how you got into Bitcoin and we&amp;rsquo;ll take it from there.
Jeremy: I first heard about Bitcoin in 2011. I was interning at MIT during high school and I was doing what interns do which is read Hacker News.</description></item><item><title>BIP: OP_SECURETHEBAG</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/bip-securethebag/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/bip-securethebag/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171750965478854656
Introduction Thank you for the introduction. Today I am going to talk to you about OP_SECURETHEBAG. It&amp;rsquo;s research that I have been working on for the last couple years. I think it&amp;rsquo;s very exciting and hopefully it will have a big compact. I have a lot of slides.
Why are we here? We are here for scaling bitcoin. The goal we have is to scale bitcoin. What is scaling, though?</description></item><item><title>General discussion on SIGHASH_NOINPUT, OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACK, and OP_SECURETHEBAG</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06/2019-06-06-noinput-etc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06/2019-06-06-noinput-etc/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1136636856093876225
There&amp;rsquo;s apparently some political messaging around OP_SECURETHEBAG and &amp;ldquo;secure the bag&amp;rdquo; might be an Andrew Yang thing.
SIGHASH_NOINPUT A bunch of us are familiar with NOINPUT. Does anyone need an explainer? What&amp;rsquo;s the difference from the original NOINPUT and the new one? NOINPUT is kind of scary to at least some people. If we just do NOINPUT, does that start causing problems in bitcoin? Does it mean exchanges need to start looking at history of transactions and blacklist NOINPUT in the recent history until it&amp;rsquo;s deeply buried?</description></item></channel></rss>