<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cryptography on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/cryptography/</link><description>Recent content in cryptography on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/cryptography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Consensus Protocol Risks And Vulnerabilities</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/consensus-protocol-risks-and-vulnerabilities/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/consensus-protocol-risks-and-vulnerabilities/</guid><description>Consensus protocol risks and vulnerabilities
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229906447808360450
Introduction I am going to talk about why cryptocurrencies matter. I am going to take the skeptics side. I am going to start from a banker&amp;rsquo;s standpoint why a lot of the things that cryptocurrency people land say don&amp;rsquo;t make any sense.
Where are the engineers coming from? An engineer will look at something like Visa and say this is horrible. These are systems from 50-100 years ago.</description></item><item><title>Security Models</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-17-john-newbery-security-models/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-17-john-newbery-security-models/</guid><description>Topic: Security Models
Location: Chaincode Labs 2019 Residency
Slides: https://residency.chaincode.com/presentations/bitcoin/security_models.pdf
John Newbery: Alright, Security Models. This is going to be like a quick whistle-stop tour of various things, very high-level view. I&amp;rsquo;m going to start by giving you some kind of framework to think about things. So in cryptography, we often talk about security proofs in terms of existing schemes, we talk about assumptions.
So, for example&amp;hellip; If you can break new scheme B, then you&amp;rsquo;ll also be able to break old scheme A.</description></item><item><title>P2P Encryption</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/p2p-encryption/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/p2p-encryption/</guid><description>bip324: v2 message transport protocol
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137312478373851136
slides: https://twitter.com/_jonasschnelli_/status/1137389541512351749
Previous talks https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/bip151-peer-encryption/
https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-09-04-jonas-schenlli-bip150-bip151/
https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06-07-p2p-encryption/
Introduction This will be a technical talk. I hope you&amp;rsquo;re prepared for some cryptography. By the way, this now has a bip number as of this morning. This is bip324. I call it v2 message transport protocol. It&amp;rsquo;s not a consensus change, it&amp;rsquo;s purely a p2p network layer change. It&amp;rsquo;s not all about encryption, but mainly about encryption.</description></item><item><title>Crypto In Cryptocurrency</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/crypto-in-cryptocurrency/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/crypto-in-cryptocurrency/</guid><description>The &amp;ldquo;crypto&amp;rdquo; in cryptocurrency: Why everything is weird and hard
I do not have any slides for you. This is my attempt to keep this non-technical, by depriving myself of any ability to write equations on screen. The topic of my talk is why everything is weird and hard in cryptocurrency. What is cryptography as a mathematics and field of science? And how does this work in practice?
Encryption Historically the purvue of cryptography is encryption, like trying to come up with something random looking.</description></item><item><title>Single Use Seals</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/single-use-seals/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/single-use-seals/</guid><description>Single use seals
Building on Bitcoin 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014168068447195136
I am going to talk about single use seals and ways to use them. They are a concept of building consensus applications and things that need consensus. I want to mention why that matters. What problem are we trying to solve? Imagine my cell phone and I open up my banking app or the banking app or lightning app&amp;hellip; I want to make sure that what I see on my screen is the same as what you see on your screen.</description></item><item><title>Bulletproofs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2018-02-02-andrew-poelstra-bulletproofs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2018-02-02-andrew-poelstra-bulletproofs/</guid><description>49th Milan Bitcoin meetup
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/962326126969442304
https://www.reddit.com/r/Bitcoin/comments/7w72pq/bulletproofs_presentation_at_feb_2_milan_meetup/
Introduction Alright. Thank you for that introduction, Giacamo. I am here to talk about bulletproofs. This is different from proof-of-bullets, which is what fiat currencies use. In bulletproofs, we use a zero-knowledge proof which has nothing to do with consensus at all, but it has a lot of exciting applications. The original motivation to create bulletproofs was for range proofs which are used in confidential transactions.</description></item><item><title>Solar Powered Space Pirates</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/solar-powered-space-pirates/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/solar-powered-space-pirates/</guid><description>Solar powered space pirates: A threat to bitcoin?
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005633917356007425
Let&amp;rsquo;s see. How do I make this fullscreen? Alright, anyone who can actually read French know how to make this fullscreen? My french teachers in high school would be very disappointed in me.
My name is Peter Todd. I do cryptography consulting. I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved in Bitcoin Core as well. I want to tell you about whether solar powered space pirates are a threat to bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Schnorr Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/schnorr-signatures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/schnorr-signatures/</guid><description>Topic: Schnorr signatures for Bitcoin
Location: Scaling Bitcoin (Milan)
Slides: URL expired
Pieter Wuille presentation on Schnorr at BPASE 2018: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/schnorr-signatures-for-bitcoin-challenges-opportunities/
Transcript completed by: Bryan Bishop Edited by: Michael Folkson
Intro Today I will be talking about Schnorr signatures for Bitcoin. I want to say a few things in advance. One is even though this is a talk about cryptography and in particular new cryptography I don&amp;rsquo;t consider myself to be a cryptographer.</description></item><item><title>History Of Lattice Based Cryptography</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/simons-institute/history-of-lattice-based-cryptography/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/simons-institute/history-of-lattice-based-cryptography/</guid><description>Historical talk on lattice-based cryptography
Daniele Micciancio, UC San Diego
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4KVJbEOqB_Q&amp;amp;list=PLgO7JBj821uGZTXEXBLckChu70kl7Celh&amp;amp;index=22
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/772649346454040577
Lattice cryptography - from computational complexity to fully homomorphic encryption
Introduction 1 So this first of all thanks for coming back from lunch, it&amp;rsquo;s always an achievement. I want to say that this is a special talk within the workshop here at Simons we have a historical cryptopapers seminars series. We try to revisit historical papers and see what led to them and how they impacted things later.</description></item><item><title>Aurora Transparent Succinct Arguments R1Cs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/aurora-transparent-succinct-arguments-r1cs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/aurora-transparent-succinct-arguments-r1cs/</guid><description>Aurora: Transparent succinct arguments for R1CS
Alessandro Chiesa
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1090741190100545536
Introduction Hi. I am Alessandro Chiesa, a faculty member at UC Berkeley. I work on cryptography. I&amp;rsquo;m also a chief scientist at Starkware. I was a founder of zcash. Today I will like to tell you about recent work in cryptographic proof systems. This is joint work with people at Starkware, UC Berkeley, MIT Media Lab, and others. In the prior talk, we talked about scalability.</description></item><item><title>Dan Boneh</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/dan-boneh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/dan-boneh/</guid><description>Dan Boneh fireside chat
Taariq Lewis
TL: I was one of the founders of SF Bitcoin Devs with aantonop. I am also the co-founder of a company called Promise. We sponsor protocols in privacy as well as mimblewimble. If you are mining or actively looking to mine in grin, please say hello to me because we&amp;rsquo;re connected with a lot of mining companies and hosting companies that are looking to host miners very cheaply.</description></item><item><title>Extracting Seeds From Hardware Wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/extracting-seeds-from-hardware-wallets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/extracting-seeds-from-hardware-wallets/</guid><description>7DC5A359D0D5B5AB6728&amp;hellip;
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137672946435198976
Introduction My talk is about extracting seeds from hardware wallets. I am chief security officer at Ledger. I joined Ledger a bit more than one year ago. I built the Ledger Donjon which is an independent red team. Our mission is to help secure Ledger&amp;rsquo;s products. So what we do day to do is try to break all the hardware wallets. We continuously challenge the security of our products.</description></item><item><title>Failures Of Secret Key Cryptography (2013)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/failures-of-secret-key-cryptography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/failures-of-secret-key-cryptography/</guid><description>FSE 2013
Welcome to the second invited talk, to be given by Dan Bernstein. Dan is one of the few members of our community who does not need an introduction. It&amp;rsquo;s a great honor and pleasure that he has agreed to give a talk here. Dan comes from UC Berkeley and from Chicago. Just a few things you might know Dan from&amp;ndash; he sued the U.S. government about export controls. In 2004, .</description></item><item><title>Matsuo</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/matsuo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/matsuo/</guid><description>bsafe.network
Giving trust by security evaluation and bsafe.network
This is a severe problem. How can we trust the output of blockchain technology? We have several security issues. There was the huge DAO attack from two weeks ago. We also have other problems, such as protocol specification, key management, implementation, operation, and vulnerability handling. Also key renewal and key revocation issues.
ISO/IEC 27000 ISO/IEC 15408 ISO/IEC 29128 ISO/IEC 29128 ISO/IEC, NIST IETF We already have several international standards on each layer.</description></item><item><title>Mimblewimble Podcast</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/mimblewimble-podcast/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/mimblewimble-podcast/</guid><description>https://soundcloud.com/heryptohow/mimblewimble-andrew-poelstra-peter-wuille-brian-deery-and-chris-odom
Andrew Poelstra (andytoshi) Pieter Wuille (sipa) Brian Deery Chris Odom Starts at 26min.
I am going to introduce our guests here in just a minute.
Launch of zcash might be delayed in order to allow the code to be analyzed by multiple third-party auditors. Zooko stated, &amp;ldquo;I feel bad that we didn&amp;rsquo;t do a better job of making TheDAO disaster-like problems harder for people&amp;rdquo;.
Our guests on the line are Andrew Poelstra and Pieter Wuille.</description></item><item><title>Safecurves - Choosing Safe Curves For Elliptic Curve Cryptography (2014)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/safecurves-choosing-safe-curves-for-elliptic-curve-cryptography-2014/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/safecurves-choosing-safe-curves-for-elliptic-curve-cryptography-2014/</guid><description>Daniel J. Bernstein (djb) and Tanja Lange
SchmooCon 2014
video 2 (same?): https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=maBOorEfOOk&amp;amp;list=PLgO7JBj821uGZTXEXBLckChu70kl7Celh&amp;amp;index=91
Video intro text There are several different standards covering selection of curves for use in elliptic-curve cryptography (ECC). Each of these standards tries to ensure that the elliptic-curve discrete-logarithm problem (ECDLP) is difficult. ECDLP is the problem of finding an ECC user&amp;rsquo;s secret key, given the user&amp;rsquo;s public key.
Unfortunately, there is a gap between ECDLP difficulty and ECC security.</description></item><item><title>Scalable Rsa Modulus Generation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/scalable-rsa-modulus-generation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/scalable-rsa-modulus-generation/</guid><description>Scalable RSA Modulus Generation with Dishonest Majority
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230545603605585920
Introduction Groups of unknown order are interesting cryptographic primitives. You can commit to integers. If you commit to a very large integer, you have to do a lot of work to do the commitment so you have a sequentiality assumption useful for VDFs. But then you have this compression property where if you take a large integer with a lot of information in it, you can compress it down to something small.</description></item><item><title>Scriptless Lotteries</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/scriptless-lotteries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/scriptless-lotteries/</guid><description>Scriptless lotteries on bitcoin from oblivious transfer
Lloyd Fournier (lloyd.fourn@gmail.com)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171717583629934593
Introduction I have no affiliations. I&amp;rsquo;m just some guy. You&amp;rsquo;re trusting a guy to talk about cryptography who got the date wrong. We&amp;rsquo;re doing scriptless bitcoin lotteries from oblivious transfer.
Lotteries Imagine a trusted party who conducts lotteries between Alice and Bob. The goal of the lottery protocol is to use a cryptographic protocol without having a lottery trusted party.</description></item><item><title>Security Assumptions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/security-assumptions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/security-assumptions/</guid><description>Hi, welcome back.
I am a developer for libsecp256k1. It&amp;rsquo;s a library that does the underlying traditional cryptography used in Bitcoin. I am going to talk about security assumptions, security models and trust models. I am going to give a high-level overview of how we should be thinking about these issues for scaling and efficiency and decentralization. Bitcoin is a crypto system. Everything about it is a crypto system. It needs to be designed with an adversarial mindset, even in an adversarial setting.</description></item><item><title>State Of Cryptography</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/state-of-cryptography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/state-of-cryptography/</guid><description>State of cryptography for blockchains beyond ECDSA and sha256
Signatures and zero-knowledge proofs
Benedikt Bunz, Stanford University
Am going to talk about cryptography relevant to blockchains. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about signatures and zero-knowledge proofs. It has a lot of applications to bitcoin. It turns out that bitcoin is pretty simple in terms of cryptography. It just uses a hash function (sha256) and,s eparately, ECDSA for signatures. I will be mentioning some other cryptography that bitcoin could use.</description></item><item><title>Todo</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/simons-institute/todo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/simons-institute/todo/</guid><description> cryptography bootcamp https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLgKuh-lKre139cwM0pjuxMa_YVzMeCiTf mathematics of modern cryptography https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLgKuh-lKre10kb0so1PQ3eNz4Q6EBfecT historical papers in cryptography https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLgKuh-lKre13lX4C_5ZCQKMDOniAn24NP securing computation https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLgKuh-lKre12ddBkIB8wNC8D1kag5dEr-</description></item></channel></rss>