<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cryptography on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/cryptography/</link><description>Recent content in cryptography on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/cryptography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Provably bug-free BIPs and implementations using hac-spec</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-14-hac-spec/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-14-hac-spec/</guid><description>https://nickler.ninja/
Alright. Strong crowd here, I can see. That&amp;rsquo;s very nice.
Introduction I am Jonas and I will talk about provably bug-free BIPs and implementations. I don&amp;rsquo;t have such a BIP nor such an implementation but if you lower your time-preference enough this could eventually be true at some point. This presentation is only 15 minutes so raise your hand if you have questions.
Just to set the stage. Specifications should be free of bugs, we want them easy to implement and hard to misinterpret.</description></item><item><title>High-assurance cryptography specifications (hac-spec)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2022-10/2022-10-11-hac-spec/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2022-10/2022-10-11-hac-spec/</guid><description>See https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-14-hac-spec/ instead for a full transcript of a similar talk.
Far far future In the far far future, we could get rid of this weird paper notation scheme and do a security proof directly for the specification. Presumably that is much harder than anything else in my slides. But this would rule out a lot of bugs.
Q: But the security proof itself is written in a paper?
A: The security proof itself would be written in hac-spec.</description></item><item><title>Consensus Protocol Risks And Vulnerabilities</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/consensus-protocol-risks-and-vulnerabilities/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/consensus-protocol-risks-and-vulnerabilities/</guid><description>Consensus protocol risks and vulnerabilities
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229906447808360450
Introduction I am going to talk about why cryptocurrencies matter. I am going to take the skeptics side. I am going to start from a banker&amp;rsquo;s standpoint why a lot of the things that cryptocurrency people land say don&amp;rsquo;t make any sense.
Where are the engineers coming from? An engineer will look at something like Visa and say this is horrible. These are systems from 50-100 years ago.</description></item><item><title>The 'Crypto' In Cryptocurrency: Why Everything is Weird and Hard</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/crypto-in-cryptocurrency/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/crypto-in-cryptocurrency/</guid><description>I do not have any slides for you. This is my attempt to keep this non-technical, by depriving myself of any ability to write equations on screen. The topic of my talk is why everything is weird and hard in cryptocurrency. What is cryptography as a mathematics and field of science? And how does this work in practice?
Encryption Historically the purvue of cryptography is encryption, like trying to come up with something random looking.</description></item><item><title>Verifiable Delay Functions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/verifiable-delay-functions/vdf-day-2019/dan-boneh/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/verifiable-delay-functions/vdf-day-2019/dan-boneh/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1152586087912673280
Introduction I&amp;rsquo;ll give an overview of VDFs and make sure that we&amp;rsquo;re on the same page. I want to make sure everyone knows what it is that we&amp;rsquo;re talking about.
The goal of a VDF is to slow things down. The question is, how do we slow things down in a verifiable way?
What is a VDF? I won&amp;rsquo;t give a precise definition, look at the manuscripts. A VDF is basically a function that is supposed to take T steps to evaluate, even if the honest party has polynomial parallelism.</description></item><item><title>Handel: Practical Multi-Signature Aggregation for Large Byzantine Committees</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/handel-practical-multisig-aggregation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/handel-practical-multisig-aggregation/</guid><description>Introduction Handle is a aggregation protocol for large scale byzantine committees. This is work with my colleagues in addition to myself.
Why aggregate? Distributed systems often require gathering statements about large subsets of nodes. However, processing (filtering, aggregating&amp;hellip;) measurements can be a bottleneck. We want to apply some processing while collecting the measurements.
Why byzantine? A byzantine node is a node that can be arbitrary. It can be offline and it can be anything it wants and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to respect the protocol specification.</description></item><item><title>Fireside chat with Dan Boneh</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/dan-boneh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/dan-boneh/</guid><description>TL: I was one of the founders of SF Bitcoin Devs with aantonop. I am also the co-founder of a company called Promise. We sponsor protocols in privacy as well as mimblewimble. If you are mining or actively looking to mine in grin, please say hello to me because we&amp;rsquo;re connected with a lot of mining companies and hosting companies that are looking to host miners very cheaply. I&amp;rsquo;d love to help.</description></item><item><title>Blind Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/blind-signatures/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/blind-signatures/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1047648050234060800
See also http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/building-on-bitcoin/2018/blind-signatures-and-scriptless-scripts/
Introduction Hi everyone. I work at Commonwealth Crypto. Today I am going to be talking to you about blind signatures. I&amp;rsquo;d like to encourage people to ask questions. Please think of questions. I&amp;rsquo;ll give time and pause for people to ask questions.
What are blind signatures? A very informal definition of blind signatures is that they are a signature scheme that allows one party to sign a message without learning the message they signed.</description></item><item><title>Bulletproofs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/bulletproofs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/bulletproofs/</guid><description>Overview of Bullet Proofs - a new zero-knowledge cryptographical solution for confidential transactions</description></item><item><title>Finite fields, Elliptic curves, ECDSA, Schnorr</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/digital-signatures/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/digital-signatures/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1047634593619181568
Introduction Thank you to Anton and to everyone at Keio University and Digital Garage. I have an hour to talk about digital signatures, finite fields, ECDSA, Schnorr signatures, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of ground to cover. I&amp;rsquo;m going to move quickly and start from a high level.
My name is John. I live in New York. I work at a company called Chaincode Labs. Most of the time, I contribute to Bitcoin Core.</description></item><item><title>Smart Signatures: Experiments in Authorization</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/2018-01-24-christopher-allen-smart-signatures/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/2018-01-24-christopher-allen-smart-signatures/</guid><description>Slides: https://www.slideshare.net/ChristopherA/smart-signaturesexperiments-in-authentication-stanford-bpase-2018-final
Intro Good afternoon. My name is Christopher Allen, I am with Blockstream and today I wanted to give you an introduction to something that isn’t about consensus, isn’t about proof of stake and other things. I want to pop up a level. I want to talk about smart signatures. These are a number of experiments in authorization.
Digital Signatures First we need to recap, what is a digital signature?</description></item><item><title>Solar Powered Space Pirates</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/solar-powered-space-pirates/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/solar-powered-space-pirates/</guid><description>Solar powered space pirates: A threat to bitcoin?
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005633917356007425
Let&amp;rsquo;s see. How do I make this fullscreen? Alright, anyone who can actually read French know how to make this fullscreen? My french teachers in high school would be very disappointed in me.
My name is Peter Todd. I do cryptography consulting. I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved in Bitcoin Core as well. I want to tell you about whether solar powered space pirates are a threat to bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Merkle Set Data Structures for Scaling Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-07-08-bram-cohen-merkle-sets/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-07-08-bram-cohen-merkle-sets/</guid><description>code: https://github.com/bramcohen/MerkleSet
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/888836850529558531
Introduction There&amp;rsquo;s been a fair amount of talk about putting UTXO commitments in bitcoin blocks. Whether this is a good idea or not, but on the off-chance that it might be a good idea, I spent a fair amount of time thinking and actually good merkle set implementation whic his what you you need to put utxo set commitments in bitcoin blocks. There are other benefits to this, in that there are actually a million and one uses for merkle sets in general, and it&amp;rsquo;s actually a general interesting problem and it performs well.</description></item><item><title>Post’s Theorem and Blockchain Languages: A Short Course in the Theory of Computation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/2017-01-26-russell-oconnor-posts-theorem/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/2017-01-26-russell-oconnor-posts-theorem/</guid><description>Intro Hi. My name is Russell O’Connor. I am here to talk to you about Post’s theorem, the theory of computation and its applications to blockchain languages. There is a bit of a debate about whether Turing complete languages are appropriate or not for doing computations, whether the DAO fiasco is related to the Turing completeness problem or is it an unrelated issue? If we do go for non-Turing complete languages for our blockchains how much expressiveness are we losing?</description></item><item><title>Key Tree Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2015-08-24-pieter-wuille-key-tree-signatures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2015-08-24-pieter-wuille-key-tree-signatures/</guid><description>Slides: https://prezi.com/vsj95ns4ucu3/key-tree-signatures/
Blog post: https://blockstream.com/2015/08/24/en-treesignatures/
Intro For those who don’t know me I’m Pieter Wuille. I have been working on Bitcoin Core for a while but this is work I have been doing at Blockstream. Today I will be talking about Key Tree Signatures which is what I have been working on these past few weeks. It is an improvement to the multisig schemes that we want to support. This is an outline of my talk.</description></item><item><title>History Of Lattice Based Cryptography</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/simons-institute/history-of-lattice-based-cryptography/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/simons-institute/history-of-lattice-based-cryptography/</guid><description>Historical talk on lattice-based cryptography
Daniele Micciancio, UC San Diego
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4KVJbEOqB_Q&amp;amp;list=PLgO7JBj821uGZTXEXBLckChu70kl7Celh&amp;amp;index=22
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/772649346454040577
Lattice cryptography - from computational complexity to fully homomorphic encryption
Introduction 1 So this first of all thanks for coming back from lunch, it&amp;rsquo;s always an achievement. I want to say that this is a special talk within the workshop here at Simons we have a historical cryptopapers seminars series. We try to revisit historical papers and see what led to them and how they impacted things later.</description></item><item><title>Cryptographic Hocus-Pocus Meaning Nothing: The Zcash Trusted Setup MPC</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/cryptographic-hocus-pocus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/cryptographic-hocus-pocus/</guid><description>or: &amp;ldquo;Peter Todd&amp;rsquo;s secret love letter to Zooko&amp;rdquo;
Background See http://web.archive.org/web/20170717025249/https://petertodd.org/2016/cypherpunk-desert-bus-zcash-trusted-setup-ceremony
and later it was then redacted: https://petertodd.org/2016/cypherpunk-desert-bus-zcash-trusted-setup-ceremony
Introduction Alright. Hopefully you guys are all awake ish or something. I am going to give a talk about the zcash trusted setup. As many of you know, I was involved in it. The way to start is to answer, what is it?
What is the zcash trusted setup? It&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of toxic waste, basically.</description></item><item><title>Enhancing Bitcoin Security and Performance with Strong Consistency via Collective Signing</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/collective-signing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/collective-signing/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785102844839985153
We are starting the session called &amp;ldquo;breaking the chain&amp;rdquo;. We will first have collective signing presentation. Thank you.
This is joint work with some collaborators.
What we have now is that real-time verification is not safe. What we managed to get is that we get transaction commitment in about 20-90 seconds at close to 1,000 transactions/second. In byzcoin, irrevocable transaction commitment in 20-90 second. Throughput up to 974 transactions per second.</description></item><item><title>Failures Of Secret Key Cryptography (2013)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/failures-of-secret-key-cryptography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/failures-of-secret-key-cryptography/</guid><description>FSE 2013
Welcome to the second invited talk, to be given by Dan Bernstein. Dan is one of the few members of our community who does not need an introduction. It&amp;rsquo;s a great honor and pleasure that he has agreed to give a talk here. Dan comes from UC Berkeley and from Chicago. Just a few things you might know Dan from&amp;ndash; he sued the U.S. government about export controls. In 2004, .</description></item><item><title>Fractal: Post-Quantum and Transparent Recursive Proofs from Holography</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/fractal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/fractal/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230295372909514752
https://eprint.iacr.org/2019/1076.pdf
Introduction One of the most powerful things that you can do with SNARKs is something called recursive proofs where you actually prove that another SNARK was correct. I can give you a proof of a proof of a proof and this is amazing because you can prove an ever-expanding computation like a blockchain is always correct. I can always give you a proof that you have the latest block and you know the entire blockchain and all the transactions in it are correct.</description></item><item><title>Hardware Accelerated RSA - VDFs, SNARKs, and Accumulators</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/hardware-accelerated-rsa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/hardware-accelerated-rsa/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230551345700069377
Introduction I am going to talk about accelerating RSA operations in hardware. So let&amp;rsquo;s just get into it.
Outline I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about what acceleration is and why we&amp;rsquo;re interested in it, then we&amp;rsquo;ll get into RSA primitives, then we&amp;rsquo;ll get into algorithms, and then various platforms for hardware. Hardware is anything you&amp;rsquo;re going to run software on. We&amp;rsquo;ll look at what the tradeoffs are, and then some performance numbers and measurements we&amp;rsquo;ve taken.</description></item><item><title>Matsuo</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/matsuo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/matsuo/</guid><description>bsafe.network
Giving trust by security evaluation and bsafe.network
This is a severe problem. How can we trust the output of blockchain technology? We have several security issues. There was the huge DAO attack from two weeks ago. We also have other problems, such as protocol specification, key management, implementation, operation, and vulnerability handling. Also key renewal and key revocation issues.
ISO/IEC 27000 ISO/IEC 15408 ISO/IEC 29128 ISO/IEC 29128 ISO/IEC, NIST IETF We already have several international standards on each layer.</description></item><item><title>Safecurves - Choosing Safe Curves For Elliptic Curve Cryptography (2014)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/safecurves-choosing-safe-curves-for-elliptic-curve-cryptography-2014/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/safecurves-choosing-safe-curves-for-elliptic-curve-cryptography-2014/</guid><description>Daniel J. Bernstein (djb) and Tanja Lange
SchmooCon 2014
video 2 (same?): https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=maBOorEfOOk&amp;amp;list=PLgO7JBj821uGZTXEXBLckChu70kl7Celh&amp;amp;index=91
Video intro text There are several different standards covering selection of curves for use in elliptic-curve cryptography (ECC). Each of these standards tries to ensure that the elliptic-curve discrete-logarithm problem (ECDLP) is difficult. ECDLP is the problem of finding an ECC user&amp;rsquo;s secret key, given the user&amp;rsquo;s public key.
Unfortunately, there is a gap between ECDLP difficulty and ECC security.</description></item><item><title>Scriptless Lotteries</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/scriptless-lotteries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/scriptless-lotteries/</guid><description>Scriptless lotteries on bitcoin from oblivious transfer
Lloyd Fournier (lloyd.fourn@gmail.com)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171717583629934593
Introduction I have no affiliations. I&amp;rsquo;m just some guy. You&amp;rsquo;re trusting a guy to talk about cryptography who got the date wrong. We&amp;rsquo;re doing scriptless bitcoin lotteries from oblivious transfer.
Lotteries Imagine a trusted party who conducts lotteries between Alice and Bob. The goal of the lottery protocol is to use a cryptographic protocol without having a lottery trusted party.</description></item><item><title>Security Assumptions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/security-assumptions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/security-assumptions/</guid><description>Hi, welcome back.
I am a developer for libsecp256k1. It&amp;rsquo;s a library that does the underlying traditional cryptography used in Bitcoin. I am going to talk about security assumptions, security models and trust models. I am going to give a high-level overview of how we should be thinking about these issues for scaling and efficiency and decentralization. Bitcoin is a crypto system. Everything about it is a crypto system. It needs to be designed with an adversarial mindset, even in an adversarial setting.</description></item><item><title>Siacoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/siacoin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/siacoin/</guid><description>I have been working on a decentralized cloud storage platform. Before I go into that, I wanted to mention that I have been working on Bitcoin since 2011. Since 2013 I have been in the wizards channel. In 2014 a friend and myself founded a company to build Siacoin. The team has grown to 3 people. Sia is the name of our decentralized storage protocol. We are trying to emulate Amazon S3.</description></item><item><title>Todo</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/simons-institute/todo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/simons-institute/todo/</guid><description> cryptography bootcamp https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLgKuh-lKre139cwM0pjuxMa_YVzMeCiTf mathematics of modern cryptography https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLgKuh-lKre10kb0so1PQ3eNz4Q6EBfecT historical papers in cryptography https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLgKuh-lKre13lX4C_5ZCQKMDOniAn24NP securing computation https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLgKuh-lKre12ddBkIB8wNC8D1kag5dEr-</description></item></channel></rss>