<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Grincon 2019 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/</link><description>Recent content in Grincon 2019 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cryptography Audit</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/cryptography-audit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/cryptography-audit/</guid><description>libsecp256k1-zkp audit
John Woeltz
It&amp;rsquo;s a real treat to be able to be a part of this.
Why bother? Just a high-level, why are we taking community resources to spend time on audits? There are some perspectives&amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s good for the community and it&amp;rsquo;s what you do.
Bitcoin had on professional security audits and did just fine. But it launched in a very different environment, and it did get audits eventually.</description></item><item><title>Dan Boneh</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/dan-boneh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/dan-boneh/</guid><description>Dan Boneh fireside chat
Taariq Lewis
TL: I was one of the founders of SF Bitcoin Devs with aantonop. I am also the co-founder of a company called Promise. We sponsor protocols in privacy as well as mimblewimble. If you are mining or actively looking to mine in grin, please say hello to me because we&amp;rsquo;re connected with a lot of mining companies and hosting companies that are looking to host miners very cheaply.</description></item><item><title>Lehnberg</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/lehnberg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/lehnberg/</guid><description>daniel/lehberg
Mimblewimble pros and cons There are no amounts, no addresses, and improved scaling. But one of hte problems is that it requires interactive transactions. But this is a pro because of this you have to participate in mining. You can send money to addresses without having to accept the money. Just as you saw here, you can identify the blue box as an output or an input. You could build up a transaction graph.</description></item><item><title>Scriptless Scripts With Mimblewimble</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/scriptless-scripts-with-mimblewimble/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/scriptless-scripts-with-mimblewimble/</guid><description>Scriptless scripts with mimblewimble
Andrew Poelstra (andytoshi)
Introduction Hi everyone. I am Andrew Poelstra. I am the research director at Blockstream. I want to talk about deploying scriptless scripts, wihch is something I haven&amp;rsquo;t talked much about over the past year or two.
History Let me give a bit of history about mimblewimble. As many of you know, this was dead-dropped anonymously in the middle of 2016 by someone named Tom Elvis Jedusor which is the French name for Voldemort.</description></item></channel></rss>