<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Stanford Blockchain Conference 2020 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/</link><description>Recent content in Stanford Blockchain Conference 2020 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Welcome Remarks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/welcome-remarks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/welcome-remarks/</guid><description>Welcome remarks
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230178753805836288
https://cbr.stanford.edu/sbc20/
telegram: https://t.me/sbc20
wifi: Stanford, blockchain/blockchain
Okay, we&amp;rsquo;re going to get started in five minutes. We&amp;rsquo;re going to get started. We have a fully packed day. Everybody can grab their seats and then we can get started.
Alright. So let&amp;rsquo;s do this.
Okay, welcome to the fourth Stanford Blockchain Conference. It&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of fun running this conference for a couple of years now. There&amp;rsquo;s a few quick administrative things I wanted to say.</description></item><item><title>Attacking EVM Resource Metering</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/attacking-evm-resource-metering/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/attacking-evm-resource-metering/</guid><description>Broken Metre: Attacking resource metering in EVM
Daniel Perez, Benjamin Livshits
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230222221110468609
https://arxiv.org/abs/1909.07220
Abstract Metering is an approach developed to assign cost to smart contract execution in blockchain systems such as Ethereum. This paper presents a detailed investigation of the metering approach based on gas taken by the Ethereum blockchain. We discover a number of discrepancies in the metering model such as significant inconsistencies in the pricing of the instructions. We further demonstrate that there is very little correlation between the gas and resources such as CPU and memory.</description></item><item><title>Arbitrum V2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/arbitrum-v2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/arbitrum-v2/</guid><description>Arbitrum 2.0: Faster Off-Chain Contracts with On-Chain Security
Ed Felten, Off-chain Labs
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230191734375628802
Introduction Thank you, good morning everybody. I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about our latest version of our Abitrum system. The first version was discussed in a paper in 2018. Since then, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of advances in my technology and a real running system has been made. This is the first working roll-up system for general smart contracts.</description></item><item><title>Atomic Multi Channel Updates</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/atomic-multi-channel-updates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/atomic-multi-channel-updates/</guid><description>Atomic Multi-Channel Updates with Constant Collateral in Bitcoin-Compatible Payment-Channel Networks
Matteo Maffei
https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/atomic-multi-channel-updates/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230929981011660800
Introduction Matteo got sick and couldn&amp;rsquo;t come. His coauthors couldn&amp;rsquo;t come either. So a talk was pre-recorded and will be played now. Our work is about realizing atomic multi-channel updates with constant collateral in bitcoin.
Scalability issues We all know that blockchains have scalability issues. Public verifiability means we have to store each transaction on the blockchain.</description></item><item><title>Beyond Hashrate Majority Attacks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/beyond-hashrate-majority-attacks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/beyond-hashrate-majority-attacks/</guid><description>Beyond 51% attacks
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230624835996250112
Introduction Alright let&amp;rsquo;s get started with the next session. Vitalik is from Canada. He is a former writer for Bitcoin Magazine and can often be seen wearing unicorn shirts. He will be telling us about &amp;ldquo;Beyond 51% attacks&amp;rdquo;. Take it away.
Okay, so hello everyone. Hi. Okay. I will start by reminding everyone that 51% attacks are in fact bad. Bear with me for a few minutes.</description></item><item><title>Block Rewards</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/block-rewards/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/block-rewards/</guid><description>An Axiomatic Approach to Block Rewards
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230574963813257216
https://arxiv.org/pdf/1909.10645.pdf
Introduction Thank you, Bram. Can you hear me in the back? I want to talk about some work I have been doing with my colleagues. This is a paper about incentive issues in blockchain protocols. I am interested in thinking about whether protocols have been designed in a way that motivates users to behave in the way that the designer had hoped.</description></item><item><title>Blockchains For Multiplayer Games</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/blockchains-for-multiplayer-games/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/blockchains-for-multiplayer-games/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230256436527034368
Introduction Alright, thanks everyone for being here. Let&amp;rsquo;s get started. I am part of a project called Forte which wants to equip the game ecosystem with blockchain finance for their in-game economies. This is a unique set of constraints compared to what a lot of people are trying to build on blockchain today. We&amp;rsquo;re game experts. There&amp;rsquo;s definitely people more experts than us on the topics we&amp;rsquo;ll cover in this presentation, but what we want you to come away with is our best sense for the best path to get game economies running on blockchain.</description></item><item><title>Boomerang - Redundancy Improves Latency and Throughput in Payment-Channel Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/boomerang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/boomerang/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230936389300080640
Introduction Redundancy can be a useful tool for speeding up payment channel networks and improving throughput. We presented last week at Financial Crypto. You just received a nice introduction to payment channels and payment channel networks.
Payment channels Alice and Bob are connected through a payment channel. This is a channel and in that channel there are some coins that are escrowed. Some coins belong to Alice some belong to Bob and they want to transact them back and forth.</description></item><item><title>Brick Async State Channels</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/brick-async-state-channels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/brick-async-state-channels/</guid><description>Brick: Asynchronous State Channels
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230943445398614016
https://arxiv.org/abs/1905.11360
Introduction I am going to be presenting on Brick for asynchronous state channels. This is joint work with my colleagues and my advisor. So far we have heard many things about payment channels and payment channel networks. They were focused on existing channel solutions. In this work, we focus on a different dimensions. We ask why do payment channels work the way they do, can we change the core design of payment channels to address some of the shortcomings.</description></item><item><title>Celo Ultralight Client</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/celo-ultralight-client/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/celo-ultralight-client/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230261714039398402
Introduction Hello everyone. My name is Marek Olszewski. We are going to be talking about Plumo which is Celo&amp;rsquo;s ultralightweight client protocol. This is joint work with a number of collaborators.
Plumo Plumo sands for &amp;ldquo;feather&amp;rdquo; in esperanto. I hope most people here are familiar with this graph. Chain sizes are growing. This is a graph of the bitcoin chain size over time. It has continued to grow. We&amp;rsquo;re now at 256 megabytes.</description></item><item><title>Clockwork Nonfrontrunning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/clockwork-nonfrontrunning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/clockwork-nonfrontrunning/</guid><description>ClockWork: An exchange protocol for proofs of non-front-running
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1231012112517844993
Introduction Clockwork is an exchange protocol for proofs of non-frontrunning.
Exchange systems Exchange systems let you trade one asset for another asset at a certain price. It&amp;rsquo;s simple and it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be fair. In this work, we&amp;rsquo;re focused on centralized exchange systems. We&amp;rsquo;re not working with decentralized exchanges just yet. These don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily need to be cryptocurrency exchanges, either. Our work applies to both.</description></item><item><title>Competitive Equilibria Staking Lending</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/competitive-equilibria-staking-lending/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/competitive-equilibria-staking-lending/</guid><description>Competitive equilibria between staking and on-chain lending
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230581977289379840
https://arxiv.org/pdf/2001.00919v1.pdf
See also &amp;ldquo;Stress testing decentralized finance&amp;rdquo; https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/stress-testing-decentralized-finance/
Introduction There have been some odd finanical attacks in the DeFi space and also on staking. This talk aims to show that the threat model for staking is definitively different from that of proof-of-work, and these financial attacks need to be part of the threat model.
Agenda I&amp;rsquo;ll go over some high level overview of intuitive market dynamics, then we will build up an agent-based model that correctly goes across multiple participants to stress test staking situations, then we go through the various assumptions, and at a high-level I&amp;rsquo;ll give some formal probability statements without proofs, and finally I have simulation results to discuss which can give you some idea about how to design a monetary policy.</description></item><item><title>Decentralized Oracles Tls</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/decentralized-oracles-tls/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/decentralized-oracles-tls/</guid><description>DECO: Liberating Web Data Using Decentralized Oracles for TLS
Fan Zhang
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230657639740108806
Introduction I am Fan from Cornell. I am going to be talking about DECO, a privacy-preserving oracle for TLS. This is joint work with some other people.
Decentralized identity What is identity? To use any system, the first thing that the user needs to do is to prove her identity and that she is a user to the system.</description></item><item><title>Fractal - Post-Quantum and Transparent Recursive Proofs from Holography</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/fractal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/fractal/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230295372909514752
https://eprint.iacr.org/2019/1076.pdf
Introduction One of the most powerful things that you can do with SNARKs is something called recursive proofs where you actually prove that another SNARK was correct. I can give you a proof of a proof of a proof and this is amazing because you can prove an ever-expanding computation like a blockchain is always correct. I can always give you a proof that you have the latest block and you know the entire blockchain and all the transactions in it are correct.</description></item><item><title>Hardware Accelerated Rsa - VDFs, SNARKs, and Accumulators</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/hardware-accelerated-rsa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/hardware-accelerated-rsa/</guid><description>Hardware Accelerated RSA - VDFs, SNARKs, and Accumulators
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230551345700069377
Introduction I am going to talk about accelerating RSA operations in hardware. So let&amp;rsquo;s just get into it.
Outline I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about what acceleration is and why we&amp;rsquo;re interested in it, then we&amp;rsquo;ll get into RSA primitives, then we&amp;rsquo;ll get into algorithms, and then various platforms for hardware. Hardware is anything you&amp;rsquo;re going to run software on. We&amp;rsquo;ll look at what the tradeoffs are, and then some performance numbers and measurements we&amp;rsquo;ve taken.</description></item><item><title>Libra Blockchain Intro</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/libra-blockchain-intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/libra-blockchain-intro/</guid><description>The Libra Blockchain &amp;amp; Move: A technical introduction
Ben Maurer
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230248685319024641
Introduction We&amp;rsquo;re building a new wallet for the system, Calibre, which we are launching. A bit about myself before we get started. I have been at Facebook for about 10 years now. Before Facebook, I was one of the co-founders of reCaptcha- the squiggly letters you type in before you login and register. I have been working at Facebook on performance, reliability, and working with web standards to make the web faster.</description></item><item><title>Linking Anonymous Transactions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/linking-anonymous-transactions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/linking-anonymous-transactions/</guid><description>Linking anonymous transactions via remote side-channel attacks
Florian Tramer
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230214874908655617
paper: https://crypto.stanford.edu/timings/paper.pdf
Introduction This is going to be talking about linking anonymous transactions in zcash and monero. Thanks for the introduction. I am going to be talking about remote side-channel attacks on anonymous transactions. This will be with respect to zcash and monero. Full disclosure, we disclosed all of the things I am talking about here today and everything has been fixed.</description></item><item><title>Lower Bounds Limits Plasma</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/lower-bounds-limits-plasma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/lower-bounds-limits-plasma/</guid><description>Lower Bounds for Off-Chain Protocols: Exploring the Limits of Plasma
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230183338746335233
Introduction Okay, thank you. The title of my talk is exploring the limits of plasma. This is joint work with others.
Plasma Let me start by telling you about Plasma. It&amp;rsquo;s a family of layer 2 solutions for scaling blockchain. It was proposed in 2017 by Poon and Buterin. It&amp;rsquo;s a family of protocols. There&amp;rsquo;s plenty of different plasmas. This is a diagram from more than a year ago.</description></item><item><title>Mixicles</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/mixicles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/mixicles/</guid><description>Mixicles: Simple Private Decentralized Finance
Ari Juels
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230666545803563008
https://chain.link/mixicles.pdf
Introduction This work was done in my capacity as technical advisor to Chainlink, and not my Cornell or IC3 affiliation. Mixicle is a combination of the words mixers and oracles. You will see why in a moment.
DeFi and privacy As of a couple of weeks ago, DeFi passed the $1 billion mark which is to say there&amp;rsquo;s over $1 billion of cryptocurrency in DeFi smart contracts today.</description></item><item><title>Motoko Language</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/motoko-language/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/motoko-language/</guid><description>Motoko, the language for the Internet Computer
Introduction Thanks, Byron. Glad to be here. My name is Dominic Williams. I am founder of the internet computer project at Dfinity Foundation. Last year we talked about consensus protocols. Today we are talking about tools for building on top of the internet computer which is great news and shows the progress we have made. I&amp;rsquo;m going to give some introductory context, and then our senior researcher from our languages division will talk about Motoko.</description></item><item><title>No Incentive</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/no-incentive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/no-incentive/</guid><description>The best incentive is no incentive
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230997662339436544
Introduction This is the last session of the conference. Time flies when you&amp;rsquo;re having fun. We&amp;rsquo;re going to be starting with David Schwartz who is one of the co-creators of Ripple and he is going to be talking about a controversial topic that &amp;ldquo;the best incentive is no incentive&amp;rdquo;.
I am David Schwartz as you just heard I am one of the co-creators of Ripple.</description></item><item><title>Optimistic Vm</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/optimistic-vm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/optimistic-vm/</guid><description>The optimistic VM
Karl Floersch
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230974707249233921
Introduction Okay, let&amp;rsquo;s get started our afternoon session. Our first talk I am very happy to introduce our speaker on optimistic virtual machines. Earlier in this conference we heard about optimistic roll-ups and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to this talk on optimistic virtual machines which is an up-and-coming approach on doing this.
Why hello everyone. I am building on ethereum and in particular we&amp;rsquo;re going to make Optimism: the attitude that will save the day.</description></item><item><title>Plonk</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/plonk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/plonk/</guid><description>PLONK: Permutations over Lagrange-bases for Oecumenical Noninteractive arguments of Knowledge
Ariel Gabizon
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230287617972768769
paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2019/pdf
Introduction One of the things you need when you design a zk proof system is that you need to know about polynomials. Two polynomials if they are the same then they are the same everywhere and if they are different then they are different almost everywhere. The other thing you need is how to get a good name.</description></item><item><title>Prism - Scaling bitcoin by 10,000x</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/prism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/prism/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230634530110730241
https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/prism/
Introduction Hello everyone. I am excited to be here to talk about our implementation and evaluation of the Prism consensus protocol which achieves 10,000x better performance than bitcoin. This is a multi-university collaboration between MIT, Stanford and a few others. I&amp;rsquo;d like to thank my collaborators, including my advisor, and other people.
Bitcoin performance We all know that bitcoin has good security, but in terms of performance it is not so good.</description></item><item><title>Proof Of Necessary Work</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/proof-of-necessary-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/proof-of-necessary-work/</guid><description>Proof of Necessary Work: Succinct State Verification with Fairness Guarantees
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230199429849743360
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230192993786720256
See also https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/190
Previous talk: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/proof-of-necessary-work/
Introduction Let&amp;rsquo;s start with something familiar. When you have a new lite client, or any client that wants to trustlessly connect to the network and joins the network for the first time&amp;hellip; they see this: they need to download a lot of data, initially, and then on an ongoing basis. They need to do a lot of verification and computation on top of this data.</description></item><item><title>Proof Of Stake</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/proof-of-stake/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/proof-of-stake/</guid><description>Proof-of-stake longest chain protocols revisited
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230646529230163968
Introduction Thanks. I am the last talk of the session so I better make it interesting, and if not interesting then short at least. I am going to talk about proof-of-stake. This is collaboration with a few people. Vivek Bagaria, &amp;hellip; et al.
Proof-of-stake prism The starting point of this project was to come up with a proof-of-stake version of prism, which we just saw in the last talk.</description></item><item><title>Scalable Rsa Modulus Generation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/scalable-rsa-modulus-generation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/scalable-rsa-modulus-generation/</guid><description>Scalable RSA Modulus Generation with Dishonest Majority
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230545603605585920
Introduction Groups of unknown order are interesting cryptographic primitives. You can commit to integers. If you commit to a very large integer, you have to do a lot of work to do the commitment so you have a sequentiality assumption useful for VDFs. But then you have this compression property where if you take a large integer with a lot of information in it, you can compress it down to something small.</description></item><item><title>Smart Contract Bug Hunting</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/smart-contract-bug-hunting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/smart-contract-bug-hunting/</guid><description>Finding Bugs Automatically in Smart Contracts with Parameterized Specifications
https://www.certora.com/pubs/sbc2020.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230906600140918784
Introduction I am from Tel Aviv University and now we have a 1-year old company called Cotera which is located in Berlin, Seattle and Tel Aviv. Our mission is to bring formal methods into code security and I will talk to you today about how we use this method to find bugs. And actually, I try to make this talk as informal as possible but there is actually a paper just download it from the certora website.</description></item><item><title>Solving Data Availability Attacks Using Coded Merkle Trees</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/solving-data-availability-attacks-using-coded-merkle-trees/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/solving-data-availability-attacks-using-coded-merkle-trees/</guid><description>Coded Merkle Tree: Solving Data Availability Attacks in Blockchains
https://eprint.iacr.org/2019/1139.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230984827651772416
Introduction I am going to talk about blockchain sharding via data availability. Good evening everybody. I am Sreeram Kannan. This talk is going to be on how to scale blockchains using data availability proofs. The work in this talk is done in collaboration with my colleagues including Fisher Yu, Songza Li, David Tse, Vivek Bagaria, Salman Avestimehr, etc.
Sharding proposals If you look at the state of sharding today, there have been many academic works:</description></item><item><title>Stark For Developers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/stark-for-developers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/stark-for-developers/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230279740570783744
Introduction It always seems like there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of different proof systems, but it turns out they really work well together and there&amp;rsquo;s great abstractions that are happening where we can take different tools and plug them together. We will see some of those in this session. I think STARKs were first announced 3 years ago back when this conference was BPASE, and now they are ready to use for developers and they are deployed in the wild and it&amp;rsquo;s exciting to see how far we&amp;rsquo;ve come in the past few years.</description></item><item><title>Streamlet</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/streamlet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/streamlet/</guid><description>Streamlet: Textbook Streamlined Blockchain Protocols
Introduction ((&amp;hellip;. stream went offline in the other room, had to catch up.))
Show you new consensus protocol called streamlet. We think it is remarkably simple intuitive. This is quite a bold claim, hopefully the protocol will speak for itself
Incredibly subtle, hard to implement in practice. We want to take this reputation and sweep it out the door.
Jump right in. First model the consensus problem.</description></item><item><title>Transparent Dishonesty</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/transparent-dishonesty/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/transparent-dishonesty/</guid><description>Transparent dishonesty: frontrunning attacks on blockchain
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1231005309310627841
Introduction The last two talks are going to be about frontrunning. One of the features of blockchain is that they are slow but this also opens them up to vulnerabilities such that I can insert my transactions before other people and this could have bad consequences and Shayan is going to explore this a little bit.
My talk will not be as intense as the previous talk, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to have more pictures.</description></item><item><title>Transparent Snarks From Dark Compilers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/transparent-snarks-from-dark-compilers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/transparent-snarks-from-dark-compilers/</guid><description>Transparent SNARKs from DARK compilers
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230561492254089224
paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2019/1229.pdf
Introduction Our next speaker is Ben Fisch, part of the Stanford Applied Crypto team and he has done a lot of work that is relevant to the blockchain space. Proofs of replication, proofs of space, he is also one of the coauthors of a paper that defined the notion of verifiable delay functions. He has also worked on accumulators, batching techniques, vector commitments, and one of his latest works is exciting which is DARKs which he is going to talk about today.</description></item></channel></rss>