<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>David Vorick on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/david-vorick/</link><description>Recent content in David Vorick on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/david-vorick/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Monero and the Privacy Doom Principle</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/monero-and-the-privacy-doom-principle/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/monero-and-the-privacy-doom-principle/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a blockchain researcher and developer. I&amp;rsquo;ve built the Sia blockchain ecosystem and I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the space for a while and today I&amp;rsquo;m talking about Monero and privacy models that ended up being explained in analytical techniques that we can use to beat error in privacy.
The Concept of Privacy in Cryptocurrencies So my name is David Vork. I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the blockchain space for about a decade. I&amp;rsquo;ve been between researching and launching blockchains, doing a lot of engineering, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the space for a while and studying things.</description></item><item><title>Blockchain Design Patterns: Layers and scaling approaches</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/blockchain-design-patterns/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/blockchain-design-patterns/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171400374336536576
Introduction Alright. Are we ready to get going? Thumbs up? Alright. Cool. I am Andrew and this is David. We&amp;rsquo;re here to talk about blockchain design patterns: layers and scaling approaches. This will be a tour of a bunch of different scaling approaches in bitcoin in particular but it&amp;rsquo;s probably applicable to other blockchains out there. Our talk is in 3 parts. We&amp;rsquo;ll talk about some existing scaling tech and related things like caching transactions and mempool propagation.</description></item><item><title>Ideal Number Of Full Bitcoin Nodes</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/ideal-number-of-full-bitcoin-nodes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/ideal-number-of-full-bitcoin-nodes/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/838481130944876544
Today I am going to be talking about bitcoin full nodes. Can everyone hear me? Okay, great. I don&amp;rsquo;t actually think there&amp;rsquo;s a specific number. I think a lot of people do. They look for a number. 5000 is about how many we have today, 6000. Some people ask whether it&amp;rsquo;s a good number. I think that&amp;rsquo;s the wrong way to look at the role of full nodes in the ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Asics</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/asics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/asics/</guid><description>ASIC design for mining
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1091056727464697856
Introduction My name is David Vorick. I am lead developer of Sia, a decentralized cloud storage solution. I come from the software side of the world, but I got into hardware. I think from the perspective of cryptocurrency developers. I am also CEO of Obelisk, which is a cryptocurrency ASIC miner manufacturing company. I was asked today to talk about cryptocurrency ASICs. This is a really broad topic and the format that I have chosen is that I am going to blast through as much as I can, and I&amp;rsquo;ll leave more time for Q&amp;amp;A at the time and have something closer to an open forum so hopefully we can get 10-15 minutes of Q&amp;amp;A at the end.</description></item><item><title>Jute Braiding</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/jute-braiding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/jute-braiding/</guid><description>Jute: New braiding techniques to achieve significant scaling gains
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785116246257856512
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong/braiding-the-blockchain/
Introduction Okay, hello. My name is David Vorick. I have been with bitcoin since 2011. I have been a full-time blockchain engineer since about 2014. I run an altcoin for decentralized cloud storage called Sia. Today I am going to be talking about braiding which basically means we take the straight line blockchain of bitcoin and we allow blocks to have multiple parents.</description></item><item><title>Microchains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/microchains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/microchains/</guid><description>Microchains
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/927257690685939712
I would like to see a blockchain ecosystem with 1000s of transactions/second at layer 1 with full security. And so, we have to look at blockchain differently if we are going to achieve this.
A brief introduction&amp;hellip; my name is David Vorick. I have been studying bitcoin since 2011. My primary gig is Sia. I have been spending a lot of time on consensus algorithms and proof-of-work. If we could start over what sorts of things could we do today that we didnt know about in 2008?</description></item><item><title>Payment Channel Recovery With Seeds</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/payment-channel-recovery-with-seeds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/payment-channel-recovery-with-seeds/</guid><description>Seed-based payment channel recovery
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1172129077765050368
Introduction Cool. This addresses the lightning network which is a scaling technique for the bitcoin network. A big challenge with the lightning network is that you have these midstates that you need to keep. If you lose them, you&amp;rsquo;re out of luck with your counterparty. We had a lot of talks this morning about how to recover midstates but a lot of them used watchtowers. However, this proposal does not require a watchtower and you can restore midstates knowing nothing but your wallet seed.</description></item><item><title>Siacoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/siacoin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/siacoin/</guid><description>Sia
I have been working on a decentralized cloud storage platform. Before I go into that, I wanted to mention that I have been working on Bitcoin since 2011. Since 2013 I have been in the wizards channel. In 2014 a friend and myself founded a company to build Siacoin. The team has grown to 3 people. Sia is the name of our decentralized storage protocol. We are trying to emulate Amazon S3.</description></item><item><title>Trust And Blockchain Marketplaces</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/trust-and-blockchain-marketplaces/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/trust-and-blockchain-marketplaces/</guid><description>Introduction I founded Sia, a decentralized storage platform started in 2014. Today, Sia is the only decentralized storage platform out there. I also founded Obelisk which is a mining equipment manufacturing company.
Mining supply chains are centralized Basically all the mining chips are coming out of TSMC or Samsung. For the longest time it was TSMC but for some reason Samsung is at the forefront for this cycle but I would expect them to fade out in the next cycle.</description></item></channel></rss>