<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>lightning on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/lightning/</link><description>Recent content in lightning on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/lightning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vortex: ZeroLink for Lightning Opens</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/vortex-zerolink-for-lightning-opens/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/vortex-zerolink-for-lightning-opens/</guid><description>(The start of the talk is missing from the source media)
What is a blind signature All these people could come, and they all can then present their signatures. And Bob will know, &amp;ldquo;okay, all of these signatures are correct, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know who gave me which one. You&amp;rsquo;ll see how we use this in the protocol to get some privacy. This is kind of the structure (referring to slide#2).</description></item><item><title>Lightning Specification Meeting - Agenda 1118</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-11-20-specification-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-11-20-specification-call/</guid><description>Agenda: https://github.com/lightning/bolts/issues/1118
Speaker 0: We won&amp;rsquo;t have posting for the mailing list anymore in one month and a half, so we should probably do something. My plan was to just wait to see what bitcoin-dev would do and do the same thing. Does someone have opinions on that or an idea on what we should do?
Speaker 1: Who&amp;rsquo;s managing the email account for the lightning-dev mailing list? You, [Redacted]?</description></item><item><title>Lightning Specification Meeting - Agenda 1116</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-11-06-specification-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-11-06-specification-call/</guid><description>Agenda: https://github.com/lightning/bolts/issues/1116
Speaker 0: I moved the first item on the to-do list today, dual funding, because we finally have interop between C-Lightning and Eclair. We were only missing the reestablished part, and everything was mostly okay from the beginning. It looks like the spec seems to be clear enough because we both understood it the same way. So now, we really have full interop on master, and I guess this should go in a release with experimental flags for CLN.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Specification Meeting - Agenda 1115</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-10-23-specification-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-10-23-specification-call/</guid><description>Agenda: https://github.com/lightning/bolts/issues/1115
Speaker 0: Alright. So, I guess the first item is something that has already been ACKed and is only one clarification. But I had one question on the PR. I was wondering, [redacted], for which feature you actually use that code because neither LND or Eclair handles — we just disconnect on anything mandatory that we haven&amp;rsquo;t set. Where are you actually using that or how are you planning on using it?</description></item><item><title>Lightning Specification Meeting - Agenda 1114</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-09-25-specification-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-09-25-specification-call/</guid><description>Agenda: https://github.com/lightning/bolts/issues/1114
Speaker 0: So, [redacted] pointed out that we did not do this, and we have to do this. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on the code so that you have to push their commitment transaction. Now, there are several problems with this. One is that in many states, there are two possible commitment transactions they could have. In theory, you know what they are. In practice, it turned out to be a bit of a nightmare to unwind the state.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Specification Meeting - Agenda 1103</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-08-28-specification-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-08-28-specification-call/</guid><description>Agenda: https://github.com/lightning/bolts/issues/1103
Speaker 0: I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve seen any discussion happening on any of the PRs. So, I don&amp;rsquo;t think we should go and have them in order, except maybe the first one that we may want to just finalize and get something into the spec to say that it should be 2016 everywhere. But, as [redacted] was saying, can probably make it a one-liner and it would be easier.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Specification Meeting - Agenda 1101</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-08-14-specification-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-08-14-specification-call/</guid><description>Agenda: https://github.com/lightning/bolts/issues/1101
Speaker 0: Alright, should we start? I want to talk a quick update on dual funding because I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with [redacted] on cross-compatibility tests between Core Lightning and Eclair, and so far, everything looks good. The only part that has not yet been fully implemented in CLN is the reconnection part — when you disconnect in the middle of the signature exchange. This kind of reconnection is supposed to complete that signature exchange with one new TLV added to channel re-establish.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Specification Meeting - Agenda 1098</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-07-31-specification-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-07-31-specification-call/</guid><description>Agenda: https://github.com/lightning/bolts/issues/1098
Speaker 0: Great. I guess, does anyone have any urgent stuff that we want to make sure we get to in the meeting today? If not, I&amp;rsquo;m just going to go ahead and start working down the recently updated proposal seeking review list. Great. Okay. First up on the list is option simple close. This is from the summit we had a few weeks ago in July. Looks like [Redacted] and [Redacted] have commented on this and [Redacted] stuff.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Specification Meeting - Agenda 1094</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-07-17-specification-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-07-17-specification-call/</guid><description>Agenda: https://github.com/lightning/bolts/issues/1094
Speaker 0: Alright. Does anyone want to volunteer to take us through the list? Nope? Okay. I will read the issue that [Redacted] very kindly left for us then. The first item on the list is Bolt 8’s chaining keys clarification. Is there anything we need to talk about here?
Speaker 1: Yeah. Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s almost under the spelling rule, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s been ACKed by everyone. So, unless people have objections to the specific wording.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Specification Meeting - Agenda 1088</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-06-19-specification-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-06-19-specification-call/</guid><description>Agenda: https://github.com/lightning/bolts/issues/1088
Speaker 0: Thanks [Redacted]. So, there isn&amp;rsquo;t much that has changed on any of the PRs that are on the pending to-do list, except for attributable errors. So, maybe since [Redacted] is here, we can start with attributable errors, and [Redacted], you can tell us what has changed about the HMAC truncation, for example.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so not that much changed. Just the realization that we could truncate the HMAC basically, because the failure message was so large already.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Specification Meeting - Agenda 1085</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-06-05-specification-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-06-05-specification-call/</guid><description>Agenda: https://github.com/lightning/bolts/issues/1085
Speaker 0: Alright, so let&amp;rsquo;s start. So, the first PR on the list is one we&amp;rsquo;ve already discussed last week. It just needs someone from another team, either Lightning Labs or LDK to hack. It&amp;rsquo;s just a clarification on Bolt 8. So, I don&amp;rsquo;t think it should be reviewed right now because just takes time to work through it and verify that it matches your implementation. But if someone on either of those teams can add it to their to-do list, hack it, and then we can merge it.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Specification Meeting - Agenda 1082</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-05-22-specification-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-05-22-specification-call/</guid><description>Agenda: https://github.com/lightning/bolts/issues/1082
Speaker 1: So, the first PR we have on the list is a clarification on Bolt 8 by [Redacted]. It looks like, if I understand correctly, someone tried to reimplement Bolt 8 and got it wrong, and it&amp;rsquo;s only clarifications. Is that correct?
Speaker 2: Yes. So LN message - a JavaScript library that speaks to nodes - had everything right except for the fact they shared a chaining key, which is correct to start with.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Specification Meeting - Agenda 1076</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-05-08-specification-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-05-08-specification-call/</guid><description>Agenda: https://github.com/lightning/bolts/issues/1076
Speaker 0: First off of the list is dual funding. [Redacted] has merged the two small patches that we had discussed adding. There&amp;rsquo;s only one small patch that is remaining, which is about making the TLV signed to allow for future splicing to make sure that splicing can also use the RBF messages for signed amounts. But apart from that, it looks like dual funding is almost complete. We plan on activating it on our node soon to be able to use it in Phoenix.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Specification Meeting - Agenda 1067</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-04-24-specification-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-04-24-specification-call/</guid><description>Agenda: https://github.com/lightning/bolts/issues/1067
Speaker 0: Alright, so first thing I&amp;rsquo;ve got on deck is 1066, which says: Correct final CLTV handling and blinded paths.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I haven&amp;rsquo;t dug as deep into the blinded path stuff, so this may be an incorrect reading that I was confused to. Basically, for a blinded path, we don&amp;rsquo;t have a final CLTV for the recipient because we just have a full CLTV delta for the full blinded path.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Specification Meeting - Agenda 1055</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-02-13-specification-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-02-13-specification-call/</guid><description>Name: Lightning specification call
Topic: Agenda below
Location: Jitsi
Video: No video posted online
Agenda: https://github.com/lightning/bolts/issues/1055
Speaker 0: A few people won&amp;rsquo;t be able to attend. I guess we can proceed. Okay. I&amp;rsquo;m going to go down the list that you prepared for this. The first thing being dual funding. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if we have any one involved here at this point.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Last time, both of them were moving closer towards interop.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Specification Meeting - Agenda 1053</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-01-30-specification-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2023-01-30-specification-call/</guid><description>Name: Lightning specification call
Topic: Agenda below
Location: Jitsi
Video: No video posted online
Agenda: https://github.com/lightning/bolts/issues/1053
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Participants that wish to be attributed are welcome to propose changes to the transcript.
Channel Pruning Speaker 2: To be honest, I don&amp;rsquo;t think anything has made a lot of progress since the last spec meeting, so I don&amp;rsquo;t think we should do the topics in order.</description></item><item><title>Lightning is Broken AF (But We Can Fix It)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/lightning-is-broken-af-but-we-can-fix-it/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/lightning-is-broken-af-but-we-can-fix-it/</guid><description>Introduction Thank you. Yeah, so, as the title says, for those of you who work in lightning or have been around lightning for a long time, hopefully you will recognize basically all the issues I&amp;rsquo;ll go through today. I&amp;rsquo;m going to go through a very long list of things. But I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to go through most of the kind of, at least my understanding of the current thinking of solutions for a lot of these issues.</description></item><item><title>How to become Signet Rich: Learn about Bitcoin Signet and Zebnet</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/how-to-become-signet-rich-learn-about-bitcoin-signet-and-zebnet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/how-to-become-signet-rich-learn-about-bitcoin-signet-and-zebnet/</guid><description>Richard: So today we are going to talk about Signet Lightning, PlebNet Playground, which was the first evolution of me playing with custom Signets, and eventually ZebNet Adventures. This is how you can become Signet-rich.
First, we should probably do an overview of the various network types. Everybody knows about Mainnet. This is what we use day to day, but there&amp;rsquo;s a few other testing networks. RegTest, or SimNet, if you are running BTCD, is a local unit testing framework.</description></item><item><title>Minisketch and Lightning gossip</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/2022/2022-06-07-alex-myers-minisketch-lightning-gossip/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/2022/2022-06-07-alex-myers-minisketch-lightning-gossip/</guid><description>Location: Bitcoin++
Slides: https://endothermic.dev/presentations/magical-minisketch
Rusty Russell on using Minisketch for Lightning gossip: https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/lightning-dev/2018-December/001741.html
Minisketch library: https://github.com/sipa/minisketch
Bitcoin Core PR review club on Minisketch (3 sessions):
https://bitcoincore.reviews/minisketch-26
https://bitcoincore.reviews/minisketch-26-2
https://bitcoincore.reviews/minisketch
Introduction Pretty new to Lightning Network development, joined the Core Lightning team. I’m going to present on Minisketch and what I’ve learnt about the gossip network.
Topics I am going to go over the role of gossip in the Lightning Network. Is everyone familiar with Lightning or at least semi enthusiast?</description></item><item><title>History of Bitcoin in GAMING</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinology/history-of-bitcoin-in-gaming/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinology/history-of-bitcoin-in-gaming/</guid><description>INTRO Christian: Before I start, it&amp;rsquo;s probably a good idea to make sure you have a Lightning wallet downloaded because, at the end, I have some games we can play and actually get some Bitcoin through the games. So if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a Lightning wallet installed, please do so. I recommend my company&amp;rsquo;s wallet, Zebedee. So if you just type in Zebedee on my t-shirt into the Google Play or App Store, you should be able to download it.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Specification Meeting - Agenda 0969</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2022-03-14-specification-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2022-03-14-specification-call/</guid><description>Name: Lightning specification call
Topic: Agenda below
Location: Jitsi
Video: No video posted online
Agenda: https://github.com/lightning/bolts/issues/969
BOLT 4: Remove legacy format, make var_onion_optin compulsory https://github.com/lightning/bolts/pull/962
I think eclair and c-lightning have both removed support for legacy payments.
I’ll probably make a PR to add the feature bit or at least flip it to required. The only wallet I can think of that is somewhat more fringe now is Simple Bitcoin Wallet.</description></item><item><title>c-lightning developer call</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/2022-03-07-developer-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/2022-03-07-developer-call/</guid><description>Name: c-lightning developer call
Topic: Various topics
Location: Jitsi online
Video: No video posted online
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Minisketch and gossip spam I’ve been working on the multi channel connect stuff, trying to not get distracted by Tether talk and other stuff like that.</description></item><item><title>Deploying Lightning at Scale (Greenlight)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2022/2022-03-03-christian-decker-greenlight/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2022/2022-03-03-christian-decker-greenlight/</guid><description>Blog post on Greenlight: https://blog.blockstream.com/en-greenlight-by-blockstream-lightning-made-easy/
Greenlight demo at London Bitcoin Devs: https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2022-03-01-lightning-panel/
Intro Jeff Gallas: Next up is Christian Decker. He is a Lightning developer at Blockstream. He has got a very simple title. It is Security, Simplicity and DevOps: the trade-offs between a Lightning PPAS and running your own node. That is already half of the talk.
Christian Decker: Thank you very much, I’m Chris and for once I am not going to shill eltoo, I promise.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2022-03-01-lightning-panel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2022-03-01-lightning-panel/</guid><description>Topic: The Lightning Network in 2022
Location: London Bitcoin Devs
Introductions Ali Taylor-Cipolla (ATC): Ali coming in from Coinbase Recruiting. I’d like to introduce to my friend Tiago who is on the Europe side.
Tiago Schmidt (TS): Hello everyone. Quick introduction, sitting in the recruiting team here in London and leading the expansion for engineering hiring across UK and Ireland. Coinbase is in hyper-growth at the moment and we will be looking to hire loads of the people.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Specification Meeting - Agenda 0957</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2022-02-14-specification-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2022-02-14-specification-call/</guid><description>Name: Lightning specification call
Topic: Agenda below
Location: Jitsi
Video: No video posted online
Agenda: https://github.com/lightning/bolts/issues/957
Organizing a Lightning Core Dev meetup I was talking about organizing a face to face Lightning Core Dev meetup. If I understand correctly there has only been one formal one and that was in 2019 in Australia. There has been two?
Milan, the kickoff. There has only ever been two.
That was probably before my time in Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Specification Meeting - Agenda 0955</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2022-01-31-specification-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2022-01-31-specification-call/</guid><description>Name: Lightning specification call
Topic: Agenda below
Location: Jitsi
Video: No video posted online
Agenda: https://github.com/lightning/bolts/issues/955
Bitcoin Core funding a transaction without looking at ancestors I have something that I wanted to ask of our implementers who implemented a wallet. It is tangentially related to Lightning especially for anchor outputs. I realized recently that when you ask Bitcoin Core to fund a transaction at a given fee rate it is not going to look at the ancestors and it is not going to take the ancestor’s fee rate into account.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Lightning Network Developments</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinology/2022-01-26-igor-korsakov-cool-ln-developments/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinology/2022-01-26-igor-korsakov-cool-ln-developments/</guid><description>Topic: Cool Lightning Network Developments
Synonym Igor Synonym is a company that John Carvalho started and he is trying to put Web3 inside of Bitcoin. But what it consists of? They&amp;rsquo;re using several things like identities and people hosting their own data.
AOPP For identity, the first thing I want to mention is Address Ownership Proof Protocol (AOPP). This is the field that we added in BlueWallet some months ago. I think it was a Switzerland exchange that wanted this, so they sent us a pull request and we merged it (PR#2915, PR#4431).</description></item><item><title>c-lightning developer call</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/2022-01-24-developer-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/2022-01-24-developer-call/</guid><description>Name: c-lightning developer call
Topic: Various topics
Location: Jitsi online
Video: No video posted online
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Individual updates Still working on the cln stuff. cln is basically the Rust libraries that I am building to interact with c-lightning and which will become the basis for the gRPC interface.</description></item><item><title>c-lightning developer call</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/2022-01-10-developer-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/2022-01-10-developer-call/</guid><description>Topic: Various topics
Location: Jitsi online
Date: January 10th 2022
Video: No video posted online
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Accounting plugin I have been working on the accounting plugin for the last few months.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Specification Meeting - Agenda 0949</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2022-01-03-specification-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2022-01-03-specification-call/</guid><description>Name: Lightning specification call
Topic: Agenda below
Location: Jitsi
Video: No video posted online
Agenda: https://github.com/lightning/bolts/issues/949
Introduction When people put comments and they are fixed they should mark them as resolved so that we don’t waste time thinking there are lots of outstanding comments and we have to read them again. I think that helps a lot.
I can spend some time doing that.
There are a lot of comments, I’m starting at the bottom to see the things that have maybe not been addressed yet.</description></item><item><title>What is Lightning Network?</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinology/what-is-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinology/what-is-lightning-network/</guid><description>Introduction Hello everyone. We&amp;rsquo;re going to sort of soft start now, and this is a new meetup group we&amp;rsquo;ve decided to call Bitcoinology. It&amp;rsquo;s a whimsical name. It&amp;rsquo;s really intended to convey the idea that we want to discuss Bitcoin not in a super developer technical code way, but we do want to discuss it—how it&amp;rsquo;s used, even what the history and culture of it are, and what are the interesting things as a user and as a sort of Bitcoin person you can learn.</description></item><item><title>c-lightning developer call</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/2021-12-13-developer-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/2021-12-13-developer-call/</guid><description>Topic: Various topics
Location: Jitsi online
Video: No video posted online
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Enabling multi channel support https://github.com/ElementsProject/lightning/pull/4984
https://github.com/ElementsProject/lightning/pull/4985
I have actually been pulling Humpty Dumpty apart. I have a series of like 40 patches which rearchitect the entire way we do c-lightning.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Specification Meeting - Agenda 0943</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2021-12-06-specification-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2021-12-06-specification-call/</guid><description>Name: Lightning specification call
Topic: Agenda below
Location: Google Meet
Video: No video posted online
Agenda: https://github.com/lightning/bolts/issues/943
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have given permission for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Add payment metadata to payment request https://github.com/lightning/bolts/pull/912
In theory you could have an invoice that is so large that it forces you to use a direct payment.</description></item><item><title>c-lightning developer call</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/2021-11-29-developer-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/2021-11-29-developer-call/</guid><description>Topic: Various topics
Location: Jitsi online
Date: November 29th 2021
Video: No video posted online
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
CI problems I will note we have been having CI problems.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Specification Meeting - Agenda 0936</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2021-11-22-specification-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-specification/2021-11-22-specification-call/</guid><description>Name: Lightning specification call
Topic: Agenda below
Location: Google Meet
Video: No video posted online
Agenda: https://github.com/lightning/bolts/issues/936
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have given permission for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
BOLT 7 onion message support https://github.com/lightning/bolts/pull/759
So PR 759 is built on PR 765 because we used the route blinding to decrypt where the end is going to go.</description></item><item><title>Privacy On Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/adopting-bitcoin/2021/2021-11-17-bastien-teinturier-privacy-on-lightning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/adopting-bitcoin/2021/2021-11-17-bastien-teinturier-privacy-on-lightning/</guid><description>Topic: Privacy On Lightning
Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1llk70vI2Mo5uQ7vnpfbl1qlr0qe0NLpySIelChIKhH4/edit
Introduction Buenos Dias San Salvador, I&amp;rsquo;m Bastien. Hopefully my slides are going to come up. Oh yay, perfect. So I&amp;rsquo;m working on the Lightning Protocol Specification and one of its main implementation at Acinq.
I&amp;rsquo;m here to talk to you about privacy. This is a big topic. It&amp;rsquo;s not a black and white thing. There are various degrees of gray when you talk about what your threat model is, who you want to protect against.</description></item><item><title>c-lightning developer call</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/2021-11-15-developer-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/2021-11-15-developer-call/</guid><description>Topic: Various topics
Location: Jitsi online
Video: No video posted online
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Upgrading c-lightning for Taproot So, Taproot. The one place in the spec where Taproot matters if you are using it as an individual, generally it doesn’t matter where you keep your funds when it is not in a channel, doesn’t affect the spec, except the shutdown case.</description></item><item><title>Liquidity Advertisements - niftynei - TABConf 2021</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/liquidity-advertisements-niftynei-tabconf-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/liquidity-advertisements-niftynei-tabconf-2021/</guid><description>Introduction Again, my name is Lisa Neigut. I work at Blockstream. I&amp;rsquo;m here today to talk to you about the spec proposal that we&amp;rsquo;ve added to c-lightning and hoping to get into more Lightning implementation soon to make it standard. This is about liquidity advertisements. So today I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking to you about what a liquidity ad is, how they work, kind of explain how data gets passed around Lightning Network just in general, and maybe get some of you excited about using them.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Dev Kit - Making Lightning More Accessible to Developers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/lightning-dev-kit-making-lightning-more-accessible-to-developers-matt-corallo-tabconf-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/lightning-dev-kit-making-lightning-more-accessible-to-developers-matt-corallo-tabconf-2021/</guid><description>Introduction So, I worked on Bitcoin Core for many many years, but I am not here to talk about that! I now spend my time, full time at Square Crypto working on a project we call the Lightning Dev Kit (LDK). So, working to enable Lightning to be more accessible to developers and I&amp;rsquo;m here to talk about that and give the lay of the land for why it exists, what the state of the Lightning ecosystem is broadly, and why we think it&amp;rsquo;s an important project and why Square is funding us, to work on it.</description></item><item><title>Scaling with LND</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/scaling-with-lnd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/scaling-with-lnd/</guid><description>Intro I wanted to talk about scaling lightning using LND. I started working at Lightning Labs three years ago and come really a long way. I started working with LND before that when I worked at BitGo. That was the barest, almost didn&amp;rsquo;t work, it was crashing everyday type of scenario. Now, three years later, we&amp;rsquo;re trying to scale this to millions of people. We&amp;rsquo;re trying to scale this to millions of payments.</description></item><item><title>c-lightning developer call</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/2021-11-01-developer-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/2021-11-01-developer-call/</guid><description>Topic: Various topics
Location: Jitsi online
Video: No video posted online
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
c-lightning v0.10.2 release https://medium.com/blockstream/c-lightning-v0-10-2-bitcoin-dust-consensus-rule-33e777d58657
We’ve tagged RC1 to get people testing. The testing found 2 regressions, both related to the database handling.</description></item><item><title>c-lightning developer call</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/2021-10-18-developer-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/2021-10-18-developer-call/</guid><description>Topic: Various topics
Location: Jitsi online
Date: October 18th 2021
Video: No video posted online
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
c-lightning v0.10.2 release https://medium.com/blockstream/c-lightning-v0-10-2-bitcoin-dust-consensus-rule-33e777d58657
We are nominally past the release date.</description></item><item><title>c-lightning developer call</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/2021-10-04-developer-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/2021-10-04-developer-call/</guid><description>Name: c-lightning developer call
Topic: Various topics
Location: Jitsi online
Video: No video posted online
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Dust HTLC exposure (Lisa Neigut) Antoine Riard email to the Lightning dev mailing list: https://lists.</description></item><item><title>c-lightning developer call</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/2021-09-20-developer-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/2021-09-20-developer-call/</guid><description>Topic: Various topics
Location: Jitsi online
Video: No video posted online
Agenda: https://hackmd.io/@cdecker/Sy-9vZIQt
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Individual updates Let’s start with a quick round of updates from the team.</description></item><item><title>c-lightning developer call</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/2021-09-06-developer-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/2021-09-06-developer-call/</guid><description>Topic: Various topics
Location: Jitsi online
Date: September 6th 2021
Video: No video posted online
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Individual updates I’ve been mostly shepherding the pull requests on c-lightning and looking into issues we need to fix for the coming release.</description></item><item><title>c-lightning developer call</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/2021-08-23-developer-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/2021-08-23-developer-call/</guid><description>Topic: Various topics
Location: Jitsi online
Video: No video posted online
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Individual updates I’ve been working on connectd, we got that merged. It was not a big change.</description></item><item><title>Basis of Lightning Technology 12</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-magazine/bitcoin-explained/basis-of-lightning-technology-12/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-magazine/bitcoin-explained/basis-of-lightning-technology-12/</guid><description>Intro Aaron Van Wirdum: 00:00:09
Live from San Salvador and Utrecht, this is the Van Wirdum Sjorsnado. Hello! Hey Sjors, welcome back.
Sjors Provoost: 00:00:19
Thank you.
Aaron Van Wirdum: 00:00:19
It&amp;rsquo;s been a while.
Sjors Provoost: 00:00:20
I mean I&amp;rsquo;m not physically back.
Aaron Van Wirdum: 00:00:24
Yeah, I&amp;rsquo;m the one who&amp;rsquo;s not physically back. I&amp;rsquo;m still hanging out in El Salvador checking out what&amp;rsquo;s going on here with the new Bitcoin law.</description></item><item><title>Socratic Seminar - Discreet Log Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2021-08-10-socratic-seminar-dlcs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2021-08-10-socratic-seminar-dlcs/</guid><description>Name: Socratic Seminar
Topic: Discreet Log Contracts
Location: London BitDevs (online)
Gist of resources discussed: https://gist.github.com/michaelfolkson/f5da6774c24f99dba5c6c16ec8d499e9
This event was livestreamed on YouTube and so comments are attributed to specific individuals by the name or pseudonym that was visible on the livestream. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be anonymized please get in touch.
Intro Michael Folkson (MF): Welcome to everyone on the call, welcome to people watching on YouTube.</description></item><item><title>c-lightning developer call</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/2021-08-09-developer-call/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/2021-08-09-developer-call/</guid><description>c-lightning developer call Topic: Various topics
Location: Jitsi online
Video: No video posted online
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Individual updates Today I started to review some pull requests. I also finished my first draft of the paid order of the metrics plugin.</description></item><item><title>Sydney Socratic Seminar</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-07-06-socratic-seminar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-07-06-socratic-seminar/</guid><description>Name: Socratic Seminar
Topic: Fee bumping and layer 2 protocols
Location: Bitcoin Sydney (online)
Video: No video posted online
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Agenda: https://github.com/bitcoin-sydney/socratic/blob/master/README.md#2021-07
First IRC workshop on L2 onchain support: https://lists.</description></item><item><title>Sydney Socratic Seminar</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-06-01-socratic-seminar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-06-01-socratic-seminar/</guid><description>Name: Socratic Seminar
Topic: Agenda in Google Doc below
Location: Bitcoin Sydney (online)
Video: No video posted online
Google Doc of the resources discussed: https://docs.google.com/document/d/1E9mzB7fmzPxZ74WZg0PsJfLwjpVZ7OClmRdGQQFlzoY/
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.</description></item><item><title>Improving the Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi-research-club/2021-05-30-rusty-russell-improving-lightning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi-research-club/2021-05-30-rusty-russell-improving-lightning/</guid><description>Topic: Improving the Lightning Network
Location: Join the Wasabikas podcast
How Rusty got into Lightning Max Hillebrand (MH): So Rusty, I am very happy that you joined me for this conversation today. You have been a pioneer in Lightning Network. To start off this conversation I am curious, 6 years ago before you got into the Lightning Network what was your understanding of Bitcoin back then and where did you see some of the big problems that needed to be solved at that point?</description></item><item><title>Lightning Development Kit</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2021-05-12-matt-corallo-ldk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2021-05-12-matt-corallo-ldk/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs Podcast (Episode 13)
Matt Corallo presentation at Advancing Bitcoin 2019: https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2019/2019-02-07-matt-corallo-rust-lightning/
rust-lightning repo: https://github.com/rust-bitcoin/rust-lightning
Intro Adam Jonas (AJ): Welcome back to the office Matt, glad to have you back on the podcast.
Matt Corallo (MC): Thank you.
Update on LDK AJ: We are going to start with LDK. Where are we at? What is going on?
MC: If listeners are aware LDK kind of grew out of a project that I started a few years ago when I was working at Chaincode called rust-lightning.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Routing</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2021-03-27-alex-bosworth-lightning-routing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2021-03-27-alex-bosworth-lightning-routing/</guid><description>Lightning Routing - Building a new economy
Location: Lightning Hack Day
media: No video posted online
Slides: https://www.dropbox.com/s/oo9o8ij62utvlfo/alex-bosworth-lightning-routing.pdf
Transcript of presentation on Channel Management (2018): https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-alex-bosworth-channel-management/
Transcript by: Michael Folkson
Intro With Lightning routing I think it is a very exciting topic because we’re doing something that no one has ever really done before, to build this peer-to-peer marketplace. It is a required component of the Lightning Network because the Lightning Network is dependent on this concept of liquidity.</description></item><item><title>Dual Funded Channels</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/dual-funded-channels/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/c-lightning/dual-funded-channels/</guid><description>Dual Funding channels explainer + demo Cool. Okay, thanks everyone for coming. I think we&amp;rsquo;re going to go ahead and get started. It&amp;rsquo;s right at 11.02 on my time, so that hopefully more people will show up, but for everyone who&amp;rsquo;s here, I want to make the best use of all of your time. Okay, great. So for those of you who aren&amp;rsquo;t really sure what dual funding is, maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve heard people say that word before, but let me give you a kind of a quick overview.</description></item><item><title>The Label, Bitcoin Dev &amp; Consulting</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2021-02-26-gleb-naumenko/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2021-02-26-gleb-naumenko/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/255/
Stephan Livera:
Gleb welcome back to the show.
Gleb Naumenko:
Hi, it’s good to be back
Stephan Livera:
Glad you’ve been pretty busy with how you’ve started up a new Bitcoin development venture and you’re up to a few different things. Tell us what you’ve been working on lately.
Gleb Naumenko:
Yeah, last year it was like, I think it’s been maybe half a year or more since I came last time, I’ve been mostly working on actually lightning and related stuff like research wise, breaking lightning and fixing some existing issues.</description></item><item><title>Sydney Socratic Seminar</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-02-23-socratic-seminar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-02-23-socratic-seminar/</guid><description>Name: Socratic Seminar
Topic: Agenda in Google Doc below
Location: Bitcoin Sydney (online)
Video: No video posted online
Google Doc of the resources discussed: https://docs.google.com/document/d/1VAP4LNjHHVLy9RJwpQ8LqXEUw79z5TTZxr9du_Z0-9A/
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Topics</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-08-13-christian-decker-lightning-topics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-08-13-christian-decker-lightning-topics/</guid><description>Topic: ANYPREVOUT, MPP, Mitigating Lightning Attacks
Location: Stephan Livera Podcast
Transcript completed by: Stephan Livera Edited by: Michael Folkson
Latest ANYPREVOUT update ANYPREVOUT BIP (BIP 118): https://github.com/ajtowns/bips/blob/bip-anyprevout/bip-0118.mediawiki
Stephan Livera (SL): Christian welcome back to the show.
Christian Decker (CD): Hey Stephan, thanks for having me.
SL: I wanted to chat with you about a bunch of stuff that you’ve been doing. We’ve got a couple of things that I was really interested to chat with you about: ANYPREVOUT, MPP, Lightning attacks, the latest with Lightning Network.</description></item><item><title>Watchtowers and BOLT 13</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2020-05-24-sergi-delgado-watchtowers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2020-05-24-sergi-delgado-watchtowers/</guid><description>Location: Potzblitz (online)
Slides: https://srgi.me/resources/slides/Potzblitz!2020-Watchtowers.pdf
The Eye of Satoshi code: https://github.com/talaia-labs/python-teos
Draft BOLT 13: https://github.com/sr-gi/bolt13/blob/master/13-watchtowers.md
c-lightning watchtower plugin: https://github.com/talaia-labs/python-teos/tree/master/watchtower-plugin
c-lightning watchtower hook discussion:
https://github.com/ElementsProject/lightning/pull/3601
https://github.com/ElementsProject/lightning/pull/3645
https://github.com/ElementsProject/lightning/pull/3659
https://github.com/ElementsProject/lightning/issues/3724
Conner Fromknecht presentation on watchtowers: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/boltathon/2019-04-06-conner-fromknecht-watchtowers/
Intro I am going to be talking about towers and a bit about BOLT 13 too. Before jumping into watchtowers and this general idea of watchtowers for the Lightning Network that most of the community knows about I would like to go back one step back to try to narrow down the paradigm that we are going to be talking about.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Privacy</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2020-05-09-sergei-tikhomirov-lightning-privacy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2020-05-09-sergei-tikhomirov-lightning-privacy/</guid><description>Quantitative Analysis of Lightning Network Privacy
Location: Lightning Hacksprint (Fulmo)
Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1H9EdrhjQ9x3q0qfsei7iFYINVf2lwPyjUKHd3CScy4k/edit#slide=id.g7774542944_0_0
Paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/303
Intro Hello everyone. I am Sergei, I am a PhD student at the University of Luxembourg. I am going to present our joint work with Pedro Moreno-Sanchez and Matteo Maffei from TU Wien on certain aspects of the privacy and scalability of the Lightning Network. The full paper can be found here.
LN intro (for completeness) Let me give some context on what Lightning Network is.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Backups</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2020-05-03-christian-decker-lightning-backups/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2020-05-03-christian-decker-lightning-backups/</guid><description>Topic: Back the f*** up
Location: Potzblitz (online)
Intro (Jeff Gallas) We’re live. Welcome to the fourth episode of Potzblitz, the weekly Lightning talk. Today we have a very special guest, Christian Decker of Blockstream. They also call him Dr Bitcoin. Our co-host today is Michael Folkson from the London BitDevs meetup. He is doing a bunch of Socratic Seminars and has a deep technical knowledge. He will be the perfect person to speak to Christian and has already prepared a bunch of questions.</description></item><item><title>Taproot Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-06-antoine-riard-taproot-lightning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-06-antoine-riard-taproot-lightning/</guid><description>Name: Antoine Riard
Topic: A Schnorr-Taproot’ed Lightning
Location: Advancing Bitcoin
Date: February 6th 2020
Slides: https://www.dropbox.com/s/9vs54e9bqf317u0/Schnorr-Taproot%27ed-LN.pdf
Intro Today Schnorr and Taproot for Lightning, it is a really exciting topic.
Lightning architecture The Lightning architecture for those who are not familiar with it. You have the blockchain as the underlying layer. On top of it you are going to build a channel, you have a HTLC and people are going to spend onions to you.</description></item><item><title>Socratic Seminar 5</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/austin-bitcoin-developers/2020-01-21-socratic-seminar-5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/austin-bitcoin-developers/2020-01-21-socratic-seminar-5/</guid><description>https://www.meetup.com/Austin-Bitcoin-Developers/events/267941700/
https://bitdevs.org/2019-12-03-socratic-seminar-99
https://bitdevs.org/2020-01-09-socratic-seminar-100
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1219817063948148737
LSATs So we usually start off with a lightning-based project demo that he has been working on for a few months.
This is not an original idea to me. This was presented by roasbeef, co-founder of Lightning Labs at the Lightning conference last October. I worked on a project that did something similar. When he presented this as a more formalized specification, it made a lot of sense based on what I was working on.</description></item><item><title>Payment Points</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-conference/2019/2019-10-20-nadav-kohen-payment-points/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-conference/2019/2019-10-20-nadav-kohen-payment-points/</guid><description>Replacing Payment Hashes with Payment Points
The Lightning Conference Day 2 (Stage 2)
Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/15l4h2_zEY4zXC6n1NqsImcjgA0fovl_lkgkKu1O3QT0/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1220453531683115020
Intro My name is Nadav Kohen. I’m a software engineer at Suredbits. I’m going to talk about payment points which have been alluded to throughout the conference by various talks.
Hash Timelocked Contract (HTLC) Routing First of all, some preliminaries, HTLCs. I don’t think I’m going to spend much time on this slide. We all know what they are.</description></item><item><title>Rust Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-conference/2019/2019-10-20-antoine-riard-rust-lightning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-conference/2019/2019-10-20-antoine-riard-rust-lightning/</guid><description>Deploying rust-lightning in the wild
The Lightning Conference Day 2 (Stage 2)
Slides: https://github.com/ariard/talk-slides/blob/master/deploying-rust-lightning-in-the-wild.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1220722130897252352
Intro Hi everyone, super happy to be here at the Lightning Conference. I’ve had an awesome weekend. Today I will talk on rust-lightning a project I’ve been contributing to for a year and a half. To get started, please take photos of the slides, not of me. So the story of rust-lightning. The idea was to build something really flexible, something really modular.</description></item><item><title>Offers and BOLT 12</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-conference/2019/2019-10-19-rusty-russell-offers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-conference/2019/2019-10-19-rusty-russell-offers/</guid><description>Make Me An Offer: Next Level Invoicing
The Lightning Conference Day 1 (Stage 1)
BOLT 11: https://github.com/lightningnetwork/lightning-rfc/blob/master/11-payment-encoding.md
BOLT 12 PR: https://github.com/lightningnetwork/lightning-rfc/pull/798
bolt12.org: https://bolt12.org/
Intro Hi. My name is Rusty Russell and this is actually my official job title at Blockstream, code contributor. It is generic, it is flexible, it is probably a little too humble maybe but that is me. Before we begin the main part of this talk I want to tell you a story.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Payment Pathfinding for Reliability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-conference/2019/lightning-payment-pathfinding-for-reliability/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-conference/2019/lightning-payment-pathfinding-for-reliability/</guid><description>Introduction I&amp;rsquo;m Joost Jager. I work for Lightning Labs. At Lightning Labs, I&amp;rsquo;m a software engineer, and my main focus is on LND. Over the last month, I spent quite some time to improve pathfinding in LND. In this talk, I would like to explain how we optimize pathfinding for the reliability of paths.
Lightning payment pathfinding So we&amp;rsquo;re looking for a path. That&amp;rsquo;s clear. But what do we optimize the path for?</description></item><item><title>A walk through the layers of Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/lightning-network-layer-by-layer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/lightning-network-layer-by-layer/</guid><description>Introduction Good afternoon everyone. My name is Carla. I&amp;rsquo;m one of the Chaincode residents from the summer residency that they ran in New York this year and this afternoon I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking about Lightning. In this talk, I&amp;rsquo;m gonna be walking you through the protocol layer by layer and having a look at the different components that make up the Lightning Network.
I&amp;rsquo;m sure a lot of you are pretty familiar with what the Lightning Network is.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Sphinx And Onion Routing</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/lightning-network-sphinx-and-onion-routing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/lightning-network-sphinx-and-onion-routing/</guid><description>Introduction Hi everyone. I am a developer of rust-lightning, it started in 2018 by BlueMatt. I started contributing about a year ago now. It&amp;rsquo;s a full featured, flexible, spec-compliant lightning library. It targets exchanges, wallet vendors, hardware, meshnet devices, and you can join us on Freenode IRC in the #rust-bitcoin channel which is a really nice one.
Privacy matters Privacy matters on the blockchain. This is the reason why lightning is taking so much time.</description></item><item><title>Lightning network topology, its creation and maintenance</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/lightning-network-topology/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/lightning-network-topology/</guid><description>Introduction Alright. Give me a second to test this. Alright. Antoine has taken you through the routing layer. I&amp;rsquo;m going to take you through what the lightning network looks like today. This is the current topology of the network and how this came about, and some approaches for maintaining the network and making the graph look like we want it to look.
Lightning brief overview There&amp;rsquo;s ideally only two transactions involved in any lightning channel, the commitment transaction and the closure transaction.</description></item><item><title>Routing Problems and Solutions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/2019-09-09-carla-kirk-cohen-routing-problems-and-solutions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/2019-09-09-carla-kirk-cohen-routing-problems-and-solutions/</guid><description>Topic: Routing Problems and Solutions
Location: Tel-Aviv 2019
Introduction I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking about routing in the Lightning Network now. So I&amp;rsquo;m going to touch on how it&amp;rsquo;s currently operating, some issues that you run into when you are routing, and then some potential expansions to the spec which are going to address some of these issues.
We ran through the Lightning Network graph: the nodes of vertices, the channels in this graph of edges.</description></item><item><title>C-Lightning Questions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockstream-webinars/2019-09-04-christian-decker-c-lightning-questions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockstream-webinars/2019-09-04-christian-decker-c-lightning-questions/</guid><description>c-lightning Q and A session
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230527903969841152
Introduction Hello everyone. I’m Christian. I’m a software developer at Blockstream and I work on Lightning, both the specification and the implementation. Today we are going to have a shortish webinar on how to get started with Lightning.
Q and A Q - Is it possible to run c-lightning and lnd on the same host in parallel?
A - It absolutely is. We actually do that on a regular basis to test compatibility between the implementations.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started With C-Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockstream-webinars/2019-07-31-rusty-russell-getting-started-with-c-lightning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockstream-webinars/2019-07-31-rusty-russell-getting-started-with-c-lightning/</guid><description>Getting started with c-lightning
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1231946205380403200
Introduction Hi everyone. We’re actually a couple of minutes early and I think we are going to give a couple of minutes past before we actually start because I think some people will probably be running late particularly with the change in times we had to make after this was announced. While we are waiting it would be interesting to find out a little bit about the attendees’ backgrounds and what they hope to get out of this.</description></item><item><title>Rendezvous Routing</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-28-christian-decker-rendezvous-routing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-28-christian-decker-rendezvous-routing/</guid><description>Rendezvous Routing (Lightning Network)
Location: Chaincode Residency 2019
Slides: https://residency.chaincode.com/presentations/lightning/Rendezvous_Routing.pdf
Transcript by: Caralie Chrisco and Davius Parvin
Introduction Okay, the second part is rendezvous routing. I basically already gave away the trick but I hope you all forgot. So what is rendezvous routing? Anybody have a good explanation of what we are trying to do here? So we have someplace where we meet in the middle, and I don&amp;rsquo;t have to know where you live, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to know where I live, we&amp;rsquo;re all really private.</description></item><item><title>Limitations of Lightweight Clients</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-26-fabrice-drouin-limitations-of-lightweight-clients/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-26-fabrice-drouin-limitations-of-lightweight-clients/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs Lightning Residency 2019
Introduction The limitations it&amp;rsquo;s uh you have to fight when you want to build lightweight clients mobile clients so this again, this is how mobile clients work, you scan payment requests, you have a view of the network that is supposed to be good enough, you compute the routes, you get an HTLC, you get a preimage back you&amp;rsquo;ve paid.
So a Lightning node is a Bitcoin node, as in, you have to be able to create, sign, and send Bitcoin transactions on the Bitcoin network.</description></item><item><title>Path Finding in the Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-26-rene-pickhardt-path-finding-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-26-rene-pickhardt-path-finding-lightning-network/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Residency 2019
Introduction Today I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk a little bit about path finding on the Lightning Network and some part of it will be about the gossip protocol which is like a little bit of a review of what the gossip messages are going to look like. So it&amp;rsquo;s a little bit basic again. But other than that, I&amp;rsquo;ve been told that you seek more for like opinionated talks and recent ideas instead of, like, how the bolts work because you already know all of that.</description></item><item><title>Splicing</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-26-rene-pickhardt-splicing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-26-rene-pickhardt-splicing/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs Lightning Residency 2019
Transcript by: Caralie Chrisco
Introduction So splicing basically means you have a payment channel, you have a certain capacity of a payment channel and you want to change the capacity on the payment channel. But you don&amp;rsquo;t want to change your balance right? For balance change,(inaudible) we&amp;rsquo;ll get some money on it. But splicing really means you want to change the capacity.
I mean the obvious way of doing this is close the channel, make a new channel with the design capacity and you could.</description></item><item><title>The Update Layer</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-26-rene-pickhardt-update-layer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-26-rene-pickhardt-update-layer/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs Lightning Residency 2019
Introduction Maybe we had a wrong impression, you can ask, like in Christian’s talk, as many questions as you want while the presentation is there. So, it&amp;rsquo;s a small disclaimer just saying: these slides are part of a much larger slide set which is open-source and you find notes and, I think, we share slides in the Google Docs anyway.
The outline of the talk is, I’m going to talk about the construction of payment channels in Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Attack Vectors of Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-fabrice-drouin-attack-vectors-of-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-fabrice-drouin-attack-vectors-of-lightning-network/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Residency – Summer 2019
Introduction All right so I&amp;rsquo;m going to introduce really quickly attack vectors on Lightning. I focus on first what you can do with the Lightning protocol, but I will mostly speak about how attacks will probably happen in real life. It&amp;rsquo;s probably not going to be direct attacks on the protocol itself.
Denial of Service So the basic attacks you can have when you&amp;rsquo;re running lightning nodes are denial of service attacks basically.</description></item><item><title>Eltoo</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-christian-decker-eltoo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-christian-decker-eltoo/</guid><description>Eltoo: The (Far) Future of Lightning
Location: Chaincode Labs
Slides: https://residency.chaincode.com/presentations/lightning/Eltoo.pdf
Eltoo white paper: https://blockstream.com/eltoo.pdf
Bitcoin Magazine article: https://bitcoinmagazine.com/articles/noinput-class-bitcoin-soft-fork-simplify-lightning
Intro Who has never heard about eltoo? It is my pet project and I am pretty proud of it. I will try to keep this short. I was told that you all have seen my presentation about the evolution of update protocols. I will probably go pretty quickly. I still want to give everybody the opportunity to ask questions if they have any.</description></item><item><title>Multiple-path Payments (MPP)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-alex-bosworth-mpp/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-alex-bosworth-mpp/</guid><description>Topic: Multiple-path Payments (MPP)
Location: Chaincode Residency 2019
Bigger, Faster, Cheaper - Multiplexing Payments Alex: How to do multiple path payments. So there&amp;rsquo;s a question: why do we even need multiple path payments? So you have a channel &amp;ndash; like &amp;ndash; we don&amp;rsquo;t have them now, so are we really hurting for them? So I kind of like describing different situations where you would need it. So in the first quadrant you can see I have two channels.</description></item><item><title>Onion Routing Deep Dive</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-christian-decker-onion-routing-deep-dive/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-christian-decker-onion-routing-deep-dive/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Residency – Summer 2019
Onion Routing Deep Dive But we&amp;rsquo;ve not seen exactly why we are using an onion, or why we chose this construction of an onion and how this construction of an onion actually looks like. So my goal right now is to basically walk you through the iterations that onion routing packets have done so far, and why we chose this construction we have here.</description></item><item><title>Routing Failures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-fabrice-drouin-routing-failures/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-fabrice-drouin-routing-failures/</guid><description>Introduction So I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about routing failures in lightning. Basically lightning is a network of payment channels and you can pay anyone, you can find a route. In routing in lightning you have two completely different concepts: how to find a route (path finding) and once you have a route how to actually send a payment through the routes to the final destination. This is what Christian showed that&amp;rsquo;s the source routing.</description></item><item><title>Base and Transport Layers of the Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-24-fabrice-drouin-base-and-transport-layers-of-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-24-fabrice-drouin-base-and-transport-layers-of-lightning-network/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs Lightning Residency 2019
Slides: https://residency.chaincode.com/presentations/lightning/Base_Transport.pdf
Introduction Fabrice: The base and transport layer, almost everything was already introduced this morning so it&amp;rsquo;s going to be very quick. So have you visited the lightning repo on GitHub? Who hasn&amp;rsquo;t?
Okay, good. So you&amp;rsquo;ve seen all this? That was a test.
We&amp;rsquo;ve covered almost everything this morning. I&amp;rsquo;m just gonna get back to the base protocol, BOLT 8 and maybe BOLT 9 because I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s been mentioned a lot.</description></item><item><title>Multihop of the Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-24-rene-pickhardt-multihop-in-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-24-rene-pickhardt-multihop-in-lightning/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs Lightning Residency 2019
Slides: https://residency.chaincode.com/presentations/lightning/Multihop_Layer.pdf
Introduction I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about Lightning Network payment channels and the update layer which is basically multihop payments and the outline of this talk is one slide myths about routing that are floating around and I just want to discuss them in the beginning very briefly. Then I will talk about the payment process on the Lightning Network and compare it a little bit with the payment process on Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>HODL Invoices</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/2019-06-09-joost-jager-hodl-invoices/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/2019-06-09-joost-jager-hodl-invoices/</guid><description>Hodl Invoices (Breaking Bitcoin training session)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1146124260324384768
Intro My name is Joost, Michael introduced me already. I’ve been working with Lightning Labs since the middle of last year and during that time I’ve worked on several subprojects within lnd. lnd is the Lightning implementation developed by Lightning Labs. I’m not sure really what the background knowledge is at this point in this three day course. One of those subprojects within lnd is called hodl invoices and this is the topic that I would like to talk about today.</description></item><item><title>Secure Protocols Bip Taproot</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/secure-protocols-bip-taproot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/secure-protocols-bip-taproot/</guid><description>36C7 1A37 C9D9 88BD E825 08D9 B1A7 0E4F 8DCD 0366
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137358557584793600
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06-06-taproot/
slides: https://nickler.ninja/slides/2019-breaking.pdf
Introduction I am going to tlak about something that is a collaboration of many people in the bitcoin community including my colleagues at Blockstream. The bip-taproot proposal was recently posted to the bitcoin-dev mailing list which proposes an improvement for bitcoin.
Disclaimer It&amp;rsquo;s not at all certain that a bip-taproot soft-fork will activate in its current form or at all.</description></item><item><title>Drivechain</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/austin-bitcoin-developers/2019-05-27-drivechain-paul-sztorc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/austin-bitcoin-developers/2019-05-27-drivechain-paul-sztorc/</guid><description>Drivechain: An interoperability layer-2, Described in terms of the lightning network- something you already understand
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1133202672570519552
About me Okay. So here&amp;rsquo;s some things about myself. I&amp;rsquo;ve been a bitcoiner since 2012. I&amp;rsquo;ve published bitcoin research on truthcoin.info blog. I&amp;rsquo;ve presented at Scaling Bitcoin 1, 2, 3, 4, tabconf, and Building on Bitcoin. My background is in economics and statistics. I worked at Yale Econ Department as a statistician for 2.5 years.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Payments</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/lightning-payments/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/lightning-payments/</guid><description>Lightning payments (and more) on the web
CL: Thank you Elizabeth and Stacy for that great talk. Who runs a lightning node here? So a lot of you. Are you guys excited about lightning? Great, we have like four more talks on lightning. Next we have Will O&amp;rsquo;Beirne who will be talking about lightning payments on the web. Big round of applause.
Introduction Hey y&amp;rsquo;all. We&amp;rsquo;re doing a DIY setup here.</description></item><item><title>Ln Present And Future Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/ln-present-and-future-panel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/ln-present-and-future-panel/</guid><description>Lightning network present &amp;amp; future panel
LC: Can everyone hear me now? Alright, alright.
WO: It&amp;rsquo;s getting some good usage. A lot of those are businesses. Definitely it&amp;rsquo;s in the early stage. Elizabeth talked about this. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of things that are mostly for fun, it&amp;rsquo;s not really at ecommerce yet.
LC: That&amp;rsquo;s for lnd?
WO: Sure, and I think Lisa can talk about c-lightning.
LC: I like these different implementations for LN.</description></item><item><title>State Of Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/state-of-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/state-of-lightning-network/</guid><description>Fireside chat on the state of the lightning network
Introduction WP: We have a fireside chat with Stacy Herbert from Kaiser Report and Elizabeth Stark. Some people say she is the CEO of Lightning Network, but she is the CEO of Lightning Labs. Let&amp;rsquo;s invite them on stage.
SH: Did anyone notice the bitcoin price today? How many here are reckless? How many of you have used lightning? Alright, how many are torchbearers?</description></item><item><title>Submarine Swaps</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/submarine-swaps/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/submarine-swaps/</guid><description>Bridging off-chain and on-chain with submarine swaps
Introduction Hi, I work at Lightning Labs. I want to talk about the dawn of hyperloop. It&amp;rsquo;s a new concept.
Hyperloop To zoom out on what problem we&amp;rsquo;re working on here, we had this cool lightning network. But it&amp;rsquo;s, the way the lightning network works, is that it&amp;rsquo;s complementary to the bitcoin network. Each side has its pros and cons. If you want the most effective way to send capital around, you want to leverage both.</description></item><item><title>Taxonomy Of Ln Nodes</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/taxonomy-of-ln-nodes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/taxonomy-of-ln-nodes/</guid><description>Introduction Hello. I work at Blockstream on c-lightning. I am here today to talk to you about a taxonomy of nodes about who&amp;rsquo;s who on the lightning network. I wnat ot go through the tools that have been built, looking through the perspectives of what different nodes are trying to accomplish.
LN map There&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of nodes on the network. Let&amp;rsquo;s look at some stats. There&amp;rsquo;s a little over 8,317 nodes.</description></item><item><title>Lnd 0.6 Beta</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2019-05-02-conner-fromknecht-lnd-0.6-beta/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2019-05-02-conner-fromknecht-lnd-0.6-beta/</guid><description>Conner Fromknecht
SF Lightning Devs
LND 0.6 Beta Deep Dive
Intro lnd 0.6 was about seven months in the making. There’s more things that we could fit into this talk alone but I cherrypicked some of the highlights and things that will have some real world impact on users of the network or people who are using the API or just generally users of lnd. The high level impact on the network going forward and how we plan to scale up for the next 100K channels that come onto the network.</description></item><item><title>JSON Interface</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/boltathon/2019-04-06-rusty-russell-json-interface/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/boltathon/2019-04-06-rusty-russell-json-interface/</guid><description>JSON Interface with c-lightning and Writing Extensions
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230892247345852416
Intro Ok I have top running. We have a plan and we’re going to start from zero. We’re going to clone c-lightning, we’re going to compile it, we’re going to set up a test node. I’m assuming Bitcoin is already installed. We’re going to talk a little about configuring it and stuff like that. All this stuff is useful to see somebody else do.</description></item><item><title>Major Limitations of Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/boltathon/2019-04-06-alex-bosworth-major-limitations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/boltathon/2019-04-06-alex-bosworth-major-limitations/</guid><description>Slides: https://drive.google.com/open?id=1UIHfYdnAWGMvsLhljTgcneCxQAHcWjxg
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1116824776952229890
Intro So I had a Twitter poll to decide what to talk about. People seem pretty interested in the limitations. Where is the line of what Lightning can do and what Lightning can’t do. That’s what I want to talk about. To make it more clear what can be done and what can’t be done.
Every Transaction A Lightning Transaction When I first started really focusing on Lightning I thought what is the goal of Lightning, what is the goal of the Lightning Network?</description></item><item><title>Watchtowers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/boltathon/2019-04-06-conner-fromknecht-watchtowers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/boltathon/2019-04-06-conner-fromknecht-watchtowers/</guid><description>Architecture of LND Watchtowers
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1117427512081100800
discussion: https://www.reddit.com/r/lightningdevs/comments/bd33cp/architecture_of_lnd_watchtowers_presentation_from/
Intro Pretty excited today to speak on the topic of watchtowers. It is something that we at Lightning Labs have been working on for almost a year now. Conceptual proof of concept code to really flushing it out into what would be today more of a full on protocol. Hopefully today we’re going to summarize a year of research into this presentation. I’m looking forward to getting into it with you guys so let’s dive right in.</description></item><item><title>Rust Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2019/2019-02-07-matt-corallo-rust-lightning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2019/2019-02-07-matt-corallo-rust-lightning/</guid><description>Flexible Lightning in Rust
Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/154bMWdcMCFUco4ZXQ3lWfF51U5dad8pQ23rKVkncnns/edit#slide=id.p
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1144256392490029057
Introduction Thanks for having me. I want to talk a little bit about a project I’ve been working on for about a year called rust-lightning. I started it in December so a year and a few months ago. This is my first presentation on it so I’m excited to finally get to talk about it a little bit.
Goals It is yet another Lightning implementation because somehow we needed another one I guess or really not.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Topological Analysis</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-topological-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-topological-analysis/</guid><description>Topological analysis of the lightning network
paper: https://arxiv.org/abs/1901.04972
https://github.com/seresistvanandras/LNTopology
Introduction Knowing the topology is not necessarily a vulnerability, but it gives you a lot of information. If I know Bryan&amp;rsquo;s full node is connected to some other nodes, I will have an easier time to cut Bryan out of the network or launch attacks against him. Knowing the topology is not necessarily a vulnerability, but it&amp;rsquo;s really strong information.
Recent research There were some recent papers published on this topic:</description></item><item><title>Lnd</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/noded-podcast/2018-12-14-laolu-conner-lnd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/noded-podcast/2018-12-14-laolu-conner-lnd/</guid><description>Noded podcast with Laolu Osuntokun and Conner Fromknecht - December 14th 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1089187758931890178
Podcast: https://noded.org/podcast/noded-0360-with-olaoluwa-osuntokun-and-conner-fromknecht/
Pierre: Welcome to the Noded Bitcoin podcast. This is episode 36. We’re joined with Laolu and Conner from Lightning Labs as well as my co-host Michael Goldstein. How’s it going guys?
roasbeef: Not bad
Pierre: So I listened to Laolu on Stephan Livera’s podcast and I would encourage any of our listeners to go listen to that first so that they can hear all about some of the latest developments in lightning.</description></item><item><title>Laolu Osuntokun - Stephan Livera</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2018-12-11-laolu-osuntokun-stephan-livera/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2018-12-11-laolu-osuntokun-stephan-livera/</guid><description>Stephan Livera podcast with Laolu Osuntokun - December 11th 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1090640881873387525
Podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/39
Stephan: Hi Laolu. Thank you very much for coming on the show.
roasbeef: It’s good to be here.
Stephan: It’s been a while since the Lighting Summit was on and now you’re back home. How’s things back home?
roasbeef: Not bad, just the usual back to work, just the regular stuff. Australia was great. I had never been.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Excel Plugin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-26-pierre-rochard-lightning-excel-plugin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-26-pierre-rochard-lightning-excel-plugin/</guid><description>Demo My project is to create a user interface for lightning that might appeal to a different crowd than ours. We’re kind of used to Linux, open source, free software so being in a proprietary environment like Excel is unfamiliar territory for us. And yet I think that there is a large demographic of people who are interested in Bitcoin who work in the business world where they use Excel day to day.</description></item><item><title>C-Lightning API</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-24-christian-decker-c-lightning-api/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-24-christian-decker-c-lightning-api/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs Lightning Residency 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1232313790311436290
Intro Good morning from the last day of presentations. I’m Chris still. Today I will be talking to you about c-lightning, how to develop on it, how to extend it, adapt it to your needs and how to customize it so it fits into whatever you are trying to do. Not whatever we thought you might want to do.
Goals First of all the goals of c-lightning are basically to be fast and lightweight.</description></item><item><title>Bootstrapping Lightning Node</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-elaine-ou-bootstrapping-lightning-node/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-elaine-ou-bootstrapping-lightning-node/</guid><description>Bootstrapping and maintaining a Lightning Node
Slides: https://lightningresidency.com/assets/presentations/Ou_Bootstrapping_and_Maintaining_a_Lightning_Node.pdf
Intro My name ie Elaine. I’ll talk about bootstrapping and maintaining a lightning node. Pretty much all of you have probably already set up a node so this should all be review. You guys will probably know more about this than I do.
Bootstrapping and Maintaining a Lightning Node We’ll start with an overview of how routing works just to understand what the nodes are trying to do and from there we’ll step back and look at ways of finding peers and getting incoming channels and maintaining capacity.</description></item><item><title>Building Lightning Applications</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-alex-bosworth-building-lightning-applications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-alex-bosworth-building-lightning-applications/</guid><description>Slides: https://lightningresidency.com/assets/presentations/Bosworth_Building_Applications.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1116327230135836673
Intro Today I’m going to talk about building on lnd from the perspective of we want to have developers building on lnd. Developers, developers, developers. I just have so many slides today that let’s leave questions to the end if I have any time because I over made slides.
Design Philosophy So what is the big idea behind lnd? What are we thinking about when we’re developing lnd and what do we want lnd to be?</description></item><item><title>Channel Management</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-alex-bosworth-channel-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-alex-bosworth-channel-management/</guid><description>Slides: https://lightningresidency.com/assets/presentations/Bosworth_Channel_Management.pdf
Intro Today I’m going to talk about something a little bit different to building apps. I’m going to talk about becoming a great router. Managing your node so that your node can be routing payments and be a good citizen if you choose to have public channels.
Uptime So basically the big message overall is and I think I’ve said this before, if you have public channels you’re kind of like waving to everybody “please use these channels to do routing”.</description></item><item><title>History of the Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-christian-decker-history-of-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-christian-decker-history-of-lightning/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs Lightning Residency 2018
Introduction Hi I&amp;rsquo;m Chris, as I said like three times before, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about the history of Lightning and history of off-chain protocols or layer two, or you name it, whatever name you want. I like to call them off chain because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t imply a hierarchy of layers but I&amp;rsquo;ll use all three terms interchangeably anyway.
I like to have an interactive presentation so if you have any questions please don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate, just ask.</description></item><item><title>Lightning ≈ Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-christian-decker-lightning-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-christian-decker-lightning-bitcoin/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs Lightning Residency 2018
Introduction Good morning everyone my name is Chris and I&amp;rsquo;m a bitcoiners anonymous. So my job today is basically to tell you why Lightning is Bitcoin and why it&amp;rsquo;s not exactly Bitcoin. So there&amp;rsquo;s a few fundamental differences between Bitcoin on-chain payments and Lightning. I will always call Bitcoin on-chain payments just because it&amp;rsquo;s sort of the classical way of doing it.
The differences between Bitcoin and Lightning are sometimes small, sometimes bigger.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Protocol</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-alex-bosworth-lightning-protocol/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-alex-bosworth-lightning-protocol/</guid><description>The Lightning Protocol, an Application Design Perspective
Slides: https://lightningresidency.com/assets/presentations/Bosworth_The_Lightning_Protocol.pdf
Intro I’m talking about the protocol design and also going through the BOLTs. What I’m going to talk about is also about the BOLTs. The BOLTs are like the spec for Lightning and there’s a bunch of them.
BOLT 00: Build Apps What I try to do is go through the BOLTs and look at only the parts of the BOLTs, the protocol design, that you as an app developer would need to care about.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Optech</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-10/2018-10-09-bitcoin-optech/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-10/2018-10-09-bitcoin-optech/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1049527415767101440
https://bitcoinops.org/
Bitcoin Optech is trying to encourage bitcoin businesses to adopt better scaling techniques and technologies, things like batching, segwit, down the line maybe Schnorr signatures, aggregatable signatures, maybe lightning. Right now we&amp;rsquo;re focusing on things that businesses could be doing right now. Exchanges could be batching, and some aren&amp;rsquo;t. We&amp;rsquo;re talking to those companies and listening to their concerns and what they&amp;rsquo;re doing, and just trying to nudge them in the right direction.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Overview, Channel Factories, Discreet Log Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/lightning-network/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048039589837852672
Introduction I have quite a while to speak. I hope it&amp;rsquo;s not too boring. I&amp;rsquo;ll have an intermission half way through. It&amp;rsquo;s not going to be two hours. It will be more like 80 minutes or something. We are going to talk about payment channels, unidirectional payment channels, lightning channels, homomorphic keys, hash trees, watchtowers, discreet log contracts, oracles, anticipated signatures, DLCS within channels, etc.
I am Tadge Dryja. I work at MIT Digital Currency Initiative.</description></item><item><title>Incentive Problems in the Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-09-18-alex-bosworth-incentive-problems-in-the-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-09-18-alex-bosworth-incentive-problems-in-the-lightning-network/</guid><description>Incentive Problems in the Lightning Network I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about high-level incentive problems in the Lighting Network.
Mechanisms The first thing to think about is that we have two different mechanisms for making Bitcoin and lightning work. One mechanism is math — If you do a SHA 256 of something you don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about incentives, whether that&amp;rsquo;s going to match to the expected result. There&amp;rsquo;s no incentive there.</description></item><item><title>Ant routing for the Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/lightning-routing-ants-pheromones/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/lightning-routing-ants-pheromones/</guid><description>Decentralized anonymous routing algorithm for LN
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014530761398145025
https://twitter.com/rperezmarco/status/1013938984718884866
Introduction I wanted to present some ideas for alternative ideas for routing on LN. This was published on arxiv: 1807.00151 (July 2018).
http://webusers.imj-prg.fr/~ricardo.perez-marco
Overview I am going to talk about what I understand to be decentralized network. Fabrice has already explained most of what is LN about and some history about it. I will just recall a few properties that I need in order to address the mathematical problem of routing.</description></item><item><title>Bootstrapping LN: What have we learned?</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/bootstrapping-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/bootstrapping-lightning-network/</guid><description>acinq
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014531050503065601
My name is Fabrice Drouin. I work with ACINQ. We are a comapny working on printing LN. I am going to talk about what happens, what was the process of bootstrapping and developing lightning and what happened on mainnet.
Timeline Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t know what lightning is? And who has used lightning? Okay, almost everyone. It&amp;rsquo;s an evolution on the idea of payment channels. I think it&amp;rsquo;s from 2011 actually.</description></item><item><title>Single Use Seals</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/single-use-seals/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/single-use-seals/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014168068447195136
I am going to talk about single use seals and ways to use them. They are a concept of building consensus applications and things that need consensus. I want to mention why that matters. What problem are we trying to solve? Imagine my cell phone and I open up my banking app or the banking app or lightning app&amp;hellip; I want to make sure that what I see on my screen is the same as what you see on your screen.</description></item><item><title>Working on Scripts with logical opcodes</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/working-on-scripts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/working-on-scripts/</guid><description>Building on Bitcoin 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014167120417091584
Bitcoin has logical opcodes in bitcoin script. Depending on whose is trying to spend coins or what information they have, they interact with logical opcodes. We could see a simple example here taken from one of the lightning network commitment transcraction scripts. It pushes a key on to the stack so that a checksig can run later. It adds a relative timelock as well. Two people can interact with that script and we can set different constraints on those.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Overview</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/layer2-summit/2018/lightning-overview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/layer2-summit/2018/lightning-overview/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005913055333675009
https://lightning.network/
Introduction First I am going to give a brief overview of how lightning works for those of who you may not be so familiar. Then I am going to discuss three technologies we&amp;rsquo;ll be working on in the next year at Lightning Labs and pushing forward.
Philosophical perspective and scalability Before I do that though, following up on what Neha was saying, I want to give a philosophical perspective on how I think about layer 2 as a scalability solution.</description></item><item><title>Exploring Lnd0.4</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2018-04-20-laolu-osuntokun-exploring-lnd0.4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2018-04-20-laolu-osuntokun-exploring-lnd0.4/</guid><description>Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1pyQgGDUcB29r8DnTaS0GQS6usjw4CpgciQx_-XBVOwU/
The Genesis of lnd First, the genesis of lnd. Here is the first commit of lnd. It was October 27 2015. This is when I was in school still. This was done when I went on break and it was the first major…. we had in terms of code. We talked about the language we’re using, the licensing, the architecture of the daemon. A fun fact, the original name of lnd was actually called Plasma.</description></item><item><title>Cross Curve Atomic Swaps</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-03/2018-03-05-cross-curve-atomic-swaps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-03/2018-03-05-cross-curve-atomic-swaps/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/971827042223345664
Draft of an upcoming scriptless scripts paper. This was at the beginning of 2017. But now an entire year has gone by.
post-schnorr lightning transactions https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/lightning-dev/2018-February/001031.html
An adaptor signature.. if you have different generators, then the two secrets to reveal, you just give someone both of them, plus a proof of a discrete log, and then you say learn the secret to one that gets the reveal to be the same.</description></item><item><title>Hardening Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/hardening-lightning/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/hardening-lightning/</guid><description>Hardening lightning network
Olaoluwa Osuntokun (roasbeef), Lightning Labs
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/959155562134102016
slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/14NuX5LTDSmmfYbAn0NupuXnXpfoZE0nXsG7CjzPXdlA/edit
previous talk (2017): http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/lightning-network-security-analysis/
previous slides (2017): https://cyber.stanford.edu/sites/default/files/olaoluwaosuntokun.pdf
Introduction I am basically going to go over some ways that I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about basically hardening lightning network, in terms of making security better and making the client more scalable itself, and then I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about some issues and pain points that come up when you&amp;rsquo;re doing fees on mainnet. And there&amp;rsquo;s going to be some relatively minor changes that I propose to Bitcoin in this talk.</description></item><item><title>Interview Adam Back Elizabeth Stark</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/interview-adam-back-elizabeth-stark/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/interview-adam-back-elizabeth-stark/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005842855271784449
stark: Thank you Giacomo. Who here had too much fun at the party last night? My voice is going. Hopefully it will stay for this interview. We are lucky to have Adam Back here today, co-founder of Blockstream and inventor of Hashcash (history). He just happened to appear and there was an available spot. Thank you for making this work.
adam3us: Thank you for inviting me.
stark: I&amp;rsquo;m a co-organizer of this event.</description></item><item><title>Neutrino</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-06-06-laolu-osuntokun-neutrino/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-06-06-laolu-osuntokun-neutrino/</guid><description>Neutrino: The Privacy Preserving Bitcoin Light Client
Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1vjJUWOZIaPshjx1svfE6rFZ2lC07n47ifOdzpKWqpb4/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1054031024085258240
Introduction My name is Laolu or Roasbeef on the internet. I’m going to talk about light clients in general and then also what we’re working on in terms of light clients and then also how that factors into the lightning network itself. The talk is called Neutrino because that is the name of our new light client that has been released.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Security Analysis</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/lightning-network-security-analysis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/lightning-network-security-analysis/</guid><description>Security analysis of the lightning network
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/957978915515092992
slides: https://cyber.stanford.edu/sites/default/files/olaoluwaosuntokun.pdf
Introduction My name is Laolu Osuntokun and I work on lightning stuff. I go by roasbeef on the internet. I work at Lightning Labs. I am going to be giving an overview of some security properties and privacy properties of lightning.
State of the hash-lock Before I start, I want to go over the state of the hash-lock which is the current progress to completion and design of lightning.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-07-18-laolu-osuntokun-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-07-18-laolu-osuntokun-lightning-network/</guid><description>Lightning Network Deep Dive
Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1OPijcjzadKkbxvGU6VcVnAeSD_DKb7gjnevBcqhPCW0/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1052238088913788928
Introduction My name is Laolu Osuntokun and I work with Lightning guys and you know me as maybe Roasbeef from the internet, on GitHub, Twitter, everything else. I’ve been Roasbeef for the past 8 years and I’m still Roasbeef that’s how it works. I’m going to give you a deep dive into the lightning network. I remember like 2 years ago when I was learning about Bitcoin initially and I went to these Bitcoin dev meetups in Mission and there was a deep dive and Taariq was the MC there, super friendly guy.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network As A Directed Graph Single Funded Channel Network Topology</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-04-11-lightning-network-as-a-directed-graph-single-funded-channel-network-topology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-04-11-lightning-network-as-a-directed-graph-single-funded-channel-network-topology/</guid><description>http://lightning.network/
slides: http://diyhpl.us/~bryan/papers2/bitcoin/Lightning%20Network%20as%20Directed%20Graph%20Single-Funded%20Channel%20Topology%20-%20Tadge%20Dryja%20-%202016-04-11.pdf
Okay. Hello everyone. Yes, okay, great. Yes. Yeah, I&amp;rsquo;m working on Lightning Network. Bitcoin is great and fun to work on.
Basic super quick summary of Lightning I am going to re-cap lightning network real quick. The basic idea is to have channels between two nodes. A channel, from the perspective of the rest of the world, is just a 2-of-2 multisig output. You can&amp;rsquo;t even tell it&amp;rsquo;s multisig, you just see an address with a 3 in front of the address.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2015-05-26-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2015-05-26-lightning-network/</guid><description>Tadge Dryja Joseph Poon How Lightning Network can offer a solution for bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s scalability problems
http://lightning.network/
slides: https://lightning.network/lightning-network-presentation-sfbitcoinsocial-2015-05-26.pdf
Great to have you guys. They are going to talk about bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s scalability problems. There they are.
Okay, hi. So yeah, I titled it solutions because that sounds more positive than talking about problems. Joseph will go after that and talk about what needs to change and the economics and things like that.</description></item><item><title>Scaling Bitcoin To Billions Of Transactions Per Day</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2015-02-23-scaling-bitcoin-to-billions-of-transactions-per-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2015-02-23-scaling-bitcoin-to-billions-of-transactions-per-day/</guid><description>Scaling Bitcoin To Billions Of Transactions Per Day
http://lightning.network/
Joseph Poon joseph@lightning.network Thaddeus Dryja rx@awsomnet.org We&amp;rsquo;re doing a presentation on the lightning network and micropayments. Right now bitcoin faces some interesting problems, like transactions aren&amp;rsquo;t instant, and micropayments don&amp;rsquo;t work. The transaction fees are 1/10th of a cent or higher depending on the exchange rate. And, &amp;ldquo;bitcoin doesn&amp;rsquo;t scale&amp;rdquo; especially if you have a lot of micropayments. One megabyte blocks? Well, let&amp;rsquo;s increase them.</description></item><item><title>Amiko Pay</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/amiko-pay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/amiko-pay/</guid><description>Amiko Pay aims to become an implementation of the lightning network. So that previous presentation was a great setup. There&amp;rsquo;s a little bit more to Amiko Pay. If you look through the basic design of the lightning network, there&amp;rsquo;s a network of payment channels. There have been several variations of this idea. Lightning Network happens to be the best so far. What Amiko Pay aims to do is to focus on the nodes, and do the routing between nodes.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Failure Modes And The Role Of The Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/bitcoin-failure-modes-and-the-role-of-the-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/bitcoin-failure-modes-and-the-role-of-the-lightning-network/</guid><description>I am going to be talking about bitcoin failure modes, and Joseph will talk about how the lightning network can help. I&amp;rsquo;ll start. We&amp;rsquo;ll start off by saying that bitcoin is working, which is really cool. Blocks starts with lots of zeroes, coins stay put, they move when you tell them to. That&amp;rsquo;s really cool and it works. That&amp;rsquo;s great. This is a good starting place. We should acknowledge that bitcoin can fail.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Protocol Development Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/bitcoin-protocol-development-panel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/bitcoin-protocol-development-panel/</guid><description>Bitcoin protocol development panel
KW: We have some wonderful panelists today. Let&amp;rsquo;s kick it off. Let&amp;rsquo;s start with Eric. Who are you and what role do you play in bitcoin development?
EL: I got into bitcoin in 2011. I had my own network stack. I almost had a full node implementation but I stopped short because it wasn&amp;rsquo;t as well tested or reviewed as Bitcoin Core. So I started to look into the community a little bit.</description></item><item><title>Day 1 Closing Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/day-1-closing-panel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/day-1-closing-panel/</guid><description>Closing panel
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043517333640241152
RS: Thanks guys for joining the panel. We just need to get one more chair. I am going to introduce Alex Petrov here because everyone else was on stage. The closing panel is going to be an overview of what&amp;rsquo;s happening in bitcoin. I want to start with the question I started with last year. What is the current state of bitcoin compared to last year? What has happened?</description></item><item><title>Day 1 Group Summaries</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/day-1-group-summaries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/day-1-group-summaries/</guid><description>Day 1 group summaries
We need two to three minute report backs from each session. Also, note takers. Please email your notes to contact@scalingbitcoin.org so that we can add notes to the wiki. Come join us. Okay, so.
Lightning We discussed routing and several aspects of routing algorithms in the lightning network. We talked about the tradeoff between privacy aspects and reliability in routing. We quickly discovered that after some of the things were already resolved by the papers&amp;ndash; the way how we deal with a general separation and channel transaction fees, is actually quite an interesting discussion topic.</description></item><item><title>Designing Lightning Wallets for the Bitcoin Users</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/lightning-wallet-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/lightning-wallet-design/</guid><description>Good morning everyone. Thank you for being here. Thank you to the organizers for this event. My talk is about designing lightning wallets for bitcoin users. I am talking about UX. But really, UX is a lot more than what wallets look like. It&amp;rsquo;s from bip39 and making backups much easier, to anything you cna imagine, to make it easier for bitcoin to use bitcoin.
I am Patricia Estevao. https://patestevao.com/</description></item><item><title>Discreet Log Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/discreet-log-contracts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/discreet-log-contracts/</guid><description>http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/discreet-log-contracts/
paper: https://adiabat.github.io/dlc.pdf
Hello everyone. I am going to give a talk about discreet log contracts. I am from MIT DCI. I work on lightning network software and discreet log contracts. A quick intro: these are pretty new. I am not sure if they work. This presentation is part of the peer review process. Maybe the math doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. Please let me know. It might also work, though.
It&amp;rsquo;s a system of smart contracts using bitcoin which is similar to lightning network.</description></item><item><title>Fee Management (Lightning Network)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-fabrice-drouin-fee-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-fabrice-drouin-fee-management/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs Lightning Residency 2019
Fabrice: So I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about fee management in Lightning which has been surprisingly one of the biggest operational issues we had when we launched the Lightning Network. So again the idea of Lightning is you have transactions that are not published but publishable, and in our case the problem is what does exactly publishable mean. So it means the UTXO that you’re spending is still spendable.</description></item><item><title>Flare Routing In Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/flare-routing-in-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/flare-routing-in-lightning/</guid><description>Flare: An approach to routing in lightning network
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784745976170999810
I will not be as technical as Olaoluwa was. You have nodes that open up payment channels. This scheme is actually developed at the moment in great detail. So how do you find the channels through which to send payments? So we wanted to propose some initial solution to this.
Routing requirements It should be source routing because we need the privacy.</description></item><item><title>Htlcs Considered Harmful</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/htlcs-considered-harmful/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/htlcs-considered-harmful/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1091033955824881664
Introduction I am here to talk about a design pattern that I don&amp;rsquo;t like. You see HTLCs a lot. You see them in a lot of protocols for cross-chain atomic exchanges and payment channel networks such as lightning. But they have some downsides, which people aren&amp;rsquo;t all familiar with. I am not affiliated with Interledger, but they convinced me that HTLCs were a bad idea and they developed an alternative to replace HTLCs.</description></item><item><title>Improving Bitcoin Smart Contract Efficiency</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2018/improving-bitcoin-smart-contract-efficiency/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2018/improving-bitcoin-smart-contract-efficiency/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/980545280973201410
Introduction I will be talking about discreet log contracts, taproot, and graftroot. Not in that order, the order will actually be taproot, graftroot, and then discreet log contracts.
Quick intro: I&amp;rsquo;m Tadge Dryja. I work here at MIT down the street at Digital Currency Initiative. I was coauthor on the lightning network paper, and I worked on lightning. I also was the author of a paper introducing discreet log contracts.</description></item><item><title>Incentives Tradeoffs Transaction Selection In Dag Based Protocols</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/incentives-tradeoffs-transaction-selection-in-dag-based-protocols/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/incentives-tradeoffs-transaction-selection-in-dag-based-protocols/</guid><description>Yonatan Sompolinsky (The Hebrew University)
Commercial effort to implement DAG-based protocols. No ICO, it&amp;rsquo;s a regular company.
A little bit background of DAG-based protocols. The background to this work is something we have been working at Hebrew University and Yoad. This idea of blockDAG is about layer 1 of bitcoin. And so it&amp;rsquo;s a generalization of the chain structure of blockchain. As such, there are two solutions- lightning network and payment channels, and were scaling up layer 1, and you&amp;rsquo;re scaling up in layer 2, it&amp;rsquo;s complementary solutions.</description></item><item><title>Incentivizing Payment Channel Watchtowers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/incentivizing-payment-channel-watchtowers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/incentivizing-payment-channel-watchtowers/</guid><description>Incentivizing payment channel watchtowers
Georgia Avarikioti, Felix Laufenberg, Jakub Sliwinski, Yuyi Wang and Roger Wattenhofer (ETH Zurich)
Zeta Avarikioti
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048767166823071746
Introduction Hi. Good morning. I am Zeta. I am going to talk about how to incentivize payment channel watchtowers. This is joint work with my collaborators.
Micropayment channels There are many ways to construct channels such as lightning channels and duplex channels. There&amp;rsquo;s hops, you can route payments, and other proposals more recent ones for doing channels in payment networks like sprites, eltoo, all of them although they are different they all share the fundamental nature of channels.</description></item><item><title>Lightning - The Transfer Layer</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-24-fabrice-drouin-the-transfer-layer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-24-fabrice-drouin-the-transfer-layer/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs Lightning Residency 2019
Context Fabrice: Alright so, I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about the payments model we use in lightning, which is mainly the HTLC, and how it works. So what we&amp;rsquo;ve explained so far is that a channel is basically a funding transaction that&amp;rsquo;s been published. And a commitment transaction that spends from the funding transaction but is not published. So the funding transaction is confirmed and it&amp;rsquo;s on-chain and it sends money to A and B.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Routing Security</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-routing-security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-routing-security/</guid><description>Security aspects of LN routing
Joost Jager, Lightning Labs
D146 D0F6 8939 4362 68FA 9A13 0E26 BB61 B76C 4D3A
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137740282139676672
Introduction Together with my colleagues I am building lnd. It&amp;rsquo;s one of the implementations of lightning. In routing, there&amp;rsquo;s the sender of the payment, the intermediate routing nodes that forward payments, and a receiver. I would like to scope this down to looking at security just from the perspective of the sender.</description></item><item><title>Multi Hop Locks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-hop-locks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-hop-locks/</guid><description>Multi-hop locks for secure, privacy-preserving and interoperable payment-channel networks
Giulio Malavolta (Friedrich-Alexander-University Erlangen-Nuernberg), Pedro Moreno-Sanchez (Purdue University), Clara Schneidewind (Vienna University of Technology), Aniket Kate (Purdue University) and Matteo Maffei (Vienna University of Technology)
https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/472.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048476273259900928
This is joint work with my colleagues. I promise I will talk slower than the last talk. In a multi-hop network, the security tool is a hash-time lock contract (HTLC) where the payment is conditioned on revealing the pre-image of a hash function.</description></item><item><title>Network Topologies And Their Scalability Implications On Decentralized Off Chain Networks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/network-topologies-and-their-scalability-implications-on-decentralized-off-chain-networks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/network-topologies-and-their-scalability-implications-on-decentralized-off-chain-networks/</guid><description>slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY2/1_layer2_3_poon.pdf
LN transactions are real Bitcoin transactions. These are real zero-confirmation transactions. What&amp;rsquo;s interesting is that the original idea behind Bitcoin was solving the double-spending problem. When you move off-chain and off-block, you sort of have this opposite situation where you use double-spends to your advantage, spending from the same output, except you have this global consensus of block but you have this local ordering that you use through this lightning system of penalties through which you can update the balances between two people.</description></item><item><title>Onion Routing In Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/onion-routing-in-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/onion-routing-in-lightning/</guid><description>http://lightning.network/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784742298089299969
Privacy-preserving decentralized micropayments
We&amp;rsquo;re excited about lightning because the second layer could be an important opportunity to improve privacy and fungibility. Also, there might be timing information in the payments themselves.
Distributed set of onion routers (OR, cite OG onionrouting paper). Users create circuits with sub-set of nodes. Difficult for oion routers to gain more info than predecessor+successor in path. Low latency - usable within greater internet. Notable success is tor, notable success of routing nodes.</description></item><item><title>Overview Of Bips Necessary For Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/overview-of-bips-necessary-for-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/overview-of-bips-necessary-for-lightning/</guid><description>Scalability of Lightning with different BIPs and some back-of-the-envelope calculations.
slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY2/1_layer2_2_dryja.pdf
I don&amp;rsquo;t have time to introduce the idea of zero-confirmation transactions and lightning. We have given talks about this. There&amp;rsquo;s some documentation available. There&amp;rsquo;s an implementation being worked on. I think it helps a lot with scalability by keeping some transactions off the blockchain. Ideally, many or most transactions. Instead, you would open and close channels. That&amp;rsquo;s all that needs to be on the blockchain.</description></item><item><title>Payment Channel Recovery With Seeds</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/payment-channel-recovery-with-seeds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/payment-channel-recovery-with-seeds/</guid><description>Seed-based payment channel recovery
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1172129077765050368
Introduction Cool. This addresses the lightning network which is a scaling technique for the bitcoin network. A big challenge with the lightning network is that you have these midstates that you need to keep. If you lose them, you&amp;rsquo;re out of luck with your counterparty. We had a lot of talks this morning about how to recover midstates but a lot of them used watchtowers. However, this proposal does not require a watchtower and you can restore midstates knowing nothing but your wallet seed.</description></item><item><title>Plasma Cash</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/plasma-cash/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/plasma-cash/</guid><description>Plasma Cash: Towards more efficient plasma constructions
Non-custodial sidechains for bitcoin utilizing plasma cash and covenants
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1172108023705284609
paper: https://github.com/loomnetwork/plasma-paper/blob/master/plasma_cash.pdf
slides: https://gakonst.com/scalingbitcoin2019.pdf
Introduction We have known how to do these things for at least a year, but the question is how can we find the minimum changes that we can figure out to do in bitcoin if any on how to explore the layer 2 space in a better sense rather than just accepting that lightning network is the dominant solution?</description></item><item><title>Privacy And Fungibility</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/privacy-and-fungibility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/privacy-and-fungibility/</guid><description>Privacy and scalability
Even though Bitcoin is the worst privacy system ever, everyone in the community very strongly values privacy.
There are at least three things: privacy censorship resistance fungibility
The easiest way to censor things is to punish communication, not prevent communication. Privacy is the weakest link in censorship resistance. Fungibility is an absolute necessity for any medium of exchange. The properties of money include fungibility. Without privacy you may not be able to have fungibility.</description></item><item><title>Rebalancing Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/rebalancing-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/rebalancing-lightning/</guid><description>Rebalancing in the lightning network: Analysis and implications
Sebastián Reca (Muun)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048753406628655105
Introduction This talk is going to be about rebalancing in the lightning network. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the implications and about running a lightning node.
Financial costs In the lightning network, routing nodes will incur in financial costs by having their money locked inside channels. They can&amp;rsquo;t use that money elsewhere. They incur a financial cost to doing this activity, at least an opportunity cost.</description></item><item><title>Reproducible Lightning Benchmark</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/reproducible-lightning-benchmark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/reproducible-lightning-benchmark/</guid><description>Reproducible lightning benchmark
https://github.com/dgarage/LightningBenchmarks
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048760545699016705
Introduction Thanks for the introduction, Jameson. I feel like a rock star now. So yeah, I won&amp;rsquo;t introduce myself. I call myself a code monkey the reason is that a lot of the talks in scaling bitcoin can surprise people but I understood very few of them. The reason is that I am more of an application developer. Basically, I try to understand a lot of the talks but if it&amp;rsquo;s too complex then I just wait until some crypto guy makes a proof-of-concept, then I just make something in C# that other people can use.</description></item><item><title>Scriptless Ecdsa</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/scriptless-ecdsa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/scriptless-ecdsa/</guid><description>Instantiating scriptless 2p-ECDSA: fungible 2-of-2 multisigs for bitcoin today
Conner Fromknecht (Lightning Labs)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048483254087573504
maybe https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/472.pdf and https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/lightning-dev/2018-April/001221.html
Introduction Alright. Thank you very much. Thank you Pedro, that was a great segue into what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about. He has been doing work on formalizing multi-hop locks. I want to also talk about what changes might be necessary to deploy this on the lightning network.
History For what it&amp;rsquo;s worth, these dates are rough.</description></item><item><title>Scriptless Scripts With Mimblewimble</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/scriptless-scripts-with-mimblewimble/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/scriptless-scripts-with-mimblewimble/</guid><description>Scriptless scripts with mimblewimble
Andrew Poelstra (andytoshi)
Introduction Hi everyone. I am Andrew Poelstra. I am the research director at Blockstream. I want to talk about deploying scriptless scripts, wihch is something I haven&amp;rsquo;t talked much about over the past year or two.
History Let me give a bit of history about mimblewimble. As many of you know, this was dead-dropped anonymously in the middle of 2016 by someone named Tom Elvis Jedusor which is the French name for Voldemort.</description></item><item><title>Segwit Lessons Learned</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/segwit-lessons-learned/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/segwit-lessons-learned/</guid><description>Lessons learned with segwit in Bitcoin
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785034301272420353
Hi. My name is Greg Sanders. I will be giving a talk about segwit in bitcoin lessons learned. I will also give some takeaways that I think are important. A little bit about myself. I work on Elements Project at Blockstream. I was a reviewer on segwit for Bitcoin Core. How do we scale protocol development? How do we scale review and keep things safe?</description></item><item><title>Statechains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/statechains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/statechains/</guid><description>Statechains: Off-chain transfer of UTXOs
I am the education director of readingbitcoin.org, and I am going to be talking about statechains for off-chain transfer of UTXOs.
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048799338703376385
Statechains This is another layer 2 scaling solution, by avoiding on-chain transactions. It&amp;rsquo;s similar to lightning network. The difference is that coin movement is not restricted. You deon&amp;rsquo;t have these channels where you have to have a path and send an exact amount. There&amp;rsquo;s some synergy with lightning; it&amp;rsquo;s not a replacement for lightning.</description></item><item><title>The Future Of Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/the-future-of-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/the-future-of-lightning/</guid><description>The future of lightning
The year of #craeful and the future of lightning
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043501348606693379
It&amp;rsquo;s great to be back here in Riga. Let&amp;rsquo;s give a round of applause to the event organizers and everyone brought us back here. This is the warmest time I&amp;rsquo;ve ever been in Riga. It&amp;rsquo;s been great. I want to come back in the summers.
Introduction I am here to talk about what has happened in the past year and the future of what we&amp;rsquo;re going to see with lightning.</description></item><item><title>Unlinkable Outsourced Channel Monitoring</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/unlinkable-outsourced-channel-monitoring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/unlinkable-outsourced-channel-monitoring/</guid><description>http://lightning.network/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784752625074012160
Okay. Hi everyone. Check. Wow. Check one two. Okay it&amp;rsquo;s working. And I have 25 minutes. Great. So I am going to talk about unlinkable outsourced channel modeling. Everyone likes channels. You can update states. You can link them together to make a network. This is really great. There are risks. These are additional risks. The price of scalability is eternal vigilance. You have to keep watching your channels.</description></item></channel></rss>