<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Milan (2016) on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/</link><description>Recent content in Milan (2016) on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Schnorr Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/schnorr-signatures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/schnorr-signatures/</guid><description>Topic: Schnorr signatures for Bitcoin
Location: Scaling Bitcoin (Milan)
Slides: URL expired
Pieter Wuille presentation on Schnorr at BPASE 2018: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/schnorr-signatures-for-bitcoin-challenges-opportunities/
Transcript completed by: Bryan Bishop Edited by: Michael Folkson
Intro Today I will be talking about Schnorr signatures for Bitcoin. I want to say a few things in advance. One is even though this is a talk about cryptography and in particular new cryptography I don&amp;rsquo;t consider myself to be a cryptographer.</description></item><item><title>BIP151 Peer Encryption</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/bip151-peer-encryption/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/bip151-peer-encryption/</guid><description>BIP151: Peer-to-peer encryption and authentication from the perspective of end-users
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785046960705339392
Good morning. Thanks for having me here. I would like to talk about the end-user perspective of p2p authentication. I would like to start with a little example of how difficult it is to be aware of end-user issues that they are facing at the front. Who is using a thin client? An &amp;ldquo;SPV&amp;rdquo; wallet on your smartphone? Yeah. Who of you are on iOS?</description></item><item><title>Breaking The Chain</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/breaking-the-chain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/breaking-the-chain/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785144266683195392
http://dpaste.com/1ZYW028
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/milan/client-side-validation/
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong/braiding-the-blockchain/
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/milan/jute-braiding/
Inclusivitiy So it seems like we have two big topics here, one is braiding and one is proof-of-publication. I had a talk in Hong Kong about braiding. The major difference is the inclusive nature. The notion that every block gets a block reward as a way to solve selfish-mining. It&amp;rsquo;s a competition between the orphans that get a reward and the ones that don&amp;rsquo;t that causes a loss of security.</description></item><item><title>Build Scale Operate</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/build-scale-operate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/build-scale-operate/</guid><description>Build - Scale - Operate: The Three Pillars of the Bitcoin Community
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784713580713246720
Good morning. This is such a beautiful conference. Eric and I are excited to speak with you. We are going to outline what our goals are. We want to be clear that we&amp;rsquo;re not here to define vision. Rather, we&amp;rsquo;re here about how to grow vision around how to grow bitcoin from a technical community perspectives. We&amp;rsquo;re going to share some of our challenges with bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Chainbreak</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/chainbreak/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/chainbreak/</guid><description>Table of Contents 1. braids 1.1. Properties of a braid system 1.1.1. Inclusivity 1.1.2. Delayed tx fee allocation 1.1.3. Network size measured by graph structure 1.1.4. cohort algorithm / sub-cohort ordering 1.1.5. outstanding problem - merging blocks of different difficulty 1.2. fee sniping 1.2.1. what even is fee sniping? 1.3. definition of a cohort 1.4. tx processing system must process all txs 1.5. can you have both high blocktime and a braid?</description></item><item><title>Client Side Validation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/client-side-validation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/client-side-validation/</guid><description>Progress on scaling via client-side validation
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785121442602029056
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/milan/breaking-the-chain/
Let&amp;rsquo;s start with what isn&amp;rsquo;t client-side validation. I am going to call this the miner-side approach. Here&amp;rsquo;s some smart contract code. In this example, it&amp;rsquo;s Chronos which is a timestamping contract. What you have here is a contract that stores in ethereum state consensus some hashes as they are received, they are timestamped. And ultimately at some point in the future you could go and ask the ethereum state machine, you know, did you go and get this hash?</description></item><item><title>Coin Selection</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/coin-selection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/coin-selection/</guid><description>Simulation-based evaluation of coin selection strategies
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785061222316113920
Introduction Thank you. ((applause))
Hi. Okay. I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about coin selection. I have been doing this for my master thesis. To take you through what I will be talking about, I will be shortly outlining my work, then talking about coin selection in general. And then the design space of coin selection. I will also be introducing the framework I have been using for simulating coin selection.</description></item><item><title>Collective Signing</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/collective-signing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/collective-signing/</guid><description>Enhancing bitcoin security and performance with strong consistency via collective signing
EPFL
Eleftherios Kokoris Kogias
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785102844839985153
We are starting the session called &amp;ldquo;breaking the chain&amp;rdquo;. We will first have collective signing presentation. Thank you.
This is joint work with some collaborators.
What we have now is that real-time verification is not safe. What we managed to get is that we get transaction commitment in about 20-90 seconds at close to 1,000 transactions/second.</description></item><item><title>Covenants</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/covenants/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/covenants/</guid><description>Bitcoin covenants: Opportunities and challenges
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785071789705728000
We published this last February at an academic workshop. The work itself has interesting ramifications. My real goal here is to start a conversation and then do a follow-up blog post where we collate feedback from the community. We would like to add this to Bitcoin Core. Covenants.
This all started from a very basic and simple observation about the current status of our computing infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>Day 1 Group Summaries</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/day-1-group-summaries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/day-1-group-summaries/</guid><description>Day 1 group summaries
We need two to three minute report backs from each session. Also, note takers. Please email your notes to contact@scalingbitcoin.org so that we can add notes to the wiki. Come join us. Okay, so.
Lightning We discussed routing and several aspects of routing algorithms in the lightning network. We talked about the tradeoff between privacy aspects and reliability in routing. We quickly discovered that after some of the things were already resolved by the papers&amp;ndash; the way how we deal with a general separation and channel transaction fees, is actually quite an interesting discussion topic.</description></item><item><title>Day 2 Group Summaries</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/day-2-group-summaries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/day-2-group-summaries/</guid><description>Day 2 group summaries
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785151245883412480
Our epic journey in Milan is coming to an end. Let&amp;rsquo;s get seated. Each group is going to have a maximum of 3 minutes to report back. First let&amp;rsquo;s have collaboration between bitcoin community and academia.
Collaboration between bitcoin community and academia In the first half the workshop, 6 universities gave introductions of their activities and relationship to engineering and companies. We share the fact that most universities have joint research work with companies.</description></item><item><title>Fast Difficulty Adjustment</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/fast-difficulty-adjustment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/fast-difficulty-adjustment/</guid><description>Fast difficulty adjustment using a low-pass finite impulse response filter
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785107422323085312
slides https://scalingbitcoin.org/milan2016/presentations/Scaling%20Bitcoin%203%20-%20Mark%20Friedenbach.pdf
Introductions I work at Blockstream Labs. This work is based on work I did in 2013 which is now only being presented. If there are any control engineers, I would encourage you. I am going to cover some mistakes that have been covered in the industry on alternative networks and proposals.
Difficulty adjustment Difficulty adjustment happens every 2016 blocks in bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Flare Routing In Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/flare-routing-in-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/flare-routing-in-lightning/</guid><description>Flare: An approach to routing in lightning network
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784745976170999810
I will not be as technical as Olaoluwa was. You have nodes that open up payment channels. This scheme is actually developed at the moment in great detail. So how do you find the channels through which to send payments? So we wanted to propose some initial solution to this.
Routing requirements It should be source routing because we need the privacy.</description></item><item><title>Fungibility Overview</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/fungibility-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/fungibility-overview/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784676022318952448
Introduction Alright. So let&amp;rsquo;s get started. Okay. Why fungibility? Let&amp;rsquo;s start. What does fungibility mean? Bitcoin is like cash. The hope is that it&amp;rsquo;s for immediate and final payments. To add some nuiance there, you might have to wait for some confirmations. Once you receive a bitcoin, you have a bitcoin and that&amp;rsquo;s final. So even with banks and PayPal, who sometimes shutdown accounts for trivial reasons or sometimes no reason at all, it&amp;rsquo;s typically not the case that it&amp;rsquo;s someone who sent you money&amp;hellip; if you were selling something on ebay, and someone bought an item from you, and that person had an account shutdown, the money you received will not be removed from your account.</description></item><item><title>Intro</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/intro/</guid><description>Introduction
Good morning. Glad to see many of you again. My name is Anton Yemelyanov. I am one of the organizers of this event. On behalf of Scaling Bitcoin planning committee, I would like to welcome everybody here to the third scaling event. We&amp;rsquo;re holding this event here in Milan. Milan has a really vibrant community. It has been a real pleasure working with everyone here to create this event. The goal of Scaling as everybody knows is to get everyone together in a single place, all engineers and academic community so that we can discuss different scaling approaches and see how they can be applied to bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Joinmarket</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/joinmarket/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/joinmarket/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784681036504522752
slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/milan2016/presentations/D1%20-%202%20-%20Adlai%20Chandrasekhar.pdf
Finding a risk-free rate for Bitcoin
Joinmarket, just to clear up a misconception&amp;hellip; Joinmarket, like bitcoin, it is a protocol. Not a company. The protocol is defined by an open-source reference implementation. There are other versions of the code out there. It&amp;rsquo;s entirely, I guess you could say it&amp;rsquo;s voluntary like bitcoin. Those of you who might have less of a finance background might not be familiar with the term risk-free rate.</description></item><item><title>Jute Braiding</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/jute-braiding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/jute-braiding/</guid><description>Jute: New braiding techniques to achieve significant scaling gains
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785116246257856512
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong/braiding-the-blockchain/
Introduction Okay, hello. My name is David Vorick. I have been with bitcoin since 2011. I have been a full-time blockchain engineer since about 2014. I run an altcoin for decentralized cloud storage called Sia. Today I am going to be talking about braiding which basically means we take the straight line blockchain of bitcoin and we allow blocks to have multiple parents.</description></item><item><title>Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/lightning/</guid><description>Lightning work group session
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784783992478466049
You have a network. Anyone can join the network. You have two points and you want to do route finding between those two points. To be clear, this is a network of channels. It is similar to the internet, but it is not the internet. How do you find such a route? It&amp;rsquo;s easy when you find all the implements of the network. Some of the information changes frequently.</description></item><item><title>Mimblewimble</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/mimblewimble/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/mimblewimble/</guid><description>Mimblewimble: private, massively-prunable public blockchains
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784696648597405696
slides: http://diyhpl.us/~bryan/papers2/bitcoin/mimblewimble-2016-scaling-bitcoin-slides.pdf
Hi, I am from Blockstream. I am here to talk about Mimblewimble. Mimblewimble is not mine. It&amp;rsquo;s from the dark lord. I am going to start with the history of the paper. It has been in the news a little bit. I will talk about the transaction structure, the block structure, try to explain the trust model and argue that it&amp;rsquo;s almost as strong as bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>On The Security And Performance Of Proof Of Work Blockchains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/on-the-security-and-performance-of-proof-of-work-blockchains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/on-the-security-and-performance-of-proof-of-work-blockchains/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785066988532068352
As most of you might know, in bitcoin and blockchains, the information is very important. Every node should receive the blocks in the network. Increase latency and risk network partition. If individual peers do not get the information, they could be victims of selfish mining and so on. Multiple blockchains has been proposed, multiple reparameterizations like litecoin, dogecoin, ethereum and others. One of the key changes they did was the block interval time.</description></item><item><title>Onion Routing In Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/onion-routing-in-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/onion-routing-in-lightning/</guid><description>http://lightning.network/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784742298089299969
Privacy-preserving decentralized micropayments
We&amp;rsquo;re excited about lightning because the second layer could be an important opportunity to improve privacy and fungibility. Also, there might be timing information in the payments themselves.
Distributed set of onion routers (OR, cite OG onionrouting paper). Users create circuits with sub-set of nodes. Difficult for oion routers to gain more info than predecessor+successor in path. Low latency - usable within greater internet. Notable success is tor, notable success of routing nodes.</description></item><item><title>Segwit Lessons Learned</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/segwit-lessons-learned/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/segwit-lessons-learned/</guid><description>Lessons learned with segwit in Bitcoin
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785034301272420353
Hi. My name is Greg Sanders. I will be giving a talk about segwit in bitcoin lessons learned. I will also give some takeaways that I think are important. A little bit about myself. I work on Elements Project at Blockstream. I was a reviewer on segwit for Bitcoin Core. How do we scale protocol development? How do we scale review and keep things safe?</description></item><item><title>Sidechains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/sidechains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/sidechains/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784767020290150400
slides https://scalingbitcoin.org/milan2016/presentations/D1%20-%209%20-%20Paul.pdf
Before we begin, we will explain how the workshops will work upstairs. There will be some topics and room numbers. Now we will start the next presentation on sidechain scaling with Paul Sztorc. Thank you everyone.
Thanks a lot. So this talk will be a little different. Scaling via strategy, not physics. This will not change the kilobytes sent over&amp;ndash; it will, just not in the literal sense.</description></item><item><title>Timestamping</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/timestamping/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/timestamping/</guid><description>slides https://scalingbitcoin.org/milan2016/presentations/D1%20-%20A%20-%20Riccardo.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784773221610586112
Hi everybody. I attended Montreal and Hong Kong. It&amp;rsquo;s a pleasurable to be here in Milan giving a talk about scaling bitcoin. I am going to be talking about scalable and accountable timestamping. Why timestamping at this conference? Then I will talk about aggregating timestamps. Also there needs to be a timestamping proof format. I will describe two of the formats for this purpose, including opentimestamps and chainpoint.</description></item><item><title>Tumblebit</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/tumblebit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/tumblebit/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784686167052709888
Hi. So I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking about tumblebit. It&amp;rsquo;s our untrusted private bitcoin payment system. Tumblebit provides payments which are private. They provide set anonymity when used as a classic tumbler. They are untrusted. The tumbler can&amp;rsquo;t violate your privacy, and can&amp;rsquo;t steal your coins. It&amp;rsquo;s also scalable. It&amp;rsquo;s compatible and works with today&amp;rsquo;s bitcoin. There are no malleability concerns. We&amp;rsquo;re going to rely on the constrained opcodes that currently exist in bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Unlinkable Outsourced Channel Monitoring</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/unlinkable-outsourced-channel-monitoring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/unlinkable-outsourced-channel-monitoring/</guid><description>http://lightning.network/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784752625074012160
Okay. Hi everyone. Check. Wow. Check one two. Okay it&amp;rsquo;s working. And I have 25 minutes. Great. So I am going to talk about unlinkable outsourced channel modeling. Everyone likes channels. You can update states. You can link them together to make a network. This is really great. There are risks. These are additional risks. The price of scalability is eternal vigilance. You have to keep watching your channels.</description></item></channel></rss>