<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>research on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/research/</link><description>Recent content in research on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Research wishlist</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2022-10/2022-10-12-research-wishlist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2022-10/2022-10-12-research-wishlist/</guid><description>https://docs.google.com/document/d/1oRCeDzY3zH2ZY-BUYIVfJ1GMkvLlqKHWCFdtS62QWAo/edit
Introduction In spirit of the conversation happening today earlier, I&amp;rsquo;ll give some motivation. In general there is a disconnect between academic researchers and people who work in open-source software. It&amp;rsquo;s a pity because these two groups are interested in bitcoin, they love difficult questions and working on them, and somehow it seems like the choice of questions and spirit of work is sometimes not aligned to the best of bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Checking Bitcoin balances privately</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/checking-bitcoin-balances-privately/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/checking-bitcoin-balances-privately/</guid><description>In this video, the Wasabi Research Club delves into the topic of checking Bitcoin balances privately. They discuss the use of homomorphic encryption and private information retrieval to protect users&amp;rsquo; privacy when querying data from a server. They explore different solutions and strategies to address challenges such as address linkability, block retrieval, and the scalability and cost of checking balances. The team also emphasizes the need for an open standard for private information retrieval to ensure decentralization. They discuss the use of Tor and homomorphic encryption together, as well as the possibility of batching requests to improve efficiency. The video concludes by highlighting the ongoing research and exploration of potential solutions to ensure private querying of Bitcoin balances and more&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin R&amp;D Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2022/bitcoin-randd-panel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2022/bitcoin-randd-panel/</guid><description>Ayush: 00:00:07
My name is Ayush Khandelwal. I am a software engineer at Google. I run a tech crypto-focused podcast on the side. And I have some amazing guests with me. So if you want to introduce yourself, what do you work on? And yeah, just get us started.
Jeremy: 00:00:31
I am Jeremy Rubin. I am a class of 2016 MIT alumni, so it&amp;rsquo;s good to be back on campus.</description></item><item><title>Block Building</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/block-building/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/block-building/</guid><description>Postdoc Researcher Clara joins Murch to discuss their block building research. They cover their proposal, which outlines suggested improvements to the current Bitcoin Core block building algorithm using candidate sets</description></item><item><title>Sydney Socratic Seminar</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-07-06-socratic-seminar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-07-06-socratic-seminar/</guid><description>Name: Socratic Seminar
Topic: Fee bumping and layer 2 protocols
Location: Bitcoin Sydney (online)
Video: No video posted online
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Agenda: https://github.com/bitcoin-sydney/socratic/blob/master/README.md#2021-07
First IRC workshop on L2 onchain support: https://lists.</description></item><item><title>Sydney Socratic Seminar</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-06-01-socratic-seminar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-06-01-socratic-seminar/</guid><description>Topic: Agenda in Google Doc below
Video: No video posted online
Google Doc of the resources discussed: https://docs.google.com/document/d/1E9mzB7fmzPxZ74WZg0PsJfLwjpVZ7OClmRdGQQFlzoY/
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Bitcoin Problems (Lloyd Fournier) https://bitcoin-problems.github.io/
This is Bitcoin Problems, it is a Jekyll website I put on GitHub.</description></item><item><title>Discrete Log Contract Specification</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/discrete-log-contract-specification/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/discrete-log-contract-specification/</guid><description>Today&amp;rsquo;s WRC episode includes Nadav Kohen and Benthecarman discuss the use of Discrete Log Contracts (DLCs) and their potential benefits and challenges. They explain that DLCs can enable various applications such as betting, options contracts, insurance, and synthetic assets. They highlight the advantages of DLCs, including high liquidity and fast trading of futures, especially once implemented on the Lightning Network. However, they also acknowledge that there may still be a need for centralized solutions depending on the specific use case. The speakers delve into the technical aspects of DLCs, including the transition to Schnorr signatures and the privacy implications of using DLCs. They also discuss the role of oracles in DLCs and the potential for coin joints with DLCs. Overall, the speakers provide a detailed overview of DLCs and their potential applications in the cryptocurrency space.</description></item><item><title>CJDNS</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/cjdns/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/cjdns/</guid><description>This WRC episode shows Caleb DeLisle, the creator of the CJDNS project, discussing the benefits of decentralized mesh networking and its potential impact on the centralized internet controlled by companies. DeLisle explains the adversary tolerance of CJDNS and its use of public keys for communication verification. He also addresses concerns about the environmental impact of crypto mining and argues that it facilitates the transition to renewable energy sources. DeLisle emphasizes the attacks on decentralized finance and crypto by centralized entities and the importance of unity in the crypto community. He highlights the creation of Packet Crypt, a bandwidth-hard proof of work that incentivizes building out large amounts of bandwidth. DeLisle asserts the need to prioritize privacy, robustness, and resilience in the face of attacks and the value of positive engagement with policymakers. He also discusses the differences between CJDNS and other networking solutions, highlighting CJDNS&amp;rsquo;s focus on infrastructure and resilient internet access. In addition, DeLisle mentions the potential for individuals to provide internet access to their neighbors and the financing possibilities for the Packet Network Steward. Finally, he touches on the use of Rust programming language for code review and the productivity improvements it brings in terms of security.</description></item><item><title>Sydney Socratic Seminar</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-02-23-socratic-seminar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-02-23-socratic-seminar/</guid><description>Topic: Agenda in Google Doc below
Video: No video posted online
Google Doc of the resources discussed: https://docs.google.com/document/d/1VAP4LNjHHVLy9RJwpQ8LqXEUw79z5TTZxr9du_Z0-9A/
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
PoDLEs revisited (Lloyd Fournier) https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/lightning-dev/2021-January/002929.html
We’ll start with me talking about my research into UTXO probing attacks on Lightning in the dual funding proposal.</description></item><item><title>Socratic Seminar</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chicago-bitdevs/2020-08-12-socratic-seminar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chicago-bitdevs/2020-08-12-socratic-seminar/</guid><description>Topic: Agenda below
Video: No video posted online
BitDevs Solo Socratic 4 agenda: https://bitdevs.org/2020-07-31-solo-socratic-4
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have given permission for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Bitcoin Core P2P IRC Meetings https://github.com/bitcoin-core/bitcoin-devwiki/wiki/P2P-IRC-meetings
They are starting P2P meetings for the Bitcoin protocol now.</description></item><item><title>CoinSwaps</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/2020-06-15-coinswap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/2020-06-15-coinswap/</guid><description>Intro (Aviv Milner) Today we are talking about CoinSwaps, massively improving Bitcoin privacy and fungibility. A lot of excitement about CoinSwaps so hopefully we can touch on some interesting things.
CoinSwaps (Belcher 2020) https://gist.github.com/chris-belcher/9144bd57a91c194e332fb5ca371d0964
This is a 2020 ongoing GitHub research paper that Chris Belcher has been working on. You can view the original file here. It is heavily based on the 2013 work by Greg Maxwell.
Wasabi Research Club Just a reminder of what we have been doing.</description></item><item><title>A Quantitative Analysis of Security, Anonymity and Scalability for the Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2020-05-09-sergei-tikhomirov-lightning-privacy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2020-05-09-sergei-tikhomirov-lightning-privacy/</guid><description>Location: Lightning Hacksprint (Fulmo)
Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1H9EdrhjQ9x3q0qfsei7iFYINVf2lwPyjUKHd3CScy4k/edit#slide=id.g7774542944_0_0
Paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/303
Intro Hello everyone. I am Sergei, I am a PhD student at the University of Luxembourg. I am going to present our joint work with Pedro Moreno-Sanchez and Matteo Maffei from TU Wien on certain aspects of the privacy and scalability of the Lightning Network. The full paper can be found here.
LN intro (for completeness) Let me give some context on what Lightning Network is.</description></item><item><title>Anonymous Credentials</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/anonymous-credentials/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/anonymous-credentials/</guid><description>Jonas Nick discusses anonymous credentials and their applications in this section. Anonymous credentials involve getting a blinded token signed by a server, where the server does not see the message being signed. These tokens contain attributes that can be selectively revealed, and range proofs can be used to verify attributes without revealing additional information. The speaker highlights the flexibility and security of anonymous credentials and how they improve on traditional signatures. They also discuss advancements in these credentials, such as mercurial signatures and delegateable anonymous credentials. The speaker mentions the work of Del Tauri and their solution for creating a divisible e-cash system using homomorphic cryptographic commitments, range proofs, and blind signature schemes. They also discuss the merging and breaking of anonymous credentials, as well as reissuing tokens without exposing the individual values. The implementation and linkability of credentials are also explored in the conversation. Overall, the participants express the need for further study and propose focusing on the cryptography part of the scheme in the next session.</description></item><item><title>Atomic Multi-Channel Updates with Constant Collateral in Bitcoin-Compatible Payment-Channel Networks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/atomic-multi-channel-updates/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/atomic-multi-channel-updates/</guid><description>https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/atomic-multi-channel-updates/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230929981011660800
Introduction Matteo got sick and couldn&amp;rsquo;t come. His coauthors couldn&amp;rsquo;t come either. So a talk was pre-recorded and will be played now. Our work is about realizing atomic multi-channel updates with constant collateral in bitcoin.
Scalability issues We all know that blockchains have scalability issues. Public verifiability means we have to store each transaction on the blockchain. The transaction rate of bitcoin is far from being satisfactory. We can reach up to about 10 transactions/second in bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Beyond 51% attacks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/beyond-hashrate-majority-attacks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/beyond-hashrate-majority-attacks/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230624835996250112
Introduction Alright let&amp;rsquo;s get started with the next session. Vitalik is from Canada. He is a former writer for Bitcoin Magazine and can often be seen wearing unicorn shirts. He will be telling us about &amp;ldquo;Beyond 51% attacks&amp;rdquo;. Take it away.
Okay, so hello everyone. Hi. Okay. I will start by reminding everyone that 51% attacks are in fact bad. Bear with me for a few minutes. Is this better?</description></item><item><title>Competitive equilibria between staking and on-chain lending</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/competitive-equilibria-staking-lending/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/competitive-equilibria-staking-lending/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230581977289379840
https://arxiv.org/pdf/2001.00919v1.pdf
See also &amp;ldquo;Stress testing decentralized finance&amp;rdquo; https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/stress-testing-decentralized-finance/
Introduction There have been some odd finanical attacks in the DeFi space and also on staking. This talk aims to show that the threat model for staking is definitively different from that of proof-of-work, and these financial attacks need to be part of the threat model.
Agenda I&amp;rsquo;ll go over some high level overview of intuitive market dynamics, then we will build up an agent-based model that correctly goes across multiple participants to stress test staking situations, then we go through the various assumptions, and at a high-level I&amp;rsquo;ll give some formal probability statements without proofs, and finally I have simulation results to discuss which can give you some idea about how to design a monetary policy.</description></item><item><title>Proof-of-Stake Longest Chain Protocols Revisited</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/proof-of-stake/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/proof-of-stake/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230646529230163968
Introduction Thanks. I am the last talk of the session so I better make it interesting, and if not interesting then short at least. I am going to talk about proof-of-stake. This is collaboration with a few people. Vivek Bagaria, &amp;hellip; et al.
Proof-of-stake prism The starting point of this project was to come up with a proof-of-stake version of prism, which we just saw in the last talk. Prism has good latency and very high throughput and it also inherits the simplicity of the longest-chain protocol because its security is maintained by the longest chain protocol on each of the 1000 voting chains.</description></item><item><title>Linking Anonymous Transactions via Remote Side-Channel Attacks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/linking-anonymous-transactions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/linking-anonymous-transactions/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230214874908655617
paper: https://crypto.stanford.edu/timings/paper.pdf
Introduction This is going to be talking about linking anonymous transactions in zcash and monero. Thanks for the introduction. I am going to be talking about remote side-channel attacks on anonymous transactions. This will be with respect to zcash and monero. Full disclosure, we disclosed all of the things I am talking about here today and everything has been fixed. No need to worry.
This is joint work with Dan Boneh and Kenny Paterson.</description></item><item><title>Opening Remarks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/opening-remarks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/opening-remarks/</guid><description>Opening remarks
http://bsafe.network/events/codefi_stanford_2020/
https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229833591716102144
Good morning. Let us start this workshop. I am a researcher at Georgetown University and it is my pleasure to host this workshop. CoDeFi is a workshop about coordination of decentralized finance. This unfortunately shares a name with a Consensys product. CoDeFi contains CoDe and DeFi. This is a multi-stakeholder workshop to discuss stakeholders that have never met before. I think we have regulators here, and engineers here, and researchers here, and business people here.</description></item><item><title>Regulatory Pain Points</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/regulatory-pain-points/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/regulatory-pain-points/</guid><description>Regulatory pain points
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229838162827993088
Introduction Hi, good morning everyone. I am a Japanese financial regulator at JFSA. My goal is to promote financial innovations and still ensure the financial stability and various regulatory goals. I have nearly 10 years experience as a regulator. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a strong background in technology, so I hope I can rely on the other stakeholders on this. I am now in Washington DC doing research on blockchain and governance policy.</description></item><item><title>Coinshuffle++ (Part 2)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/coinshuffle-plusplus-part-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/coinshuffle-plusplus-part-2/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s episode Tim Ruffing explores the concept of disruption in the Coinshuffle++ protocol and how it can be detected. He explains that the protocol passively observes messages and their outcomes, without knowing which message belongs to each participant. The speaker also discusses the practicality of blocking someone from the protocol, mentioning the role of network setting and the potential power of an attacker. Additionally, Ruffing highlights the importance of multiple communication rounds, protocols for key exchange, and the need for peers to verify if the protocol has been disrupted. Further Tim explains the concept of introducing another broadcast round in Coinshuffle++ to avoid disruption. By replacing one broadcast with another, the protocol ensures that if one message is disrupted, all messages are disrupted. This eliminates the need for a broadcast round to check for disruption, as participants can simply look at the list of messages and determine if their own message is there or not. This approach provides a guarantee of message integrity without additional broadcasts. Ruffing also addresses the limitations of Coinshuffle++, such as the lack of privacy in transactions with unequal inputs and the inability to pay while mixing. He discusses potential solutions for the anonymity of payments and emphasizes the benefits of Coinshuffle++ for coin shuffling. The timing and trust aspects of the protocol are also discussed, with a mention of potential delays and the need to trust other peers. Overall, Coinshuffle++ offers improvements in message integrity and coin mixing, but there is room for further development in addressing certain limitations and ensuring robust anonymity.</description></item><item><title>CoinShuffle++ (Part 1)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/coinshuffle-plusplus-part-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/coinshuffle-plusplus-part-1/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s episode Tim Ruffing introduces the CoinShuffle++ protocol and explains its key components. He describes how the protocol uses power sums and polynomial roots to ensure secure messaging between participants. The protocol consists of four stages: Dimi Hellman key exchange, commitment, DC net, and confirmation. The protocol handles malicious peers by revealing secret keys and excluding them in the next round. Ruffing also highlights the scalability of the CoinShuffle++ protocol, as it can accommodate a large number of participants and complete the process in a relatively short time. The use of dice mix enhances the efficiency of the protocol compared to its predecessor, CoinShuffle. Futher Tim dives into the challenges of implementing CoinShuffle++, a decentralized protocol for coinjoining cryptocurrencies. He highlights the issues caused by varying internet connection speeds and round communication, leading to slower performance. Ruffing also discusses concerns about the negotiation process and cryptography affecting communication speed. Additionally, he acknowledges the complexity of the topic and expresses a desire to simplify it for wider understanding and implementation. Overall, Ruffing emphasizes the importance of maintaining privacy in peer-to-peer transactions and the potential of cryptography in various applications.</description></item><item><title>CoinShuffle</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/coinshuffle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/coinshuffle/</guid><description>CoinShuffle is a decentralized coinjoin protocol that aims to address the privacy and centralization issues of traditional coinjoins. Participants can anonymously submit their addresses in a process that uses encryption to prevent linking the addresses to specific individuals. The addresses are then shuffled using secure multi-party computation, creating coinjoin outputs that include inputs from all participants. CoinShuffle eliminates the need for a central coordinator and is resilient to denial of service attacks. However, the decryption process is sequential and the time cost increases with the number of participants. The protocol also has measures to handle misbehaving participants and failed rounds. Additionally, alternative approaches such as using mixnets and integrating with other infrastructures like the Lightning Network are discussed. Overall, CoinShuffle provides a viable solution for decentralized and coordinated coinjoins, but the performance is dependent on the number of participants. Further we discuss the importance of integrating second layer technologies like the Lightning Network in a private way and the challenges of achieving efficiency in coin mixing. They propose steps to improve the space efficiency of coin mixing and finding algorithms that perform well in simulations. They also explore the trade-off between space efficiency and privacy, suggesting that higher coin denominations could be more efficient and private. They discuss the idea of using existing data to simulate mixing transactions and score mixes based on real-world data. They also mention the possibility of using the knapsack algorithm for scoring and discuss the challenge of arranging inputs and outputs in a trustless manner. The speakers plan to explore different mixing networks and techniques, such as cache fusion, to improve coordination and trustlessness.</description></item><item><title>SNICKER</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/snicker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/snicker/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s episode Adam Gibson discusses various aspects of the SNICKER protocol. He introduces the concept of non-interactive coinjoin and how SNICKER aims to address the privacy and coordination issues of current coinjoin systems. He explains the process of constructing a transaction in the SNICKER protocol, including the use of shared secrets, diffie-hellman key exchange, and the role of participants in signing and validating the transaction. He also explores the potential improvements and future developments of SNICKER, such as competitive proposals and encryption methods. Overall, this section provides a comprehensive overview of the SNICKER protocol and its potential applications in improving the privacy and efficiency of Bitcoin transactions.
Later on the discussions revolve around the efficiency and privacy of retrieving proposals from a receiver, the potential usefulness of SNICKER outside of mobile devices, the implementation of SNICKER as a proof-of-concept, analyzing different blockchain transactions, and expressing gratitude for the insightful presentation and interest in future sessions. There is also a focus on investigating different protocols like CashShuffle and CoinShuffle, as well as the possibility of implementing CoinJoin. The participants express their interest in exploring these topics further in future discussions.</description></item><item><title>Knapsack Mixing</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/knapsack-mixing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/knapsack-mixing/</guid><description>In this video, the participants of the Wasabi Research Club discuss the concept of knapsack mixing and its potential for privacy in Bitcoin transactions. They explain the process of merging inputs and outputs to create sub-transactions, and how different versions of the knapsack mixing algorithm have improved over time. However, they acknowledge that perfect anonymity is difficult to achieve and there are computational complexities involved. They also discuss the challenges of handling transaction fees and the difficulty of implementing efficient algorithms for finding all possible mappings and partitions. Overall, the speaker believes that knapsack mixing has the potential for anonymity but more research and testing is needed.
Furthermore, they discuss various aspects of knapsack mixing, including the potential benefits and limitations. They explore the possibility of combining multiple inputs in a transaction and its impact on privacy. The necessity of calculating mappings in Wasabi is also debated, with the suggestion that it could help identify bottlenecks in blockchain analysis companies. The participants discuss the idea of setting a lower bound for the number of participants and outputs in a transaction to ensure computational privacy. Additionally, they consider the possibility of allowing non-mixing participants to participate in Wasabi transactions for stronger privacy. The conversation then shifts to the concept of users participating in knapsack-type coin joints for spending purposes only, which could be offered as a separate service in Wasabi. They also touch upon topics like blockchain with lists of inputs and outputs, determining conjoined transactions, RBF in transactions, and feedback for improving future episodes of the club. Overall, the participants engage in an informative discussion on knapsack mixing and its implications.</description></item><item><title>Current state of P2P research in Bitcoin /Erlay</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2019-11-13-gleb-naumenko-p2p-erlay/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2019-11-13-gleb-naumenko-p2p-erlay/</guid><description>London Bitcoin Devs
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1201861687097352198
Introduction My name is Gleb. I’ve worked on Bitcoin stuff since 2015, building wallets and exchanges in Ukraine. Then I realized that I can do more fun stuff. I want to do more protocol research, improving Bitcoin itself, not just using it. I decided I will go to Canada to do a Masters. I started working on this topic on research stuff more precisely and I realized that not many people do work on peer-to-peer (P2P) of Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Knowledge Aggregation And Propagation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/knowledge-aggregation-and-propagation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/knowledge-aggregation-and-propagation/</guid><description>Intro https://docs.google.com/document/d/1a1uRy10dBBcxrnzjdUaO2y03f5H34yFlxktOcanvVYE/edit
https://cess.pubpub.org/pub/knowledge-aggregation/branch/2/
I&amp;rsquo;ll be the contrarian - I think academia is awful and should be destroyed.
Reputation is completely independent of content and should not be the mechanism by which you judge the quality of research; your reputation is worthless to me. (laughter)
My perspective: [first, slidemaker&amp;rsquo;s regret! might have reorganized this] I&amp;rsquo;m a bitcoin core developer. Also worked at LedgerX (4 years). I also work on biotech on the hobbyist side, garage engineering &amp;ndash; what I was doing when bitcoin was launched.</description></item><item><title>The Quest for Practical Threshold Schnorr Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/threshold-schnorr-signatures/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/threshold-schnorr-signatures/</guid><description>Slides: https://slides.com/real-or-random/schnorr-threshold-sigs-ces-summit-2019
Introduction It&amp;rsquo;s great to be here. My name is Tim Ruffing and I work for the research team at Blockstream. This is a talk about practical threshold Schnorr signatures and our quest for constructing them.
Disclaimer First of all, this is work in progress. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty early work in progress, mostly based on discussions with people at Blockstream. I describe the problem we want to solve, and we have some initial ideas, but they are very initial and I have tried to put one or two sentences about those ideas into the slides but nothing is really done yet.</description></item><item><title>A2L: Anonymous Atomic Locks for Scalability and Interoperability in Payment Channel Hubs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/anonymous-atomic-locks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/anonymous-atomic-locks/</guid><description>paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2019/589.pdf
https://github.com/etairi/A2L
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1172116189742546945
Introduction I am going ot talk about anonymous atomic locks for scalability and interoperability in payment-channel hubs. This is joint work with my colleagues.
Scalability I will try to keep this section as short as possible. This talk is also about scalability in bitcoin. You&amp;rsquo;re probably aware of the scalability issues. There is decentralized data structure recording each transaction in order to provide public verifiability. Global consensus is required, such that everyone checks the whole blockchain.</description></item><item><title>Atomic Multi-Channel Updates with Constant Collateral in Bitcoin-Compatible Payment-Channel Networks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/atomic-multi-channel-updates/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/atomic-multi-channel-updates/</guid><description>paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2019/583
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1172102203995283456
Introduction Thank you for coming to my talk after lunch. This talk today is about atomic multi-channel updates with constant collateral in bitcoin-compatible payment-channel networks. It&amp;rsquo;s a long title, but I hope you will understand. This is collaborative work with my colleagues.
Scalability We&amp;rsquo;re at Scaling Bitcoin so you&amp;rsquo;re probably not suprised that I think bitcoin has scaling issues. It&amp;rsquo;s a decentralized data structure called blockchain where we store every transaction that happens.</description></item><item><title>Plasma Cash: Towards more efficient Plasma Constructions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/plasma-cash/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/plasma-cash/</guid><description>Non-custodial sidechains for bitcoin utilizing plasma cash and covenants
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1172108023705284609
paper: https://github.com/loomnetwork/plasma-paper/blob/master/plasma_cash.pdf
slides: https://gakonst.com/scalingbitcoin2019.pdf
Introduction We have known how to do these things for at least a year, but the question is how can we find the minimum changes that we can figure out to do in bitcoin if any on how to explore the layer 2 space in a better sense rather than just accepting that lightning network is the dominant solution?</description></item><item><title>Proof-of-Verification for Proof-of-Work: Miners Must Verify the Signatures on Bitcoin Transactions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/proof-of-verification-for-proof-of-work/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/proof-of-verification-for-proof-of-work/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1172142603007143936
extended abstract: http://kmlab.iis.u-tokyo.ac.jp/papers/scaling19-matsuura-final.pdf
History lesson In the 90s, we had some timestamping schemes where things are aggregated into one hash and then it would be publicized later in the newspaper. This scheme was commercialized, in fact. However, the resolution of the trust anchor is very limited. It&amp;rsquo;s one day or half-day at best. When we want to verify, we need to visit the online-offline database maintained by a trusted party to get the merkle inclusion paths.</description></item><item><title>Applying Private Information Retrieval to Lightweight Bitcoin Clients</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/private-information-retrieval/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/private-information-retrieval/</guid><description>SPV overview I have to thank the prior speaker. This is basically the same, except this time we&amp;rsquo;re not using SGX. We&amp;rsquo;re looking at bitcoin lightweight clients. You have a lite client with not much space not much computing power, can&amp;rsquo;t store the bitcoin blockchain. All it knows about is the header information. We assume it has the blockheader history. In the header, we can find the merkle tree, and given the merkle tree we can make a merkle proof that a given transaction is included in a block.</description></item><item><title>BIP: OP_SECURETHEBAG</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/bip-securethebag/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/bip-securethebag/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171750965478854656
Introduction Thank you for the introduction. Today I am going to talk to you about OP_SECURETHEBAG. It&amp;rsquo;s research that I have been working on for the last couple years. I think it&amp;rsquo;s very exciting and hopefully it will have a big compact. I have a lot of slides.
Why are we here? We are here for scaling bitcoin. The goal we have is to scale bitcoin. What is scaling, though?</description></item><item><title>Developing secure Bitcoin contracts using BitML</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/bitml/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/bitml/</guid><description>paper: https://arxiv.org/abs/1905.07639
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171695588116746240
This is shared work with my collaborators and coauthors.
Smart contracts I am sure everyone here knows what a smart contract is. It&amp;rsquo;s a program that can move cryptoassets. It&amp;rsquo;s executed in a decentralized environment. Generally speaking, we can say there&amp;rsquo;s two classes of smart contracts. A smart contract is a program. While in blockchain like bitcoin, smart contracts are cryptographic protocols. This effects how we can reason about a blockchain; bitcoin has many more security proofs for script than ethereum.</description></item><item><title>Socratic Seminar 2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/austin-bitcoin-developers/2019-08-22-socratic-seminar-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/austin-bitcoin-developers/2019-08-22-socratic-seminar-2/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1164710800910692353
Introduction Hello. The idea was to do a more socratic style meetup. This was popularized by Bitdevs NYC and spread to SF. We tried this a few months ago with Jay. The idea is we run through research news, newsletters, podcasters, talk about what happened in the technical bitcoin community. We&amp;rsquo;re going to have different presenters.
Mike Schmidt is going to talk about some optech newsletters that he has been contributing to.</description></item><item><title>Watchtowers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/boltathon/2019-04-06-conner-fromknecht-watchtowers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/boltathon/2019-04-06-conner-fromknecht-watchtowers/</guid><description>Architecture of LND Watchtowers
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1117427512081100800
discussion: https://www.reddit.com/r/lightningdevs/comments/bd33cp/architecture_of_lnd_watchtowers_presentation_from/
Intro Pretty excited today to speak on the topic of watchtowers. It is something that we at Lightning Labs have been working on for almost a year now. Conceptual proof of concept code to really flushing it out into what would be today more of a full on protocol. Hopefully today we’re going to summarize a year of research into this presentation. I’m looking forward to getting into it with you guys so let’s dive right in.</description></item><item><title>Handel: Practical Multi-Signature Aggregation for Large Byzantine Committees</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/handel-practical-multisig-aggregation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/handel-practical-multisig-aggregation/</guid><description>Introduction Handle is a aggregation protocol for large scale byzantine committees. This is work with my colleagues in addition to myself.
Why aggregate? Distributed systems often require gathering statements about large subsets of nodes. However, processing (filtering, aggregating&amp;hellip;) measurements can be a bottleneck. We want to apply some processing while collecting the measurements.
Why byzantine? A byzantine node is a node that can be arbitrary. It can be offline and it can be anything it wants and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to respect the protocol specification.</description></item><item><title>Building Mimblewimble/Grin, an implementation for privacy and scalability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/building-mimblewimble-and-grin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/building-mimblewimble-and-grin/</guid><description>Quentin Le Sceller (Grin Dev Team), Ignotus Peverell (Grin Dev Team), Yeastplume (Grin Dev Team), Antioch Peverell (Grin Dev Team), HashMap (Grin Dev Team), John Tromp (Grin Dev Team), Daniel Lehnberg (Grin Dev Team)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1090662484275384320
Our first talk is from the Grin project. It was just launched a few weeks ago. Okay, let&amp;rsquo;s get started.
Introduction Hi everyone. My name is Quentin Le Sceller. I&amp;rsquo;m a developer at Blockcypher. I am here to talk about grin, specifically about building mimblewimble and grin an implementation for privacy and scalability.</description></item><item><title>Quisquis: A New Design for Anonymous Cryptocurrencies</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/quisquis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/quisquis/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1090677466216128512
https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/990
Introduction Good morning. I am here to talk to you about Quisquis which is a new design for an anonymous cryptocurrency. This talk is going to focus on the transaction layer. We don&amp;rsquo;t talk about consensus or smart contracts or higher applications.
Outline I am going to talk about bitcoin and anonymity. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about existing cryptocurrencies that claim to have anonymity and about their limitations. Then I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about our basic solution, where one public key is one coin, updateable public keys, and N-to-N transactions without interactions.</description></item><item><title>SybilQuorum: Open Distributed Ledgers Through Trust Networks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/sybilquorum/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/sybilquorum/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1090777875253407745
Introduction This is joint work with George Danezis who couldn&amp;rsquo;t be here today and also cofounded Chainspace. Among all the possible challenges we may have on a blockchain, this talk will be about how to build strong sybil resistance. We would consider a subset of the problem, how will we bootstrap a federated agreement system?
Sybil attacks I am sure everyone knows about sybil attacks. Imagine you have a classic setting where you have an attacker creating fake identities.</description></item><item><title>Topological Analysis of the Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-topological-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-topological-analysis/</guid><description>Topological analysis of the lightning network
paper: https://arxiv.org/abs/1901.04972
https://github.com/seresistvanandras/LNTopology
Introduction Knowing the topology is not necessarily a vulnerability, but it gives you a lot of information. If I know Bryan&amp;rsquo;s full node is connected to some other nodes, I will have an easier time to cut Bryan out of the network or launch attacks against him. Knowing the topology is not necessarily a vulnerability, but it&amp;rsquo;s really strong information.
Recent research There were some recent papers published on this topic:</description></item><item><title>Unchained Capital Socratic Seminar</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2019-01-05-unchained-capital-socratic-seminar/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2019-01-05-unchained-capital-socratic-seminar/</guid><description>Unchained Capital Bitcoin Socratic Seminar
Socratic Seminar 87 at BitDevs NYC has all of the links on meetup.com available.
https://www.meetup.com/BitDevsNYC/events/256924041/
https://www.meetup.com/Austin-Bitcoin-Developers/events/257718282/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1081674259880120323
Last time Last time Andrew Poelstra gave a talk about research at Blockstream. He also talked about scriptless scripts and using the properties of Schnorr signatures to do all of your scripting. There was also talk about taproot and graftroot.
J: The chaincode labs guys in NYC .. we had a lot of participation, it was very cool.</description></item><item><title>The State of Atomic Swaps</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/atomic-swaps/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/atomic-swaps/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048790167283068929
History This should be easy to follow. I want to start off with some history. The first mention of atomic swap concepts was in 2013 in a bitcointalk.org thread where people were wondering how to exchange coins between independent ledgers in a trustless way. There were a few comments on the thread every now and then asking has anyone implemented this. It was quiet until last year when people started doing atomic swaps last year.</description></item><item><title>Compact Multi-Signatures For Smaller Blockchains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/compact-multi-signatures-for-smaller-blockchains/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/compact-multi-signatures-for-smaller-blockchains/</guid><description>Dan Boneh (Stanford University), Manu Drijvers and Gregory Neven (DFINITY)
paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/483.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048441176024469504
Introduction Hi. Thanks a lot for coming in after lunch. This slot is often known as &amp;ldquo;the slot of death&amp;rdquo;. Some of us are jetlagged, this is the perfect time to doze off and only wake up at the end of the talk. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to prevent that from happening. I think the best way to do that is to start about what this talk can do for you.</description></item><item><title>Improving SPV Client Validation and Security with Fraud Proofs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/fraud-proofs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/fraud-proofs/</guid><description>paper: https://arxiv.org/pdf/1809.09044.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048446183004233731
Introduction I am going to be talking about fraud proofs. It allows lite clients to have a leve lof security of almost the level of a full node. Before I describe fraud proofs, how about we talk about motivations.
Motivations There&amp;rsquo;s a large tradeoff between blockchain decentralization and how much on-chain throughput you can get. The more transactions you have on the chain, the more resources you need to validate the chain.</description></item><item><title>Multi-Hop Locks for Secure, Privacy-Preserving and Interoperable Payment-Channel Networks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-hop-locks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-hop-locks/</guid><description>Giulio Malavolta (Friedrich-Alexander-University Erlangen-Nuernberg), Pedro Moreno-Sanchez (Purdue University), Clara Schneidewind (Vienna University of Technology), Aniket Kate (Purdue University) and Matteo Maffei (Vienna University of Technology)
https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/472.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048476273259900928
This is joint work with my colleagues. I promise I will talk slower than the last talk. In a multi-hop network, the security tool is a hash-time lock contract (HTLC) where the payment is conditioned on revealing the pre-image of a hash function. This is pretty much the main setup for the lightning network today.</description></item><item><title>Schnorr Signatures For Bitcoin: Challenges and Opportunities</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/schnorr-signatures-for-bitcoin-challenges-opportunities/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/schnorr-signatures-for-bitcoin-challenges-opportunities/</guid><description>slides: https://prezi.com/bihvorormznd/schnorr-signatures-for-bitcoin/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/958776403977220098
https://blockstream.com/2018/02/15/schnorr-signatures-bpase.html
Introduction My name is Pieter Wuille. I work at Blockstream. I contribute to Bitcoin Core and bitcoin research in general. I work on various proposals for the bitcoin system for some time now. Today I will be talking about Schnorr signatures for bitcoin, which is a project we&amp;rsquo;ve been working on, on-and-off, for a couple of years now. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the cool things that we can do that might be non-obvious, and also some non-obvious challenges that we ran into while doing this.</description></item><item><title>Incentives and Trade-offs in Transaction Selection in DAG-based Protocols</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/incentives-tradeoffs-transaction-selection-in-dag-based-protocols/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/incentives-tradeoffs-transaction-selection-in-dag-based-protocols/</guid><description>Commercial effort to implement DAG-based protocols. No ICO, it&amp;rsquo;s a regular company.
A little bit background of DAG-based protocols. The background to this work is something we have been working at Hebrew University and Yoad. This idea of blockDAG is about layer 1 of bitcoin. And so it&amp;rsquo;s a generalization of the chain structure of blockchain. As such, there are two solutions- lightning network and payment channels, and were scaling up layer 1, and you&amp;rsquo;re scaling up in layer 2, it&amp;rsquo;s complementary solutions.</description></item><item><title>Weak-Signal Radio Communications For Bitcoin Network Resilience</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/weak-signal-radio-communications-for-bitcoin-network-resilience/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/weak-signal-radio-communications-for-bitcoin-network-resilience/</guid><description>What is weak-signal HF radio? These are called high frequency. That&amp;rsquo;s the official name for these frequencies. Short wave is for historical reasons is longer waves and much higher frequency compared to our wireless internet frequencies. The terminology is backwards. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the ionosphere and how we&amp;rsquo;re bouncing signals off of it. This is really long-range stuff. This is an old Voice of America broadcast station that broadcasted radio programs across the pacific.</description></item><item><title>BlockSci: a Platform for Blockchain Science and Exploration</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/blocksci-platform/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/blocksci-platform/</guid><description>Alright well, my name is Harry Kalodner, I am a student at Princeton University and I am here to tell you about a tool I built alon with some colleagues at Princeton which could be used for analyzing the blockchain in different ways. So far most of the talks today have been constructive about new ways to use the blockchain and protocols to slightly modify bitcoin in roder to improve privacy or scaling.</description></item><item><title>BOLT Anonymous Payment Channels for Decentralized Currencies</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/bolt-anonymous-payment-channels-for-decentralized-currencies/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/bolt-anonymous-payment-channels-for-decentralized-currencies/</guid><description>paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2016/701.pdf
To make questions easier, we are going to have a mic on the isle. Please line up so that we can have questions quickly. Okay, now we have Ian Miers.
My name is Ian Miers. Just got my PhD at Hpkins&amp;hellip; authors of zcash, zerocash, &amp;hellip; My interest in bitcoin was, first getting involved, was dealing with the privacy aspect. There is also a scaling problem. I assume you are aware of that.</description></item><item><title>ValueShuffle: Mixing Confidential Transactions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/valueshuffle-mixing-confidential-transactions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/valueshuffle-mixing-confidential-transactions/</guid><description>paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2017/238.pdf
Thank you.
We have seen two talks now about putting privacy in layer two. But let&amp;rsquo;s talk about layer one. We still don&amp;rsquo;t have great privacy there. So the title of this talk is valueshuffle - mixing confidential transactions. I don&amp;rsquo;t have to convince you that bitcoin at the moment is not really private. There are a lot of possibilities to link&amp;hellip; to deal them as, to link addresses together.</description></item><item><title>Hunting Moby Dick, an Analysis of 2015-2016 Spam Attacks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/spam-attacks-analysis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/spam-attacks-analysis/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005525351517360129
Introduction Hi. Thanks for Breaking Bitcoin to invite me to speak and to present this research on Moby Dick.
Moby Dick and spam attacks&amp;ndash; let me explain, Moby Dick is an entity that spammed or sent a lot of transactions in bitcoin in 2015. We did some analysis on who this person is or what they were doing. This is bitcoin archaeology, where we analyze past activities and try to analyze what happened and get insight into what could happen.</description></item><item><title>Scalable Smart Contracts Via Proofs And Single Use Seals</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/scalable-smart-contracts-via-proofs-and-single-use-seals/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/scalable-smart-contracts-via-proofs-and-single-use-seals/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/957660108137418752
slides: https://cyber.stanford.edu/sites/default/files/petertodd.pdf
https://petertodd.org/2016/commitments-and-single-use-seals
https://petertodd.org/2016/closed-seal-sets-and-truth-lists-for-privacy
Introduction I am petertodd and I am here to break your blockchain. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of interesting following a talk like that, in some ways I&amp;rsquo;m going in a more extreme direcion for consensus. Do we actually need consensus at all? Can we make a more robust system by eliminating it to the maximum extent possible? I think for some use case at least I have some techniques that will let you go do this.</description></item><item><title>Ivy: A Declarative Predicate Language for Smart Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/2017-01-26-dan-robinson-ivy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/2017-01-26-dan-robinson-ivy/</guid><description>Intro Hi I’m Dan Robinson, I’m one of the Product Architects at Chain which is an enterprise blockchain infrastructure company for financial institutions. We have a full stack blockchain protocol and what I am going to talk about is part of that that also can be used for other applications including as I am going to demo here, make it easier to write scripts for Bitcoin Script.
Introduction: Two Blockchain Models To start out I want to talk about two blockchain models.</description></item><item><title>On the Security and Performance of Proof of Work Blockchains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/on-the-security-and-performance-of-proof-of-work-blockchains/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/on-the-security-and-performance-of-proof-of-work-blockchains/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785066988532068352
As most of you might know, in bitcoin and blockchains, the information is very important. Every node should receive the blocks in the network. Increase latency and risk network partition. If individual peers do not get the information, they could be victims of selfish mining and so on. Multiple blockchains has been proposed, multiple reparameterizations like litecoin, dogecoin, ethereum and others. One of the key changes they did was the block interval time.</description></item><item><title>Flare: An Approach to Routing in Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/flare-routing-in-lightning/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/flare-routing-in-lightning/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784745976170999810
I will not be as technical as Olaoluwa was. You have nodes that open up payment channels. This scheme is actually developed at the moment in great detail. So how do you find the channels through which to send payments? So we wanted to propose some initial solution to this.
Routing requirements It should be source routing because we need the privacy. When a user sends a payment, so the decision of what route to choose should be on the sender side, because if he delegates it to an intermediate node then they don&amp;rsquo;t have the necessity to privacy as much.</description></item><item><title>TumbleBit: An Untrusted Bitcoin-Compatible Anonymous Payment Hub</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/tumblebit/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/tumblebit/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784686167052709888
Hi. So I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking about tumblebit. It&amp;rsquo;s our untrusted private bitcoin payment system. Tumblebit provides payments which are private. They provide set anonymity when used as a classic tumbler. They are untrusted. The tumbler can&amp;rsquo;t violate your privacy, and can&amp;rsquo;t steal your coins. It&amp;rsquo;s also scalable. It&amp;rsquo;s compatible and works with today&amp;rsquo;s bitcoin. There are no malleability concerns. We&amp;rsquo;re going to rely on the constrained opcodes that currently exist in bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Dan Boneh</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-developers-miners-meeting-2016/dan-boneh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-developers-miners-meeting-2016/dan-boneh/</guid><description>A conversation with Dan Boneh
Part of the challenge was that the Google Maps directions in the email were going down some roads that had construction&amp;hellip;. been here 10 minutes, and some arriving in another 10 minutes. They are building a new biology building. Large campus here. In whatever direction you walk, there are buildings and more buildings. In two years there will be a new biology building, and two years later there will be a new computer science building.</description></item><item><title>Invertible Bloom Lookup Tables (IBLT) and weak block propagation performance</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/invertible-bloom-lookup-tables-and-weak-block-propagation-performance/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/invertible-bloom-lookup-tables-and-weak-block-propagation-performance/</guid><description>slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY1/3_block_propagation_1_rosenbaum.pdf
Before we get started, for privacy reasons, and for reasons of zero attribution, please do not take pictures of attendees. Do not have pictures of attendees in the photographs. Taking pictures of the stage and slides are OK, since they are being broadcasted. No photographs of any attendees, please let them remain anonymous and private. For Chinese speakers, please ask in Chinese and I will use American English to translate.</description></item><item><title>Sharding the Blockchain</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/sharding-the-blockchain/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/sharding-the-blockchain/</guid><description>I am going to talk about blockchain sharding. This is one of the scaling solutions that I like the most. I have done the most work on it. In case you don&amp;rsquo;t know who I am, I am a researcher mostly with the ethereum project. Basically the basics of sharding is that in non-sharding, every node does every validation. In a sharding solution, nodes hold a subset of the state, and a subset of the blockchain.</description></item><item><title>Systematizing Knowledge</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/systematizing-knowledge/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/systematizing-knowledge/</guid><description>There should be a SNARK wiki. Any website that is better than someone saying &amp;ldquo;you know, check the June July 2014 bitcoin-wizard logs&amp;rdquo;. We need to research gmaxwell scalability. We should probably fix that.
Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about what some of the goals are that we might get out of this. We have some different ideas for approaches to systematizing knowledge. There are at least three camps here. I think Bryan&amp;rsquo;s paper repositories.</description></item><item><title>Privacy-Preserving Smart Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/privacy-preserving-smart-contracts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/privacy-preserving-smart-contracts/</guid><description>ranjit@csail.mit.edu
http://people.csail.mit.edu/ranjit/
We have been looking at how much we can support or what limitations we might encounter. There are also efficiency issues and privacy guarantees. And then there are some potential relaxations that will help with removing the fundamental limitations and express the power and make smart contracts more useful.
The point of this talk is off-chain transactions and secure computation. I will also highlight the relationship of secure computation and bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Security Of Diminishing Block Subsidy</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/security-of-diminishing-block-subsidy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/security-of-diminishing-block-subsidy/</guid><description>Miners no longer incentivized to mine all the time. The future of mining hardware. Impact on the bitcoin ecosystem. Implications and assumptions of the model.
Are minting rewards and transaction fees the same? Transaction fees are time-dependent. A miner can only claim transaction fees as transactions are added to their block. As transaction fees start to dominate the block reward, they become time-dependent. We are modeling this block reward as a linear function of time, we have this factor B which might be initial minting reward, and we have some scaling factor, the block reward is like &amp;ldquo;b + at&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Key Tree Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2015-08-24-pieter-wuille-key-tree-signatures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2015-08-24-pieter-wuille-key-tree-signatures/</guid><description>Slides: https://prezi.com/vsj95ns4ucu3/key-tree-signatures/
Blog post: https://blockstream.com/2015/08/24/en-treesignatures/
Intro For those who don’t know me I’m Pieter Wuille. I have been working on Bitcoin Core for a while but this is work I have been doing at Blockstream. Today I will be talking about Key Tree Signatures which is what I have been working on these past few weeks. It is an improvement to the multisig schemes that we want to support. This is an outline of my talk.</description></item><item><title>A Tale of Two Trees: One Writes, and Other Reads, Scaling Oblivious Accesses to Large-Scale Blockchains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/scaling-oblivious-read-write/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/scaling-oblivious-read-write/</guid><description>Introduction We are trying to get optimized oblivious accesses to large-scale blockchains. This is collaborative work with our colleagues.
Motivation As we all know, bitfcoin data has become too large to store in resource-constrained devices. It&amp;rsquo;s like 240 GB. The current solution today is bip37 + Nakamoto&amp;rsquo;s idea for simplified payment verification (SPV) clients which don&amp;rsquo;t run the bitcoin network rules. Resource-constrained clients (thin clients) have to rely on other potentially malicious full clients to obtain transaction information.</description></item><item><title>A Wishlist For Verifiable Computation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/simons-institute/a-wishlist-for-verifiable-computation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/simons-institute/a-wishlist-for-verifiable-computation/</guid><description>A wishlist for verifiable computation: An applied computer science perspective
http://www.pepper-project.org/ https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z4jzA6ts2j4 http://simons.berkeley.edu/talks/mike-walfish-2015-06-10 slides: http://www.pepper-project.org/surveywishlist.pptx slides (again): http://simons.berkeley.edu/sites/default/files/docs/3316/surveywishlist2.pptx more: http://www.pepper-project.org/talks.htm Okay, thanks. I want to begin by thanking the organizers, especially the tall guy for allowing me to be here. This talk will be talking about a research area where the goal is deployable systems for verifiable computation for probabilistic proofs like SNARKs etc. The goal of this talk is to motivate the next theoretical steps in this area.</description></item><item><title>Accumulators for blockchains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/accumulators/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/accumulators/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1090748293234094082
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1090741715059695617
https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/accumulators/
paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/1188
Introduction I am going to be talking about batching techniques for accumulators with applications to interactive oracle proofs and blockchains. I&amp;rsquo;ll maybe also talk about how to make these proofs even smaller. The main thing that we are going to focus on today is the bitcoin state and this application of accumulators to bitcoin and blockchain.
Bitcoin UTXO states The bitcoin state is the UTXO set.</description></item><item><title>Alternatives To Block Size As Aggregate Resource Limits</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/alternatives-to-block-size-as-aggregate-resource-limits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/alternatives-to-block-size-as-aggregate-resource-limits/</guid><description>I am talking about block size, but not any particular proposal. Why do we have the block size limit and is it a good thing in the first place? The block size exists as a denial-of-service limiter. It limits the amount of resources that a node validating the blockchain can exhaust when validating a block. We want to do this because in the early days of bitcoin there are often certain kinds of transactions there are ways to slow down a validator by using a non-standard transaction or filling up a block with tons of spam.</description></item><item><title>Aurora: Transparent Succinct Arguments for R1CS</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/aurora-transparent-succinct-arguments-r1cs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/aurora-transparent-succinct-arguments-r1cs/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1090741190100545536
Introduction Hi. I am Alessandro Chiesa, a faculty member at UC Berkeley. I work on cryptography. I&amp;rsquo;m also a chief scientist at Starkware. I was a founder of zcash. Today I will like to tell you about recent work in cryptographic proof systems. This is joint work with people at Starkware, UC Berkeley, MIT Media Lab, and others. In the prior talk, we talked about scalability. But this current talk is more about privacy by using cryptographic proofs.</description></item><item><title>Automatic Detection of Vulnerabilities in Smart Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/vulnerability-detection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/vulnerability-detection/</guid><description>Introduction If you find a bug in a smart contract, it&amp;rsquo;s really hard to mitigate that bug. In formal verification, we really look for bugs. We can identify subtle bugs, like reentrancy attacks, ownership violation, incorrect transactions, bugs due to updated code. We also want to assure the absence of bugs.
Device drivers I come from the domain of Windows device drivers. These are drivers produced by third parties, and it integrates with operating system code.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Block Propagation and IBLT</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/bitcoin-block-propagation-iblt-rusty-russell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/bitcoin-block-propagation-iblt-rusty-russell/</guid><description>This is not what I do. But I was doing it anyway.
The problem is that blocks are transmitted in their entirety. If you have a 1 MB uplink and you&amp;rsquo;re connecting to 8 peers, your first peer will see a 1MB block in about 66.8 seconds. And the last one will get it in 76.4 seconds, because we basically blast out blocks in parallel to our peers. Miners can solve this problem of slow block transmission by centralizing and all using the same pool.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Core V0.17</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/jnewbery-bitcoin-core-v0.17/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/jnewbery-bitcoin-core-v0.17/</guid><description>Bitcoin Core v0.17
slides: https://www.dropbox.com/s/9kt32069hoxmgnt/john-newbery-bitcoincore0.17.pptx
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1031960170027536384
Introduction I am John Newbery. I work on Bitcoin Core. This talk is going to be mostly about Bitcoin Core 0.17 which was branched on Monday. Hopefully the final release will be in the next couple of weeks.
whoami I live in New York and work at Chaincode Labs. I&amp;rsquo;m not actually a native born New Yorker. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to be back in London and talking with you guys about bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Load Spike Simulation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/bitcoin-load-spike-simulation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/bitcoin-load-spike-simulation/</guid><description>Our goal for this project, our rationale of what we&amp;rsquo;re interesting is when many transactions arrive in a short period of time. This could be because of denial of service attacks where few entities are creating a large number of transactions, or many people wanting to create transactions, like a shopping spree. We wanted to answer two questions, how does the temporary spike in transaction rate affect confirmation delay distribution? For a given spike shape, can we change the block size and how would that effect the evolution of the system?</description></item><item><title>Blockchain Testbed</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/blockchain-testbed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/blockchain-testbed/</guid><description>A testbed for bitcoin scaling
I want to talk today about how to scale bitcoin. We want lower latency, we want higher throughput, more bandwidth and more transactions per second, and we want security. We can try to tune the parameters. In all of the plots, I have time going from left to right and these are blocks in rectangles. We have larger blocks which might give us more throughput. We could have shorter block length, and transactions would come faster on the chain and we have better throughput but we get forks and orphans when that happens.</description></item><item><title>Casper the Friendly Ghost: A 'Correct-by-Construction' Blockchain Consensus Protocol</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/casper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/casper/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1091460316288868352
I have one announcement to make before we start the session. If you feel like after all of these talks that the thing you really need is a drink, then there&amp;rsquo;s help. Chainlink is hosting the Stanford Blockchain Conference happy hour at The Patio which is the most famous bar in Palo Alto. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that much, but it&amp;rsquo;s good fun. It&amp;rsquo;s at 412 Evans St in Palo Alto, from 5-8pm and it&amp;rsquo;s an open bar.</description></item><item><title>Competitive Fee Market Urgency</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/competitive-fee-market-urgency/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/competitive-fee-market-urgency/</guid><description>The urgency of a competitive fee market to ensure a scalable future
I am Marshall. I run Firehash. CTO Cryptsy also. Some people have higher cost, some people have lower cost. I think those were some good estimates for true costs. I am going to be talking about why fees are going to be very important very soon. We&amp;rsquo;ll talk about what happens without fees, talk about why bitcoin really isn&amp;rsquo;t free but how we can do things like microtransactions, real microtransactions, talk about the cost and talk about solutions.</description></item><item><title>Concurrency And Privacy With Payment Channel Networks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/concurrency-and-privacy-with-payment-channel-networks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/concurrency-and-privacy-with-payment-channel-networks/</guid><description>paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2017/820.pdf
Introduction I am going to talk about concurrency and privacy. This was joint work with my collaborators.
Bitcoin has scalability issues. That&amp;rsquo;s the main reason why we are here today. Currently the bitcoin network allows for less than 10 transactions/second. Today we have more than 135 gigabytes of memory requirement. And there are some high fees and micropayments are not really possible. One of the proposals to fix this is payment channels.</description></item><item><title>Cryptography Audit</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/cryptography-audit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/cryptography-audit/</guid><description>libsecp256k1-zkp audit
It&amp;rsquo;s a real treat to be able to be a part of this.
Why bother? Just a high-level, why are we taking community resources to spend time on audits? There are some perspectives&amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s good for the community and it&amp;rsquo;s what you do.
Bitcoin had on professional security audits and did just fine. But it launched in a very different environment, and it did get audits eventually.
Beyond just covering your ass, it&amp;rsquo;s good to have these audits because if there&amp;rsquo;s a vulnerability then you can have someone with liability.</description></item><item><title>DECO: Liberating Web Data Using Decentralized Oracles for TLS</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/decentralized-oracles-tls/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/decentralized-oracles-tls/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230657639740108806
Introduction I am Fan from Cornell. I am going to be talking about DECO, a privacy-preserving oracle for TLS. This is joint work with some other people.
Decentralized identity What is identity? To use any system, the first thing that the user needs to do is to prove her identity and that she is a user to the system. The identity can be descriptive. You can think of digital identity as a set of descriptions about a user.</description></item><item><title>Dex: Deterministic Predicate Expressions for Smarter Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/petertodd-dex/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/petertodd-dex/</guid><description>I have been working on deterministic expressions language called DEX. It looks like lambda calculus. But really we&amp;rsquo;re trying to create a way to specify expressions that would return true if a signature is valid. Something like this, which is really just check a signature against a pubkey for a message, is essentially something that would be baked into your software anyway. We&amp;rsquo;re trying to move into a layer of abstraction where you can specify the conditions you need for your particular use case.</description></item><item><title>Efficient Distributed Key Generation for Threshold Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/threshold-signatures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/threshold-signatures/</guid><description>Threshold signatures Threshold signature schemes are schemes where n parties and at least t are necessary and sufficient for signing. They want to make sure that t parties are necessary. Any threshold signature scheme typically has 3 protocols: key generation, signing, and verifying.
In key generation, one party creates a group public key as an output. Also, for each node that participates in the protocol, the protocol should output a secret key.</description></item><item><title>Elastic Block Caps</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/elastic-block-caps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/elastic-block-caps/</guid><description>Introduction Thank you everyone. I am from the Israeli Bitcoin Association. I will start by describing the problem.
The problem The problem is variable transaction fees. The transaction fees shot up. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of fluctuation. To understand why this is a problem, let&amp;rsquo;s go back to the basics.
Block size limit We can have big blocks or small blocks. Each one has advantages and disadvantages. One of the benefits of small blocks is that it&amp;rsquo;s easier to run a node.</description></item><item><title>Enhancing Bitcoin Security and Performance with Strong Consistency via Collective Signing</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/collective-signing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/collective-signing/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785102844839985153
We are starting the session called &amp;ldquo;breaking the chain&amp;rdquo;. We will first have collective signing presentation. Thank you.
This is joint work with some collaborators.
What we have now is that real-time verification is not safe. What we managed to get is that we get transaction commitment in about 20-90 seconds at close to 1,000 transactions/second. In byzcoin, irrevocable transaction commitment in 20-90 second. Throughput up to 974 transactions per second.</description></item><item><title>Ethereum 2.0 and beyond</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/ethereum2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/ethereum2/</guid><description>Please welcome Vitalik who needs no introduction.
Introduction Okay. I have 20 minutes. I will get right to it. Vlad gave a presentation on some of his research into CBC Casper and how CBC Casper can be extended into sharding contexts. This presentation will be about taking some of the existing research into consensus algorithms and sharding and other things we have done in the last few years and see how they concretely translate into what is actually going to be deployed to Ethereum Foundation in the short to medium term future.</description></item><item><title>Finding Bugs Automatically in Smart Contracts with Parameterized Specifications</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/smart-contract-bug-hunting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/smart-contract-bug-hunting/</guid><description>https://www.certora.com/pubs/sbc2020.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230906600140918784
Introduction I am from Tel Aviv University and now we have a 1-year old company called Cotera which is located in Berlin, Seattle and Tel Aviv. Our mission is to bring formal methods into code security and I will talk to you today about how we use this method to find bugs. And actually, I try to make this talk as informal as possible but there is actually a paper just download it from the certora website.</description></item><item><title>Flash Boys V2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/flash-boys-v2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/flash-boys-v2/</guid><description>&amp;ndash; Disclaimer &amp;ndash;
These are unpaid transcriptions, performed in real-time and in-person during the actual source presentation. Due to personal time constraints they are usually not reviewed against the source material once published. Errors are possible. If the original author/speaker or anyone else finds errors of substance, please email me at kanzure@gmail.com for corrections.
I sometimes add annotations to the transcription text. These will always be denoted by a standard editor&amp;rsquo;s note in parenthesis brackets ((like this)), or in a numbered footnote.</description></item><item><title>Flyclient: Super Light Client For Cryptocurrencies</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/flyclient-super-light-clients-for-cryptocurrencies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/flyclient-super-light-clients-for-cryptocurrencies/</guid><description>As you know, the blockchain is a chain because each block connects to the previous block through these hashes. In the header of each block is a commitment to all the transactions. It&amp;rsquo;s using this merkle hash tree where at each level the parent node hashes to the children and this gives you some nice properties which I will talk about later. I need to check consistency though. The first thing I need to check is that the transactions don&amp;rsquo;t spend more than they have&amp;hellip; then I need to check that the tree was onstructed correctly.</description></item><item><title>Formal verification: the road to complete security of smart contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/formal-verification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/formal-verification/</guid><description>slides: https://twitter.com/MartinLundfall/status/1091119463276064769
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1091103595016085504
Introduction Thank you everyone. It&amp;rsquo;s exciting to be here speaking about formal verification. The road to complete security of smart contracts is a sensationalist title. I&amp;rsquo;ll be spending a few moments making a huge disclaimer.
Disclaimer This can only be interpreted as a very long road or a very narrow sense in which complete security is actually cheap. There&amp;rsquo;s still a sense of completeness, which is one of the aspects I want to focus on in this talk.</description></item><item><title>Fractal: Post-Quantum and Transparent Recursive Proofs from Holography</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/fractal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/fractal/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230295372909514752
https://eprint.iacr.org/2019/1076.pdf
Introduction One of the most powerful things that you can do with SNARKs is something called recursive proofs where you actually prove that another SNARK was correct. I can give you a proof of a proof of a proof and this is amazing because you can prove an ever-expanding computation like a blockchain is always correct. I can always give you a proof that you have the latest block and you know the entire blockchain and all the transactions in it are correct.</description></item><item><title>G20 Discussion</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/g20-discussion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/g20-discussion/</guid><description>Why do we need a multi-stakeholder discussion in a blockchain world? A report from G20 discussions.
https://bsafe.network
Introduction I am the cofounder of the bsafe.network which focuses on blockchain research. I was a program co-chair for Scaling Bitcoin at Keio University last year. I also work with IEEE, ACM conferences, Ledger Journal, and more. My background is engagement with Bank of Japan NTT internet cash in 1998-2000.
Several huge incidents From a regulatory point of view, there are many big events that have occurred: MtGox, the DAO attack, coincheck, monacoin, and Zaif.</description></item><item><title>Group Updates.Md</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/rebooting-web-of-trust/2019-prague/group-updates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/rebooting-web-of-trust/2019-prague/group-updates/</guid><description>Group updates
Alice abuses verifiable credentials We restricted our scope to a manageable slice of the problem we think we can realistically handle. It&amp;rsquo;s been very productive. We made an outline together, and now everyone can work on individual parts of the paper. I think it&amp;rsquo;s been great.
Blockcerts v3 We categorized what we wanted to write about and work on and kind of going back and looking at the history of blockcerts and specific things that were added, and an extension that were added, and looking more closely at the verifiable credentials schema.</description></item><item><title>Improvements to Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/maaku-panel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/maaku-panel/</guid><description>This can be a broad range of topics for improvements. I am Mark Friedenbach, I have worked on Bitcoin protocol research, but I also do Core tech engineering at Blockstream. We also have Jonas, an independent Bitcoin Core developer. We also have Andrew Poelstra, who has been core to the crypto work which has been incoporated into Bitcoin, such as libsecp256k1 which we recently integrated in the 0.12 release. It speeds up Bitcoin validation by 7-8x.</description></item><item><title>Jute: New Braiding Techniques to Achieve Significant Scaling Gains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/jute-braiding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/jute-braiding/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785116246257856512
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong/braiding-the-blockchain/
Introduction Okay, hello. My name is David Vorick. I have been with bitcoin since 2011. I have been a full-time blockchain engineer since about 2014. I run an altcoin for decentralized cloud storage called Sia. Today I am going to be talking about braiding which basically means we take the straight line blockchain of bitcoin and we allow blocks to have multiple parents. We get consensus by either picking a ste of blocks to choose and deleting the rest, or apply a story to the blocks we have.</description></item><item><title>Lessons For Bitcoin From 150 Years Of Decentralization</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/lessons-for-bitcoin-from-150-years-of-decentralization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/lessons-for-bitcoin-from-150-years-of-decentralization/</guid><description>Arvind Narayanan (twitter- random_walker) - Princeton University
Another 30 seconds. Take your seats. We have Arvind Narayanan. Some of the research from Princeton has rivaled the work of MIT. Professor Narayanan is going to teach us some lessons for Bitcoin.
Thank you. Can you hear me? I think you can. What I want to do today is to look at lessons from history for the future of Bitcoin, the next 10 years for Bitcoin, the next 30 years for Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Lower Bounds for Off-Chain Protocols: Exploring the Limits of Plasma</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/lower-bounds-limits-plasma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/lower-bounds-limits-plasma/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230183338746335233
Introduction Okay, thank you. The title of my talk is exploring the limits of plasma. This is joint work with others.
Plasma Let me start by telling you about Plasma. It&amp;rsquo;s a family of layer 2 solutions for scaling blockchain. It was proposed in 2017 by Poon and Buterin. It&amp;rsquo;s a family of protocols. There&amp;rsquo;s plenty of different plasmas. This is a diagram from more than a year ago. There are many variants.</description></item><item><title>Matsuo</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/matsuo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/matsuo/</guid><description>bsafe.network
Giving trust by security evaluation and bsafe.network
This is a severe problem. How can we trust the output of blockchain technology? We have several security issues. There was the huge DAO attack from two weeks ago. We also have other problems, such as protocol specification, key management, implementation, operation, and vulnerability handling. Also key renewal and key revocation issues.
ISO/IEC 27000 ISO/IEC 15408 ISO/IEC 29128 ISO/IEC 29128 ISO/IEC, NIST IETF We already have several international standards on each layer.</description></item><item><title>Mixicles: Simple Private Decentralized Finance</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/mixicles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/mixicles/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230666545803563008
https://chain.link/mixicles.pdf
Introduction This work was done in my capacity as technical advisor to Chainlink, and not my Cornell or IC3 affiliation. Mixicle is a combination of the words mixers and oracles. You will see why in a moment.
DeFi and privacy As of a couple of weeks ago, DeFi passed the $1 billion mark which is to say there&amp;rsquo;s over $1 billion of cryptocurrency in DeFi smart contracts today. This is great, but wait just a minute.</description></item><item><title>Motoko, the language for the Internet Computer</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/motoko-language/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/motoko-language/</guid><description>Introduction Thanks, Byron. Glad to be here. My name is Dominic Williams. I am founder of the internet computer project at Dfinity Foundation. Last year we talked about consensus protocols. Today we are talking about tools for building on top of the internet computer which is great news and shows the progress we have made. I&amp;rsquo;m going to give some introductory context, and then our senior researcher from our languages division will talk about Motoko.</description></item><item><title>Multi Party Channels In The Utxo Model Challenges And Opportunities</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-party-channels-in-the-utxo-model-challenges-and-opportunities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-party-channels-in-the-utxo-model-challenges-and-opportunities/</guid><description>Multi-party channels in the UTXO model: Challenges and opportunities
Olaoluwa Osuntokun (Lightning Labs) (roasbeef)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048468663089618944
Introductions Hi. So my name is Laolu. I am also known as roasbeef and I am co-founder of Lightning Labs. I am going to go over some cool research and science fiction. In the actual implementation for these things and cool to discuss and get some discussions around this. first I am going to talk about single-party channels and multi-party channels.</description></item><item><title>Near Misses</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/near-misses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/near-misses/</guid><description>Near misses: What could have gone wrong
Introduction Thank you. I am Ethan Heilman. I am a research whose has done a bunch of work in security of cryptocurrencies. I am also CTO of Arwen which does secure atomic swaps. I am a little sick today so please excuse my coughing, wheezing and drinking lots of water.
Bitcoin scary stories The general outline of this talk is going to be &amp;ldquo;scary stories in bitcoin&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>New and Simple Consensus Algorithms for ThunderCore’s Main-Net</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/thundercore/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/thundercore/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1090773938479624192
Introduction Synchronous with a chance of partition tolerance. Thank you for inviting me. I am going to be talking about some new updates. It&amp;rsquo;s joint work with my collaborators. The problem is state-machine replication, sometimes called blockchain or consensus. These terms are going to be the same thing in this talk. The nodes are trying to agree on a linearly updated transaction log.
State-machine replication We care about consistency and liveness.</description></item><item><title>Prism - Scaling bitcoin by 10,000x</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/prism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/prism/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230634530110730241
https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/prism/
Introduction Hello everyone. I am excited to be here to talk about our implementation and evaluation of the Prism consensus protocol which achieves 10,000x better performance than bitcoin. This is a multi-university collaboration between MIT, Stanford and a few others. I&amp;rsquo;d like to thank my collaborators, including my advisor, and other people.
Bitcoin performance We all know that bitcoin has good security, but in terms of performance it is not so good.</description></item><item><title>Prism: Scaling Bitcoin to Physical Limits</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/prism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/prism/</guid><description>Introduction Prism is a consensus protocol which is a one-stop solution to all of bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s scaling problems. The title is 7 to 70000 transactions per second. We have a full stack implementation of prism running and we were able to obtain 70,000 transactions/second. Before we get started, here are my collaborators.
This workshop is on scaling bitcoin so I won&amp;rsquo;t spend any time justifying why we would want to scale bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Preserving Multi Hop Locks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/privacy-preserving-multi-hop-locks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/privacy-preserving-multi-hop-locks/</guid><description>Privacy preserving multi-hop locks for blockchain scalability and interoperability
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1091026195032924160
paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/472.pdf
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-hop-locks/
Introduction This is joint work with my collaborators. Permissionless blockchains have some issues. The permissionless nature leads to the transaction rate that they have. This limits widespread adoption of blockchain technology like bitcoin or ethereum. Scalability approaches can be roughly grouped into two groups, one is on-chain layer 1 solutions. The other group is off-chain layer 2, which is the focus of this talk today.</description></item><item><title>Proof of necessary work: Succinct state verification with fairness guarantees</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/proof-of-necessary-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/proof-of-necessary-work/</guid><description>Introduction I am going to show you proof of necessary work today. We use proof of work in a prototype. This is joint work with my collaborators.
Problems We wanted to tackle the problem of bitcoin blockchain size increases. Every 10 minutes, a block is added to the blockchain and the blockchain grows linearly in size over time. Initial block download increases over time.
Proof of necessary work We use proof-of-work to verify transactions.</description></item><item><title>Proof of Necessary Work: Succinct State Verification with Fairness Guarantees</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/proof-of-necessary-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/proof-of-necessary-work/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230199429849743360
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230192993786720256
See also https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/190
Previous talk: https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/proof-of-necessary-work/
Introduction Let&amp;rsquo;s start with something familiar. When you have a new lite client, or any client that wants to trustlessly connect to the network and joins the network for the first time&amp;hellip; they see this: they need to download a lot of data, initially, and then on an ongoing basis. They need to do a lot of verification and computation on top of this data.</description></item><item><title>R&amp;D Goals &amp; Challenges</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2015-02/research-and-development-goals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2015-02/research-and-development-goals/</guid><description>We often see people saying they are testing the waters, they fixed a typo, they made a tiny little fix that doesn&amp;rsquo;t impact much, they are getting used to the process. They are finding that it&amp;rsquo;s really easy to contribut to Bitcoin Core. You code your changes, you submit your changes, there&amp;rsquo;s not much to it.
There&amp;rsquo;s a difference, and the lines are fuzzy and undefined, and you can make a change to Core that changes a spelling error or a change to policy or consensus rules, for those high-level things, for ecosystem-level things, there&amp;rsquo;s several mailing lists, the dev list gets the most traffic.</description></item><item><title>Scalable RSA Modulus Generation with Dishonest Majority</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/scalable-rsa-modulus-generation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/scalable-rsa-modulus-generation/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230545603605585920
Introduction Groups of unknown order are interesting cryptographic primitives. You can commit to integers. If you commit to a very large integer, you have to do a lot of work to do the commitment so you have a sequentiality assumption useful for VDFs. But then you have this compression property where if you take a large integer with a lot of information in it, you can compress it down to something small.</description></item><item><title>Security and Attacks on Decentralized Mining Pools</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/security-attacks-decentralized-mining-pools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/security-attacks-decentralized-mining-pools/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137373752038240262
Introduction Hi, I am Alexei. I am a research student at Imperial College London and I will be talking about the security of decentralized mining pools.
Motivation The motivation behind this talk is straightforward. I think we can all agree that to some extent the hashrate in bitcoin has seen some centralization around large mining pools, which undermines the base properties of censorship resistance in bitcoin which I think bitcoin solves in a nice matter.</description></item><item><title>Security Assumptions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/security-assumptions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/security-assumptions/</guid><description>Hi, welcome back.
I am a developer for libsecp256k1. It&amp;rsquo;s a library that does the underlying traditional cryptography used in Bitcoin. I am going to talk about security assumptions, security models and trust models. I am going to give a high-level overview of how we should be thinking about these issues for scaling and efficiency and decentralization. Bitcoin is a crypto system. Everything about it is a crypto system. It needs to be designed with an adversarial mindset, even in an adversarial setting.</description></item><item><title>Self Reproducing Coins As Universal Turing Machine</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/self-reproducing-coins-as-universal-turing-machine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/self-reproducing-coins-as-universal-turing-machine/</guid><description>paper: https://arxiv.org/abs/1806.10116
Introduction This is joint work with my colleagues. I am Alexander Chepurnoy. We work for Ergo Platform. Vasily is an external member. This talk is about turing completeness in the blockchain. This talk will be pretty high-level. This talk is based on already-published paper, which was presented at the CBT conference. Because of copyright agreements with Springer, you will not find the latest version on arxiv.
The general question of scalability is how can we do more with less until we can do everything with nothing?</description></item><item><title>Snarks And Their Practical Applications</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/simons-institute/snarks-and-their-practical-applications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/simons-institute/snarks-and-their-practical-applications/</guid><description>Joint works with:
Eli Ben-Sasson Matthew Green Alessandro Chiesa Ian Miers Christina Garman Madars Virza Daniel Genkin Thank you very much. I would like to thank the organizers for giving this opportunity to learn so much from my peers and colleagues some of which are here. This is a wonderful survey of many of the works in this area. As I was sitting here, I was in real-time adjusting my slides to minimize the overlap.</description></item><item><title>Streamlet: Textbook Streamlined Blockchain Protocols</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/streamlet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/streamlet/</guid><description>((&amp;hellip;. stream went offline in the other room, had to catch up.))
Show you new consensus protocol called streamlet. We think it is remarkably simple intuitive. This is quite a bold claim, hopefully the protocol will speak for itself
Incredibly subtle, hard to implement in practice. We want to take this reputation and sweep it out the door.
Jump right in. First model the consensus problem. Motivating simplicity as a goal.</description></item><item><title>The GHOSTDAG protocol</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/ghostdag/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/ghostdag/</guid><description>paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/104.pdf
Introduction This is joint work with Yonatan. I am going to talk about a DAG-based protocol to scale on-chain. The reason why I like this protocol is because it&amp;rsquo;s a very simple generalization of the longest-chain protocol that we all know and love. It gives some insight into what the role of proof-of-work is in these protocols. I&amp;rsquo;ll start with an overview of bitcoin protocol because I want to contrast against it.</description></item><item><title>The optimistic VM</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/optimistic-vm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/optimistic-vm/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230974707249233921
Introduction Okay, let&amp;rsquo;s get started our afternoon session. Our first talk I am very happy to introduce our speaker on optimistic virtual machines. Earlier in this conference we heard about optimistic roll-ups and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to this talk on optimistic virtual machines which is an up-and-coming approach on doing this.
Why hello everyone. I am building on ethereum and in particular we&amp;rsquo;re going to make Optimism: the attitude that will save the day.</description></item><item><title>Threshold Scriptless Scripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/threshold-scriptless-scripts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/threshold-scriptless-scripts/</guid><description>Omer Shlomovits (KZen Research) (omershlomovits, zengo)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171690582445580288
Scriptless scripts We can write smart contracts in bitcoin today, but there&amp;rsquo;s some limitations. We can do a lot of great things. We can do atomic swaps, multisig, payment channels, etc. There&amp;rsquo;s a cost, though. Transactions become bigger with bigger scripts. Also, it&amp;rsquo;s kind of heavy on the verifiers. The verifiers now need to verify more things. There&amp;rsquo;s also privacy issues because you put your contract publicly on chain.</description></item><item><title>Tight Proofs of Space and Replication</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/proofs-of-space-and-replication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/proofs-of-space-and-replication/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1091064672831234048
paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/702.pdf
Introduction This talk is about proofs of space and tight proofs of space.
Proof of Space A proof-of-space is an alternative to proof-of-work. Applications have been proposed like spam prevention, DoS attack prevention, sybil resistance in consensus networks which is most relevant to this conference. In proof-of-space, it&amp;rsquo;s an interactive protocol between a miner and a prover who has some disk storage and claims that hey I am storing 1 gigabyte of data.</description></item><item><title>Transparent Dishonesty: front-running attacks on Blockchain</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/transparent-dishonesty/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/transparent-dishonesty/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1231005309310627841
Introduction The last two talks are going to be about frontrunning. One of the features of blockchain is that they are slow but this also opens them up to vulnerabilities such that I can insert my transactions before other people and this could have bad consequences and Shayan is going to explore this a little bit.
My talk will not be as intense as the previous talk, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to have more pictures.</description></item><item><title>Transparent SNARKs from DARK compilers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/transparent-snarks-from-dark-compilers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/transparent-snarks-from-dark-compilers/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230561492254089224
paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2019/1229.pdf
Introduction Our next speaker is Ben Fisch, part of the Stanford Applied Crypto team and he has done a lot of work that is relevant to the blockchain space. Proofs of replication, proofs of space, he is also one of the coauthors of a paper that defined the notion of verifiable delay functions. He has also worked on accumulators, batching techniques, vector commitments, and one of his latest works is exciting which is DARKs which he is going to talk about today.</description></item><item><title>TxProbe: Discovering bitcoin's network topology using orphan transactions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/txprobe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/txprobe/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171723329453142016
paper: https://arxiv.org/abs/1812.00942
https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/coinscope-andrew-miller/
Introduction I am Sergi. I will be presenting txprobe. This is baout discovering the topology of the bitcoin network using orphan transactions. There are a bunch of coauthors and collaborators.
What we know about the topology I want to start by talking a little bit about what we know about the network topology without using txprobe.
When we talk about topology, we know a few things beforehand.</description></item><item><title>Validation Cost Metric</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/validation-cost-metric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/validation-cost-metric/</guid><description>slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY2/3_tweaking_the_chain_3_nick.pdf
Motivation As we&amp;rsquo;ve seen over the last two days scalability is a multidimensional problem. One of the main topics of research is increasing the blocksize to increase transaction throughput. The assumption is that as technological progress is continuing and transaction throughput is increased accordingly, the cost for runnning a fully validating node stays constant.
However, blocksize proposals usually only directly change one aspect of full node costs - the blocksize.</description></item><item><title>Zerolink Sudoku - real vs perceived anonymity</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/zerolink-sudoku/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/zerolink-sudoku/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171788514326908928
Introduction I used to work in software. I transitioned to something else, but bitcoin changed my mind. This talk is a little bit of a work in progress. This was started by a guy named Aviv Milner who is involved with Wasabi. He roped me into this and then subsequently became unavailable. So this is basically me presenting his work. It&amp;rsquo;s been severely &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;. as I said, Aviv started this project, he defined the research questions and then became unavailable so I&amp;rsquo;m here presenting in his stead.</description></item></channel></rss>