<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>research on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/research/</link><description>Recent content in research on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Research wishlist</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2022-10/2022-10-12-research-wishlist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2022-10/2022-10-12-research-wishlist/</guid><description>https://docs.google.com/document/d/1oRCeDzY3zH2ZY-BUYIVfJ1GMkvLlqKHWCFdtS62QWAo/edit
Introduction In spirit of the conversation happening today earlier, I&amp;rsquo;ll give some motivation. In general there is a disconnect between academic researchers and people who work in open-source software. It&amp;rsquo;s a pity because these two groups are interested in bitcoin, they love difficult questions and working on them, and somehow it seems like the choice of questions and spirit of work is sometimes not aligned to the best of bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin R&amp;D Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2022/bitcoin-randd-panel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2022/bitcoin-randd-panel/</guid><description>Ayush: 00:00:07
My name is Ayush Khandelwal. I am a software engineer at Google. I run a tech crypto-focused podcast on the side. And I have some amazing guests with me. So if you want to introduce yourself, what do you work on? And yeah, just get us started.
Jeremy: 00:00:31
I am Jeremy Rubin. I am a class of 2016 MIT alumni, so it&amp;rsquo;s good to be back on campus.</description></item><item><title>Sydney Socratic Seminar</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-07-06-socratic-seminar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-07-06-socratic-seminar/</guid><description>Name: Socratic Seminar
Topic: Fee bumping and layer 2 protocols
Location: Bitcoin Sydney (online)
Video: No video posted online
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Agenda: https://github.com/bitcoin-sydney/socratic/blob/master/README.md#2021-07
First IRC workshop on L2 onchain support: https://lists.</description></item><item><title>Sydney Socratic Seminar</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-06-01-socratic-seminar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-06-01-socratic-seminar/</guid><description>Name: Socratic Seminar
Topic: Agenda in Google Doc below
Location: Bitcoin Sydney (online)
Video: No video posted online
Google Doc of the resources discussed: https://docs.google.com/document/d/1E9mzB7fmzPxZ74WZg0PsJfLwjpVZ7OClmRdGQQFlzoY/
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.</description></item><item><title>Sydney Socratic Seminar</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-02-23-socratic-seminar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-02-23-socratic-seminar/</guid><description>Name: Socratic Seminar
Topic: Agenda in Google Doc below
Location: Bitcoin Sydney (online)
Video: No video posted online
Google Doc of the resources discussed: https://docs.google.com/document/d/1VAP4LNjHHVLy9RJwpQ8LqXEUw79z5TTZxr9du_Z0-9A/
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.</description></item><item><title>Coinswap</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi-research-club/2020-06-15-coinswap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi-research-club/2020-06-15-coinswap/</guid><description>Name: Wasabi Research Club
Topic: CoinSwaps
Location: Wasabi Research Club (online)
Wasabi Research Club: https://github.com/zkSNACKs/WasabiResearchClub
Intro (Aviv Milner) Today we are talking about CoinSwaps, massively improving Bitcoin privacy and fungibility. A lot of excitement about CoinSwaps so hopefully we can touch on some interesting things.
CoinSwaps (Belcher 2020) https://gist.github.com/chris-belcher/9144bd57a91c194e332fb5ca371d0964
This is a 2020 ongoing GitHub research paper that Chris Belcher has been working on. You can view the original file here.</description></item><item><title>Opening Remarks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/opening-remarks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/opening-remarks/</guid><description>Opening remarks
http://bsafe.network/events/codefi_stanford_2020/
https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229833591716102144
Good morning. Let us start this workshop. I am a researcher at Georgetown University and it is my pleasure to host this workshop. CoDeFi is a workshop about coordination of decentralized finance. This unfortunately shares a name with a Consensys product. CoDeFi contains CoDe and DeFi. This is a multi-stakeholder workshop to discuss stakeholders that have never met before. I think we have regulators here, and engineers here, and researchers here, and business people here.</description></item><item><title>Regulatory Pain Points</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/regulatory-pain-points/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/regulatory-pain-points/</guid><description>Regulatory pain points
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229838162827993088
Introduction Hi, good morning everyone. I am a Japanese financial regulator at JFSA. My goal is to promote financial innovations and still ensure the financial stability and various regulatory goals. I have nearly 10 years experience as a regulator. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a strong background in technology, so I hope I can rely on the other stakeholders on this. I am now in Washington DC doing research on blockchain and governance policy.</description></item><item><title>Current state of P2P research in Bitcoin /Erlay</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2019-11-13-gleb-naumenko-p2p-erlay/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2019-11-13-gleb-naumenko-p2p-erlay/</guid><description>London Bitcoin Devs
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1201861687097352198
Introduction My name is Gleb. I’ve worked on Bitcoin stuff since 2015, building wallets and exchanges in Ukraine. Then I realized that I can do more fun stuff. I want to do more protocol research, improving Bitcoin itself, not just using it. I decided I will go to Canada to do a Masters. I started working on this topic on research stuff more precisely and I realized that not many people do work on peer-to-peer (P2P) of Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Knowledge Aggregation And Propagation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/knowledge-aggregation-and-propagation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/knowledge-aggregation-and-propagation/</guid><description>Intro https://docs.google.com/document/d/1a1uRy10dBBcxrnzjdUaO2y03f5H34yFlxktOcanvVYE/edit
https://cess.pubpub.org/pub/knowledge-aggregation/branch/2/
I&amp;rsquo;ll be the contrarian - I think academia is awful and should be destroyed.
Reputation is completely independent of content and should not be the mechanism by which you judge the quality of research; your reputation is worthless to me. (laughter)
My perspective: [first, slidemaker&amp;rsquo;s regret! might have reorganized this] I&amp;rsquo;m a bitcoin core developer. Also worked at LedgerX (4 years). I also work on biotech on the hobbyist side, garage engineering &amp;ndash; what I was doing when bitcoin was launched.</description></item><item><title>Threshold Schnorr Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/threshold-schnorr-signatures/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/threshold-schnorr-signatures/</guid><description>Topic: The Quest for Practical Threshold Schnorr Signatures
Location: Cryptoeconomic Systems Summit 2019
Slides: https://slides.com/real-or-random/schnorr-threshold-sigs-ces-summit-2019
Transcript completed by: Bryan Bishop Edited by: Michael Folkson
Introduction It&amp;rsquo;s great to be here. My name is Tim Ruffing and I work for the research team at Blockstream. This is a talk about practical threshold Schnorr signatures and our quest for constructing them.
Disclaimer First of all, this is work in progress. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty early work in progress, mostly based on discussions with people at Blockstream.</description></item><item><title>Wallet Architecture in Bitcoin Core</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/wallet-architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/wallet-architecture/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171018684816605185
Introduction Thanks Bryan for talking about HD wallets. I am going to be talking about wallet architecture in Bitcoin Core. Alright. Who am I? I work on Bitcoin Core. I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing code on Bitcoin Core for about 3 years. Lately I have been working on the wallet. I work for Chaincode Labs which is why I get to work on Bitcoin Core. We are a small research lab in New York.</description></item><item><title>Socratic Seminar 2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/austin-bitcoin-developers/2019-08-22-socratic-seminar-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/austin-bitcoin-developers/2019-08-22-socratic-seminar-2/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1164710800910692353
Introduction Hello. The idea was to do a more socratic style meetup. This was popularized by Bitdevs NYC and spread to SF. We tried this a few months ago with Jay. The idea is we run through research news, newsletters, podcasters, talk about what happened in the technical bitcoin community. We&amp;rsquo;re going to have different presenters.
Mike Schmidt is going to talk about some optech newsletters that he has been contributing to.</description></item><item><title>Drivechain</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/austin-bitcoin-developers/2019-05-27-drivechain-paul-sztorc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/austin-bitcoin-developers/2019-05-27-drivechain-paul-sztorc/</guid><description>Drivechain: An interoperability layer-2, Described in terms of the lightning network- something you already understand
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1133202672570519552
About me Okay. So here&amp;rsquo;s some things about myself. I&amp;rsquo;ve been a bitcoiner since 2012. I&amp;rsquo;ve published bitcoin research on truthcoin.info blog. I&amp;rsquo;ve presented at Scaling Bitcoin 1, 2, 3, 4, tabconf, and Building on Bitcoin. My background is in economics and statistics. I worked at Yale Econ Department as a statistician for 2.5 years.</description></item><item><title>Watchtowers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/boltathon/2019-04-06-conner-fromknecht-watchtowers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/boltathon/2019-04-06-conner-fromknecht-watchtowers/</guid><description>Architecture of LND Watchtowers
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1117427512081100800
discussion: https://www.reddit.com/r/lightningdevs/comments/bd33cp/architecture_of_lnd_watchtowers_presentation_from/
Intro Pretty excited today to speak on the topic of watchtowers. It is something that we at Lightning Labs have been working on for almost a year now. Conceptual proof of concept code to really flushing it out into what would be today more of a full on protocol. Hopefully today we’re going to summarize a year of research into this presentation. I’m looking forward to getting into it with you guys so let’s dive right in.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Topological Analysis</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-topological-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-topological-analysis/</guid><description>Topological analysis of the lightning network
paper: https://arxiv.org/abs/1901.04972
https://github.com/seresistvanandras/LNTopology
Introduction Knowing the topology is not necessarily a vulnerability, but it gives you a lot of information. If I know Bryan&amp;rsquo;s full node is connected to some other nodes, I will have an easier time to cut Bryan out of the network or launch attacks against him. Knowing the topology is not necessarily a vulnerability, but it&amp;rsquo;s really strong information.
Recent research There were some recent papers published on this topic:</description></item><item><title>Unchained Capital Socratic Seminar</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2019-01-05-unchained-capital-socratic-seminar/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2019-01-05-unchained-capital-socratic-seminar/</guid><description>Unchained Capital Bitcoin Socratic Seminar
Socratic Seminar 87 at BitDevs NYC has all of the links on meetup.com available.
https://www.meetup.com/BitDevsNYC/events/256924041/
https://www.meetup.com/Austin-Bitcoin-Developers/events/257718282/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1081674259880120323
Last time Last time Andrew Poelstra gave a talk about research at Blockstream. He also talked about scriptless scripts and using the properties of Schnorr signatures to do all of your scripting. There was also talk about taproot and graftroot.
J: The chaincode labs guys in NYC .. we had a lot of participation, it was very cool.</description></item><item><title>Schnorr Signatures For Bitcoin - Challenges and Opportunities</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/schnorr-signatures-for-bitcoin-challenges-opportunities/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/schnorr-signatures-for-bitcoin-challenges-opportunities/</guid><description>Schnorr signatures for Bitcoin: Opportunities and challenges
slides: https://prezi.com/bihvorormznd/schnorr-signatures-for-bitcoin/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/958776403977220098
https://blockstream.com/2018/02/15/schnorr-signatures-bpase.html
Introduction My name is Pieter Wuille. I work at Blockstream. I contribute to Bitcoin Core and bitcoin research in general. I work on various proposals for the bitcoin system for some time now. Today I will be talking about Schnorr signatures for bitcoin, which is a project we&amp;rsquo;ve been working on, on-and-off, for a couple of years now. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the cool things that we can do that might be non-obvious, and also some non-obvious challenges that we ran into while doing this.</description></item><item><title>Mimblewimble And Scriptless Scripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/realworldcrypto/2018/mimblewimble-and-scriptless-scripts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/realworldcrypto/2018/mimblewimble-and-scriptless-scripts/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/954531580848082944
We&amp;rsquo;re about ready for the second session of RWC. We are going to move on to cryptocurrencies. So we have 3 talks lined up in this session. The first one is on mimblewimble and scriptless scripts, delivered by Andrew Poelstra from Blockstream.
Introduction Thank you. Cool. Hello. My name is Andrew Poelstra. I am the research director at Blockstream and I&amp;rsquo;m here to talk about a couple of things that I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about over the past year, called mimblewimble, and also scriptless scripts.</description></item><item><title>Banks As Bitcoin Custodians</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/banks-as-bitcoin-custodians/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/banks-as-bitcoin-custodians/</guid><description>Traditional banks as bitcoin custodians: Security challenges and implications
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005545022559866880
Our next speaker is Giacomo Zucco. Yeah, have fun.
categories: [&amp;lsquo;conference&amp;rsquo;] tags: [&amp;lsquo;security&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;research&amp;rsquo;] As you can hear, there are a lot of italians here. Okay. So, good afternoon everyone. I am Giacomo Zucco.
I am a theoretical physicist. I worked at Accenture as a technology consultant and now I work at BHB Network which is a bridge between free open-source development and research on the bitcoin protocol, and the world of the incumbents.</description></item><item><title>Spam Attacks Analysis</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/spam-attacks-analysis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/spam-attacks-analysis/</guid><description>Hunting moby dick, an analysis of 2015-2016 spam attacks
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005525351517360129
Introduction Hi. Thanks for Breaking Bitcoin to invite me to speak and to present this research on Moby Dick.
Moby Dick and spam attacks&amp;ndash; let me explain, Moby Dick is an entity that spammed or sent a lot of transactions in bitcoin in 2015. We did some analysis on who this person is or what they were doing. This is bitcoin archaeology, where we analyze past activities and try to analyze what happened and get insight into what could happen.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Mining And Trustlessness</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/bitcoin-mining-and-trustlessness/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/bitcoin-mining-and-trustlessness/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/838500313212518404
Yes, something like that. As mentioned, I&amp;rsquo;ve been contributing to Bitcoin Core since 2011 and I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on various parts of bitcoin, such as the early payment channel work, some wallet stuff, and now I work for Chaincode Lab one of the sponsors&amp;ndash; we&amp;rsquo;re a bitcoin research lab. We all kind of hang out and work on various bitcoin projects we find interesting. I want to talk about reflections on trusting trust.</description></item><item><title>Dan Boneh</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-developers-miners-meeting-2016/dan-boneh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-developers-miners-meeting-2016/dan-boneh/</guid><description>A conversation with Dan Boneh
Part of the challenge was that the Google Maps directions in the email were going down some roads that had construction&amp;hellip;. been here 10 minutes, and some arriving in another 10 minutes. They are building a new biology building. Large campus here. In whatever direction you walk, there are buildings and more buildings. In two years there will be a new biology building, and two years later there will be a new computer science building.</description></item><item><title>A Wishlist For Verifiable Computation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/simons-institute/a-wishlist-for-verifiable-computation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/simons-institute/a-wishlist-for-verifiable-computation/</guid><description>A wishlist for verifiable computation: An applied computer science perspective
http://www.pepper-project.org/ https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z4jzA6ts2j4 http://simons.berkeley.edu/talks/mike-walfish-2015-06-10 slides: http://www.pepper-project.org/surveywishlist.pptx slides (again): http://simons.berkeley.edu/sites/default/files/docs/3316/surveywishlist2.pptx more: http://www.pepper-project.org/talks.htm Okay, thanks. I want to begin by thanking the organizers, especially the tall guy for allowing me to be here. This talk will be talking about a research area where the goal is deployable systems for verifiable computation for probabilistic proofs like SNARKs etc. The goal of this talk is to motivate the next theoretical steps in this area.</description></item><item><title>Bip Securethebag</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/bip-securethebag/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/bip-securethebag/</guid><description>BIP: OP_SECURETHEBAG
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171750965478854656
Introduction Thank you for the introduction. Today I am going to talk to you about OP_SECURETHEBAG. It&amp;rsquo;s research that I have been working on for the last couple years. I think it&amp;rsquo;s very exciting and hopefully it will have a big compact. I have a lot of slides.
Why are we here? We are here for scaling bitcoin. The goal we have is to scale bitcoin. What is scaling, though?</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Block Propagation and IBLT</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/bitcoin-block-propagation-iblt-rusty-russell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/bitcoin-block-propagation-iblt-rusty-russell/</guid><description>This is not what I do. But I was doing it anyway.
The problem is that blocks are transmitted in their entirety. If you have a 1 MB uplink and you&amp;rsquo;re connecting to 8 peers, your first peer will see a 1MB block in about 66.8 seconds. And the last one will get it in 76.4 seconds, because we basically blast out blocks in parallel to our peers. Miners can solve this problem of slow block transmission by centralizing and all using the same pool.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Core V0.17</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/jnewbery-bitcoin-core-v0.17/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/jnewbery-bitcoin-core-v0.17/</guid><description>Bitcoin Core v0.17
slides: https://www.dropbox.com/s/9kt32069hoxmgnt/john-newbery-bitcoincore0.17.pptx
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1031960170027536384
Introduction I am John Newbery. I work on Bitcoin Core. This talk is going to be mostly about Bitcoin Core 0.17 which was branched on Monday. Hopefully the final release will be in the next couple of weeks.
whoami I live in New York and work at Chaincode Labs. I&amp;rsquo;m not actually a native born New Yorker. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to be back in London and talking with you guys about bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Day 2 Group Summaries</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/day-2-group-summaries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/day-2-group-summaries/</guid><description>Day 2 group summaries
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785151245883412480
Our epic journey in Milan is coming to an end. Let&amp;rsquo;s get seated. Each group is going to have a maximum of 3 minutes to report back. First let&amp;rsquo;s have collaboration between bitcoin community and academia.
Collaboration between bitcoin community and academia In the first half the workshop, 6 universities gave introductions of their activities and relationship to engineering and companies. We share the fact that most universities have joint research work with companies.</description></item><item><title>Designing Lightning Wallets for the Bitcoin Users</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/lightning-wallet-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/lightning-wallet-design/</guid><description>Good morning everyone. Thank you for being here. Thank you to the organizers for this event. My talk is about designing lightning wallets for bitcoin users. I am talking about UX. But really, UX is a lot more than what wallets look like. It&amp;rsquo;s from bip39 and making backups much easier, to anything you cna imagine, to make it easier for bitcoin to use bitcoin.
I am Patricia Estevao. https://patestevao.com/</description></item><item><title>Ethereum 2.0 and beyond</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/ethereum2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/ethereum2/</guid><description>Please welcome Vitalik who needs no introduction.
Introduction Okay. I have 20 minutes. I will get right to it. Vlad gave a presentation on some of his research into CBC Casper and how CBC Casper can be extended into sharding contexts. This presentation will be about taking some of the existing research into consensus algorithms and sharding and other things we have done in the last few years and see how they concretely translate into what is actually going to be deployed to Ethereum Foundation in the short to medium term future.</description></item><item><title>Flash Boys V2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/flash-boys-v2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/flash-boys-v2/</guid><description>&amp;ndash; Disclaimer &amp;ndash;
These are unpaid transcriptions, performed in real-time and in-person during the actual source presentation. Due to personal time constraints they are usually not reviewed against the source material once published. Errors are possible. If the original author/speaker or anyone else finds errors of substance, please email me at kanzure@gmail.com for corrections.
I sometimes add annotations to the transcription text. These will always be denoted by a standard editor&amp;rsquo;s note in parenthesis brackets ((like this)), or in a numbered footnote.</description></item><item><title>G20 Discussion</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/g20-discussion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/g20-discussion/</guid><description>Why do we need a multi-stakeholder discussion in a blockchain world? A report from G20 discussions.
https://bsafe.network
Introduction I am the cofounder of the bsafe.network which focuses on blockchain research. I was a program co-chair for Scaling Bitcoin at Keio University last year. I also work with IEEE, ACM conferences, Ledger Journal, and more. My background is engagement with Bank of Japan NTT internet cash in 1998-2000.
Several huge incidents From a regulatory point of view, there are many big events that have occurred: MtGox, the DAO attack, coincheck, monacoin, and Zaif.</description></item><item><title>Group Updates.Md</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/rebooting-web-of-trust/2019-prague/group-updates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/rebooting-web-of-trust/2019-prague/group-updates/</guid><description>Group updates
Alice abuses verifiable credentials We restricted our scope to a manageable slice of the problem we think we can realistically handle. It&amp;rsquo;s been very productive. We made an outline together, and now everyone can work on individual parts of the paper. I think it&amp;rsquo;s been great.
Blockcerts v3 We categorized what we wanted to write about and work on and kind of going back and looking at the history of blockcerts and specific things that were added, and an extension that were added, and looking more closely at the verifiable credentials schema.</description></item><item><title>Improvements to Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/maaku-panel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/maaku-panel/</guid><description>This can be a broad range of topics for improvements. I am Mark Friedenbach, I have worked on Bitcoin protocol research, but I also do Core tech engineering at Blockstream. We also have Jonas, an independent Bitcoin Core developer. We also have Andrew Poelstra, who has been core to the crypto work which has been incoporated into Bitcoin, such as libsecp256k1 which we recently integrated in the 0.12 release. It speeds up Bitcoin validation by 7-8x.</description></item><item><title>Lessons For Bitcoin From 150 Years Of Decentralization</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/lessons-for-bitcoin-from-150-years-of-decentralization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/lessons-for-bitcoin-from-150-years-of-decentralization/</guid><description>Arvind Narayanan (twitter- random_walker) - Princeton University
Another 30 seconds. Take your seats. We have Arvind Narayanan. Some of the research from Princeton has rivaled the work of MIT. Professor Narayanan is going to teach us some lessons for Bitcoin.
Thank you. Can you hear me? I think you can. What I want to do today is to look at lessons from history for the future of Bitcoin, the next 10 years for Bitcoin, the next 30 years for Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Matsuo</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/matsuo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/matsuo/</guid><description>bsafe.network
Giving trust by security evaluation and bsafe.network
This is a severe problem. How can we trust the output of blockchain technology? We have several security issues. There was the huge DAO attack from two weeks ago. We also have other problems, such as protocol specification, key management, implementation, operation, and vulnerability handling. Also key renewal and key revocation issues.
ISO/IEC 27000 ISO/IEC 15408 ISO/IEC 29128 ISO/IEC 29128 ISO/IEC, NIST IETF We already have several international standards on each layer.</description></item><item><title>Mimblewimble Podcast</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/mimblewimble-podcast/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/mimblewimble-podcast/</guid><description>https://soundcloud.com/heryptohow/mimblewimble-andrew-poelstra-peter-wuille-brian-deery-and-chris-odom
Andrew Poelstra (andytoshi) Pieter Wuille (sipa) Brian Deery Chris Odom Starts at 26min.
I am going to introduce our guests here in just a minute.
Launch of zcash might be delayed in order to allow the code to be analyzed by multiple third-party auditors. Zooko stated, &amp;ldquo;I feel bad that we didn&amp;rsquo;t do a better job of making TheDAO disaster-like problems harder for people&amp;rdquo;.
Our guests on the line are Andrew Poelstra and Pieter Wuille.</description></item><item><title>Motoko Language</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/motoko-language/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/motoko-language/</guid><description>Motoko, the language for the Internet Computer
Introduction Thanks, Byron. Glad to be here. My name is Dominic Williams. I am founder of the internet computer project at Dfinity Foundation. Last year we talked about consensus protocols. Today we are talking about tools for building on top of the internet computer which is great news and shows the progress we have made. I&amp;rsquo;m going to give some introductory context, and then our senior researcher from our languages division will talk about Motoko.</description></item><item><title>Multi Party Channels In The Utxo Model Challenges And Opportunities</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-party-channels-in-the-utxo-model-challenges-and-opportunities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-party-channels-in-the-utxo-model-challenges-and-opportunities/</guid><description>Multi-party channels in the UTXO model: Challenges and opportunities
Olaoluwa Osuntokun (Lightning Labs) (roasbeef)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048468663089618944
Introductions Hi. So my name is Laolu. I am also known as roasbeef and I am co-founder of Lightning Labs. I am going to go over some cool research and science fiction. In the actual implementation for these things and cool to discuss and get some discussions around this. first I am going to talk about single-party channels and multi-party channels.</description></item><item><title>Near Misses</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/near-misses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/near-misses/</guid><description>Near misses: What could have gone wrong
Introduction Thank you. I am Ethan Heilman. I am a research whose has done a bunch of work in security of cryptocurrencies. I am also CTO of Arwen which does secure atomic swaps. I am a little sick today so please excuse my coughing, wheezing and drinking lots of water.
Bitcoin scary stories The general outline of this talk is going to be &amp;ldquo;scary stories in bitcoin&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Rootstock</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/rootstock/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/rootstock/</guid><description>Rootstock
Sergio is co-founder and chief scientist at RSK Labs. The whitepaper was pretty good. I am happy that he is here. Thank you. Just give me a minute.
Alicia Bendhan Lous Parker BitDevsNYC
Yes, I use powerpoint. Please don&amp;rsquo;t read my emails.
Thanks everyone for staying here and not going to the next room. Thanks for the organizers for inviting me. Today I am going to talk about Rootstock. It&amp;rsquo;s a codename for a smart contracting platform that we are developing for SKY labs, which is a company we founded in 2015.</description></item><item><title>Scalable Rsa Modulus Generation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/scalable-rsa-modulus-generation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/scalable-rsa-modulus-generation/</guid><description>Scalable RSA Modulus Generation with Dishonest Majority
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230545603605585920
Introduction Groups of unknown order are interesting cryptographic primitives. You can commit to integers. If you commit to a very large integer, you have to do a lot of work to do the commitment so you have a sequentiality assumption useful for VDFs. But then you have this compression property where if you take a large integer with a lot of information in it, you can compress it down to something small.</description></item><item><title>Scriptless Scripts With Mimblewimble</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/scriptless-scripts-with-mimblewimble/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/scriptless-scripts-with-mimblewimble/</guid><description>Scriptless scripts with mimblewimble
Andrew Poelstra (andytoshi)
Introduction Hi everyone. I am Andrew Poelstra. I am the research director at Blockstream. I want to talk about deploying scriptless scripts, wihch is something I haven&amp;rsquo;t talked much about over the past year or two.
History Let me give a bit of history about mimblewimble. As many of you know, this was dead-dropped anonymously in the middle of 2016 by someone named Tom Elvis Jedusor which is the French name for Voldemort.</description></item><item><title>Security Assumptions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/security-assumptions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/security-assumptions/</guid><description>Hi, welcome back.
I am a developer for libsecp256k1. It&amp;rsquo;s a library that does the underlying traditional cryptography used in Bitcoin. I am going to talk about security assumptions, security models and trust models. I am going to give a high-level overview of how we should be thinking about these issues for scaling and efficiency and decentralization. Bitcoin is a crypto system. Everything about it is a crypto system. It needs to be designed with an adversarial mindset, even in an adversarial setting.</description></item><item><title>Security Attacks Decentralized Mining Pools</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/security-attacks-decentralized-mining-pools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/security-attacks-decentralized-mining-pools/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137373752038240262
Introduction Hi, I am Alexei. I am a research student at Imperial College London and I will be talking about the security of decentralized mining pools.
Motivation The motivation behind this talk is straightforward. I think we can all agree that to some extent the hashrate in bitcoin has seen some centralization around large mining pools, which undermines the base properties of censorship resistance in bitcoin which I think bitcoin solves in a nice matter.</description></item><item><title>Self Reproducing Coins As Universal Turing Machine</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/self-reproducing-coins-as-universal-turing-machine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/self-reproducing-coins-as-universal-turing-machine/</guid><description>paper: https://arxiv.org/abs/1806.10116
Introduction This is joint work with my colleagues. I am Alexander Chepurnoy. We work for Ergo Platform. Vasily is an external member. This talk is about turing completeness in the blockchain. This talk will be pretty high-level. This talk is based on already-published paper, which was presented at the CBT conference. Because of copyright agreements with Springer, you will not find the latest version on arxiv.
The general question of scalability is how can we do more with less until we can do everything with nothing?</description></item><item><title>Sharding The Blockchain</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/sharding-the-blockchain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/sharding-the-blockchain/</guid><description>I am going to talk about blockchain sharding. This is one of the scaling solutions that I like the most. I have done the most work on it. In case you don&amp;rsquo;t know who I am, I am a researcher mostly with the ethereum project. Basically the basics of sharding is that in non-sharding, every node does every validation. In a sharding solution, nodes hold a subset of the state, and a subset of the blockchain.</description></item><item><title>Snarks And Their Practical Applications</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/simons-institute/snarks-and-their-practical-applications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/simons-institute/snarks-and-their-practical-applications/</guid><description>Joint works with:
Eli Ben-Sasson Matthew Green Alessandro Chiesa Ian Miers Christina Garman Madars Virza Daniel Genkin Thank you very much. I would like to thank the organizers for giving this opportunity to learn so much from my peers and colleagues some of which are here. This is a wonderful survey of many of the works in this area. As I was sitting here, I was in real-time adjusting my slides to minimize the overlap.</description></item><item><title>Systematizing Knowledge</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/systematizing-knowledge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/systematizing-knowledge/</guid><description>There should be a SNARK wiki. Any website that is better than someone saying &amp;ldquo;you know, check the June July 2014 bitcoin-wizard logs&amp;rdquo;. We need to research gmaxwell scalability. We should probably fix that.
Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about what some of the goals are that we might get out of this. We have some different ideas for approaches to systematizing knowledge. There are at least three camps here. I think Bryan&amp;rsquo;s paper repositories.</description></item><item><title>Validation Cost Metric</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/validation-cost-metric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/validation-cost-metric/</guid><description>slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY2/3_tweaking_the_chain_3_nick.pdf
Motivation As we&amp;rsquo;ve seen over the last two days scalability is a multidimensional problem. One of the main topics of research is increasing the blocksize to increase transaction throughput. The assumption is that as technological progress is continuing and transaction throughput is increased accordingly, the cost for runnning a fully validating node stays constant.
However, blocksize proposals usually only directly change one aspect of full node costs - the blocksize.</description></item><item><title>Zerolink Sudoku - real vs perceived anonymity</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/zerolink-sudoku/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/zerolink-sudoku/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171788514326908928
Introduction I used to work in software. I transitioned to something else, but bitcoin changed my mind. This talk is a little bit of a work in progress. This was started by a guy named Aviv Milner who is involved with Wasabi. He roped me into this and then subsequently became unavailable. So this is basically me presenting his work. It&amp;rsquo;s been severely &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;. as I said, Aviv started this project, he defined the research questions and then became unavailable so I&amp;rsquo;m here presenting in his stead.</description></item></channel></rss>