<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dan Boneh on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/dan-boneh/</link><description>Recent content in Dan Boneh on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/dan-boneh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Welcome Remarks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/welcome-remarks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/welcome-remarks/</guid><description>Welcome remarks
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230178753805836288
https://cbr.stanford.edu/sbc20/
telegram: https://t.me/sbc20
wifi: Stanford, blockchain/blockchain
Okay, we&amp;rsquo;re going to get started in five minutes. We&amp;rsquo;re going to get started. We have a fully packed day. Everybody can grab their seats and then we can get started.
Alright. So let&amp;rsquo;s do this.
Okay, welcome to the fourth Stanford Blockchain Conference. It&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of fun running this conference for a couple of years now. There&amp;rsquo;s a few quick administrative things I wanted to say.</description></item><item><title>Verifiable Delay Functions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/verifiable-delay-functions/vdf-day-2019/dan-boneh/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/verifiable-delay-functions/vdf-day-2019/dan-boneh/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1152586087912673280
Introduction I&amp;rsquo;ll give an overview of VDFs and make sure that we&amp;rsquo;re on the same page. I want to make sure everyone knows what it is that we&amp;rsquo;re talking about.
The goal of a VDF is to slow things down. The question is, how do we slow things down in a verifiable way?
What is a VDF? I won&amp;rsquo;t give a precise definition, look at the manuscripts. A VDF is basically a function that is supposed to take T steps to evaluate, even if the honest party has polynomial parallelism.</description></item><item><title>Dan Boneh</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-developers-miners-meeting-2016/dan-boneh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-developers-miners-meeting-2016/dan-boneh/</guid><description>A conversation with Dan Boneh
Part of the challenge was that the Google Maps directions in the email were going down some roads that had construction&amp;hellip;. been here 10 minutes, and some arriving in another 10 minutes. They are building a new biology building. Large campus here. In whatever direction you walk, there are buildings and more buildings. In two years there will be a new biology building, and two years later there will be a new computer science building.</description></item><item><title>Pairing Cryptography</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/simons-institute/pairing-cryptography/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/simons-institute/pairing-cryptography/</guid><description>Dan Boneh (see also 1)
slides: http://crypto.biu.ac.il/sites/default/files/3rd_BIU_Winter_School/Boneh-basics-of-pairings.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/772287326999293952
original video: https://video.simons.berkeley.edu/2015/other-events/historical-papers/05-Dan-Boneh.mp4
original video sha256 hash: 1351217725741cd3161de95905da7477b9966e55a6c61686f7c88ba5a1ca0414
Okay, so um I&amp;rsquo;m very happy to introduce another speaker in this historical papers series seminar seminar series which is organized by Daniel Wigs and Vanakutanata. Daniel is here but where&amp;rsquo;s..? Okay. All of these talks are being recorded, you can watch some online if you have missed some. It&amp;rsquo;s a pleasure to introduce Dan Boneh, a professor at Stanford.</description></item><item><title>Accumulators</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/accumulators/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/accumulators/</guid><description>A scalable drop-in replacement for merkle trees
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048454406755168257
Introduction Hello. Test. Okay. I am going to talk about accumulators for UTXOs. The previous two talks were a great setup for this. This is joint work with Ben Fisch who is also here today and Dan Boneh. I first want to advertise the Stanford Blockchain Conference (formerly known as BPASE) happening at the end of January 2019 at Stanford. Whether you give a talk or not, you should try to attend.</description></item><item><title>Compact Multi Signatures For Smaller Blockchains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/compact-multi-signatures-for-smaller-blockchains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/compact-multi-signatures-for-smaller-blockchains/</guid><description>Compact multi-signatures for smaller blockchains
Dan Boneh (Stanford University), Manu Drijvers and Gregory Neven (DFINITY)
paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/483.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048441176024469504
Introduction Hi. Thanks a lot for coming in after lunch. This slot is often known as &amp;ldquo;the slot of death&amp;rdquo;. Some of us are jetlagged, this is the perfect time to doze off and only wake up at the end of the talk. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to prevent that from happening. I think the best way to do that is to start about what this talk can do for you.</description></item><item><title>Opening Remarks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/opening-remarks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/opening-remarks/</guid><description>Opening remarks
We will be starting in 10 minutes. I would like to ask the first speaker in the first session for grin to walk to the back of the room to get your microphone ready for the talk.
It&amp;rsquo;s 9 o&amp;rsquo;clock and time to get started. Could everyone please get to their seats? Alright, let&amp;rsquo;s do this. Welcome everybody. This is the Stanford Blockchain Conference. This is the third time we&amp;rsquo;re running this conference.</description></item></channel></rss>