<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>proof-of-work on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/proof-of-work/</link><description>Recent content in proof-of-work on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/proof-of-work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Breaking The Chain</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/breaking-the-chain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/breaking-the-chain/</guid><description>Breaking the chain
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785144266683195392
http://dpaste.com/1ZYW028
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/milan/client-side-validation/
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong/braiding-the-blockchain/
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/milan/jute-braiding/
Inclusivitiy So it seems like we have two big topics here, one is braiding and one is proof-of-publication. I had a talk in Hong Kong about braiding. The major difference is the inclusive nature. The notion that every block gets a block reward as a way to solve selfish-mining. It&amp;rsquo;s a competition between the orphans that get a reward and the ones that don&amp;rsquo;t that causes a loss of security.</description></item><item><title>Competitive Equilibria Staking Lending</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/competitive-equilibria-staking-lending/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/competitive-equilibria-staking-lending/</guid><description>Competitive equilibria between staking and on-chain lending
Tarun Chitra
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230581977289379840
https://arxiv.org/pdf/2001.00919v1.pdf
See also &amp;ldquo;Stress testing decentralized finance&amp;rdquo; https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/stress-testing-decentralized-finance/
Introduction There have been some odd finanical attacks in the DeFi space and also on staking. This talk aims to show that the threat model for staking is definitively different from that of proof-of-work, and these financial attacks need to be part of the threat model.
Agenda I&amp;rsquo;ll go over some high level overview of intuitive market dynamics, then we will build up an agent-based model that correctly goes across multiple participants to stress test staking situations, then we go through the various assumptions, and at a high-level I&amp;rsquo;ll give some formal probability statements without proofs, and finally I have simulation results to discuss which can give you some idea about how to design a monetary policy.</description></item><item><title>Epicenter Bitcoin Adam3Us Scalability (2015-09-07)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2015-09-07-epicenter-bitcoin-adam3us-scalability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2015-09-07-epicenter-bitcoin-adam3us-scalability/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Why bitcoin needs a measured approach to scaling&amp;rdquo;
video: https://youtube.com/watch?v=wYHyR2E5Pic
Adam Back (adam3us) Epicenter (EC)
Sebastien Couture (SC) Brian Fabian Crain (BC)
BC: Adam Back is here for the second time on this show. Some of you will be familiar that Adam Back is the inventor of proof-of-work or hashcash as it was then. He was one of the few people cited in the original Bitcoin whitepaper. More recently he has been involved in sidechains and Blockstream where he is a founder.</description></item><item><title>Ethereum2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/ethereum2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/ethereum2/</guid><description>Ethereum 2.0 and beyond
Vitalik Buterin
Please welcome Vitalik who needs no introduction.
Introduction Okay. I have 20 minutes. I will get right to it. Vlad gave a presentation on some of his research into CBC Casper and how CBC Casper can be extended into sharding contexts. This presentation will be about taking some of the existing research into consensus algorithms and sharding and other things we have done in the last few years and see how they concretely translate into what is actually going to be deployed to Ethereum Foundation in the short to medium term future.</description></item><item><title>Fiat Money Fiat Food</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/fiat-money-fiat-food/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/fiat-money-fiat-food/</guid><description>Fiat money and fiat food
Saifedean Ammous
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1162734566479728641
Introduction Saife saved my life. Until I met Saife, and had him on my show and talked to him, I was a shitcoiner. Okay? Sorry guys. I am going to lay it out there. He talked to me, he came on my show, he sent me his book, his writings, and before I knew it, I started something I really wanted to share with everyone.</description></item><item><title>Flyclient Super Light Clients For Cryptocurrencies</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/flyclient-super-light-clients-for-cryptocurrencies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/flyclient-super-light-clients-for-cryptocurrencies/</guid><description>Flyclient Super light client for cryptocurrencies
Benedikt Buenz, Mahdi Zamani
buenz@cs.stanford.edu
Thank you.
As you know, the blockchain is a chain because each block connects to the previous block through these hashes. In the header of each block is a commitment to all the transactions. It&amp;rsquo;s using this merkle hash tree where at each level the parent node hashes to the children and this gives you some nice properties which I will talk about later.</description></item><item><title>Ghostdag</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/ghostdag/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/ghostdag/</guid><description>The GHOSTDAG protocol
Yonatan Sompolinsky and Aviv Zohar (The Hebrew University of Jerusalem)
paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/104.pdf
Introduction This is joint work with Yonatan. I am going to talk about a DAG-based protocol to scale on-chain. The reason why I like this protocol is because it&amp;rsquo;s a very simple generalization of the longest-chain protocol that we all know and love. It gives some insight into what the role of proof-of-work is in these protocols.</description></item><item><title>Jihan Wu Google Tech Talk (2016)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-developers-miners-meeting-2016/jihan-wu-google-tech-talk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-developers-miners-meeting-2016/jihan-wu-google-tech-talk/</guid><description>Jihan Wu
Bitcoin
Google Tech Talk
Okay so maybe we will start. Thank you for coming. We have about 25 folks here from the Bitcoin community, both miners and Core developers. Don&amp;rsquo;t know exactly what the definition of a Core developer is, but I guess I know one when I see one. So anyway, we&amp;rsquo;re lucky here to have Jihan Wu. He&amp;rsquo;s the co-founder of Bitmain, a leading Chinese bitcoin technology company and mining pool.</description></item><item><title>Law Enforcement And Anonymous Transactions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coindesk-consensus-2016/law-enforcement-and-anonymous-transactions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coindesk-consensus-2016/law-enforcement-and-anonymous-transactions/</guid><description>Preliminary notes:
Contact me- https://twitter.com/kanzure
Law enforcement and anonymous transactions
Jason Weinstein, Blockchain Alliance, moderator
Brian Klein, Baker Marquart
Prakash Santhana, Deloitte
James Smith, Elliptic
Zooko Wilcox, doing essential zooko things (zerocash)
Ladies and gentlemen. Please take your seats. The session is about to begin.
Please welcome Jason Weinstein, Brian Klein, Prakash Santhana, James Smith, and Zooko Wilcox.
JW: Any proof-of-work finalists should go to the 7th floor elevators and leave right now.</description></item><item><title>Marco Santori Delaware Initiative</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coindesk-consensus-2016/marco-santori-delaware-initiative/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coindesk-consensus-2016/marco-santori-delaware-initiative/</guid><description>Preliminary notes:
Contact me- https://twitter.com/kanzure
Marco Santori
Delaware initiative
It&amp;rsquo;s good to see so many friendly audiences in the audience. I am at Pillsbury Wintrhop Shaw Pittman. We are focusing on distinct areas of law as it applies to blockchain tech. We have been in the space as early as 2011 so we were trying to do the land grab. My team has been asked by the State of Delaware to serve as legal ambassadors to the blockchain industry.</description></item><item><title>Microchains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/microchains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/microchains/</guid><description>Microchains
David Vorick
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/927257690685939712
I would like to see a blockchain ecosystem with 1000s of transactions/second at layer 1 with full security. And so, we have to look at blockchain differently if we are going to achieve this.
A brief introduction&amp;hellip; my name is David Vorick. I have been studying bitcoin since 2011. My primary gig is Sia. I have been spending a lot of time on consensus algorithms and proof-of-work.</description></item><item><title>On The Security And Performance Of Proof Of Work Blockchains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/on-the-security-and-performance-of-proof-of-work-blockchains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/on-the-security-and-performance-of-proof-of-work-blockchains/</guid><description>On the security and performance of proof-of-work blockchains
Arthur Gervais
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785066988532068352
As most of you might know, in bitcoin and blockchains, the information is very important. Every node should receive the blocks in the network. Increase latency and risk network partition. If individual peers do not get the information, they could be victims of selfish mining and so on. Multiple blockchains has been proposed, multiple reparameterizations like litecoin, dogecoin, ethereum and others.</description></item><item><title>Proof Of Necessary Work</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/proof-of-necessary-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/proof-of-necessary-work/</guid><description>Proof of necessary work: Succinct state verification with fairness guarantees
Assimakis Kattis
Introduction I am going to show you proof of necessary work today. We use proof of work in a prototype. This is joint work with my collaborators.
Problems We wanted to tackle the problem of bitcoin blockchain size increases. Every 10 minutes, a block is added to the blockchain and the blockchain grows linearly in size over time. Initial block download increases over time.</description></item><item><title>Proof Of Stake</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/proof-of-stake/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/proof-of-stake/</guid><description>Proof-of-stake longest chain protocols revisited
David Tse
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230646529230163968
Introduction Thanks. I am the last talk of the session so I better make it interesting, and if not interesting then short at least. I am going to talk about proof-of-stake. This is collaboration with a few people. Vivek Bagaria, &amp;hellip; et al.
Proof-of-stake prism The starting point of this project was to come up with a proof-of-stake version of prism, which we just saw in the last talk.</description></item><item><title>Proofs Of Space And Replication</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/proofs-of-space-and-replication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/proofs-of-space-and-replication/</guid><description>Tight proofs of space and and replication
Ben Fisch (Stanford University)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1091064672831234048
paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/702.pdf
Introduction This talk is about proofs of space and tight proofs of space.
Proof of Space A proof-of-space is an alternative to proof-of-work. Applications have been proposed like spam prevention, DoS attack prevention, sybil resistance in consensus networks which is most relevant to this conference. In proof-of-space, it&amp;rsquo;s an interactive protocol between a miner and a prover who has some disk storage and claims that hey I am storing 1 gigabyte of data.</description></item><item><title>Sharding The Blockchain</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/sharding-the-blockchain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/sharding-the-blockchain/</guid><description>Sharding the blockchain
Vlad Zamfir
I am going to talk about blockchain sharding. This is one of the scaling solutions that I like the most. I have done the most work on it. In case you don&amp;rsquo;t know who I am, I am a researcher mostly with the ethereum project. Basically the basics of sharding is that in non-sharding, every node does every validation. In a sharding solution, nodes hold a subset of the state, and a subset of the blockchain.</description></item><item><title>Sybilquorum</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/sybilquorum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/sybilquorum/</guid><description>SybilQuorum: Open distributed ledgers through trust networks
Alberto Sonnino from UCL and chainspace.io
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1090777875253407745
Introduction This is joint work with George Danezis who couldn&amp;rsquo;t be here today and also cofounded Chainspace. Among all the possible challenges we may have on a blockchain, this talk will be about how to build strong sybil resistance. We would consider a subset of the problem, how will we bootstrap a federated agreement system?
Sybil attacks I am sure everyone knows about sybil attacks.</description></item><item><title>There Can Only Be One</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/there-can-only-be-one/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/there-can-only-be-one/</guid><description>Bitcoin: There can only be one
Tone Vays
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1162742007460192256
Introduction I am basically going to talk about why bitcoin will basically eat all the shitcoins and why all of them are going away and I am going to point to some of the details. The big graphic right there is my attempt to categorize all of the altcoins, the ICO space, and so on. Everyone is slowly starting to merge mine with bitcoin, since they can&amp;rsquo;t keep up with the charadde.</description></item><item><title>Why Block Sizes Should Not Be Too Big</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/why-block-sizes-should-not-be-too-big/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/why-block-sizes-should-not-be-too-big/</guid><description>Briefly, why block sizes shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too big
Luke Dashjr
slides: https://luke.dashjr.org/tmp/code/block-sizes-mcc.pdf
Video: https://youtu.be/JJF5Gnro1GU
I am luke-jr. I am going to go over why block size shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too big.
How does bitcoin work? Miners put transactrions into blocks. Users verify that the blocks are valid. If the users don&amp;rsquo;t verify this, then miners can do basically anything. Because the users do this, 51% attacks are limited to reorgs which is undoing transactions.</description></item><item><title>Work In Progress</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/work-in-progress/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/work-in-progress/</guid><description>Work in progress sessions
Scaling Bitcoin 2019 Tel Aviv &amp;ldquo;yesod&amp;rdquo;
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1172173183329476609
Optical proof of work Mikael Dubrovsky
I am working on optical proof-of-work. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to pack a lot into the 10 minutes. I spent a year and a half at Techion.
Physical scaling limits Probably the three big ones are, there&amp;rsquo;s first the demand for blockchain or wanting to use bitcoin more. I think more people want to use bitcoin.</description></item></channel></rss>