<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>career on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/career/</link><description>Recent content in career on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The State of Bitcoin Core Development</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-2024/the-state-of-bitcoin-core-development/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-2024/the-state-of-bitcoin-core-development/</guid><description>Discover the latest developments in Bitcoin Core with our expert panel featuring key contributors to the project. This video delves into recent changes in security vulnerability disclosures, the challenges of funding open-source development, and the careful process of introducing new features to Bitcoin Core. Our panelists offer unique perspectives on the project&amp;rsquo;s priorities and the distinction between Bitcoin Core and protocol development.</description></item><item><title>Choosing a Career in Bitcoin Open Source Development</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2024/choosing-a-career-in-bitcoin-open-source-development/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2024/choosing-a-career-in-bitcoin-open-source-development/</guid><description>Adam Jonas, from Chaincode Labs, presents a compelling case for choosing a career in Bitcoin open-source development. Highlighting the limited number of full-time developers, he seeks individuals driven by professional freedom, long-term impact, and innovative challenges. Jonas emphasizes Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s potential to address systemic issues like inflation, financial surveillance, and government overreach, presenting it as a revolutionary technology with a focus on decentralization. He shares inspiring stories of contributors like Gloria Zhao and ZmnSCPxj, illustrating the merit-based, inclusive nature of the community. Jonas outlines Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s technical challenges and innovations, such as the Lightning Network and ASMap project, inviting passionate individuals to join and contribute to this transformative project</description></item><item><title>Lightning Dev Kit: Making Lightning More Accessible to Developers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/lightning-dev-kit-making-lightning-more-accessible-to-developers-matt-corallo-tabconf-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/lightning-dev-kit-making-lightning-more-accessible-to-developers-matt-corallo-tabconf-2021/</guid><description>Introduction So, I worked on Bitcoin Core for many many years, but I am not here to talk about that! I now spend my time, full time at Square Crypto working on a project we call the Lightning Dev Kit (LDK). So, working to enable Lightning to be more accessible to developers and I&amp;rsquo;m here to talk about that and give the lay of the land for why it exists, what the state of the Lightning ecosystem is broadly, and why we think it&amp;rsquo;s an important project and why Square is funding us, to work on it.</description></item><item><title>A hardCORE workout</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2018-04-23-jeremy-rubin-bitcoin-core/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2018-04-23-jeremy-rubin-bitcoin-core/</guid><description>Slides: https://drive.google.com/file/d/149Ta1WRXL5WEvnBdlL-HxmsFDXUbvFDy/view
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1152926849879760896
Intro Thank you very much for the warm welcome. So welcome to the hard core workout. It is not going to be that difficult but you can stretch if you need to. It is going to be a lot of material so I’m going to go a little bit fast. If you have any questions feel free to stop me in the middle. There’s a lot of material to get through so I might say “Hold it” or “Find me after” but if there is anything that would help your understanding fee free to classroom style raise your hand and I’ll try to answer it.</description></item><item><title>How can we get 10x the number of "core" contributors?</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/more-core-devs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/more-core-devs/</guid><description>10x the number of core devs
Objectives:
10x would only be like &amp;lt;1000 bitcoin developers 7000 fedora developers how do we grow developers? how many tor developers? how many linux developers?
poaching from each other is not cool
There&amp;rsquo;s not enough people with the necessary skills. There&amp;rsquo;s no clear way to train new people. Apprenticeship works, but it scales very very poorly. It&amp;rsquo;s better than a static fixed number of developers.</description></item><item><title>Funding bitcoin development</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/funding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/funding/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s basically open-source funding. It&amp;rsquo;s a subset of open-source funding. But these are similar problems with many open-source projects. As far as I can tell, all these digital currency cryptocurrency projects are licensed with open-source licenses. There may be some that are not, and some things are patented. I generally steer clear of the patented work. If it&amp;rsquo;s decentralized and open-source, then why are you just delivering a binary to me?</description></item></channel></rss>