<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pieter Wuille on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/pieter-wuille/</link><description>Recent content in Pieter Wuille on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/pieter-wuille/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mempool Clustering</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2023-04/2023-04-25-mempool-clustering/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2023-04/2023-04-25-mempool-clustering/</guid><description>Current Problems lot of problems in the mempool
eviction is broken mining algorithm is part of the problem, it’s not perfect RBF is like totally broken we complain all the time, sometimes we do/don&amp;rsquo;t RBF when we should/shouldn&amp;rsquo;t Eviction Eviction is when mempool is full, and we want to throw away the worst tx. Example, we think a tx is worst in mempool but it’s a descendant of a &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; tx.</description></item><item><title>Nesting, ROAST, Half-Aggregation, Adaptor Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/nesting-roast-half-aggregation-adaptor-signatures/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/nesting-roast-half-aggregation-adaptor-signatures/</guid><description>Speaker 1: 00:00:00
Just as a warning, so don&amp;rsquo;t do this at home.
Speaker 0: 00:00:01
Yes, of course. Still have your friendly neighborhood cryptographer have a look at it.
Speaker 2: 00:00:16
This is the second half of the conversation with Tim and Peter. If you have not listened to the first half, I&amp;rsquo;d suggest going back and listening to that episode. We cover all sorts of fun things, including when to roll your own cryptography, why we prefer Schnorr signatures over ECDSA, Schnorr efficiency improvements, multi-sig, mu-sig, interactive versus non-interactive signing, Frost, and more.</description></item><item><title>Schnorr, MuSig, FROST and more</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/schnorr-musig-frost-and-more/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/schnorr-musig-frost-and-more/</guid><description>Pieter Wuille and Tim Ruffing treat us to a conversation about Schnorr, multisignatures, MuSig, and more. We covered a lot so this is part one of a two part conversation.</description></item><item><title>v2 P2P Transport Protocol for Bitcoin (BIP324)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2022-11-13-dhruv-pieter-wuille-and-tim-ruffing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2022-11-13-dhruv-pieter-wuille-and-tim-ruffing/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/433/
Stephan Livera – 00:03:20:
Gentlemen, welcome to the show.
Dhruv – 00:03:22:
Hello.
Tim Ruffing – 00:03:23:
Hi.
Stephan Livera – 00:03:24:
Yeah, so thanks, guys, for joining me and interested to chat about what you’re working on and especially what’s going on with P2P transport, a v2 P2P transport protocol for bitcoin core.
Dhruv – 00:03:36:
Bitcoin?
Stephan Livera – 00:03:37:
Yeah, for a course for bitcoin. So I think, Pieter and Tim, I think listeners probably know you, Dhruv, if you want to just give a quick intro for yourself, just for listeners to know who you are.</description></item><item><title>SLP321 On-chain scaling with Bitcoin Core Developers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2021-11-16-pieter-wuille-andrew-poelstra-andrew-chow-mark-erhardt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2021-11-16-pieter-wuille-andrew-poelstra-andrew-chow-mark-erhardt/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/321/
Emcee:
All right. I’m really excited for this next panel. I’ve heard some of them speak in different rooms and I can’t wait to hear what they all have to say today. Next up, I’m going to bring up our moderator. He has a podcast. It is a self-titled podcast and he’s also the managing director of Swan Bitcoin International. Please everybody, welcome to the stage Stephan Livera, everyone.</description></item><item><title>The P2P network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/the-p2p-network-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/the-p2p-network-2/</guid><description>P2P experts Amiti Uttarwar and Pieter Wuille discuss various aspects of peer-to-peer communication in Bitcoin, with Adam Jonas facilitating the conversation. They delve into the challenges and objectives of address relay, highlighting its complexities and the importance of propagating IP addresses to maintain network connectivity and prevent partitioning and eclipse attacks. The discussion covers the design and evolution of AddrMan, introduced in 2012 to manage IP addresses, and the impact of changes like rate-limiting address gossip to mitigate spam. Pieter and Amiti also touch on the significance of maintaining separate network stacks for different network protocols and the potential of employing ASMAP to improve network resilience. The conversation underscores ongoing efforts and future directions for enhancing Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s P2P network.</description></item><item><title>Socratic Seminar - BIP Taproot (BIP 341)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-07-21-socratic-seminar-bip-taproot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-07-21-socratic-seminar-bip-taproot/</guid><description>Pastebin of the resources discussed: https://pastebin.com/vsT3DNqW
Transcript of Socratic Seminar on BIP-Schnorr: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-16-socratic-seminar-bip-schnorr/
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have given permission for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Introductions Michael Folkson (MF): This is a Socratic Seminar on BIP-Taproot. Sorry for the delay for the people on the YouTube livestream.</description></item><item><title>Socratic Seminar - BBIP Schnorr (BIP 340)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-16-socratic-seminar-bip-schnorr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-16-socratic-seminar-bip-schnorr/</guid><description>Pastebin of the resources discussed: https://pastebin.com/uyktht33
August 2020 update: Since this Socratic on BIP Schnorr there has been a proposed change to the BIP revisting the squaredness tiebreaker for the R point.
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have given permission for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.</description></item><item><title>Pieter Wuille (part 1 of 2)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2020-01-28-pieter-wuille-part1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2020-01-28-pieter-wuille-part1/</guid><description>Part 2: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q2lXSRcacAo
Jonas: Welcome to the podcast
John: Hi Pieter
Pieter: Hello John and Jonas
John: Thank you for being the first guest on our podcast.
Jonas: So far the most important guest we’ve had.
Pieter: That’s an amazing honor. Thank you so much for having me.
John: We’re here to talk about Bitcoin and Bitcoin Core development. We have Pieter Wuille as our guest who is a Bitcoin Core contributor of many years standing.</description></item><item><title>Pieter Wuille (part 2 of 2)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2020-01-28-pieter-wuille-part2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2020-01-28-pieter-wuille-part2/</guid><description>Jonas: We are gonna pick up where we left off in episode 1 with a discussion of lessons learned from the 0.8 consensus failure. We then go on to cover libsecp and Pieter&amp;rsquo;s thoughts about Bitcoin in 2020. We hope you enjoy this as much as we did.
John: Ok I have a bunch of questions from that. One is what are the lessons from that?
Pieter: One of the things I think learned from that is specifying what your consensus rules is really hard.</description></item><item><title>BIP Taproot and BIP Tapscript</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2019-12-16-bip-taproot-bip-tapscript/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2019-12-16-bip-taproot-bip-tapscript/</guid><description>slides: https://prezi.com/view/AlXd19INd3isgt3SvW8g/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1208438837845929987
https://twitter.com/SFBitcoinDevs/status/1206678306721894400
bip-taproot: https://github.com/sipa/bips/blob/bip-schnorr/bip-taproot.mediawiki
bip-tapscript: https://github.com/sipa/bips/blob/bip-schnorr/bip-tapscript.mediawiki
bip-schnorr: https://github.com/sipa/bips/blob/bip-schnorr/bip-schnorr.mediawiki
Please try to find seats. Today we have a special treat. We have Pieter here, who is well known as a contributor to Bitcoin Core, stackexchange, the mailing list, and he has been around forever. He&amp;rsquo;s the author of multiple BIPs. Today he is going to talk about taproot and tapscript which is basically what the whole Schnorr movement thing became.</description></item><item><title>The Tools and The Work</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lets-talk-bitcoin-podcast/2019-06-09-ltb-pieter-wuille-jonas-nick/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lets-talk-bitcoin-podcast/2019-06-09-ltb-pieter-wuille-jonas-nick/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s Talk Bitcoin with Pieter Wuille and Jonas Nick - June 9th 2019
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1155851797568917504
Part 1: https://letstalkbitcoin.com/blog/post/lets-talk-bitcoin-400-the-tools-and-the-work
Part 2: https://letstalkbitcoin.com/blog/post/lets-talk-bitcoin-401-the-tools-and-the-work-part-2
Draft of BIP-Schnorr: https://github.com/sipa/bips/blob/bip-schnorr/bip-schnorr.mediawiki
Draft of BIP-Taproot: https://github.com/sipa/bips/blob/bip-schnorr/bip-taproot.mediawiki
Draft of BIP-Tapscript: https://github.com/sipa/bips/blob/bip-schnorr/bip-tapscript.mediawiki
Part 1 Adam: On this episode we&amp;rsquo;ll be digging deeply into some of the most important changes coming soon to the Bitcoin protocol in the form of BIPs or Bitcoin Improvement Proposals focused on Taproot, Tapscript and Schnorr signatures.</description></item><item><title>Taproot</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06/2019-06-06-taproot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06/2019-06-06-taproot/</guid><description>https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/master/bip-0340.mediawiki
https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2019-May/016914.html
https://bitcoinmagazine.com/articles/taproot-coming-what-it-and-how-it-will-benefit-bitcoin/
previously: http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-03-06-taproot-graftroot-etc/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1136616356827283456
Introduction Okay, so, first question- who put my name on that list and what do they want? It wasn&amp;rsquo;t me. I&amp;rsquo;ll ask questions. I can give a summary, but there&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of talk already and I don&amp;rsquo;t know what to focus on. What would sipa like us to review in particular about it? What design decisions do you feel least confident about? Is there anything where you would like other people to investigate design decisions before charging ahead?</description></item><item><title>Script Descriptors</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-10/2018-10-08-script-descriptors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-10/2018-10-08-script-descriptors/</guid><description>https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/blob/master/doc/descriptors.md
I would like to talk about script descriptors. There&amp;rsquo;s a number of projects we&amp;rsquo;re working on and they are all kind of related. I&amp;rsquo;d like to clarify how things fit together.
Note: there is an earlier transcript that has not been published (needs review) about script descriptors.
Agenda History of script descriptors and how we came to this. What&amp;rsquo;s currently in Bitcoin Core v0.17 Wallet integration DESCRIPT About script descriptors The problem that I wanted to tackle was that currently in Bitcoin Core wallet we have a blob of public keys and private keys and HD chains and scripts and a bunch of other metadata and keypools.</description></item><item><title>Taproot, Schnorr signatures, and SIGHASH_NOINPUT</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2018-07-09-taproot-schnorr-signatures-and-sighash-noinput-oh-my/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2018-07-09-taproot-schnorr-signatures-and-sighash-noinput-oh-my/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1021880538020368385
slides: https://prezi.com/view/YkJwE7LYJzAzJw9g1bWV/
Introduction I am Pieter Wuille. I will just dive in. Today I want to talk about improvements to the bitcoin scripting language. There is feedback in the microphone. Okay.
I will mostly be talking about improvements to the bitcoin scripting language. This is by no means an exhaustive list of all the things that are going on. It&amp;rsquo;s more my personal focus in the things that I am interested in and excited about seeing happen.</description></item><item><title>Schnorr Signatures For Bitcoin: Challenges and Opportunities</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/schnorr-signatures-for-bitcoin-challenges-opportunities/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/schnorr-signatures-for-bitcoin-challenges-opportunities/</guid><description>slides: https://prezi.com/bihvorormznd/schnorr-signatures-for-bitcoin/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/958776403977220098
https://blockstream.com/2018/02/15/schnorr-signatures-bpase.html
Introduction My name is Pieter Wuille. I work at Blockstream. I contribute to Bitcoin Core and bitcoin research in general. I work on various proposals for the bitcoin system for some time now. Today I will be talking about Schnorr signatures for bitcoin, which is a project we&amp;rsquo;ve been working on, on-and-off, for a couple of years now. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the cool things that we can do that might be non-obvious, and also some non-obvious challenges that we ran into while doing this.</description></item><item><title>New Address Type For Segwit Addresses</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-03-29-new-address-type-for-segwit-addresses/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-03-29-new-address-type-for-segwit-addresses/</guid><description>Topic: Bech32 addresses for Bitcoin
Slides: https://prezi.com/gwnjkqjqjjbz/bech32-a-base32-address-format/
Proposal: https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/master/bip-0173.mediawiki
Demo website: http://bitcoin.sipa.be/bech32/demo/demo.html
Twitter announcement: https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/847569047902273536
Transcript completed by: Bryan Bishop Edited by: Michael Folkson
Intro Can everyone hear me fine through this microphone? Anyone who can&amp;rsquo;t hear me please raise your hand. Oh wait. All good now? Tonight I will be speaking on a project I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on on and off for the past year or so, which is the question of what kind of addresses we will be using in Bitcoin in the future.</description></item><item><title>Schnorr Signatures for Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/schnorr-signatures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/schnorr-signatures/</guid><description>Slides: URL expired
Pieter Wuille presentation on Schnorr at BPASE 2018: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/schnorr-signatures-for-bitcoin-challenges-opportunities/
Transcript completed by: Bryan Bishop Edited by: Michael Folkson
Intro Today I will be talking about Schnorr signatures for Bitcoin. I want to say a few things in advance. One is even though this is a talk about cryptography and in particular new cryptography I don&amp;rsquo;t consider myself to be a cryptographer. Most of the work I will be talking about is a result of talking to a lot of smart people for a long time.</description></item><item><title>Mimblewimble Podcast</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/mimblewimble-podcast/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/mimblewimble-podcast/</guid><description>Andrew Poelstra (andytoshi) Pieter Wuille (sipa) Brian Deery Chris Odom Starts at 26min.
I am going to introduce our guests here in just a minute.
Launch of zcash might be delayed in order to allow the code to be analyzed by multiple third-party auditors. Zooko stated, &amp;ldquo;I feel bad that we didn&amp;rsquo;t do a better job of making TheDAO disaster-like problems harder for people&amp;rdquo;.
Our guests on the line are Andrew Poelstra and Pieter Wuille.</description></item><item><title>Key Tree Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2015-08-24-pieter-wuille-key-tree-signatures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2015-08-24-pieter-wuille-key-tree-signatures/</guid><description>Slides: https://prezi.com/vsj95ns4ucu3/key-tree-signatures/
Blog post: https://blockstream.com/2015/08/24/en-treesignatures/
Intro For those who don’t know me I’m Pieter Wuille. I have been working on Bitcoin Core for a while but this is work I have been doing at Blockstream. Today I will be talking about Key Tree Signatures which is what I have been working on these past few weeks. It is an improvement to the multisig schemes that we want to support. This is an outline of my talk.</description></item><item><title>Miniscript</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/miniscript/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/miniscript/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1091116834219151360
Jeremy: Our next speaker really needs no introduction. However, I am obligated to deliver an introduction anyway. I&amp;rsquo;m not just trying to avoid pronouncing his name which is known to be unpronounceable. I am pleased to welcome Pieter Wuille to stage to present on miniscript.
Introduction Thanks, Jeremy. I am Pieter Wuille. I work at Blockstream. I do various things. Today I will be talking about miniscript, which is a joint effort between myself and some colleagues at Blockstream particularly Andrew Poelstra.</description></item><item><title>Segregated Witness And Its Impact On Scalability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/segregated-witness-and-its-impact-on-scalability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/segregated-witness-and-its-impact-on-scalability/</guid><description>slides: https://prezi.com/lyghixkrguao/segregated-witness-and-deploying-it-for-bitcoin/
code: https://github.com/sipa/bitcoin/commits/segwit
SPV = simplified payment verification
CSV = checksequenceverify
CLTV = checklocktimeverify
Segregated witness (segwit) and deploying it for Bitcoin
Okay. So I am Pieter Wuille. I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about segregated witness for Bitcoin. Before I can explain this, I want to give some context. We all know how bitcoin transactions work. Every bitcoin transaction gets inputs, which refer to previous outputs being spent. Every input has the txid and the signature to prove that it is allowed, plus an amount and script in every output.</description></item></channel></rss>