<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Alex Bosworth on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/alex-bosworth/</link><description>Recent content in Alex Bosworth on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/alex-bosworth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SLP324 Scaling Bitcoin off-chain with Matt Corallo, Alex Bosworth, Lisa Neigut, and Graham Krizek</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2021-11-27-lisa-neigut-alex-bosworth-graham-krizek-and-matt-corallo/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2021-11-27-lisa-neigut-alex-bosworth-graham-krizek-and-matt-corallo/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/324/
Stephan Livera:
So guys, thanks for joining us. We’re talking about off-chain scaling. And so obviously Lightning is the first thing that comes to our mind, but maybe we could start with this idea of What is off-chain scaling? I think Lisa, you had something to add on this, didn’t you?
Matt Corallo:
We had a meeting in the back and we decided we were moving Lightning to TRON.</description></item><item><title>Scaling with LND</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/scaling-with-lnd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/scaling-with-lnd/</guid><description>Intro I wanted to talk about scaling lightning using LND. I started working at Lightning Labs three years ago and come really a long way. I started working with LND before that when I worked at BitGo. That was the barest, almost didn&amp;rsquo;t work, it was crashing everyday type of scenario. Now, three years later, we&amp;rsquo;re trying to scale this to millions of people. We&amp;rsquo;re trying to scale this to millions of payments.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Routing</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2021-03-27-alex-bosworth-lightning-routing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2021-03-27-alex-bosworth-lightning-routing/</guid><description>Lightning Routing - Building a new economy
Location: Lightning Hack Day
media: No video posted online
Slides: https://www.dropbox.com/s/oo9o8ij62utvlfo/alex-bosworth-lightning-routing.pdf
Transcript of presentation on Channel Management (2018): https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-alex-bosworth-channel-management/
Transcript by: Michael Folkson
Intro With Lightning routing I think it is a very exciting topic because we’re doing something that no one has ever really done before, to build this peer-to-peer marketplace. It is a required component of the Lightning Network because the Lightning Network is dependent on this concept of liquidity.</description></item><item><title>Submarine Swaps, Lightning Loop, Hyperloop</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2019-10-24-alex-bosworth-submarine-swaps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2019-10-24-alex-bosworth-submarine-swaps/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/119/
Stephan Livera: Alex, welcome to the show.
Alex Bosworth: Hi. It’s great to be on the show. Finally.
Stephan Livera: Yeah, I’ve been meaning to get you on for a while and you know, now we’re finally making it happen. So just, context for the listeners, we are recording this one in person just before the lightning conference, the inaugural lightning conference. So just a couple of days before there was lightning meetup last night.</description></item><item><title>Submarine Swaps</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2019-07-03-alex-bosworth-submarine-swaps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2019-07-03-alex-bosworth-submarine-swaps/</guid><description>London Bitcoin Devs
Submarine Swaps and Loop
Slides: https://www.dropbox.com/s/cyh97jv81hrz8tf/alex-bosworth-submarine-swaps-loop.pdf?dl=0
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1151158631527849985
Intro Thanks for inviting me. I’m going to talk about submarine swaps and Lightning Loop which is something that I work on at Lightning Labs.
Bitcoin - One Currency, Multiple Settlement Networks Something that is pretty important to understand about Lightning is that it is a flow network so once you set up your channels and you’re in a network of channels with other people, the balances can only shift along flow properties of the network.</description></item><item><title>Multiple-path Payments (MPP)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-alex-bosworth-mpp/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-alex-bosworth-mpp/</guid><description>Topic: Multiple-path Payments (MPP)
Location: Chaincode Residency 2019
Bigger, Faster, Cheaper - Multiplexing Payments Alex: How to do multiple path payments. So there&amp;rsquo;s a question: why do we even need multiple path payments? So you have a channel &amp;ndash; like &amp;ndash; we don&amp;rsquo;t have them now, so are we really hurting for them? So I kind of like describing different situations where you would need it. So in the first quadrant you can see I have two channels.</description></item><item><title>Ln Present And Future Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/ln-present-and-future-panel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/ln-present-and-future-panel/</guid><description>Lightning network present &amp;amp; future panel
LC: Can everyone hear me now? Alright, alright.
WO: It&amp;rsquo;s getting some good usage. A lot of those are businesses. Definitely it&amp;rsquo;s in the early stage. Elizabeth talked about this. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of things that are mostly for fun, it&amp;rsquo;s not really at ecommerce yet.
LC: That&amp;rsquo;s for lnd?
WO: Sure, and I think Lisa can talk about c-lightning.
LC: I like these different implementations for LN.</description></item><item><title>Submarine Swaps</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/submarine-swaps/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/submarine-swaps/</guid><description>Bridging off-chain and on-chain with submarine swaps
Introduction Hi, I work at Lightning Labs. I want to talk about the dawn of hyperloop. It&amp;rsquo;s a new concept.
Hyperloop To zoom out on what problem we&amp;rsquo;re working on here, we had this cool lightning network. But it&amp;rsquo;s, the way the lightning network works, is that it&amp;rsquo;s complementary to the bitcoin network. Each side has its pros and cons. If you want the most effective way to send capital around, you want to leverage both.</description></item><item><title>Major Limitations of Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/boltathon/2019-04-06-alex-bosworth-major-limitations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/boltathon/2019-04-06-alex-bosworth-major-limitations/</guid><description>Slides: https://drive.google.com/open?id=1UIHfYdnAWGMvsLhljTgcneCxQAHcWjxg
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1116824776952229890
Intro So I had a Twitter poll to decide what to talk about. People seem pretty interested in the limitations. Where is the line of what Lightning can do and what Lightning can’t do. That’s what I want to talk about. To make it more clear what can be done and what can’t be done.
Every Transaction A Lightning Transaction When I first started really focusing on Lightning I thought what is the goal of Lightning, what is the goal of the Lightning Network?</description></item><item><title>Building Lightning Applications</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-alex-bosworth-building-lightning-applications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-alex-bosworth-building-lightning-applications/</guid><description>Slides: https://lightningresidency.com/assets/presentations/Bosworth_Building_Applications.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1116327230135836673
Intro Today I’m going to talk about building on lnd from the perspective of we want to have developers building on lnd. Developers, developers, developers. I just have so many slides today that let’s leave questions to the end if I have any time because I over made slides.
Design Philosophy So what is the big idea behind lnd? What are we thinking about when we’re developing lnd and what do we want lnd to be?</description></item><item><title>Channel Management</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-alex-bosworth-channel-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-alex-bosworth-channel-management/</guid><description>Slides: https://lightningresidency.com/assets/presentations/Bosworth_Channel_Management.pdf
Intro Today I’m going to talk about something a little bit different to building apps. I’m going to talk about becoming a great router. Managing your node so that your node can be routing payments and be a good citizen if you choose to have public channels.
Uptime So basically the big message overall is and I think I’ve said this before, if you have public channels you’re kind of like waving to everybody “please use these channels to do routing”.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Protocol</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-alex-bosworth-lightning-protocol/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-alex-bosworth-lightning-protocol/</guid><description>The Lightning Protocol, an Application Design Perspective
Slides: https://lightningresidency.com/assets/presentations/Bosworth_The_Lightning_Protocol.pdf
Intro I’m talking about the protocol design and also going through the BOLTs. What I’m going to talk about is also about the BOLTs. The BOLTs are like the spec for Lightning and there’s a bunch of them.
BOLT 00: Build Apps What I try to do is go through the BOLTs and look at only the parts of the BOLTs, the protocol design, that you as an app developer would need to care about.</description></item><item><title>Incentive Problems in the Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-09-18-alex-bosworth-incentive-problems-in-the-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-09-18-alex-bosworth-incentive-problems-in-the-lightning-network/</guid><description>Incentive Problems in the Lightning Network I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about high-level incentive problems in the Lighting Network.
Mechanisms The first thing to think about is that we have two different mechanisms for making Bitcoin and lightning work. One mechanism is math — If you do a SHA 256 of something you don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about incentives, whether that&amp;rsquo;s going to match to the expected result. There&amp;rsquo;s no incentive there.</description></item></channel></rss>