<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>video on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/categories/video/</link><description>Recent content in video on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/categories/video/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Choosing a Career in Bitcoin Open Source Development</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2024/choosing-a-career-in-bitcoin-open-source-development/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2024/choosing-a-career-in-bitcoin-open-source-development/</guid><description>Adam Jonas, from Chaincode Labs, presents a compelling case for choosing a career in Bitcoin open-source development. Highlighting the limited number of full-time developers, he seeks individuals driven by professional freedom, long-term impact, and innovative challenges. Jonas emphasizes Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s potential to address systemic issues like inflation, financial surveillance, and government overreach, presenting it as a revolutionary technology with a focus on decentralization. He shares inspiring stories of contributors like Gloria Zhao and ZmnSCPxj, illustrating the merit-based, inclusive nature of the community. Jonas outlines Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s technical challenges and innovations, such as the Lightning Network and ASMap project, inviting passionate individuals to join and contribute to this transformative project</description></item><item><title>Translational Bitcoin Development</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/layer-2/translational-bitcoin-development/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/layer-2/translational-bitcoin-development/</guid><description>Introduction This is called Translational Bitcoin Development or Why Johnny Can&amp;rsquo;t Verify. So quick intro, I&amp;rsquo;m Tadge Dryja. Stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on in Bitcoin over the last decade is the Bitcoin Lightning Network paper, the Discreet Log Contracts paper, Utreexo, and building out a lot of that software. In terms of places I&amp;rsquo;ve worked, Lightning Labs, founded that, and then MIT DCI is where I used to work for a couple years and now I&amp;rsquo;m at a company called Lightspark.</description></item><item><title>How to Design Schnorr Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinology/how-to-design-schnorr-signatures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinology/how-to-design-schnorr-signatures/</guid><description>Passwords So, I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk to you today about passwords and about the problem with passwords and how we might be able to solve it, right? So we&amp;rsquo;re all familiar with using passwords on the internet and we&amp;rsquo;re all sort of sometimes annoyed about it. Maybe you use a password manager, maybe you don&amp;rsquo;t, but you have this problem, I think we all understand this problem that it&amp;rsquo;s not just about you losing the password, but it&amp;rsquo;s also about keeping it secret, right?</description></item></channel></rss>