<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>signet on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/signet/</link><description>Recent content in signet on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/signet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to become Signet Rich: Learn about Bitcoin Signet and Zebnet</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/how-to-become-signet-rich-learn-about-bitcoin-signet-and-zebnet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/how-to-become-signet-rich-learn-about-bitcoin-signet-and-zebnet/</guid><description>Richard: So today we are going to talk about Signet Lightning, PlebNet Playground, which was the first evolution of me playing with custom Signets, and eventually ZebNet Adventures. This is how you can become Signet-rich.
First, we should probably do an overview of the various network types. Everybody knows about Mainnet. This is what we use day to day, but there&amp;rsquo;s a few other testing networks. RegTest, or SimNet, if you are running BTCD, is a local unit testing framework.</description></item><item><title>Socratic Seminar - Signet</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-08-19-socratic-seminar-signet/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-08-19-socratic-seminar-signet/</guid><description>Topic: Signet
Name: Socratic Seminar
Location: London BitDevs (online)
Pastebin of the resources discussed: https://pastebin.com/rAcXX9Tn
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have given permission for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Intro Michael Folkson (MF): This is a Socratic Seminar organized by London BitDevs.</description></item><item><title>Signet annd its uses for development</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/signet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/signet/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171310731100381184
https://explorer.bc-2.jp/
Introduction I was going to talk about signet yesterday but people had some delay downloading docker images. How many of you have signet right now? How many think you have signet right now? How many downloaded something yesterday? How many docker users? And how many people have compiled it themselves? Okay. I think we have like 10 people. The people that compiled it yourself, I think you&amp;rsquo;re going to be able to do this.</description></item></channel></rss>