<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>signet on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/signet/</link><description>Recent content in signet on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/signet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to become Signet Rich: Learn about Bitcoin Signet and Zebnet</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/how-to-become-signet-rich-learn-about-bitcoin-signet-and-zebnet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/how-to-become-signet-rich-learn-about-bitcoin-signet-and-zebnet/</guid><description>Richard: So today we are going to talk about Signet Lightning, PlebNet Playground, which was the first evolution of me playing with custom Signets, and eventually ZebNet Adventures. This is how you can become Signet-rich.
First, we should probably do an overview of the various network types. Everybody knows about Mainnet. This is what we use day to day, but there&amp;rsquo;s a few other testing networks. RegTest, or SimNet, if you are running BTCD, is a local unit testing framework.</description></item><item><title>Explaining Signet</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-magazine/bitcoin-explained/explaining-signet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-magazine/bitcoin-explained/explaining-signet/</guid><description>Intro Aaron van Wirdum: 00:00:07
Live from Utrecht, this is the Van Wirdum Sjorsnedo. Hello! Sjors, welcome.
Sjors Provoost: 00:00:12
Thank you. It&amp;rsquo;s good to be back. Well, I never left, but&amp;hellip;
Aaron van Wirdum: 00:00:15
Yeah, well, we&amp;rsquo;re at your home now, so you never left, I think. You probably literally never left because of corona
Sjors Provoost: 00:00:21
Exactly we&amp;rsquo;re at my secret location
Aaron van Wirdum: 00:00:25</description></item><item><title>Socratic Seminar - Signet</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-08-19-socratic-seminar-signet/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-08-19-socratic-seminar-signet/</guid><description>Pastebin of the resources discussed: https://pastebin.com/rAcXX9Tn
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have given permission for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Intro Michael Folkson (MF): This is a Socratic Seminar organized by London BitDevs. We have a few in the past. We had a couple on BIP-Schnorr and BIP-Taproot that were really good with Pieter Wuille, Russell O’Connor and various other people joined those.</description></item><item><title>Signet Workshop</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-07-kalle-alm-signet-workshop/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-07-kalle-alm-signet-workshop/</guid><description>Video: No video posted online
Let’s prepare mkdir workspace cd workspace git clone https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin.git cd bitcoin git remote add kallewoof https://github.com/kallewoof/bitcoin.git git fetch kallewoof git checkout signet ./autogen.sh ./configure -C --disable-bench --disable-test --without-gui make -j5 When you try to run the configure part you are going to have some problems if you don’t have the dependencies. If you don’t have the dependencies Google your OS and “Bitcoin build”. If you have Windows you’re out of luck.</description></item><item><title>Signet Integration</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-06-kalle-alm-signet-integration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-06-kalle-alm-signet-integration/</guid><description>Slides: https://www.dropbox.com/s/6fqwhx7ugr3ppsg/Signet%20Integration%20V2.pdf
BIP 325: https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/master/bip-0325.mediawiki
Signet on Bitcoin Wiki: https://en.bitcoin.it/wiki/Signet
Bitcoin dev mailing list: https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2019-March/016734.html
Bitcoin Core PR 16411 (closed): https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/16411
Bitcoin Core PR 18267 (open): https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/18267
Intro I am going to talk about Signet. Do you guys know what Signet is? A few people know. I will explain it briefly. I have an elevator pitch, I have three actually depending on the height of the elevator. Basically Signet is testnet except all the broken parts are removed.</description></item><item><title>Signet annd its uses for development</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/signet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/signet/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171310731100381184
https://explorer.bc-2.jp/
Introduction I was going to talk about signet yesterday but people had some delay downloading docker images. How many of you have signet right now? How many think you have signet right now? How many downloaded something yesterday? How many docker users? And how many people have compiled it themselves? Okay. I think we have like 10 people. The people that compiled it yourself, I think you&amp;rsquo;re going to be able to do this.</description></item><item><title>Signet</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06/2019-06-07-signet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06/2019-06-07-signet/</guid><description>https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2019-March/016734.html
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1136980462524608512
Introduction I am going to talk a little bit about signet. Does anyone not know what signet is? The idea is to have a signature of the block or the previous block. The idea is that testnet is horribly broken for testing things, especially testing things for long-term. You have large reorgs on testnet. What about testnet with a less broken difficulty adjustment? Testnet is for miner testing really.</description></item></channel></rss>