<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>proof-of-stake on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/proof-of-stake/</link><description>Recent content in proof-of-stake on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/proof-of-stake/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ethereum 2.0 and beyond</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/ethereum2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/ethereum2/</guid><description>Please welcome Vitalik who needs no introduction.
Introduction Okay. I have 20 minutes. I will get right to it. Vlad gave a presentation on some of his research into CBC Casper and how CBC Casper can be extended into sharding contexts. This presentation will be about taking some of the existing research into consensus algorithms and sharding and other things we have done in the last few years and see how they concretely translate into what is actually going to be deployed to Ethereum Foundation in the short to medium term future.</description></item><item><title>Handel Practical Multisig Aggregation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/handel-practical-multisig-aggregation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/handel-practical-multisig-aggregation/</guid><description>Handel: Practical multi-signature aggregation for large byzantine committees
Introduction Handle is a aggregation protocol for large scale byzantine committees. This is work with my colleagues in addition to myself.
Why aggregate? Distributed systems often require gathering statements about large subsets of nodes. However, processing (filtering, aggregating&amp;hellip;) measurements can be a bottleneck. We want to apply some processing while collecting the measurements.
Why byzantine? A byzantine node is a node that can be arbitrary.</description></item><item><title>Proof Of Stake</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/proof-of-stake/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/proof-of-stake/</guid><description>Proof-of-stake longest chain protocols revisited
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230646529230163968
Introduction Thanks. I am the last talk of the session so I better make it interesting, and if not interesting then short at least. I am going to talk about proof-of-stake. This is collaboration with a few people. Vivek Bagaria, &amp;hellip; et al.
Proof-of-stake prism The starting point of this project was to come up with a proof-of-stake version of prism, which we just saw in the last talk.</description></item></channel></rss>