<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Amiti Uttarwar on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/amiti-uttarwar/</link><description>Recent content in Amiti Uttarwar on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/amiti-uttarwar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Attacking Bitcoin Core</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/la-bitdevs/2020-04-16-amiti-uttarwar-attacking-bitcoin-core/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/la-bitdevs/2020-04-16-amiti-uttarwar-attacking-bitcoin-core/</guid><description>Location: BitDevs LA
Intro I’m going to talk to you today about attacking Bitcoin Core.
Bitcoin To start with the fundamentals. As we all know Bitcoin is a money and it is different to our existing centralized solution of money because instead we have nodes that are running all around the world.
Consensus Fundamentally what is required for this to work is the idea of consensus where all the nodes must agree on the same fundamental values.</description></item><item><title>Transaction Rebroadcast</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-09-09-amiti-uttarwar-transaction-rebroadcast/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-09-09-amiti-uttarwar-transaction-rebroadcast/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1199710296199385088
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/edgedevplusplus/rebroadcasting/
Introduction Hello. Thank you for joining me today. My name is Amiti and I’d like to tell you a bit about my Bitcoin journey.
Professional Background I graduated from Carnegie Mellon five years ago and ever since I’ve worked at a few different startups in San Francisco Bay Area. My adventures with blockchains began when I worked at Simbi. Simbi is a marketplace for trading and bartering services. Here I found a community of people who were living outside of their means.</description></item><item><title>Rebroadcasting</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/edgedevplusplus/rebroadcasting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/edgedevplusplus/rebroadcasting/</guid><description>Rebroadcasting
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171042478088232960
Introduction Hi, my name is Amiti. Thank you for having me here today. I wanted to talk with you about rebroadcasting logic in Bitcoin Core. For some context, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on improving it this summer. I wanted to tell you all about it.
What is rebroadcasting? We all know what a broadcast is. It&amp;rsquo;s hwen we send an INV message out to our peers and we let them know about a new transaction.</description></item></channel></rss>