<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jimmy Song on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/jimmy-song/</link><description>Recent content in Jimmy Song on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/jimmy-song/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Taproot multisig</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2022/2022-03-03-jimmy-song-taproot-multisig/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2022/2022-03-03-jimmy-song-taproot-multisig/</guid><description>Slides: https://jimmysong.github.io/taproot-multisig
Pull request adding multisig Taproot support to buidl-python: https://github.com/buidl-bitcoin/buidl-python/pull/109
Intro (Jeff Gallas) The next speaker is Jimmy Song who doesn’t really need an introduction but in any case, he has been, which is important for this conference, running the Programming Blockchain workshops for 5 years now. Leon is one of his alumni so there is a direct connection to this conference. He has also just released a new book which is a bit more political than technical, it is called “Bitcoin and the American Dream”.</description></item><item><title>Schnorr Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/schnorr-signatures-jimmy-song/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/schnorr-signatures-jimmy-song/</guid><description>Introduction Anyway, like I said, this is a technical talk and we&amp;rsquo;re going to talk about Schnorr signatures and the benefits that it brings. So let&amp;rsquo;s get started.
Agenda So here&amp;rsquo;s the agenda. We&amp;rsquo;re going to talk about, we&amp;rsquo;re going to review the signature algorithm that&amp;rsquo;s currently on Bitcoin. This is Elliptic Curve Digital Signature Algorithm or ECDSA. Then we&amp;rsquo;re going to go describe what Schnorr signatures are. And then we&amp;rsquo;re going to go over all of the key and signature aggregation stuff that you can do or some of the benefits that you get out of Schnorr.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Data Structures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/bitcoin-data-structures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/bitcoin-data-structures/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1170974373089632257
Introduction Alright guys. Come on in. There&amp;rsquo;s plenty of seats, guys. If you&amp;rsquo;re sitting out on the edge, be nice to the other folks and get in the middle. Sitting at the edge is kind of being a dick. You&amp;rsquo;re not letting anyone through. Come on guys, you don&amp;rsquo;t have USB-C yet? You all have powerbanks. Get with the times. Okay, we&amp;rsquo;re getting started.
I have 90 minutes to teach you the rest of my book.</description></item><item><title>Socialized Costs Of Hard Forks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/socialized-costs-of-hard-forks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/socialized-costs-of-hard-forks/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005518746260262912
KL: Can you hear me? Is it good? Okay. I hope you have practiced your French because.. no, the presentations are in English. Welcome and thank you very much for being here. This conference will very probably be the best we&amp;rsquo;ve had in the bitcoin sphere. The crowd is pretty crazy. I&amp;rsquo;ve had the ticket list and I can say the people in this room, not just the speakers, the attendees are all super amazing.</description></item><item><title>Fud Perceived Vs Real Bitcoin Risks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/fud-perceived-vs-real-bitcoin-risks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/fud-perceived-vs-real-bitcoin-risks/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137285873534492672
Eric Voskuil 3CD8 C07F 0B5C E14E
Jimmy FAA6 17E3 2679 E455
Rodolfo 1C9E 033C 6C65 8606
Introduction AW: Some topics might have more agreement between the three of you, and some maybe less. It&amp;rsquo;s up to you guys to say smart things.
JS: Can&amp;rsquo;t guarantee anything there.
FUD: bitcoin too volatile to be used as money AW: What about, bitcoin is too volatile to be used as money?
EV: It is used as money, so.</description></item><item><title>Neutrino</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/neutrino/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/neutrino/</guid><description>Neutrino bip158
&amp;hellip; 228C D70C FAA6 17E3 2679 E455
bip157 &amp;amp;&amp;amp; bip158
Introduction I want to start this talk with a question for the audience. How many of you have a mobile wallet on your phone right now? How many know the security model that the wallets are using? Okay, how many of you trust those security assumptions? Okay, less of you. I am going to talk about Neutrino. In order to talk about it, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about before Neutrino.</description></item></channel></rss>