<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mit Bitcoin Expo 2016 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/</link><description>Recent content in Mit Bitcoin Expo 2016 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cory Fields</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/cory-fields/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/cory-fields/</guid><description>MIT Bitcoin Expo 2016 transcript
last year- http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/ this year- http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/
Welcome everyone to MIT Bitcoin Expo 2016. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of Bitcoin by now, then I am not sure how you got here. My name is nchinda. I am the reigning Bitcoin club president. I am going to have some fun. The club is hijacking the #mit-dci IRC channel. You can twitter with #mitbitcoinexpo. There&amp;rsquo;s a link up on our website for livestreaming.</description></item><item><title>Fraud Proofs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/fraud-proofs-petertodd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/fraud-proofs-petertodd/</guid><description>In Bitcoin we have made this tradeoff where we don&amp;rsquo;t have everyone running full nodes. Not everyone is participating equally. If you have a full node, you have lots of gigs of hard drive space, but if you do that, you only get a few transactions per second. Modularizing validation an argument for this is how to improve on this situation.
What&amp;rsquo;s the problem we are trying to solve? This is a real screenshot from one of the Android wallets.</description></item><item><title>Improvements to Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/maaku-panel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/maaku-panel/</guid><description>This can be a broad range of topics for improvements. I am Mark Friedenbach, I have worked on Bitcoin protocol research, but I also do Core tech engineering at Blockstream. We also have Jonas, an independent Bitcoin Core developer. We also have Andrew Poelstra, who has been core to the crypto work which has been incoporated into Bitcoin, such as libsecp256k1 which we recently integrated in the 0.12 release. It speeds up Bitcoin validation by 7-8x.</description></item><item><title>Lessons For Bitcoin From 150 Years Of Decentralization</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/lessons-for-bitcoin-from-150-years-of-decentralization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/lessons-for-bitcoin-from-150-years-of-decentralization/</guid><description>Arvind Narayanan (twitter- random_walker) - Princeton University
Another 30 seconds. Take your seats. We have Arvind Narayanan. Some of the research from Princeton has rivaled the work of MIT. Professor Narayanan is going to teach us some lessons for Bitcoin.
Thank you. Can you hear me? I think you can. What I want to do today is to look at lessons from history for the future of Bitcoin, the next 10 years for Bitcoin, the next 30 years for Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Linq</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/linq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/linq/</guid><description>NASDAQ Linq
I have heard that Alex Zinder has a grasp of what makes NASDAQ Linq good and bad, and the advantages of a public versus permissioned blockchain. Alex is director of global software development at NASDAQ, but he is here to talk about Linq, which is a platform for managing securities. Alex?
This is possibly Adam Ludwin&amp;rsquo;s / chain.com&amp;rsquo;s doing?
We have been looking at this for a while at NASDAQ.</description></item><item><title>R3</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/r3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/r3/</guid><description>Distributed Ledger Group
R3
I work at R3. It manages the distributed ledger group, of 42 banks interested in using blockchain or distributed ledger tech. People wonder when I tell them that I work for a consortium that wants to use electronic ledgers. What does that have to do with capital markets?
Ledgers can track transactions. Typically in a capital market context, this responsibility falls to the backoffice. After a trade, you finalize it and actually transfer value.</description></item><item><title>Rootstock</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/rootstock/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/rootstock/</guid><description>Rootstock
Sergio is co-founder and chief scientist at RSK Labs. The whitepaper was pretty good. I am happy that he is here. Thank you. Just give me a minute.
Alicia Bendhan Lous Parker BitDevsNYC
Yes, I use powerpoint. Please don&amp;rsquo;t read my emails.
Thanks everyone for staying here and not going to the next room. Thanks for the organizers for inviting me. Today I am going to talk about Rootstock. It&amp;rsquo;s a codename for a smart contracting platform that we are developing for SKY labs, which is a company we founded in 2015.</description></item><item><title>Scaling Debate Is A Proxy Battle Over Centralization</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/scaling-debate-is-a-proxy-battle-over-centralization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/scaling-debate-is-a-proxy-battle-over-centralization/</guid><description>I really appreciated the fact that&amp;hellip;. I really appreciated Cory&amp;rsquo;s talk. I quoted someone in my talk. It was a fairly recent quote. His whole talk was speaking about governance. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of governing issues coming into Bitcoin. We like the solving the whole world with technical.
The word that I am fascinated with is the one highlighted here, the word &amp;ldquo;consensus&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m just going to reach out to you guys.</description></item><item><title>Siacoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/siacoin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/siacoin/</guid><description>Sia
I have been working on a decentralized cloud storage platform. Before I go into that, I wanted to mention that I have been working on Bitcoin since 2011. Since 2013 I have been in the wizards channel. In 2014 a friend and myself founded a company to build Siacoin. The team has grown to 3 people. Sia is the name of our decentralized storage protocol. We are trying to emulate Amazon S3.</description></item><item><title>What Internet governance can learn from Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/pindar-wong/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/pindar-wong/</guid><description>Pindar Wong
Forked to Death: What Internet governance can learn from Bitcoin
So, the last talk today is going to be from Pindar Wong. He&amp;rsquo;s been involved with Internet in Hong Kong. He also helped organize the Scaling Bitcoin workshops. It&amp;rsquo;s my pleasure to have him speaking today.
Okay. Thank you very much for staying until the bitter end. My topic today is forked to death, what Internet governance can learn from Bitcoin.</description></item></channel></rss>