<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ethereum on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/ethereum/</link><description>Recent content in ethereum on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/ethereum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Andrew Miller</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/andrew-miller/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/andrew-miller/</guid><description>Step by Step Towards Writing a Safe Contract: Insights from an Undergraduate Ethereum Lab
Andrew Miller Elaine Shi Next up I want to introduce Elaine Shi and Andrew Miller from University of Maryland. Andrew is also on the zerocash team.
Okay. I am an assistant professor at the University of Maryland. We all believe that cryptocurrency is the way of the future and smart contracts. So students in the future have to program smart contracts.</description></item><item><title>Cali 2016</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-developers-miners-meeting-2016/cali2016/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-developers-miners-meeting-2016/cali2016/</guid><description>California Gathering 2016
Transcription introduction Some Bitcoin developers and miners gathered together during the end of the July to socialize and become better acquainted with each other. The following discussions were live transcribed by an untrained volunteer with attribution removed as per Chatham House rules. In bitcoin, discussions can move very quickly, which can cause an increase in errors, including semantic errors, when typing in real time. This text was not produced from an audio recording.</description></item><item><title>Casper</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/casper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/casper/</guid><description>Casper the friendly ghost: A &amp;ldquo;correct-by-construction&amp;rdquo; blockchain consensus protocol
Vlad Zamfir (Ethereum Foundation)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1091460316288868352
I have one announcement to make before we start the session. If you feel like after all of these talks that the thing you really need is a drink, then there&amp;rsquo;s help. Chainlink is hosting the Stanford Blockchain Conference happy hour at The Patio which is the most famous bar in Palo Alto. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that much, but it&amp;rsquo;s good fun.</description></item><item><title>Dan Boneh</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-developers-miners-meeting-2016/dan-boneh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-developers-miners-meeting-2016/dan-boneh/</guid><description>A conversation with Dan Boneh
2016-08-01
Part of the challenge was that the Google Maps directions in the email were going down some roads that had construction&amp;hellip;. been here 10 minutes, and some arriving in another 10 minutes. They are building a new biology building. Large campus here. In whatever direction you walk, there are buildings and more buildings. In two years there will be a new biology building, and two years later there will be a new computer science building.</description></item><item><title>Ethcore</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/ethcore/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/ethcore/</guid><description>ethcore
At ethcore, we are building the infrastructure for the future of the decentralized web. Unless we get distracted by TheDAO and soft-forks and hard-forks. Maybe decentralization is not the most important thing. We want to build a p2p secure serverless web. Why is decentralization such an important notion? There&amp;rsquo;s no intrinsic value in being decentralized. There&amp;rsquo;s intrinsic value in being utilized and secure by people.
This is a bit of how we see the architecture.</description></item><item><title>Ethereum2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/ethereum2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/ethereum2/</guid><description>Ethereum 2.0 and beyond
Vitalik Buterin
Please welcome Vitalik who needs no introduction.
Introduction Okay. I have 20 minutes. I will get right to it. Vlad gave a presentation on some of his research into CBC Casper and how CBC Casper can be extended into sharding contexts. This presentation will be about taking some of the existing research into consensus algorithms and sharding and other things we have done in the last few years and see how they concretely translate into what is actually going to be deployed to Ethereum Foundation in the short to medium term future.</description></item><item><title>On The Security And Performance Of Proof Of Work Blockchains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/on-the-security-and-performance-of-proof-of-work-blockchains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/on-the-security-and-performance-of-proof-of-work-blockchains/</guid><description>On the security and performance of proof-of-work blockchains
Arthur Gervais
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785066988532068352
As most of you might know, in bitcoin and blockchains, the information is very important. Every node should receive the blocks in the network. Increase latency and risk network partition. If individual peers do not get the information, they could be victims of selfish mining and so on. Multiple blockchains has been proposed, multiple reparameterizations like litecoin, dogecoin, ethereum and others.</description></item><item><title>Optimistic Vm</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/optimistic-vm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/optimistic-vm/</guid><description>The optimistic VM
Karl Floersch
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230974707249233921
Introduction Okay, let&amp;rsquo;s get started our afternoon session. Our first talk I am very happy to introduce our speaker on optimistic virtual machines. Earlier in this conference we heard about optimistic roll-ups and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to this talk on optimistic virtual machines which is an up-and-coming approach on doing this.
Why hello everyone. I am building on ethereum and in particular we&amp;rsquo;re going to make Optimism: the attitude that will save the day.</description></item><item><title>Plasma Cash</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/plasma-cash/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/plasma-cash/</guid><description>Plasma Cash: Towards more efficient plasma constructions
Non-custodial sidechains for bitcoin utilizing plasma cash and covenants
Georgios Konstantopoulos
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1172108023705284609
paper: https://github.com/loomnetwork/plasma-paper/blob/master/plasma_cash.pdf
slides: https://gakonst.com/scalingbitcoin2019.pdf
Introduction We have known how to do these things for at least a year, but the question is how can we find the minimum changes that we can figure out to do in bitcoin if any on how to explore the layer 2 space in a better sense rather than just accepting that lightning network is the dominant solution?</description></item><item><title>Reaching Consensus Open Blockchains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coindesk-consensus-2016/reaching-consensus-open-blockchains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coindesk-consensus-2016/reaching-consensus-open-blockchains/</guid><description>Preliminary notes:
Contact me- https://twitter.com/kanzure
Reaching consensus on open blockchains
Moderator- Pindar Wong
Gavin Andresen, MIT Digital Currency Initiative
Vitalik Buterin, Ethereum Foundation
Eric Lombrozo, Ciphrex and Bitcoin Core
Neha Narula, MIT Media Lab Digital Currency Initiative
Please silence your cell phone during this session. Thank you. Please silence your cell phones during this session. Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, please take your seats. The session is about to begin.</description></item></channel></rss>