<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scriptless multisignatures on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/multisignature/</link><description>Recent content in Scriptless multisignatures on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/multisignature/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Instantiating (Scriptless) 2P-ECDSA: Fungible 2-of-2 MultiSigs for Today's Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/scriptless-ecdsa/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/scriptless-ecdsa/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048483254087573504
maybe https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/472.pdf and https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/lightning-dev/2018-April/001221.html
Introduction Alright. Thank you very much. Thank you Pedro, that was a great segue into what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about. He has been doing work on formalizing multi-hop locks. I want to also talk about what changes might be necessary to deploy this on the lightning network.
History For what it&amp;rsquo;s worth, these dates are rough. Andrew Poelstra started working on this and released something in 2016 for a Schnorr-based scriptless script model.</description></item><item><title>Multi-Hop Locks for Secure, Privacy-Preserving and Interoperable Payment-Channel Networks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-hop-locks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-hop-locks/</guid><description>Giulio Malavolta (Friedrich-Alexander-University Erlangen-Nuernberg), Pedro Moreno-Sanchez (Purdue University), Clara Schneidewind (Vienna University of Technology), Aniket Kate (Purdue University) and Matteo Maffei (Vienna University of Technology)
https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/472.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048476273259900928
This is joint work with my colleagues. I promise I will talk slower than the last talk. In a multi-hop network, the security tool is a hash-time lock contract (HTLC) where the payment is conditioned on revealing the pre-image of a hash function. This is pretty much the main setup for the lightning network today.</description></item></channel></rss>