<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hard fork on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/hard-fork/</link><description>Recent content in hard fork on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/hard-fork/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Checkmultisig Bug</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2020-08-27-greg-maxwell-checkmultisig-bug/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2020-08-27-greg-maxwell-checkmultisig-bug/</guid><description>What is stopping the OP_CHECKMULTISIG extra pop bug from being fixed?
Location: Bitcointalk
https://bitcointalk.org/index.php?topic=5271566.msg55079521#msg55079521
What is stopping the OP_CHECKMULTISIG extra pop bug from being fixed? I think it is probably wrong to describe it as a bug. I think it was intended to indicate which signatures were present to fix the otherwise terrible performance of CHECKMULTISIG.
Regardless, there is no real point to fixing it: Any &amp;lsquo;fix&amp;rsquo; would require that all software using CHECKMULTISIG get an incompatible change (as part of a highly disruptive hard fork).</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Full Nodes</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2018-07-23-john-light-bitcoin-full-nodes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2018-07-23-john-light-bitcoin-full-nodes/</guid><description>Location: London Bitcoin Devs
John Light blog post on soft forks and hard forks: https://medium.com/@lightcoin/the-differences-between-a-hard-fork-a-soft-fork-and-a-chain-split-and-what-they-mean-for-the-769273f358c9
Intro My presentation today is going to be about Bitcoin full nodes. Everything you wanted to know and more. There should perhaps be an asterisk because I’m not going to say literally everything but if anyone in the audience has any questions that want to go really deep down the rabbit hole then we’ll see just how far down we can go.</description></item><item><title>Consensus Uasf And Forks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lets-talk-bitcoin-podcast/2017-06-04-consensus-uasf-and-forks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lets-talk-bitcoin-podcast/2017-06-04-consensus-uasf-and-forks/</guid><description>On Consensus and All Kinds of Forks
Location: Let’s Talk Bitcoin podcast (Episode 333)
User activated soft forks vs hard forks Adam Levine (AL): I’m trying to look at the user activated soft fork thing and not see hypocrisy just steaming out of its ears. I’m really in need of you to help me understand why this is not the case Andreas. The argument to this point about scaling, one of the arguments, one of the larger arguments, has been that hard forks are the worst thing that can happen.</description></item></channel></rss>