<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Consensus cleanup soft fork on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/consensus-cleanup/</link><description>Recent content in Consensus cleanup soft fork on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/consensus-cleanup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Great Consensus Cleanup Revival (And an Update on the Tornado Cash and Samourai Wallet Arrests)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/the-great-consensus-cleanup-revival/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/the-great-consensus-cleanup-revival/</guid><description>In this episode of Bitcoin, Explained, Aaron and Sjors discuss the Great Consensus Cleanup Revival soft fork(s). This proposal would fix some known bugs in the Bitcoin protocol, specifically the timewarp vulnerability, large block validation times, 64 byte transactions and BIP 30 verification.</description></item><item><title>Great Consensus Cleanup</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2024-04/great-consensus-cleanup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2024-04/great-consensus-cleanup/</guid><description>How bad are the bugs?
How good are the mitigations?
Improvements to mitigations in the last 5 years?
Anything else to fix?
The talk is a summary of https://delvingbitcoin.org/t/great-consensus-cleanup-revival/710 .
Time warp What is it? Off by one in the retargeting period 2015 blocks instead of 2016 Impact Spam (since difficulty is 1 and block times are what restricts tx) UXTO set growth for the same reason 40 days to kill the chain Empowers 51% attacker Political games (users individually incentivized short-term to benefit from more block space, miners individually incentivized short-term to benefit of more subsidy) Minority miners not incentivized to try but it doesn’t cost anything Original mitigation is good Mandating new restrictions on the timestamp of the first block of a retarget period in relation to last blocks timestamp Merkle tree attacks w/64 byte txs Fake SPV inclusion &amp;lt;visual merkle tree diagram illustrating issue&amp;gt; Years ago the attack required more work than proof of work, so was less of a concern, not so now Arbitrary confs, less work Simple mitigation Require the coinbase transaction too, as all transactions on the same level of the merkle tree Block malleability Separate but similar attack Fork nodes Simple mitigation Dont cache context-less checks BIP’s original Mitigation Forbid &amp;lt;=64 byte transactions No need to disable &amp;lt;64 bytes transactions, since 64 is the issue Concern about existing, unbroadcasted 64 byte transaction?</description></item><item><title>Great Consensus Cleanup</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06/2019-06-06-great-consensus-cleanup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06/2019-06-06-great-consensus-cleanup/</guid><description>https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2019-March/016714.html
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1136591286012698626
Introduction There&amp;rsquo;s not much new to talk about. Unclear about CODESEPARATOR. You want to make it a consensus rule that transactions can&amp;rsquo;t be larger than 100 kb. No reactions to that? Alright. Fine, we&amp;rsquo;re doing it. Let&amp;rsquo;s do it. Does everyone know what this proposal is?
Validation time for any block&amp;ndash; we were lazy about fixing this. Segwit was a first step to fixing this, by giving people a way to do this in a more efficient way.</description></item></channel></rss>