<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>regulation on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/regulation/</link><description>Recent content in regulation on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/regulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bitcoin Custody</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/bitcoin-custody/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/bitcoin-custody/</guid><description>Bryan Bishop
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048014038179823617
Bitcoin Custody
Baltic Honey Badger 2018 Bitcoin conference, Riga, Latvia, Day 2
Schedule: https://bh2018.hodlhodl.com/
Transcript
Start time: 6:09:50
Youtube: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D2WXxgZ8h-0&amp;amp;t=22160s
My name is Bryan Bishop, I’m going to be talking about bitcoin custody. Here is my PGP fingerprint, we should be doing that. So who am I, I have a software development background, I don’t just type transcripts. I’m actually no longer at LedgerX as of Friday (Sept 21 2018) when I came here.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Regulation Landscape</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/bitcoin-regulation-landscape/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/bitcoin-regulation-landscape/</guid><description>Elizabeth Stark Jerry Brito Constance Choi Christian Catalini (moderator) MIT Compton Labs - Building 26, room 100
http://mitbitcoinexpo.org/
Okay guys, we are getting close to the time for the next panel. Head back to your seats. You may bring food in with you. We also started 15 minutes late. People have 15 minutes .. we ended lunch on time. One of our speakers literally only came for 30 minutes today, 2 to 230.</description></item><item><title>Compliance And Confidentiality</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/compliance-and-confidentiality/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/compliance-and-confidentiality/</guid><description>Compliance and confidentiality: can they co-exist?
Alexander Zaidelson, Beam
Introduction Hi everyone. It&amp;rsquo;s a great pleasure to be here. I&amp;rsquo;m Alexander Zaidelson, CEO of Beam. I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting our view on the regulation and how we live with it as a project. I&amp;rsquo;m not an expert in regulation. Whatever I&amp;rsquo;m showing here is how we see the landscape from what we understand.
Beam is a confidential transaction. The question is, how can confidential cryptocurrency co-exist with regulation?</description></item><item><title>Future Of Regulation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coindesk-consensus-2016/future-of-regulation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coindesk-consensus-2016/future-of-regulation/</guid><description>Preliminary notes:
Contact me- https://twitter.com/kanzure
The future of regulation
Jerry Brito, Coin Center
J. Christopher Giancarlo, CFTC
Benjamin Lawsky, Lawsky Group
Mark Wetjen, DTCC
JB: I want to start with Giancarlo. Your approach has been &amp;ldquo;first do no harm&amp;rdquo;. What opportunity is this?
Giancarlo: There are a number of elements to my interest. I want to go back to a moment of time where it became clear tome that something like this, although I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it would be this, was tremendously necessary.</description></item><item><title>G20 Discussion</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/g20-discussion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/g20-discussion/</guid><description>Why do we need a multi-stakeholder discussion in a blockchain world? A report from G20 discussions.
Shinichiro Matsuo
https://bsafe.network
Introduction I am the cofounder of the bsafe.network which focuses on blockchain research. I was a program co-chair for Scaling Bitcoin at Keio University last year. I also work with IEEE, ACM conferences, Ledger Journal, and more. My background is engagement with Bank of Japan NTT internet cash in 1998-2000.
Several huge incidents From a regulatory point of view, there are many big events that have occurred: MtGox, the DAO attack, coincheck, monacoin, and Zaif.</description></item><item><title>Implications</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/implications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/implications/</guid><description>Implications on regulation and governance of blockchain-based finance
Yuta Takanashi (Financial Services Agency, Japan)
Disclaimer First, please note that the opinions presented here belong to myself and don&amp;rsquo;t represent the organizations to which I belong.
Major goals for financial regulators The primary goals of financial regulators are to maintain financial stability, protect investors and consumers, and prevent financial crimes. These goals are public interests and are needed to be achieved regardless of the technology used in the financial systems.</description></item><item><title>NY DFS Bitlicense Lawsky Update (2014-12-18)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/nydfs-bitlicense-lawsky-update/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/nydfs-bitlicense-lawsky-update/</guid><description>NY DFS BitLicense update 2014-12-18
http://bipartisanpolicy.org/events/payment-policy-in-the-21st-century-the-promise-of-innovation-and-the-challenge-of-regulation/
And that&amp;rsquo;s a serious problem that we all need to address with a hightened sense of urgency and focus. Let me start with the BitLicense and virtual currencies. These came on our radar screen last year at DFS because like all of the other states we regulate money transmitters like Moneygram and Western Union. We were worried that virtual currency firms were transmitting currency. Our regulatory rules were written before the internet and before virtual currencies.</description></item><item><title>Regulatory Pain Points</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/regulatory-pain-points/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/regulatory-pain-points/</guid><description>Regulatory pain points
Ryosuke Ushida
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229838162827993088
Introduction Hi, good morning everyone. I am a Japanese financial regulator at JFSA. My goal is to promote financial innovations and still ensure the financial stability and various regulatory goals. I have nearly 10 years experience as a regulator. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a strong background in technology, so I hope I can rely on the other stakeholders on this. I am now in Washington DC doing research on blockchain and governance policy.</description></item><item><title>Security And Usability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/security-and-usability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/security-and-usability/</guid><description>Melanie Shapiro Alan Reiner Kristov Atlas Elizabeth Stark (moderator) and maybe Melanie Shapiro? malani? Security and usability.
Elizabeth: I think this is a highly relevant discussion. I talked a bit about regulation. Regulation might be the number threat, but security might be the number two threat. I am excited to have a panel of leaders in this space who are actively building in this ecosystem. I am going to ask each to do a quick intro.</description></item></channel></rss>