<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>incentives on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/incentives/</link><description>Recent content in incentives on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/incentives/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>In Adversarial Environments Blockchains Dont Scale</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/in-adversarial-environments-blockchains-dont-scale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/in-adversarial-environments-blockchains-dont-scale/</guid><description>petertodd
slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY1/2_security_and_incentives_2_todd.pdf
video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ivgxcEOyWNs&amp;amp;t=30m35s
That was a very useful talk (on security assumptions), thank you Andrew.
I am going to start by talking about nitty-gritty applications where adversarial thinking is useful for incentives for decentralization. In an environment where everyone has the data, we are kind of limited as to what we can do. When we talk about scale, I am talking about 5 or 10 orders of magnitude. Do we have a system that has fundamentally different scaling characteristics?</description></item><item><title>Mechanism Design</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/mechanism-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/mechanism-design/</guid><description>&amp;ndash; Disclaimer &amp;ndash;
These are unpaid transcriptions, performed in real-time and in-person during the actual source presentation. Due to personal time constraints they are usually not reviewed against the source material once published. Errors are possible. If the original author/speaker or anyone else finds errors of substance, please email me at kanzure@gmail.com for corrections.
I sometimes add annotations to the transcription text. These will always be denoted by a standard editor&amp;rsquo;s note in parenthesis brackets ((like this)), or in a numbered footnote.</description></item><item><title>No Incentive</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/no-incentive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/no-incentive/</guid><description>The best incentive is no incentive
David Schwartz
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230997662339436544
Introduction This is the last session of the conference. Time flies when you&amp;rsquo;re having fun. We&amp;rsquo;re going to be starting with David Schwartz who is one of the co-creators of Ripple and he is going to be talking about a controversial topic that &amp;ldquo;the best incentive is no incentive&amp;rdquo;.
I am David Schwartz as you just heard I am one of the co-creators of Ripple.</description></item><item><title>Validation Costs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/validation-costs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/validation-costs/</guid><description>Validation costs and incentives
Eric Lombrozo (CodeShark)
How many of you have read the Satoshi whitepaper? It&amp;rsquo;s a good paper. As we have discovered, it has some serious limitations that we think can be fixed but they are serious challenges for scaling. Amongst these are, it was really built as a single code base which was meant to be run in its entirety. All machines were going to participate equally in this p2p network.</description></item><item><title>Why Miners Will Not Voluntarily Individually Produce Smaller Blocks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/why-miners-will-not-voluntarily-individually-produce-smaller-blocks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/why-miners-will-not-voluntarily-individually-produce-smaller-blocks/</guid><description>Jonathan Bier
slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY1/2_security_and_incentives_3_bier.pdf
video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ivgxcEOyWNs&amp;amp;t=1h30s
Marginal cost is very low.
In about 2011, people started discussing the idea of needing an artificial cap for a block size limit to kind of kick up the transaction fees. The orphan risk is a marginal cost the larger the block, the higher the chance of an orphan.
Now I&amp;rsquo;ve got some issues why orphan risk may not be so great. As technology improves, over time the technology cost of orphaning gets lower and lower, so you are relying on driving miner revenue or fees, would become less relevant.</description></item></channel></rss>