<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Chaincode Podcast on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/</link><description>Recent content in Chaincode Podcast on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Privacy and robustness in Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/privacy-and-robustness-in-lightning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/privacy-and-robustness-in-lightning/</guid><description>Speaker 0: 00:00:00
Simplicity is a virtue in itself, right? So you can try to increase fairness. If you reduce simplicity, you end up actually often stepping backwards. So I really, the thing that really appeals about element symmetry is it&amp;rsquo;s simple. And every scheme to fix things by introducing more fairness and try to reintroduce penalties and everything else ends up destroying the simplicity.
Speaker 1: 00:00:27
So soon again.</description></item><item><title>Simple Taproot Channels</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/simple-taproot-channels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/simple-taproot-channels/</guid><description>Elle Mouton and Oliver Gugger join us to talk with us about the Simple Taproot Channel proposal.</description></item><item><title>The Bitcoin Development Kit (BDK)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/the-bitcoin-development-kit-bdk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/the-bitcoin-development-kit-bdk/</guid><description>The podcast covers the evolution of the Bitcoin Development Kit (BDK), originally known as the Magical Bitcoin Library, from its inception at Blockstream to its current status as a fully-fledged open-source project. Key topics include the renaming of BDK, its foundational use of Rust and descriptors for wallet architecture, and the broad applicability for both individual and enterprise users. Early adopters and contributors to BDK&amp;rsquo;s development are highlighted, alongside discussions on the challenges and technical hurdles such as asynchronous operations and wallet management across multiple descriptors. The conversation also touches on the motivations behind developers preferring to build wallets from scratch and the potential advantages of adopting BDK for future-proofing wallet applications. Upcoming features in BDK 1.0 promise further enhancements, particularly in syncing mechanisms and transaction planning.</description></item><item><title>Lightning History and everything else</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/lightning-history-and-everything-else/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/lightning-history-and-everything-else/</guid><description>Tadge Dryja chats with us about writing the Lightning Network paper and working in the Bitcoin space.</description></item><item><title>The Bitcoin Core Wallet</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/the-bitcoin-core-wallet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/the-bitcoin-core-wallet/</guid><description>The discussion with Andrew Chow explores the evolution of the Bitcoin Core wallet, emphasizing significant developments like descriptor wallets and PSBT for enhancing functionality and interoperability. The conversation highlights the continuous efforts to refactor and improve the wallet&amp;rsquo;s codebase, addressing challenges and introducing innovations in coin selection and transaction management. The importance of maintaining high security and review standards is underscored, reflecting the wallet&amp;rsquo;s role in supporting Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s core principles. Future directions include improving the wallet&amp;rsquo;s performance, user experience, and GUI.</description></item><item><title>SIGHASH_ANYPREVOUT, ephemeral anchors and LN symmetry (ELTOO)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/sighash-anyprevout-ephemeral-anchors-and-ln-symmetry-eltoo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/sighash-anyprevout-ephemeral-anchors-and-ln-symmetry-eltoo/</guid><description>Greg Sanders joins us to discuss ANYPREVOUT, ephemeral anchors and LN symmetry (a.k.a. ELTOO).</description></item><item><title>Watchtowers, Lightning Privacy</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/watchtowers-lightning-privacy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/watchtowers-lightning-privacy/</guid><description>Speaker 0: 00:00:00
I came into Bitcoin because I like peer-to-peer. I discover more things that I love by doing so. And again, these are not feelings, but they are feelings related to research. Sorry, failing time.
Speaker 1: 00:00:12
We&amp;rsquo;re going to make sure our editor takes out The love word. We are back in the studio. We are.
Speaker 2: 00:00:24
And today we&amp;rsquo;re going to be joined by Sergi Delgado.</description></item><item><title>Nesting, ROAST, Half-Aggregation, Adaptor Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/nesting-roast-half-aggregation-adaptor-signatures/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/nesting-roast-half-aggregation-adaptor-signatures/</guid><description>Speaker 1: 00:00:00
Just as a warning, so don&amp;rsquo;t do this at home.
Speaker 0: 00:00:01
Yes, of course. Still have your friendly neighborhood cryptographer have a look at it.
Speaker 2: 00:00:16
This is the second half of the conversation with Tim and Peter. If you have not listened to the first half, I&amp;rsquo;d suggest going back and listening to that episode. We cover all sorts of fun things, including when to roll your own cryptography, why we prefer Schnorr signatures over ECDSA, Schnorr efficiency improvements, multi-sig, mu-sig, interactive versus non-interactive signing, Frost, and more.</description></item><item><title>Schnorr, MuSig, FROST and more</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/schnorr-musig-frost-and-more/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/schnorr-musig-frost-and-more/</guid><description>Pieter Wuille and Tim Ruffing treat us to a conversation about Schnorr, multi-signatures, MuSig, and more. We covered a lot so this is part one of a two part conversation.</description></item><item><title>Channel Jamming on the Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/channel-jamming-on-the-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/channel-jamming-on-the-lightning-network/</guid><description>Clara and Sergei stop by to chat about their recent proposal on mitigating jamming attacks in the Lightning Network. We talk unconditional fees, local reputation, the impact on decentralization and UX, and the state of Lightning in general.</description></item><item><title>The Bitcoin Core wallet and wrangling bitcoin data</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/the-bitcoin-core-wallet-and-wrangling-bitcoin-data/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/the-bitcoin-core-wallet-and-wrangling-bitcoin-data/</guid><description>In this conversation, Adam Jonas and Mark Erhardt discuss their work with Josie Baker on Bitcoin data analysis, focusing on mempool data collection and Bitcoin Core wallet improvements. Josie explains his work in standardizing and cleaning mempool data to create a comprehensive, open-source dataset. This dataset will facilitate research and development in areas such as fee estimation and transaction propagation. They also delve into Bitcoin Core wallet enhancements, including privacy improvements and efficient coin selection methods. The conversation highlights the importance of reproducibility, empirical analysis, and open-source collaboration in advancing Bitcoin technology. Josie’s efforts emphasize the value of making Bitcoin data accessible and fostering a community of contributors in the Bitcoin development ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Lightning updates / Stratum V2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/lightning-updates-stratum-v2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/lightning-updates-stratum-v2/</guid><description>Speaker 0: 00:00:00
Hey Jonas.
Speaker 1: 00:00:00
Hey Merch. What are we up to? We are back.
Speaker 0: 00:00:03
Who are we recording today? We have Steve Lee in the office this week. He is the head at Spiral. Yeah. He&amp;rsquo;s done a lot of open source development. He talks to a bunch of people. He&amp;rsquo;s also the PM for the LDK team. So we&amp;rsquo;re going to talk Lightning, the challenges that are open with Lightning, and maybe a little bit about other projects in the space.</description></item><item><title>Tracepoints and monitoring the Bitcoin network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/tracepoints-and-monitoring-the-bitcoin-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/tracepoints-and-monitoring-the-bitcoin-network/</guid><description>Speaker 0: 00:00:00
Hey, Merch. What up? We are back in the studio.
Speaker 1: 00:00:02
Who are we talking to today? We&amp;rsquo;re talking to OXB10C.
Speaker 0: 00:00:06
I know him as Timo. So we&amp;rsquo;re going to call him Timo.
Speaker 1: 00:00:09
OK, fine.
Speaker 0: 00:00:12
It doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite roll off the tongue. Is there anything in particular that you&amp;rsquo;re interested in learning from Timo today?
Speaker 1: 00:00:17</description></item><item><title>Package Relay</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/package-relay/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/package-relay/</guid><description>Gloria Zhao sits down with us to discuss her package relay proposal and what it is like as a relative newcomer to propose a big change.</description></item><item><title>Address Relay</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/address-relay/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/address-relay/</guid><description>Martin Zumsande joins us to tell us about the address spam in the summer of 2021 and his interests in AddrRelay and Bitcoin Core development.</description></item><item><title>Lightning privacy</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/lightning-privacy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/lightning-privacy/</guid><description>Postdoc Researcher Sergei joins Murch and Jonas to talk about channel balance probing in Lightning, privacy concerns in general, and the importance of researcher-developer collaboration.</description></item><item><title>Block Building</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/block-building/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/block-building/</guid><description>Postdoc Researcher Clara joins Murch to discuss their block building research. They cover their proposal, which outlines suggested improvements to the current Bitcoin Core block building algorithm using candidate sets</description></item><item><title>Miniscript</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/miniscript/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/miniscript/</guid><description>Sanket describes to Murch his work on Miniscript. We explore uses for Miniscript, learn about intersections with PSBTs, Output Descriptors, and Taproot, and suss out the difference between Miniscript and Miniscript Policy.</description></item><item><title>The P2P network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/the-p2p-network-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/the-p2p-network-2/</guid><description>P2P experts Pieter and Amiti chat about the P2P network.</description></item><item><title>The P2P network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/the-p2p-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/the-p2p-network/</guid><description>In this episode of the Chaincode Podcast, Amiti Uttarwar discusses the intricacies of peer-to-peer (P2P) networks in Bitcoin with hosts Adam Jonas and Mark Erhardt. Amiti explains her fascination with P2P due to its logical yet complex interactions across the global network of nodes. She outlines five key principles for designing effective P2P networks: reliability, timeliness, accessibility, privacy, and upgradeability. The conversation delves into specific challenges, such as Eclipse attacks, address relay, and the role of the address manager (AddrMan) in maintaining network integrity. Amiti also highlights the delicate balance between ensuring privacy and achieving network reliability. Overall, the discussion emphasizes the importance of continuous collaboration and innovation in Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s P2P network development.</description></item><item><title>Chaincode Decoded: Blockchain</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/chaincode-decoded-blockchain/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/chaincode-decoded-blockchain/</guid><description>In this Chaincode Decoded segment we talk about the fundamental role of Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s blockchain and some of its peculiarities.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Development Kit</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2021-05-12-matt-corallo-ldk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2021-05-12-matt-corallo-ldk/</guid><description>Matt Corallo presentation at Advancing Bitcoin 2019: https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2019/2019-02-07-matt-corallo-rust-lightning/
rust-lightning repo: https://github.com/rust-bitcoin/rust-lightning
Intro Adam Jonas (AJ): Welcome back to the office Matt, glad to have you back on the podcast.
Matt Corallo (MC): Thank you.
Update on LDK AJ: We are going to start with LDK. Where are we at? What is going on?
MC: If listeners are aware LDK kind of grew out of a project that I started a few years ago when I was working at Chaincode called rust-lightning.</description></item><item><title>Chaincode Decoded: Mempool</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/chaincode-decoded-mempool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/chaincode-decoded-mempool/</guid><description>The Chaincode Decoded segment returns and we jump into the deep end of the mempool.</description></item><item><title>Chaincode Decoded: Bech32m</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/chaincode-decoded-bech32m/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/chaincode-decoded-bech32m/</guid><description>This revisits a segment we call Chaincode Decoded. In this episode, we&amp;rsquo;ll learn how to say Bech32 and also what it and Bech32m are.</description></item><item><title>Modularizing the Bitcoin Consensus Engine</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/modularizing-the-bitcoin-consensus-engine/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/modularizing-the-bitcoin-consensus-engine/</guid><description>AJ: Do you want to talk about isolating the consensus engine?
CD: Sure. More recently I have dove into the codebase a little bit more. That started with looking at Matt’s async ProcessNewBlock work and playing around with that. Learning from that how do you make a change to the core engine of Bitcoin Core.
Matt Corallo’s PR on async ProcessNewBlock https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/16175
AJ: Can you talk about that PR a little bit and what it would do?</description></item><item><title>Reproducible Builds</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2020-11-30-carl-dong-reproducible-builds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2020-11-30-carl-dong-reproducible-builds/</guid><description>Carl Dong’s presentation at Breaking Bitcoin 2019 on “Bitcoin Build System Security”: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/breaking-bitcoin/2019/bitcoin-build-system/
Intro Adam Jonas (AJ): Welcome to the Chaincode podcast Carl.
Carl Dong (CD): Hello.
AJ: You know we’ve been doing this podcast for a while now. How come you haven’t been on the show yet?
CD: We’ve been at home.
AJ: We did a few episodes before that though.
Murch (M): It is fine. We’ve got you now.</description></item><item><title>Enterprise Wallets/UTXO Management</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2020-11-09-enterprise-walletsutxo-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2020-11-09-enterprise-walletsutxo-management/</guid><description>Mark Erhardt: 00:00:00
Just to throw out a few numbers there, non-SegWit inputs cost almost 300 bytes, and native SegWit inputs cost slightly more than 100 bytes. There&amp;rsquo;s almost a reduction by two-thirds in fees if you switch from non-SegWit to native SegWit.
Introduction Caralie Chrisco: 00:00:29
Hi, everyone, welcome to the Chaincode podcast. My name is Caralie.
Adam Jonas: 00:00:32
And it&amp;rsquo;s Jonas.
Caralie Chrisco: 00:00:33
And we&amp;rsquo;re back!</description></item><item><title>Payment Points</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/payment-points/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/payment-points/</guid><description>Nadav Kohen: 00:00:00
Right now in the Lightning Network, if I were to make a payment every single hop along that route, they would know that they&amp;rsquo;re on the same route, because every single HTLC uses the same hash. It&amp;rsquo;s a bad privacy leak. It&amp;rsquo;s actually a much worse privacy leak now that we have multi-path payments, because every single path along your multi-path payment uses the same hash as well.</description></item><item><title>Compact Blocks and Fibre</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2020-03-12-matt-corallo-compact-blocks-fibre/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2020-03-12-matt-corallo-compact-blocks-fibre/</guid><description>Intro Adam Jonas (AJ): Welcome Matt
Matt Corallo (MC): Hi
John Newbery (JN): Hi Matt
AJ: Today we are going to do a little bit of a “This is your life Bitcoin”.
MC: I am not dead yet.
AJ: You have a lot of contributions over the years so there is lots to talk about but we’ll start with three. Let’s start with compact blocks. Tell us a little bit about what compact blocks are and then we can dive a little bit deeper.</description></item><item><title>Chaincode Decoded: UTXOs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/utxos-chaincode-decoded/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/utxos-chaincode-decoded/</guid><description>Introduction John Newbery: 00:00:00
If we go back in time to version 0.1, all that was stored was the blockchain and I think a marker saying whether that coin was spent or not. I mean that&amp;rsquo;s okay for your first version but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really scale and it&amp;rsquo;s bad performance because every time you want to access a coin you need to read it from disk.
Adam Jonas: 00:00:28
Welcome back to the Chaincode Podcast.</description></item><item><title>AssumeUTXO</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/assumeutxo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/assumeutxo/</guid><description>Next in the studio, we caught James O&amp;rsquo;Beirne, who until recently was a co-worker of ours at Chaincode. We talked to James about his experience at the Chaincode residency, his most recent project AssumeUTXO and how he champions and effects change in Bitcoin Core.</description></item><item><title>CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY (CTV)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2020-02-11-jeremy-rubin-ctv/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2020-02-11-jeremy-rubin-ctv/</guid><description>CTV BIP review workshop transcript: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/ctv-bip-review-workshop/
Intro Jonas: Welcome to the podcast Jeremy.
Jeremy: Thanks for having me on.
Jonas: I think to start us off tell us a bit about your background, how you got into Bitcoin and we&amp;rsquo;ll take it from there.
Jeremy: I first heard about Bitcoin in 2011. I was interning at MIT during high school and I was doing what interns do which is read Hacker News.</description></item><item><title>Pieter Wuille (part 1 of 2)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2020-01-28-pieter-wuille-part1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2020-01-28-pieter-wuille-part1/</guid><description>Part 2: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q2lXSRcacAo
Jonas: Welcome to the podcast
John: Hi Pieter
Pieter: Hello John and Jonas
John: Thank you for being the first guest on our podcast.
Jonas: So far the most important guest we’ve had.
Pieter: That’s an amazing honor. Thank you so much for having me.
John: We’re here to talk about Bitcoin and Bitcoin Core development. We have Pieter Wuille as our guest who is a Bitcoin Core contributor of many years standing.</description></item><item><title>Pieter Wuille (part 2 of 2)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2020-01-28-pieter-wuille-part2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2020-01-28-pieter-wuille-part2/</guid><description>Jonas: We are gonna pick up where we left off in episode 1 with a discussion of lessons learned from the 0.8 consensus failure. We then go on to cover libsecp and Pieter&amp;rsquo;s thoughts about Bitcoin in 2020. We hope you enjoy this as much as we did.
John: Ok I have a bunch of questions from that. One is what are the lessons from that?
Pieter: One of the things I think learned from that is specifying what your consensus rules is really hard.</description></item></channel></rss>