<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SF Bitcoin Meetup on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/</link><description>Recent content in SF Bitcoin Meetup on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Socratic Seminar 20</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2020-11-30-socratic-seminar-20/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2020-11-30-socratic-seminar-20/</guid><description>SF Bitcoin Devs socratic seminar #20
((Names anonymized.))
XX01: For everyone new who has joined- this is an experiment for us. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how this first online event goes. So far no major issues. Nice background, Uyluvolokutat. Should we let Harkenpost in?
XX06: People around America are showing up since they don&amp;rsquo;t have to show up in person.
XX01: How do we block NY IPs?
XX06: We already have people from Western Africa joining.</description></item><item><title>BIP Taproot and BIP Tapscript</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2019-12-16-bip-taproot-bip-tapscript/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2019-12-16-bip-taproot-bip-tapscript/</guid><description>slides: https://prezi.com/view/AlXd19INd3isgt3SvW8g/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1208438837845929987
https://twitter.com/SFBitcoinDevs/status/1206678306721894400
bip-taproot: https://github.com/sipa/bips/blob/bip-schnorr/bip-taproot.mediawiki
bip-tapscript: https://github.com/sipa/bips/blob/bip-schnorr/bip-tapscript.mediawiki
bip-schnorr: https://github.com/sipa/bips/blob/bip-schnorr/bip-schnorr.mediawiki
Please try to find seats. Today we have a special treat. We have Pieter here, who is well known as a contributor to Bitcoin Core, stackexchange, the mailing list, and he has been around forever. He&amp;rsquo;s the author of multiple BIPs. Today he is going to talk about taproot and tapscript which is basically what the whole Schnorr movement thing became.</description></item><item><title>Lnd 0.6 Beta</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2019-05-02-conner-fromknecht-lnd-0.6-beta/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2019-05-02-conner-fromknecht-lnd-0.6-beta/</guid><description>Conner Fromknecht
SF Lightning Devs
LND 0.6 Beta Deep Dive
Intro lnd 0.6 was about seven months in the making. There’s more things that we could fit into this talk alone but I cherrypicked some of the highlights and things that will have some real world impact on users of the network or people who are using the API or just generally users of lnd. The high level impact on the network going forward and how we plan to scale up for the next 100K channels that come onto the network.</description></item><item><title>Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2019-03-15-partially-signed-bitcoin-transactions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2019-03-15-partially-signed-bitcoin-transactions/</guid><description>Topic: PSBT
Location: SF Bitcoin Devs
Introduction Andrew: So as Mark said I&amp;rsquo;m Andrew Chow and today I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking about BIP 174, partially signed Bitcoin transactions, also known as PSBT. Today I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking a bit about why we need PSBTs, or Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions, what they are, and the actual format of the transaction itself and how to use a PSBT and the workflows around that.</description></item><item><title>Threshold Signatures And Accountability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2019-02-04-threshold-signatures-and-accountability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2019-02-04-threshold-signatures-and-accountability/</guid><description>Topic: Threshold Signatures and Accountability
Location: SF Bitcoin Devs
Slides: https://download.wpsoftware.net/bitcoin/wizardry/2019-02-sfdevs-threshold/slides.pdf
Transcript completed by: Bryan Bishop Edited by: Michael Folkson
Twitter announcement: https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1092665108960968704
Introduction (Mark Erhardt) Sorry for the delays. We&amp;rsquo;re finally ready to talk. Welcome to our talk. We&amp;rsquo;d like to thank our sponsors including Blockstream and Digital Garage. Today we have Andrew Poelstra to talk about threshold signatures and accountability. He is known for working on Mimblewimble, Bitcoin Core, libsecp256k1, and at Blockstream.</description></item><item><title>Taproot, Schnorr signatures, and SIGHASH_NOINPUT</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2018-07-09-taproot-schnorr-signatures-and-sighash-noinput-oh-my/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2018-07-09-taproot-schnorr-signatures-and-sighash-noinput-oh-my/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1021880538020368385
slides: https://prezi.com/view/YkJwE7LYJzAzJw9g1bWV/
Introduction I am Pieter Wuille. I will just dive in. Today I want to talk about improvements to the bitcoin scripting language. There is feedback in the microphone. Okay.
I will mostly be talking about improvements to the bitcoin scripting language. This is by no means an exhaustive list of all the things that are going on. It&amp;rsquo;s more my personal focus in the things that I am interested in and excited about seeing happen.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Core</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2018-04-23-jeremy-rubin-bitcoin-core/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2018-04-23-jeremy-rubin-bitcoin-core/</guid><description>A hardCORE workout
Slides: https://drive.google.com/file/d/149Ta1WRXL5WEvnBdlL-HxmsFDXUbvFDy/view
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1152926849879760896
Intro Thank you very much for the warm welcome. So welcome to the hard core workout. It is not going to be that difficult but you can stretch if you need to. It is going to be a lot of material so I’m going to go a little bit fast. If you have any questions feel free to stop me in the middle. There’s a lot of material to get through so I might say “Hold it” or “Find me after” but if there is anything that would help your understanding fee free to classroom style raise your hand and I’ll try to answer it.</description></item><item><title>Exploring Lnd0.4</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2018-04-20-laolu-osuntokun-exploring-lnd0.4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2018-04-20-laolu-osuntokun-exploring-lnd0.4/</guid><description>Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1pyQgGDUcB29r8DnTaS0GQS6usjw4CpgciQx_-XBVOwU/
The Genesis of lnd First, the genesis of lnd. Here is the first commit of lnd. It was October 27 2015. This is when I was in school still. This was done when I went on break and it was the first major…. we had in terms of code. We talked about the language we’re using, the licensing, the architecture of the daemon. A fun fact, the original name of lnd was actually called Plasma.</description></item><item><title>Bip150 Bip151</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-09-04-jonas-schnelli-bip150-bip151/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-09-04-jonas-schnelli-bip150-bip151/</guid><description>bip150 and bip151: Bitcoin p2p network encryption and authentication
https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/master/bip-0150.mediawiki
https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/master/bip-0151.mediawiki
https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/bip151-peer-encryption/
Introduction Alright guys.. take a seat. ((various mumblings)) Want to thank our sponsors, Digital Garage (applause). Second order of business, if you guys could&amp;hellip; trash away.. that would be awesome. There are trash cans in the back and right there and right next to the drinks. So at the end of the night, that would be great. Jonas Schnelli is a bitcoin core developer and he is here to talk about bitcoin encryption and authentication on the p2p network.</description></item><item><title>Merkle Sets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-07-08-bram-cohen-merkle-sets/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-07-08-bram-cohen-merkle-sets/</guid><description>Merkle set data structures for scaling bitcoin
code: https://github.com/bramcohen/MerkleSet
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/888836850529558531
Introduction There&amp;rsquo;s been a fair amount of talk about putting UTXO commitments in bitcoin blocks. Whether this is a good idea or not, but on the off-chance that it might be a good idea, I spent a fair amount of time thinking and actually good merkle set implementation whic his what you you need to put utxo set commitments in bitcoin blocks.</description></item><item><title>Neutrino</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-06-06-laolu-osuntokun-neutrino/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-06-06-laolu-osuntokun-neutrino/</guid><description>Neutrino: The Privacy Preserving Bitcoin Light Client
Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1vjJUWOZIaPshjx1svfE6rFZ2lC07n47ifOdzpKWqpb4/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1054031024085258240
Introduction My name is Laolu or Roasbeef on the internet. I’m going to talk about light clients in general and then also what we’re working on in terms of light clients and then also how that factors into the lightning network itself. The talk is called Neutrino because that is the name of our new light client that has been released.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Scripting</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-04-03-andreas-antonopoulos-bitcoin-scripting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-04-03-andreas-antonopoulos-bitcoin-scripting/</guid><description>Topic: Advanced Bitcoin Scripting
Location: SF Bitcoin Devs
Mastering Bitcoin on GitHub: https://github.com/bitcoinbook/bitcoinbook
Intro Today’s talk is different from some of the other talks I’ve done so bear with me. We are going to do this slowly in a very casual manner. This is not one of my usual talks where I am going to tell you about big picture vision and stuff like that. What I want to do is talk about some interesting features of Bitcoin Script and explain them.</description></item><item><title>New Address Type For Segwit Addresses</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-03-29-new-address-type-for-segwit-addresses/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-03-29-new-address-type-for-segwit-addresses/</guid><description>Topic: Bech32 addresses for Bitcoin
Location: SF Bitcoin Devs
Slides: https://prezi.com/gwnjkqjqjjbz/bech32-a-base32-address-format/
Proposal: https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/master/bip-0173.mediawiki
Demo website: http://bitcoin.sipa.be/bech32/demo/demo.html
Twitter announcement: https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/847569047902273536
Transcript completed by: Bryan Bishop Edited by: Michael Folkson
Intro Can everyone hear me fine through this microphone? Anyone who can&amp;rsquo;t hear me please raise your hand. Oh wait. All good now? Tonight I will be speaking on a project I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on on and off for the past year or so, which is the question of what kind of addresses we will be using in Bitcoin in the future.</description></item><item><title>Mimblewimble</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-11-21-mimblewimble/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-11-21-mimblewimble/</guid><description>Mimblewimble
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aHTRlbCaUyM
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/801990263543648256
History As Denise said, I gave a talk in Milan about mimblewimble about a month ago (slides). This is more or less the same talk, but rebalanced a bit to try to emphasize what I think is important and add some history that has happened in the intervening time. I&amp;rsquo;ll get started.
Many of you have heard of mimblewimble. It&amp;rsquo;s been in the news. It has a catchy name.</description></item><item><title>Bcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-09-28-christopher-jeffrey-bcoin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-09-28-christopher-jeffrey-bcoin/</guid><description>Topic: Bcoin
Location: SF Bitcoin Devs
Bcoin repo: https://github.com/bcoin-org/bcoin
Intro Hey everyone. I’m JJ with Purse. Tonight I want to talk to you about full nodes and full node implementations in general. In particular my project and the project we’ve been working on at Purse which is bcoin. A little history about me. I’ve actually given a presentation here before two years ago at the dev meetup. What I gave my talk on two years ago was actually the process of turning bitcoind into a shared object, into a library so you could link to it and call functions directly and call consensus code.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-07-18-laolu-osuntokun-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-07-18-laolu-osuntokun-lightning-network/</guid><description>Lightning Network Deep Dive
Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1OPijcjzadKkbxvGU6VcVnAeSD_DKb7gjnevBcqhPCW0/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1052238088913788928
Introduction My name is Laolu Osuntokun and I work with Lightning guys and you know me as maybe Roasbeef from the internet, on GitHub, Twitter, everything else. I’ve been Roasbeef for the past 8 years and I’m still Roasbeef that’s how it works. I’m going to give you a deep dive into the lightning network. I remember like 2 years ago when I was learning about Bitcoin initially and I went to these Bitcoin dev meetups in Mission and there was a deep dive and Taariq was the MC there, super friendly guy.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network As A Directed Graph Single Funded Channel Network Topology</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-04-11-lightning-network-as-a-directed-graph-single-funded-channel-network-topology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-04-11-lightning-network-as-a-directed-graph-single-funded-channel-network-topology/</guid><description>http://lightning.network/
slides: http://diyhpl.us/~bryan/papers2/bitcoin/Lightning%20Network%20as%20Directed%20Graph%20Single-Funded%20Channel%20Topology%20-%20Tadge%20Dryja%20-%202016-04-11.pdf
Okay. Hello everyone. Yes, okay, great. Yes. Yeah, I&amp;rsquo;m working on Lightning Network. Bitcoin is great and fun to work on.
Basic super quick summary of Lightning I am going to re-cap lightning network real quick. The basic idea is to have channels between two nodes. A channel, from the perspective of the rest of the world, is just a 2-of-2 multisig output. You can&amp;rsquo;t even tell it&amp;rsquo;s multisig, you just see an address with a 3 in front of the address.</description></item><item><title>Key Tree Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2015-08-24-pieter-wuille-key-tree-signatures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2015-08-24-pieter-wuille-key-tree-signatures/</guid><description>Topic: Key Tree Signatures
Location: SF Bitcoin Devs
Slides: https://prezi.com/vsj95ns4ucu3/key-tree-signatures/
Blog post: https://blockstream.com/2015/08/24/en-treesignatures/
Intro For those who don’t know me I’m Pieter Wuille. I have been working on Bitcoin Core for a while but this is work I have been doing at Blockstream. Today I will be talking about Key Tree Signatures which is what I have been working on these past few weeks. It is an improvement to the multisig schemes that we want to support.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2015-05-26-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2015-05-26-lightning-network/</guid><description>Tadge Dryja Joseph Poon How Lightning Network can offer a solution for bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s scalability problems
http://lightning.network/
slides: https://lightning.network/lightning-network-presentation-sfbitcoinsocial-2015-05-26.pdf
Great to have you guys. They are going to talk about bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s scalability problems. There they are.
Okay, hi. So yeah, I titled it solutions because that sounds more positive than talking about problems. Joseph will go after that and talk about what needs to change and the economics and things like that.</description></item><item><title>Scaling Bitcoin To Billions Of Transactions Per Day</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2015-02-23-scaling-bitcoin-to-billions-of-transactions-per-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2015-02-23-scaling-bitcoin-to-billions-of-transactions-per-day/</guid><description>Scaling Bitcoin To Billions Of Transactions Per Day
http://lightning.network/
Joseph Poon joseph@lightning.network Thaddeus Dryja rx@awsomnet.org We&amp;rsquo;re doing a presentation on the lightning network and micropayments. Right now bitcoin faces some interesting problems, like transactions aren&amp;rsquo;t instant, and micropayments don&amp;rsquo;t work. The transaction fees are 1/10th of a cent or higher depending on the exchange rate. And, &amp;ldquo;bitcoin doesn&amp;rsquo;t scale&amp;rdquo; especially if you have a lot of micropayments. One megabyte blocks? Well, let&amp;rsquo;s increase them.</description></item></channel></rss>