<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>workshop on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/categories/workshop/</link><description>Recent content in workshop on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/categories/workshop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Consensus Protocol Risks And Vulnerabilities</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/consensus-protocol-risks-and-vulnerabilities/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/consensus-protocol-risks-and-vulnerabilities/</guid><description>Consensus protocol risks and vulnerabilities
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229906447808360450
Introduction I am going to talk about why cryptocurrencies matter. I am going to take the skeptics side. I am going to start from a banker&amp;rsquo;s standpoint why a lot of the things that cryptocurrency people land say don&amp;rsquo;t make any sense.
Where are the engineers coming from? An engineer will look at something like Visa and say this is horrible. These are systems from 50-100 years ago.</description></item><item><title>Communication With Regulators</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/communication-with-regulators/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/communication-with-regulators/</guid><description>Communication with regulators
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229856579324760064
Backgrounds NTT JFSA SEC (enforcement division) celo compliance gold reserves, central bank digital currencies (monetary policy controls) soc1/soc2 audits engineer Developers and regulators: lawfulness questions Are software developers liable from a regulatory perspective for software that they write? There was a case against EtherDelta. He was receiving income from it. In any crime, for enforcement agencies&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s a line between regulators and criminal enforcement. Regulators create rules.</description></item><item><title>Opening Remarks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/opening-remarks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/opening-remarks/</guid><description>Opening remarks
http://bsafe.network/events/codefi_stanford_2020/
https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229833591716102144
Good morning. Let us start this workshop. I am a researcher at Georgetown University and it is my pleasure to host this workshop. CoDeFi is a workshop about coordination of decentralized finance. This unfortunately shares a name with a Consensys product. CoDeFi contains CoDe and DeFi. This is a multi-stakeholder workshop to discuss stakeholders that have never met before. I think we have regulators here, and engineers here, and researchers here, and business people here.</description></item><item><title>Regulatory Pain Points</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/regulatory-pain-points/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/regulatory-pain-points/</guid><description>Regulatory pain points
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229838162827993088
Introduction Hi, good morning everyone. I am a Japanese financial regulator at JFSA. My goal is to promote financial innovations and still ensure the financial stability and various regulatory goals. I have nearly 10 years experience as a regulator. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a strong background in technology, so I hope I can rely on the other stakeholders on this. I am now in Washington DC doing research on blockchain and governance policy.</description></item><item><title>Risk Overview</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/risk-overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/risk-overview/</guid><description>Overview of risk in decentralized financial systems
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229878346709782528
Introduction This is an overview of catastrophic failure risk in decentralized systems. There are certain degrees of risk in this system where losses can be moderate but not entirely destructive, but also potential failure modes where losses can be serious and ruinous equivalent to the global financial crisis.
From a regulator&amp;rsquo;s perspective, there&amp;rsquo;s a couple of primary mandates that regulators are tasked with making rules for.</description></item><item><title>Stress Testing Decentralized Finance</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/stress-testing-decentralized-finance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/stress-testing-decentralized-finance/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229844754990370816
Introduction More quantitatively, I think coming up with stress tests is akin to Bryan&amp;rsquo;s question&amp;hellip;. stress testing is something that people in this space kind of do, and I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about what that looks like and what an actuarial analysis should look like.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to go through three examples of where an actuarial analysis shows certain weaknesses that need to be monitored and understood. They are going to be more on the scifi end of cryptocurrency.</description></item><item><title>Technological Stability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/technological-stability/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/technological-stability/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229891596688052226
Controversial thesis: the primary source of economic instability is unreasonable demands (from regulators, but really from the general public) for violating certain cryptocurrency tech design principles, like on sound money- privacy and confidentiality (like confidential transactions and confidential assets), monetary policy (like scarcity economics), identity vs anonymity, AML/KYC requirements, censorship, sanctions requirements and discrimination (e.g. denying money to certain parties), and issues of fungibility (like mixing and history-indistinguishability).
Financial stability goals- like avoiding global economic crashes- might be at odds with goals like producing sound money and privacy for everyone.</description></item><item><title>Debugging Workshop</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-07-fabian-jahr-debugging-workshop/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-07-fabian-jahr-debugging-workshop/</guid><description>Topic: Debugging Bitcoin Core Workshop
Location: Advancing Bitcoin
Video: No video was posted online
Fabian presentation at Bitcoin Edge Dev++ 2019: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/edgedevplusplus/debugging-bitcoin/
Debugging Bitcoin Core doc: https://github.com/fjahr/debugging_bitcoin
Debugging Bitcoin Core Workshop: https://gist.github.com/fjahr/5bf65daaf9ff189a0993196195005386
Introduction First of all welcome to the debugging Bitcoin Core workshop. Everything I know more or less about using a debugger to learn from Bitcoin Core and to fix problems in Bitcoin Core. I didn’t go with traditional slides because I want to teach you how to use this tool, the debugger, in the context of Bitcoin Core.</description></item><item><title>Signet Workshop</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-07-kalle-alm-signet-workshop/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-07-kalle-alm-signet-workshop/</guid><description>Topic: Signet Workshop
Location: Advancing Bitcoin
Video: No video posted online
Let’s prepare mkdir workspace cd workspace git clone https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin.git cd bitcoin git remote add kallewoof https://github.com/kallewoof/bitcoin.git git fetch kallewoof git checkout signet ./autogen.sh ./configure -C --disable-bench --disable-test --without-gui make -j5 When you try to run the configure part you are going to have some problems if you don’t have the dependencies. If you don’t have the dependencies Google your OS and “Bitcoin build”.</description></item><item><title>Descriptor Wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-06-andrew-chow-descriptor-wallets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-06-andrew-chow-descriptor-wallets/</guid><description>Topic: Rethinking Wallet Architecture: Native Descriptor Wallets
Location: Advancing Bitcoin
Slides: https://www.dropbox.com/s/142b4o4lrbkvqnh/Rethinking%20Wallet%20Architecture_%20Native%20Descriptor%20Wallets.pptx
Support for Output Descriptors in Bitcoin Core: https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/blob/master/doc/descriptors.md
Bitcoin Optech on Output script descriptors: https://bitcoinops.org/en/topics/output-script-descriptors/
Bitcoin Core dev wiki on Wallet Class Structure Changes: https://github.com/bitcoin-core/bitcoin-devwiki/wiki/Wallet-Class-Structure-Changes
Intro Hi everyone. I am Andrew Chow, I am an engineer at Blockstream and also a Bitcoin Core contributor working mostly on the Bitcoin Core wallet. Today I am going to be talking about rethinking the wallet architecture with native descriptor wallets.</description></item><item><title>Schnorr and Taproot workshop</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinops/2019-09-27-schnorr-taproot-workshop/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinops/2019-09-27-schnorr-taproot-workshop/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs, NYC
https://github.com/bitcoinops/taproot-workshop
https://bitcoinops.slack.com
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1177697093462482949
Run: jupyter notebook
See also Schnorr signatures and taproot: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2018-07-09-taproot-schnorr-signatures-and-sighash-noinput-oh-my/
https://github.com/sipa/bips/blob/bip-schnorr/bip-schnorr.mediawiki
https://github.com/sipa/bips/blob/bip-schnorr/bip-taproot.mediawiki
https://github.com/sipa/bips/blob/bip-schnorr/bip-tapscript.mediawiki
Why Schnorr and why taproot? Who here already feels comfortbale with Schnorr/Taproot? This is a proposed consensus change to bitcoin. When we talk about consensus changes, we often talk about tradeoffs and compromises. It would be irresponsible to say taproot has no downsides, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s important to mention it&amp;rsquo;s a clear win for bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Custody Group</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/custody-group/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/custody-group/</guid><description>Custody working group
One of the problems in the ecosystem was nomenclature. We started working on a report about what features a nomenclature would have. Airgaps, constant-time software, sidechannel resistance, Faraday cage, deterministic software, entropy, blind signatures, proof-of-reserve, multi-vendor hardware to minimize compromise. Multi-location and multi-sig. Insurance guarantee scheme. Canaries, dead man switches, tripwires, heartbeat mechanisms. Shamir&amp;rsquo;s secret sharing vs multisig. The second part of this report was going to be market analysis.</description></item><item><title>Intro to W3 Blockchain Workshop</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/intro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/intro/</guid><description>Blockchains and standards
W3C Workshop
29-30 June 2016
Cambridge, Massachusetts
Doug Schepers schepers@w3.org
@shepazu
https://www.w3.org/2016/04/blockchain-workshop/
irc.w3.org #blockchain
https://etherpad.w3ctag.org/p/blockchain
My name is Doug. I am ostensibly the organizer. Along with my chairs, Neha, where are you? Please stand up so that everyone can embarras you. She is with DCI here at MIT, the Digital Currency Initiative. Daza, also with MIT, he is the guy who grbabed the space for us, and he is going to do video stuff later.</description></item><item><title>Archival Science</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/archival-science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/archival-science/</guid><description>Blockchain is a memory transfer sytsem. These memories are moving through space and time. This is something that I recognized. As a type of record, a ledger is a type of record traditionally. There are a number of international standards. One of them is ISO 15489, international records amangemetn. You will see this idea of memory of transactions as evidence. You will see something like &amp;ldquo;proofs on the blockchain&amp;rdquo;. This is information received and created and maintained.</description></item><item><title>Arvind Narayanan</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/arvind-narayanan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/arvind-narayanan/</guid><description>I would like to introduce Arvind. He is a professor at Princeton. He has talked about this in a number of different forums.
Hi everyone. My name is Arvind. This is turning out to be one of the more unusual and interesting events that I have been to. Someone at my table called the first session a quasi-religious experience. Not sure whether that was a good thing or not. Joking aside, my favorite thing about this is that the position statements were available on the website.</description></item><item><title>Blockchain Hub</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/blockchain-hub/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/blockchain-hub/</guid><description>My understanding is that there is application logic, consensus mechanism, distributed timestamp and ledger structure. With these layers, the blockchain can give total control of assets to the end. This materializes the attitude and philosophy of the internet. The intention is I think great. There is a missing link, though. It would be nice if these blockchain could manage the digital representational of physical assets.
I have been working with real estate escrow company in Japan to work on the proof-of-concept service of the real estate trading based on blockchain.</description></item><item><title>Christopher Allen</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/christopher-allen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/christopher-allen/</guid><description>Whta makes for a great wonderful magical calliberation? Collaboration? Grab one card randomly. Keep it with you. What is this particular pattern of greatness? See if you can&amp;rsquo;t embody it or can&amp;rsquo;t recommend it ofr find it in the next two days. I would like each of you to tell a story about a collaboration that was really meaningful to you. It could be a business effort, it could be another team in your company, or it could be a personal collaboration that you found really powerful.</description></item><item><title>Compliance And Confidentiality</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/compliance-and-confidentiality/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/compliance-and-confidentiality/</guid><description>Compliance and confidentiality: can they co-exist?
Alexander Zaidelson, Beam
Introduction Hi everyone. It&amp;rsquo;s a great pleasure to be here. I&amp;rsquo;m Alexander Zaidelson, CEO of Beam. I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting our view on the regulation and how we live with it as a project. I&amp;rsquo;m not an expert in regulation. Whatever I&amp;rsquo;m showing here is how we see the landscape from what we understand.
Beam is a confidential transaction. The question is, how can confidential cryptocurrency co-exist with regulation?</description></item><item><title>Day 2 Groups</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/day-2-groups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/day-2-groups/</guid><description>Browsers One was creating a new API or updating an existing API for Web Auth or an expansion to the web auth spec, where the browser would understand blockchain-based identity. We want to resolve and display blockchain identity in the browser, anything identified as an identity in a blockchain in a browser. Request payload signature. Apps receiving payloads could check from the user. Those are the four areas we are interested in pursuing for standards.</description></item><item><title>Deterministic Signatures Group</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/deterministic-signatures-group/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/deterministic-signatures-group/</guid><description>Deterministic expressions (group)
So please give your name and organization and what would you like to hear in the next twenty or thirty minutes.
ECDSA threshold signatures. Signature systems. Multisig predicate expressions.
new crypto systems build pipeline things, gitian things git signatures interop smart signatures &amp;ldquo;crypto conditions&amp;rdquo; ECDSA threshold signatures https://github.com/WebOfTrustInfo/ID2020DesignWorkshop/blob/master/topics-and-advance-readings/DexPredicatesForSmarterSigs.md
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/christopher-allen/
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/petertodd-dex/
https://petertodd.org/2016/talks-dex-arnhem-dev-workshop
http://web.archive.org/web/20220119164821/http://www.weboftrust.info/downloads/smart-signatures.pdf
Probably what people are least familiar with is crypto conditions. I am going to say a tiny bit about it.</description></item><item><title>Economic Risks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/economic-risks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/economic-risks/</guid><description>We looked at economic risks, and how to build a social safety net while allowing innovations. We talked about a bunch of different projects and looked at different systemic risk views from different countries. So the idea was to understand it from an economic perspective. I don&amp;rsquo;t think we came to any great conclusions. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of economic risk, and people don&amp;rsquo;t really understand it yet. One idea is to have more forums for central banks and regulators to understand what the technology can do, so that they can give insights for what the ramifications might be.</description></item><item><title>Ethcore</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/ethcore/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/ethcore/</guid><description>ethcore
At ethcore, we are building the infrastructure for the future of the decentralized web. Unless we get distracted by TheDAO and soft-forks and hard-forks. Maybe decentralization is not the most important thing. We want to build a p2p secure serverless web. Why is decentralization such an important notion? There&amp;rsquo;s no intrinsic value in being decentralized. There&amp;rsquo;s intrinsic value in being utilized and secure by people.
This is a bit of how we see the architecture.</description></item><item><title>G20 Discussion</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/g20-discussion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/g20-discussion/</guid><description>Why do we need a multi-stakeholder discussion in a blockchain world? A report from G20 discussions.
https://bsafe.network
Introduction I am the cofounder of the bsafe.network which focuses on blockchain research. I was a program co-chair for Scaling Bitcoin at Keio University last year. I also work with IEEE, ACM conferences, Ledger Journal, and more. My background is engagement with Bank of Japan NTT internet cash in 1998-2000.
Several huge incidents From a regulatory point of view, there are many big events that have occurred: MtGox, the DAO attack, coincheck, monacoin, and Zaif.</description></item><item><title>Groups Identity</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/groups-identity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/groups-identity/</guid><description>The topic that we have been working on is identity for everyone. In terms of trusted set of parties if you will, that can potentially provide some level of attestation to the identity and that can be provided in a digitized manner as to what levels of service an be provided to that level of identity as well.
&amp;hellip;
What belongs in a blockchain? What works in a blockchain? What doesn&amp;rsquo;t work in a blockchain?</description></item><item><title>Implications</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/implications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/implications/</guid><description>Implications on regulation and governance of blockchain-based finance
Yuta Takanashi (Financial Services Agency, Japan)
Disclaimer First, please note that the opinions presented here belong to myself and don&amp;rsquo;t represent the organizations to which I belong.
Major goals for financial regulators The primary goals of financial regulators are to maintain financial stability, protect investors and consumers, and prevent financial crimes. These goals are public interests and are needed to be achieved regardless of the technology used in the financial systems.</description></item><item><title>Intro to W3C standards</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/wendy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/wendy/</guid><description>08:45–09:00 - Keynote: “Intro to W3C standards” Wendy Seltzer, W3C.
https://goo.gl/3ZqAuo
We are working to make a web that is global and nteroperable and usable by everyone. If you have tech that you want to work on a global working basis, and distributed manner, then the web is the platform on which to do that. W3C is the consortium and standards body that works to help keep the web open and available.</description></item><item><title>Introduction (2019)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/introduction/</guid><description>Introduction to DFA Workshop
We are an international conference that focuses on the latest development in software and its scalability in the bitcoin ecosystem. We have come here to Israel. We are running 5 days of events, including this current workshop. Over the next 4 days following today, we&amp;rsquo;re running Bitcoin Edge Dev++ workshop at Tel Aviv University for 2 days, and then Scaling Bitcoin for 2 days which is compromised of over 44 high tech sessions on complex scalability and security related topics in the bitcoin ecosystem, mainly for developers.</description></item><item><title>Ipfs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/ipfs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/ipfs/</guid><description>I will not have time to describe IPFS. We have multiformats that allow protocol agility, interop and avoid lock-in. Multihash, multiaddr, multibase, multicodec, multistream, multikey. What do you do with cryptographic hashes? When you have four different hashes all the same length that happen to be coming from different functions, what are those functions? sha256? sha512? sha3? blake2b? How do you know which hash type it is?
The problem is that the values aren&amp;rsquo;t self-describing.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/lightning-network/</guid><description>I am going to talk about blockchain scalability using payment channel networks. I am working on Lightning Network. It&amp;rsquo;s currently being built in bitcoin but it can support other things. One of the fundamental problems with blockchain is scalability. How can you have millions of users and rapid transactions?
Fundamentally, the blockchain is shared. You can call it a DLT but it&amp;rsquo;s really a copied ledger. Every user has a copy.</description></item><item><title>Matsuo</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/matsuo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/matsuo/</guid><description>bsafe.network
Giving trust by security evaluation and bsafe.network
This is a severe problem. How can we trust the output of blockchain technology? We have several security issues. There was the huge DAO attack from two weeks ago. We also have other problems, such as protocol specification, key management, implementation, operation, and vulnerability handling. Also key renewal and key revocation issues.
ISO/IEC 27000 ISO/IEC 15408 ISO/IEC 29128 ISO/IEC 29128 ISO/IEC, NIST IETF We already have several international standards on each layer.</description></item><item><title>Metadata</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/metadata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/metadata/</guid><description>website: https://dfa2019.bitcoinedge.org/
twitter: https://twitter.com/thebitcoinedge
https://gnso.icann.org/sites/default/files/file/field-file-attach/presentation-pre-icann65-policy-report-13jun19-en.pdf</description></item><item><title>Perspective</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/perspective/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/perspective/</guid><description>Regulators should focus on consumer protection
Regulators should focus on operating (or overseeing) rating agencies, and formal review of proposed standards
Fungibility is important, and many regulatory goals are contrary to fungibility, indicating that their forms of money will be inferior and their economy will be left behind.
Anonymity should be a core value&amp;ndash; the society with the most privacy will have the most advantages.
The importance of regulatory sandboxes (which should be optional).</description></item><item><title>Petertodd Dex</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/petertodd-dex/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/petertodd-dex/</guid><description>I have been working on deterministic expressions language called DEX. It looks like lambda calculus. But really we&amp;rsquo;re trying to create a way to specify expressions that would return true if a signature is valid. Something like this, which is really just check a signature against a pubkey for a message, is essentially something that would be baked into your software anyway. We&amp;rsquo;re trying to move into a layer of abstraction where you can specify the conditions you need for your particular use case.</description></item><item><title>Physical Assets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/physical-assets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/physical-assets/</guid><description>Physical assets, archival science
We are going to spend 20 minutes talkign about the topics. Then we will spend 10 minutes getting summaries. Then we will spend 20 minutes summarizing everything.
Why is archival science important? I have a background in finance too. Blockchain securitizes things as well. It combines value and memory in one. Also, people have studied archives and how to get records and how to store records.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Anonymity And Identity Group</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/privacy-anonymity-and-identity-group/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/privacy-anonymity-and-identity-group/</guid><description>Anonymous identity
Another part of it is that all of those IoT things have firmware that can update. The moment that someone gets a key to update this, you can hack the grid by making rapid changes on power usage which actually destroys the &amp;hellip;. do the standards make things less secure? It should be illegal to design broken cryptosystems. Engineers should go to jail. It&amp;rsquo;s too dangerous. Do you think there should be smart grids at all?</description></item><item><title>Provenance Groups</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/provenance-groups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/provenance-groups/</guid><description>Give the name of your tech topic table. You have three minutes to summarize. When you have one minute to summarize, I will give you the one minute warning. When you have zero minutes left, you will be thrown out the window.
Media rights We talked about media rights and payments. The ability to figure out the incentive structure for whether we can compensate people who create page views with people who have view rights and how that all works.</description></item><item><title>Royalties</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/royalties/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/royalties/</guid><description>Chris Tse
Monegraph person
I am going to talk about rights systems. A system that lets us trade rights, like to make movie off of a character, off of the things that Disney makes whenever I buy toys for my two year-old son. This is used in intellectual property. Monegraph is known as the media rights blockchain-ish company. What we discovered about how to model rights, but why is it important, kind of extending and maybe contradicting the point further that the rights are not just the identity mapped to it in the blockchain, it&amp;rsquo;s just, in a lot of cases you are trading, selling or lending rights.</description></item><item><title>Smart Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/smart-signatures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/smart-signatures/</guid><description>Christopher Allen
Smart signatures and smarter signatures
Signatures are a 50+ year old technology. I am talking about the digital signature. It&amp;rsquo;s a hash of an object that has been encrypted by private key and verified by a public key against the hash of the object. All of our systems are using this in a varity of complex ways at high level to either do identity, sign a block, or do a variety of different things.</description></item></channel></rss>