<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Christian Decker on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/christian-decker/</link><description>Recent content in Christian Decker on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/christian-decker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploying Lightning at Scale (Greenlight)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2022/2022-03-03-christian-decker-greenlight/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2022/2022-03-03-christian-decker-greenlight/</guid><description>Blog post on Greenlight: https://blog.blockstream.com/en-greenlight-by-blockstream-lightning-made-easy/
Greenlight demo at London Bitcoin Devs: https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2022-03-01-lightning-panel/
Intro Jeff Gallas: Next up is Christian Decker. He is a Lightning developer at Blockstream. He has got a very simple title. It is Security, Simplicity and DevOps: the trade-offs between a Lightning PPAS and running your own node. That is already half of the talk.
Christian Decker: Thank you very much, I’m Chris and for once I am not going to shill eltoo, I promise.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2022-03-01-lightning-panel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2022-03-01-lightning-panel/</guid><description>Topic: The Lightning Network in 2022
Location: London Bitcoin Devs
Introductions Ali Taylor-Cipolla (ATC): Ali coming in from Coinbase Recruiting. I’d like to introduce to my friend Tiago who is on the Europe side.
Tiago Schmidt (TS): Hello everyone. Quick introduction, sitting in the recruiting team here in London and leading the expansion for engineering hiring across UK and Ireland. Coinbase is in hyper-growth at the moment and we will be looking to hire loads of the people.</description></item><item><title>ANYPREVOUT, MPP, Mitigating LN Attacks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-08-13-christian-decker/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-08-13-christian-decker/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/200/
Stephan Livera:
Christian welcome back to the show.
Christian Decker:
Hey, Stephan, thanks for having me
Stephan Livera:
Wanted to chat with you about a bunch of stuff that you’ve been doing. We’ve got a couple of things that I was really interested to chat with you about ANYPREVOUT, MPP, lightning attacks. What’s the latest with lightning network. But yeah, let’s start with a little bit around ANYPREVOUT. So I see that yourself and AJ towns just recently did an update and I think AJ Towns just did an email to the mailing list saying, okay, here’s the update to ANYPREVOUT, do you want to just give us a little bit of background?</description></item><item><title>Lightning Topics</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-08-13-christian-decker-lightning-topics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-08-13-christian-decker-lightning-topics/</guid><description>Topic: ANYPREVOUT, MPP, Mitigating Lightning Attacks
Location: Stephan Livera Podcast
Transcript completed by: Stephan Livera Edited by: Michael Folkson
Latest ANYPREVOUT update ANYPREVOUT BIP (BIP 118): https://github.com/ajtowns/bips/blob/bip-anyprevout/bip-0118.mediawiki
Stephan Livera (SL): Christian welcome back to the show.
Christian Decker (CD): Hey Stephan, thanks for having me.
SL: I wanted to chat with you about a bunch of stuff that you’ve been doing. We’ve got a couple of things that I was really interested to chat with you about: ANYPREVOUT, MPP, Lightning attacks, the latest with Lightning Network.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Backups</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2020-05-03-christian-decker-lightning-backups/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2020-05-03-christian-decker-lightning-backups/</guid><description>Topic: Back the f*** up
Location: Potzblitz (online)
Intro (Jeff Gallas) We’re live. Welcome to the fourth episode of Potzblitz, the weekly Lightning talk. Today we have a very special guest, Christian Decker of Blockstream. They also call him Dr Bitcoin. Our co-host today is Michael Folkson from the London BitDevs meetup. He is doing a bunch of Socratic Seminars and has a deep technical knowledge. He will be the perfect person to speak to Christian and has already prepared a bunch of questions.</description></item><item><title>C-Lightning Questions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockstream-webinars/2019-09-04-christian-decker-c-lightning-questions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockstream-webinars/2019-09-04-christian-decker-c-lightning-questions/</guid><description>c-lightning Q and A session
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230527903969841152
Introduction Hello everyone. I’m Christian. I’m a software developer at Blockstream and I work on Lightning, both the specification and the implementation. Today we are going to have a shortish webinar on how to get started with Lightning.
Q and A Q - Is it possible to run c-lightning and lnd on the same host in parallel?
A - It absolutely is. We actually do that on a regular basis to test compatibility between the implementations.</description></item><item><title>Multiparty Channels (Lightning Network)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-28-christian-decker-multiparty-channels/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-28-christian-decker-multiparty-channels/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs Lightning Residency 2019
Slides: https://residency.chaincode.com/presentations/lightning/Multiparty_Channels.pdf
Symmetric Update Protocols eltoo Update Mechanism Two days ago, we’ve seen the symmetric update mechanism called eltoo, and having a symmetric update mechanism has some really nice properties that enable some really cool stuff. Just to remind everybody, this is what eltoo looks like. That’s the one you&amp;rsquo;ve already seen. It’s not the only symmetric update mechanism, though.
Duplex Micropayment Channels It was predated by this stuff.</description></item><item><title>Rendezvous Routing</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-28-christian-decker-rendezvous-routing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-28-christian-decker-rendezvous-routing/</guid><description>Rendezvous Routing (Lightning Network)
Location: Chaincode Residency 2019
Slides: https://residency.chaincode.com/presentations/lightning/Rendezvous_Routing.pdf
Transcript by: Caralie Chrisco and Davius Parvin
Introduction Okay, the second part is rendezvous routing. I basically already gave away the trick but I hope you all forgot. So what is rendezvous routing? Anybody have a good explanation of what we are trying to do here? So we have someplace where we meet in the middle, and I don&amp;rsquo;t have to know where you live, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to know where I live, we&amp;rsquo;re all really private.</description></item><item><title>Eltoo</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-christian-decker-eltoo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-christian-decker-eltoo/</guid><description>Eltoo: The (Far) Future of Lightning
Location: Chaincode Labs
Slides: https://residency.chaincode.com/presentations/lightning/Eltoo.pdf
Eltoo white paper: https://blockstream.com/eltoo.pdf
Bitcoin Magazine article: https://bitcoinmagazine.com/articles/noinput-class-bitcoin-soft-fork-simplify-lightning
Intro Who has never heard about eltoo? It is my pet project and I am pretty proud of it. I will try to keep this short. I was told that you all have seen my presentation about the evolution of update protocols. I will probably go pretty quickly. I still want to give everybody the opportunity to ask questions if they have any.</description></item><item><title>Onion Routing Deep Dive</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-christian-decker-onion-routing-deep-dive/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-christian-decker-onion-routing-deep-dive/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Residency – Summer 2019
Onion Routing Deep Dive But we&amp;rsquo;ve not seen exactly why we are using an onion, or why we chose this construction of an onion and how this construction of an onion actually looks like. So my goal right now is to basically walk you through the iterations that onion routing packets have done so far, and why we chose this construction we have here.</description></item><item><title>Channel Factories</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2019-03-14-christian-decker-channel-factories/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2019-03-14-christian-decker-channel-factories/</guid><description>Topic: Lightning Channel Factories
Location: Stephan Livera Podcast
Lightning topology limitation Stephan: Christian, welcome to the show. I’m a big fan of your work.
Christian: Thank you so much for having me Stephan. I am a long time listener and I am happy to be joining you today.
Stephan: There has been a lot of chatter in the Bitcoin community on what might happen in the future. One of the ideas you presented in one of your papers you wrote in 2016 called Scalable Funding of Bitcoin Micropayment Channel Networks That is the discussion where we are going to go.</description></item><item><title>C-Lightning API</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-24-christian-decker-c-lightning-api/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-24-christian-decker-c-lightning-api/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs Lightning Residency 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1232313790311436290
Intro Good morning from the last day of presentations. I’m Chris still. Today I will be talking to you about c-lightning, how to develop on it, how to extend it, adapt it to your needs and how to customize it so it fits into whatever you are trying to do. Not whatever we thought you might want to do.
Goals First of all the goals of c-lightning are basically to be fast and lightweight.</description></item><item><title>History of the Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-christian-decker-history-of-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-christian-decker-history-of-lightning/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs Lightning Residency 2018
Introduction Hi I&amp;rsquo;m Chris, as I said like three times before, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about the history of Lightning and history of off-chain protocols or layer two, or you name it, whatever name you want. I like to call them off chain because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t imply a hierarchy of layers but I&amp;rsquo;ll use all three terms interchangeably anyway.
I like to have an interactive presentation so if you have any questions please don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate, just ask.</description></item><item><title>Lightning ≈ Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-christian-decker-lightning-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-22-christian-decker-lightning-bitcoin/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs Lightning Residency 2018
Introduction Good morning everyone my name is Chris and I&amp;rsquo;m a bitcoiners anonymous. So my job today is basically to tell you why Lightning is Bitcoin and why it&amp;rsquo;s not exactly Bitcoin. So there&amp;rsquo;s a few fundamental differences between Bitcoin on-chain payments and Lightning. I will always call Bitcoin on-chain payments just because it&amp;rsquo;s sort of the classical way of doing it.
The differences between Bitcoin and Lightning are sometimes small, sometimes bigger.</description></item></channel></rss>