<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>TABConf 2022 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/</link><description>Recent content in TABConf 2022 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Braidpool (2022-10-15)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-15-braidpool/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-15-braidpool/</guid><description>Introduction I am going to talk today about Braidpool which is a decentralized mining pool. I hope some of you were in the mining panel earlier today in particular p2pool which this is a successor to. I gave a talk a long time ago about a directed acyclic graph blockchain.
Braidpool Braidpool is a proposal for a decentralized mining pool which uses a merge-mined DAG with Nakamoto-like consensus to track shares.</description></item><item><title>Misconceptions about segwit vbytes (2022-10-15)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-15-segwit-vbytes-misconceptions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-15-segwit-vbytes-misconceptions/</guid><description>Weighing transactions: The witness discount You&amp;rsquo;ve already heard from someone that this presentation will be more interactive. I probably won&amp;rsquo;t get through all of my material. If you have questions during the talk, please feel free to raise your hand and we can cover it right away. I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to walk you through a transaction serialization for both a non-segwit transaction and a segwit transaction. By the end of the talk, I hope you understand how the transaction weight is calculated and how the witness discount works.</description></item><item><title>Silent Payments and Alternatives (2022-10-15)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-15-silent-payments/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-15-silent-payments/</guid><description>Introduction I will talk about silent payments but also in general the design space around what kind of constructs you can have to pay people in a non-interactive way. In the bitcoin world, there are a couple common ways of paying someone. Making a payment is such a basic thing. &amp;hellip; The alternative we have is that you can generate a single address and put it in your twitter profile and everyone can pay you, but that&amp;rsquo;s not private.</description></item><item><title>Provably bug-free BIPs and implementations using hac-spec (2022-10-14)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-14-hac-spec/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-14-hac-spec/</guid><description>https://nickler.ninja/
Alright. Strong crowd here, I can see. That&amp;rsquo;s very nice.
Introduction I am Jonas and I will talk about provably bug-free BIPs and implementations. I don&amp;rsquo;t have such a BIP nor such an implementation but if you lower your time-preference enough this could eventually be true at some point. This presentation is only 15 minutes so raise your hand if you have questions.
Just to set the stage. Specifications should be free of bugs, we want them easy to implement and hard to misinterpret.</description></item><item><title>ROAST - Robust asynchronous Schnorr threshold signatures (2022-10-14)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-14-roast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-14-roast/</guid><description>paper: https://ia.cr/2022/550
slides: https://slides.com/real-or-random/roast-tabconf22/
Hey. Hello. My name is Tim and I work at Blockstream. This is some academic work in joint with some of my coworkers.
Schnorr signatures in Bitcoin We recently got support for Schnorr signatures in bitcoin, introduced as part of bip340 which was activated as part of the taproot soft-fork. There are three main reasons why we want Schnorr signatures and prefer them over ECDSA bitcoin signatures which can still be used: one is that Schnorr signatures have provable security and give the theory guys more confidence; Schnorr signatures are more efficient; and the main thing is that we can get easier constructions of advanced signing protocols.</description></item></channel></rss>