<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bitcoin Review Podcast on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/</link><description>Recent content in Bitcoin Review Podcast on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Covenants, Introspection, CTV and Activation Impasse</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/covenants-introspection-ctv-and-activation-impasse/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/covenants-introspection-ctv-and-activation-impasse/</guid><description>Introduction NVK: 00:01:10
As usual, nothing is happening in Bitcoin and we figured, what a great day to put people to sleep in a one to three hour podcast. We don&amp;rsquo;t know yet how it&amp;rsquo;s going to be. We actually don&amp;rsquo;t know how this is going to play out at all. I have here with me Mr. Rijndael. Hello, sir. Welcome back.
Rijndael: 00:01:30
Hello. Good morning.
NVK: 00:01:32
Good morning.</description></item><item><title>Libsec Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/libsec-panel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/libsec-panel/</guid><description>Intros NVK: I have an absolute rock star team here. So why don&amp;rsquo;t I start introducing the panel? Tim, hello! Do you want to tell a very brief what do you do?
Tim: Yes, so my name is Tim Ruffing. I am a maintainer of the libsecp256k1 library. I do work for Blockstream, who pay me to do this and also who pay me to do research on cryptography and all kinds of aspects related to Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>#MPCbros vs #TeamScript Debate</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/mpcbros-vs-teamscript-debate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/mpcbros-vs-teamscript-debate/</guid><description>Intros Speaker 0: 00:01:08
Hello and welcome back to the Bitcoin.review. Today we have a very interesting show. It&amp;rsquo;s going to be a knife fight. Two men go into a room with one knife. One comes out. On my left side, Rindell for team MPC, weighing 64 kilobytes. On my right side, Rob for team script with variable sizing, so we don&amp;rsquo;t know. Is this already a loss? We don&amp;rsquo;t know, let&amp;rsquo;s find out.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Privacy &amp; Splice Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/lightning-privacy-splice-panel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/lightning-privacy-splice-panel/</guid><description>Housekeeping Speaker 0: 00:01:17
Today we&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking about Lightning privacy, splicing and other very cool things with an absolute amazing panel here. Just before that, I have a couple of things that I want to set out some updates. So OpenSats is now taking grants for a Bitcoin application, sorry, taking grant applications for Bitcoin projects and Nostra projects and Lightning projects. And there is about five mil for an OSTER, five mil for Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>OP_VAULT Round 2 &amp; OP_CTV</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/op_vault-round-2-op_ctv/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/op_vault-round-2-op_ctv/</guid><description>The podcast episode discusses the OP_VAULT proposal for enhancing Bitcoin self-custody and security. NVK hosts a panel with James O&amp;rsquo;Beirne, Rijndael, Greg Sanders, and Ben Carman, who delve into the technical aspects and benefits of OP_VAULT. The proposal aims to improve Bitcoin custody by introducing vaults, allowing users to lock their coins with predetermined spend conditions, enhancing security against theft and accidental loss. They compare OP_VAULT with other proposals like CTV and ANYPREVOUT, highlighting its simplicity and operational efficiency. The conversation also addresses potential concerns about covenants and the importance of community engagement and education to facilitate the proposal&amp;rsquo;s acceptance and activation. The episode emphasizes the need for better custody solutions to secure large amounts of Bitcoin, especially as the user base grows and the value of Bitcoin increases.</description></item><item><title>Cashu &amp; Fedimint: ecash, Bitcoin's layer 3 &amp; scalability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/cashu-and-fedimint/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/cashu-and-fedimint/</guid><description>Introduction If you haven&amp;rsquo;t had your brain completely destroyed by the segregated witness episode, I hope that the e-cash episode will finalize. It&amp;rsquo;s going to be fatality of your brain on this one. So I have with me a really good group of folks, two of them who are working on the biggest projects, who are deploying E-cash out there in the world.
Guest introductions NVK: 00:01:30
Welcome Calle.
Calle: 00:01:33</description></item><item><title>Demystifying and Understanding Bitcoin Core Development</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/demystifying-and-understanding-bitcoin-core-development/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/demystifying-and-understanding-bitcoin-core-development/</guid><description>Intro NVK: 00:00:40
Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking about Bitcoin Core development and trying to demystify it, maybe sort of like shed some light. So, some of the FUD goes away and new FUD comes in maybe, who knows?
Guest introductions NVK: 00:00:51
I have this awesome panel with me. I have a James O&amp;rsquo;Beirne. Hi James.
James O&amp;rsquo;Beirne: 00:00:56
Hi, good to be here.
NVK: 00:00:58
Thanks for coming.</description></item><item><title>OP_VAULT for Bitcoin Covenants Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/op_vault-for-bitcoin-covenants-panel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/op_vault-for-bitcoin-covenants-panel/</guid><description>Speaker 0: 00:00:45
Today we have an absolute all-star panel here. We&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking about the Bitcoin Op Vault. It&amp;rsquo;s a new proposal by James. And you know, like any new proposals to Bitcoin, there is a lot to go over. And It&amp;rsquo;s a very big, interesting topic. So today we have Rindell.
Speaker 2: 00:01:05
Hey, good morning. Yeah, I&amp;rsquo;m here talking about vaults, Bitcoin developer, and I work a lot on multi-sig and vaults that don&amp;rsquo;t use covenants.</description></item></channel></rss>