<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>P2P on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/p2p/</link><description>Recent content in P2P on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/p2p/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>BIP324 - Version 2 of p2p encrypted transport protocol</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2022-10-10-p2p-encryption/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2022-10-10-p2p-encryption/</guid><description>Previous talks https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/bip151-peer-encryption/
https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-09-04-jonas-schnelli-bip150-bip151/
https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06-07-p2p-encryption/
https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/p2p-encryption/
Introduction and motivation Can we turn down the lights? &amp;ldquo;Going dark&amp;rdquo; is a nice theme for the talk. I also have dark coffee. Okay.
We&amp;rsquo;re going to talk a little bit about bip324. This is a BIP that has had a long history. We even have a page about the history. It all started more than 6 years ago&amp;hellip; Bitcoin p2p traffic is unencrypted. It always has been.</description></item><item><title>Misc</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2022-10-10-misc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2022-10-10-misc/</guid><description>Web of Trust Some of the public key server operators interpreted GDPR to mean that they can&amp;rsquo;t operate public key infrastructure anymore. There needs to be another solution for p2p distribution of keys and Web-of-Trust.
&amp;lt;bitcoin-otc.com&amp;gt; continues to be the longest operating PGP web-of-trust using public key infrastructure. Rumplepay might be able to bootstrap a web-of-trust over time.
Stealth addresses and silent payments Here&amp;rsquo;s something controversial. Say you keep an in-memory map of all addresses that have already been used.</description></item><item><title>Minisketch and Lightning gossip</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/2022/2022-06-07-alex-myers-minisketch-lightning-gossip/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/2022/2022-06-07-alex-myers-minisketch-lightning-gossip/</guid><description>Location: Bitcoin++
Slides: https://endothermic.dev/presentations/magical-minisketch
Rusty Russell on using Minisketch for Lightning gossip: https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/lightning-dev/2018-December/001741.html
Minisketch library: https://github.com/sipa/minisketch
Bitcoin Core PR review club on Minisketch (3 sessions):
https://bitcoincore.reviews/minisketch-26
https://bitcoincore.reviews/minisketch-26-2
https://bitcoincore.reviews/minisketch
Introduction Pretty new to Lightning Network development, joined the Core Lightning team. I’m going to present on Minisketch and what I’ve learnt about the gossip network.
Topics I am going to go over the role of gossip in the Lightning Network. Is everyone familiar with Lightning or at least semi enthusiast?</description></item><item><title>Transaction Relay Policy</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/adopting-bitcoin/2021/2021-11-16-gloria-zhao-transaction-relay-policy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/adopting-bitcoin/2021/2021-11-16-gloria-zhao-transaction-relay-policy/</guid><description>Topic: Transaction Relay Policy for L2 Developers
Location: Adopting Bitcoin
Slides: https://github.com/glozow/bitcoin-notes/blob/master/Tx%20Relay%20Policy%20for%20L2%20Devs%20-%20Adopting%20Bitcoin%202021.pdf
Intro Hi I’m Gloria, I work on Bitcoin Core at Brink. Today I am going to talk a bit about mempool policy and why you cannot always expect your transactions to propagate or your fee bumps to work. What we are doing to try to resolve stuff like that. This talk is for those of you who find the mempool a bit murky or unstable or unpredictable.</description></item><item><title>Sydney Socratic Seminar</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-11-02-socratic-seminar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-11-02-socratic-seminar/</guid><description>Name: Socratic Seminar
Topic: Package relay
Location: Bitcoin Sydney (online)
Video: No video posted online
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Agenda: https://github.com/bitcoin-sydney/socratic/blob/master/README.md#2021-11
Package Mempool Accept and Package RBF: https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2021-September/019464.html
With illustrations: https://gist.</description></item><item><title>Current state of P2P research in Bitcoin /Erlay</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2019-11-13-gleb-naumenko-p2p-erlay/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2019-11-13-gleb-naumenko-p2p-erlay/</guid><description>London Bitcoin Devs
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1201861687097352198
Introduction My name is Gleb. I’ve worked on Bitcoin stuff since 2015, building wallets and exchanges in Ukraine. Then I realized that I can do more fun stuff. I want to do more protocol research, improving Bitcoin itself, not just using it. I decided I will go to Canada to do a Masters. I started working on this topic on research stuff more precisely and I realized that not many people do work on peer-to-peer (P2P) of Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>P2P Privacy Attacks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-10-09-giulia-fanti-p2p-privacy-attacks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-10-09-giulia-fanti-p2p-privacy-attacks/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs 2019 Residency
Slides: https://residency.chaincode.com/presentations/bitcoin/giulia_fanti_bitcoin_p2p.pdf
Giulia: So today I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk to you about some work that my collaborators and I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on for the last three years now. So this was joint work with a bunch of people who are now spread across a few different universities but it started at the University of Illinois: Shaileshh Bojja Venkatakrishnan, Surya Bakshi, Brad Denby, Shruti Bhargava, Andrew Miller, Pramod Viswanath.</description></item><item><title>Network Partitioning Attacks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-12-ethan-heilman-network-partitioning-attacks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-12-ethan-heilman-network-partitioning-attacks/</guid><description>Bitcoin network partitioning &amp;amp; network-level privacy attacks
Location: Chaincode Labs 2019 Residency
Slides: https://residency.chaincode.com/presentations/bitcoin/ethan_heilman_p2p.pdf
Eclipse attack paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2015/263.pdf
Bitcoin’s P2P Network Please interrupt me. I&amp;rsquo;m going to go through this stuff a little bit quickly because I hear that you&amp;rsquo;ve already read Eclipse attack paper and you&amp;rsquo;ve already looked at some of the peer to peer stuff.
Bitcoin uses a peer-to-peer network to announce transactions and blocks. It makes 8 outgoing connections.</description></item><item><title>P2P Encryption</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/p2p-encryption/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/p2p-encryption/</guid><description>bip324: v2 message transport protocol
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137312478373851136
slides: https://twitter.com/_jonasschnelli_/status/1137389541512351749
Previous talks https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/bip151-peer-encryption/
https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-09-04-jonas-schenlli-bip150-bip151/
https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06-07-p2p-encryption/
Introduction This will be a technical talk. I hope you&amp;rsquo;re prepared for some cryptography. By the way, this now has a bip number as of this morning. This is bip324. I call it v2 message transport protocol. It&amp;rsquo;s not a consensus change, it&amp;rsquo;s purely a p2p network layer change. It&amp;rsquo;s not all about encryption, but mainly about encryption.</description></item><item><title>P2P Encryption</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06-07-p2p-encryption/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06-07-p2p-encryption/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1136939003666685952
https://github.com/bitcoin-core/bitcoin-devwiki/wiki/P2P-Design-Philosophy
&amp;ldquo;Elligator Squared: Uniform Points on Elliptic Curves of Prime Order as Uniform Random Strings&amp;rdquo; https://eprint.iacr.org/2014/043
Previous talks https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/bip151-peer-encryption/
https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-09-04-jonas-schnelli-bip150-bip151/
Introduction This proposal has been in progress for years. Many ideas from sipa and gmaxwell went into bip151. Years ago I decided to try to move this forward. There is bip151 that again most of the ideas are not from myself but come from sipa and gmaxwell. The original proposal was withdrawn because we figured out ways to do it better.</description></item><item><title>Efficient P2P Transaction Relay</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-10-08-efficient-p2p-transaction-relay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-10-08-efficient-p2p-transaction-relay/</guid><description>p2p transaction relay protocol improvements with set reconciliation gleb
I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I need to motivate this problem. I presented a work in progress session at Scaling. The cost of relaying transactions or announcing a transaction in a network&amp;ndash; how many announcements do you have? Every link has an announcement in either direction right now, and then there&amp;rsquo;s the number of nodes multiplied by the number of connections per node.</description></item><item><title>Dandelion</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/dandelion/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/dandelion/</guid><description>Dandelion: Privacy-preserving transaction propagation in bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s p2p network
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014196927062249472
Today I will be talking to you about privacy in bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s p2p layer. This was joint work with some talented colleagues.
Bitcoin p2p layer I want to give a brief overview of the p2p layer. Users in bitcoin are connected over a p2p network with tcp links. Users are identified by ip address and port number. Users have a second identity, which is their address or public key or however you want to think about it.</description></item><item><title>Bip150 Bip151</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-09-04-jonas-schnelli-bip150-bip151/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-09-04-jonas-schnelli-bip150-bip151/</guid><description>bip150 and bip151: Bitcoin p2p network encryption and authentication
https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/master/bip-0150.mediawiki
https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/master/bip-0151.mediawiki
https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/bip151-peer-encryption/
Introduction Alright guys.. take a seat. ((various mumblings)) Want to thank our sponsors, Digital Garage (applause). Second order of business, if you guys could&amp;hellip; trash away.. that would be awesome. There are trash cans in the back and right there and right next to the drinks. So at the end of the night, that would be great. Jonas Schnelli is a bitcoin core developer and he is here to talk about bitcoin encryption and authentication on the p2p network.</description></item><item><title>BIP151 Peer Encryption</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/bip151-peer-encryption/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/bip151-peer-encryption/</guid><description>BIP151: Peer-to-peer encryption and authentication from the perspective of end-users
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785046960705339392
Good morning. Thanks for having me here. I would like to talk about the end-user perspective of p2p authentication. I would like to start with a little example of how difficult it is to be aware of end-user issues that they are facing at the front. Who is using a thin client? An &amp;ldquo;SPV&amp;rdquo; wallet on your smartphone? Yeah. Who of you are on iOS?</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Block Propagation and IBLT</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/bitcoin-block-propagation-iblt-rusty-russell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/bitcoin-block-propagation-iblt-rusty-russell/</guid><description>This is not what I do. But I was doing it anyway.
The problem is that blocks are transmitted in their entirety. If you have a 1 MB uplink and you&amp;rsquo;re connecting to 8 peers, your first peer will see a 1MB block in about 66.8 seconds. And the last one will get it in 76.4 seconds, because we basically blast out blocks in parallel to our peers. Miners can solve this problem of slow block transmission by centralizing and all using the same pool.</description></item><item><title>Compact Multi Signatures For Smaller Blockchains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/compact-multi-signatures-for-smaller-blockchains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/compact-multi-signatures-for-smaller-blockchains/</guid><description>Compact multi-signatures for smaller blockchains
Dan Boneh (Stanford University), Manu Drijvers and Gregory Neven (DFINITY)
paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/483.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048441176024469504
Introduction Hi. Thanks a lot for coming in after lunch. This slot is often known as &amp;ldquo;the slot of death&amp;rdquo;. Some of us are jetlagged, this is the perfect time to doze off and only wake up at the end of the talk. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to prevent that from happening. I think the best way to do that is to start about what this talk can do for you.</description></item><item><title>Erlay</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/erlay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/erlay/</guid><description>Erlay: Bandwidth-efficient transaction relay for bitcoin
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171744449396953090
paper: https://arxiv.org/abs/1905.10518
Introduction Hi, my name is Gleb. I work at Chaincode Labs. I am working on making nodes better and stronger and make the network more robust. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on erlay with Pieter and Greg and some other guys.
Bitcoin p2p network There are private nodes that are behind firewalls like ones run at home. If your node is connected to a router, your router tries to protect you from the internet accessing your endpoint.</description></item><item><title>Ethcore</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/ethcore/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/ethcore/</guid><description>ethcore
At ethcore, we are building the infrastructure for the future of the decentralized web. Unless we get distracted by TheDAO and soft-forks and hard-forks. Maybe decentralization is not the most important thing. We want to build a p2p secure serverless web. Why is decentralization such an important notion? There&amp;rsquo;s no intrinsic value in being decentralized. There&amp;rsquo;s intrinsic value in being utilized and secure by people.
This is a bit of how we see the architecture.</description></item><item><title>Graphene Set Reconciliation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/graphene-set-reconciliation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/graphene-set-reconciliation/</guid><description>Brian N. Levine, College of Information and Computer Sciences, UMass Amherst
This is joint work with some people I work with at UMass, including Gavin Andresen.
The problem I am going to focus on in this presentation is how to relay information to a new block, to a neighbor, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t know about next. This would be on the fast relay network or on the regular p2p network. It&amp;rsquo;s about avoiding a situation where, the naieve situation is to send the entire block data.</description></item><item><title>Issues Impacting Block Size Proposals</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/issues-impacting-block-size-proposals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/issues-impacting-block-size-proposals/</guid><description>Issues impacting block size proposals
Jeff Garzik (jgarzik)
Bitcoin was introduced as a p2p electronic cash system. That&amp;rsquo;s what it says in the whitepaper. That&amp;rsquo;s what the users were exposed to. The 1 MB block size was set for anti-spam purposes. Otherwise when bitcoin value is low, it&amp;rsquo;s trivial to DOS the network with large blocks.
Moving on to some observations. The process of finding distributed ocnsensus takes time; it&amp;rsquo;s a settlement system.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Routing</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/edgedevplusplus/lightning-network-routing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/edgedevplusplus/lightning-network-routing/</guid><description>Introduction Good afternoon everyone. My name is Carla. I am one of the chaincode residents this summer. This talk is going to walk through the protocol layer by layer and look at the different components that make up the network. Lightning is an off-chain scaling solution which consists of a p2p network of payment channels. It allows payments to be forwarded by nodes in exchange for fees.
Scaling with payment channels This involves a payment channel.</description></item><item><title>Measuring Network Maximum Sustained Transaction Throughput</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/measuring-network-maximum-sustained-transaction-throughput/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/measuring-network-maximum-sustained-transaction-throughput/</guid><description>Measuring maximum sustained transaction throughput on a global network of Bitcoin nodes
Andrew Stone, Bitcoin Unlimited
We are 25 minutes behind schedule.
We have the rest of the team wathcing remotely. I think the motivation for this project is clear. Transaction volume on the bitcoin network could be growing exponentially except that there is a limit on the number of confirmed transactions. Transaction fees have increased and confirmation times are not reliable, and bitcoin is unusable for some applications.</description></item><item><title>P2P with John Newbery</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/edgeplusplus/p2p-john-newbery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/edgeplusplus/p2p-john-newbery/</guid><description>Name: John Newbery
Topic: Bitcoin Peer-to-Peer Network and Mempool
Location: Bitcoin Edge Dev++ 2017 - Stanford University
Slides: https://johnnewbery.com/presentation/2017/11/02/dev-plus-plus-stanford/p2p.pdf &amp;amp; https://johnnewbery.com/presentation/2017/11/02/dev-plus-plus-stanford/mempool.pdf
Bitcoin Peer-to-Peer Network John: So far today, we&amp;rsquo;ve talked about transactions and blocks and the blockchain. Those are the fundamental building blocks of Bitcoin. Those are the data structures that we use. On a more practical level, how does a Bitcoin network actually function? How do we transmit these transactions and blocks around?</description></item><item><title>P2Pkh P2Wpkh P2H P2Wsh</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/edgedevplusplus/p2pkh-p2wpkh-p2h-p2wsh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/edgedevplusplus/p2pkh-p2wpkh-p2h-p2wsh/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1047697572444270592
Introduction This is going to be a bit of a re-tread I think. I am going to be talking about common bitcoin script templates used in bitcoin today.
Addresses do not exist on the blockchain. But scripts do. You&amp;rsquo;ve heard about p2pk, p2pkh, p2sh, and others. I&amp;rsquo;m going to go over these anyway.
Pay-to-pubkey (p2pk) This was the first type. It had no address format actually. Nodes connected to each other over IP address, with no authentication.</description></item><item><title>Reworking Bitcoin Core P2P Code For Robustness And Event Driven</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/reworking-bitcoin-core-p2p-code-for-robustness-and-event-driven/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/reworking-bitcoin-core-p2p-code-for-robustness-and-event-driven/</guid><description>That is me. I want to apologize right off. I am here to talk about reworking Bitcoin Core p2p code. This is a Bitcoin Core specific topic. I have been working on some software for the past few weeks to talk about working things rather than theory. The presentation is going to suffer because of this.
Bitcoin Core has a networking stack that dates back all the way to the initial implementation from Satoshi or at least it&amp;rsquo;s been patched and hacked on ever since.</description></item><item><title>Validation Costs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/validation-costs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/validation-costs/</guid><description>Validation costs and incentives
How many of you have read the Satoshi whitepaper? It&amp;rsquo;s a good paper. As we have discovered, it has some serious limitations that we think can be fixed but they are serious challenges for scaling. Amongst these are, it was really built as a single code base which was meant to be run in its entirety. All machines were going to participate equally in this p2p network.</description></item></channel></rss>