<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>P2P Network Protocol on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/p2p/</link><description>Recent content in P2P Network Protocol on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/p2p/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Erlay</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2024-10/erlay/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2024-10/erlay/</guid><description>Idea from 2018, code since 2021 code-wise, only 20% of the high-level code is merged (not counting low-level minisketch code): The basic structure, plus code for peer signaling has been merged -&amp;gt; good time to join, Review is needed
Open questions mostly concern policies (decisions of nodes) - there are various details still under discussion, such as picking parameters, details in logic etc. BIP330 only defines protocol, but not the policy decisions</description></item><item><title>Discussing Pre-25.0 Bitcoin Core Vulnerability Disclosures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/the-bitcoin-development-podcast/discussing-pre-25-0-bitcoin-core-vulnerability-disclosures/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/the-bitcoin-development-podcast/discussing-pre-25-0-bitcoin-core-vulnerability-disclosures/</guid><description>Brink engineers Gloria Zhao and Niklas Gögge are joined by 0xB10C talk through the recently disclosed Bitcoin Core pre-25.0 vulnerabilities.</description></item><item><title>ASMap</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2024-04/asmap/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2024-04/asmap/</guid><description>From virtu&amp;rsquo;s presentation Distribution of nodes in ASes is low 8k reachable clearnet nodes / 30k unreachable A contributor has different statistics that show a lot more nodes, not sure which numbers are (more) correct. These numbers are would mean that some of the simulations are already a reality. Most nodes from Hetzner and AWS Shift compute and bandwidth to nodes in small ASes Unreachable nodes cannot sustain ten outbound connections Discussions Ignore AS for blocks-only connections?</description></item><item><title>P2P Monitoring</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2024-04/p2p-monitoring/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2024-04/p2p-monitoring/</guid><description>Slides
Started working on this about 2 years ago; in 2021. After we accidentally observed the address flooding anomaly/attack Primarily uses https://github.com/0xB10C/peer-observer to extract data from Bitcoin Core nodes with tracepoints. The infrastructure also includes a fork-observer connected to each node as well as an addrman-observer for each node. Additionally, detailed Bitcoin Core debug logs are avaliable. The main part are the Grafana dashboards. There’s a public version at public.peer.observer, which is redacted to not leak honeynode IP addresses.</description></item><item><title>Private tx broadcast</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2024-04/private-tx-broadcast/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2024-04/private-tx-broadcast/</guid><description>Updates:
TX is validated before broadcast (using mempool test). The sender ignores incoming messages from the receiver (except the handshake and PONG), so the sender cannot send back the tx before disconnection. When it receives the tx back, it becomes &amp;ldquo;just a tx in mempool&amp;rdquo;. TODO/NICE TO HAVE
Check if the wallet is going to rebroadcast a tx it has created but has been broadcast via private broadcast and if yes, prevent that.</description></item><item><title>P2P Design Goals</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2023-09/p2p-design-goals/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2023-09/p2p-design-goals/</guid><description>Guiding Questions What are we trying to achieve?
What are we trying to prevent?
How so we weight performance over privacy?
What is our tolerance level for net attacks?
Are we trying to add stuff to the network or are we trying to prevent people getting information?
Network topology: By design we are trying to prevent the topology being known Information creation, addresses, txs or blocks
We want blocks at tips fast - consensus critical information needs to be as fast as possible - ability to get the information - forgetting that there are multiple networks - the purpose is to know what the current most work chain tip is Even the addr relay network - everything falls apart if you can’t get that information The crux of the p2p network is to propagate what is the most work Txs can take much much longer but don’t want to leak the source of the origin The privacy implications of Txs makes it difficult Could give up fast propagations for privacy for txs that would be fine but not for blocks.</description></item><item><title>P2P working session</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2023-09/p2p-working-session/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2023-09/p2p-working-session/</guid><description>Erlay Gleb is active and ready to move forward - #21515 Are there people generally interested in review? I wanted first to convince myself that this is useful. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t reproduce the numbers from the paper - 5% was what I got with ~100 connections. My node is listening on a non-standard port. It may be that I don&amp;rsquo;t have a normal sample. There is a pull request that could add RPC stats to bitcoind - that might get better numbers.</description></item><item><title>Package Relay Primer</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2023-04/2023-04-25-package-relay-primer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2023-04/2023-04-25-package-relay-primer/</guid><description>Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/12YPlmmaCiNNL83b3FDmYwa7FKHP7yD0krzkEzM-tkTM
Problems CPFP Doesn’t Work When Mempool Min Feerate Rises Bad for users who want to use CPFP and L2s, but also a glaring limitation in our ability to assess transaction incentive compatibility
Pinning being able to feebump transaction is a pinning concern counterpart can intentionally censor your transactions, and in L2 that can mean stealing your money because you didn’t meet the timelock Pinning examples ANYONECANPAY -&amp;gt; anyonecanpin: add input that comes from huge unconfirmed low-fee rate tx -&amp;gt; absolute feerate needs to increase, so you&amp;rsquo;re paying more fees for the tx to confirm slower shared descendant limit can be monopolized descendant limit is 25 txs, so someone else can fill up that limit we have a carve-out for CPFP already to try and mitigate that RBF Rule 3 is gameable replacement fees must &amp;gt; all descendants, and they may be large, low feerate -&amp;gt; expensive most L2s have pinning problems, so we need to fix that Get rid of txid-based relay we want to avoid txid based relay can&amp;rsquo;t deduplicate txid and wtxid that correspond to the same tx can&amp;rsquo;t deduplicate txs that only differ in witness we still require txid-based relay for orphans, because txs specify prevouts by txid -&amp;gt; so we don&amp;rsquo;t know which wtxid to request Definitions pinning attack: a censorship attack on relay/mempool level, abusing policy</description></item><item><title>Minisketch and Lightning gossip</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/2022/2022-06-07-alex-myers-minisketch-lightning-gossip/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/2022/2022-06-07-alex-myers-minisketch-lightning-gossip/</guid><description>Location: Bitcoin++
Slides: https://endothermic.dev/presentations/magical-minisketch
Rusty Russell on using Minisketch for Lightning gossip: https://gnusha.org/url/https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/lightning-dev/2018-December/001741.html
Minisketch library: https://github.com/sipa/minisketch
Bitcoin Core PR review club on Minisketch (3 sessions):
https://bitcoincore.reviews/minisketch-26
https://bitcoincore.reviews/minisketch-26-2
https://bitcoincore.reviews/minisketch
Introduction Pretty new to Lightning Network development, joined the Core Lightning team. I’m going to present on Minisketch and what I’ve learnt about the gossip network.
Topics I am going to go over the role of gossip in the Lightning Network. Is everyone familiar with Lightning or at least semi enthusiast?</description></item><item><title>Address Relay</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-podcast/address-relay/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-podcast/address-relay/</guid><description>Martin Zumsande joins us to tell us about the address spam in the summer of 2021 and his interests in AddrRelay and Bitcoin Core development.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Was Under ATTACK!</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/bitcoin-was-under-attack/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/bitcoin-was-under-attack/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hosts Aaron van Wirdum and Sjors Provoost finally met in Utrecht again to record Bitcoin, Explained. In this episode, they discuss a recent attack on the Bitcoin network, where some nodes were flooding peers with fake IP-addresses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As previously discussed in episode 13, Bitcoin nodes connect to peers on the network through IP-addresses, which they learn from their existing peers. Nodes on the network essentially share the IP-addresses of other nodes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, however, some Bitcoin nodes shared large amounts of IP-addresses that weren’t associated with real Bitcoin nodes at all. While this attack did not do very much damage, it did waste resources from nodes on the network. On top of that, Aaron and Sjors explain, the attack could offer the attacker insight into Bitcoin’s network topology by analyzing how the fake IP-addresses spread through the network.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, Aaron and Sjors discuss how the attack was solved by rate limiting the amount of IP-addresses than any node will allow its peers to be shared. Further, they consider how in free and open source software development, fixing problems is not always as straightforward as it may seem…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The P2P network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-podcast/the-p2p-network-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-podcast/the-p2p-network-2/</guid><description>P2P experts Amiti Uttarwar and Pieter Wuille discuss various aspects of peer-to-peer communication in Bitcoin, with Adam Jonas facilitating the conversation. They delve into the challenges and objectives of address relay, highlighting its complexities and the importance of propagating IP addresses to maintain network connectivity and prevent partitioning and eclipse attacks. The discussion covers the design and evolution of AddrMan, introduced in 2012 to manage IP addresses, and the impact of changes like rate-limiting address gossip to mitigate spam. Pieter and Amiti also touch on the significance of maintaining separate network stacks for different network protocols and the potential of employing ASMAP to improve network resilience. The conversation underscores ongoing efforts and future directions for enhancing Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s P2P network.</description></item><item><title>The P2P network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-podcast/the-p2p-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-podcast/the-p2p-network/</guid><description>In this episode of the Chaincode Podcast, Amiti Uttarwar discusses the intricacies of peer-to-peer (P2P) networks in Bitcoin with hosts Adam Jonas and Mark Erhardt. Amiti explains her fascination with P2P due to its logical yet complex interactions across the global network of nodes. She outlines five key principles for designing effective P2P networks: reliability, timeliness, accessibility, privacy, and upgradeability. The conversation delves into specific challenges, such as Eclipse attacks, address relay, and the role of the address manager (AddrMan) in maintaining network integrity. Amiti also highlights the delicate balance between ensuring privacy and achieving network reliability. Overall, the discussion emphasizes the importance of continuous collaboration and innovation in Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s P2P network development.</description></item><item><title>Socratic Seminar</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chicago-bitdevs/2020-08-12-socratic-seminar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chicago-bitdevs/2020-08-12-socratic-seminar/</guid><description>BitDevs Solo Socratic 4 agenda: https://bitdevs.org/2020-07-31-solo-socratic-4
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have given permission for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Bitcoin Core P2P IRC Meetings https://github.com/bitcoin-core/bitcoin-devwiki/wiki/P2P-IRC-meetings
They are starting P2P meetings for the Bitcoin protocol now. The trend for organizing backbone development for Bitcoin is starting to become more modular.</description></item><item><title>Attacking Bitcoin Core</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/la-bitdevs/2020-04-16-amiti-uttarwar-attacking-bitcoin-core/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/la-bitdevs/2020-04-16-amiti-uttarwar-attacking-bitcoin-core/</guid><description>Intro I’m going to talk to you today about attacking Bitcoin Core.
Bitcoin To start with the fundamentals. As we all know Bitcoin is a money and it is different to our existing centralized solution of money because instead we have nodes that are running all around the world.
Consensus Fundamentally what is required for this to work is the idea of consensus where all the nodes must agree on the same fundamental values.</description></item><item><title>Current state of P2P research in Bitcoin /Erlay</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2019-11-13-gleb-naumenko-p2p-erlay/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2019-11-13-gleb-naumenko-p2p-erlay/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1201861687097352198
Introduction My name is Gleb. I’ve worked on Bitcoin stuff since 2015, building wallets and exchanges in Ukraine. Then I realized that I can do more fun stuff. I want to do more protocol research, improving Bitcoin itself, not just using it. I decided I will go to Canada to do a Masters. I started working on this topic on research stuff more precisely and I realized that not many people do work on peer-to-peer (P2P) of Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>P2P Privacy Attacks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-residency/2019-10-09-giulia-fanti-p2p-privacy-attacks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-residency/2019-10-09-giulia-fanti-p2p-privacy-attacks/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs 2019 Residency
Slides: https://residency.chaincode.com/presentations/bitcoin/giulia_fanti_bitcoin_p2p.pdf
Giulia: So today I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk to you about some work that my collaborators and I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on for the last three years now. So this was joint work with a bunch of people who are now spread across a few different universities but it started at the University of Illinois: Shaileshh Bojja Venkatakrishnan, Surya Bakshi, Brad Denby, Shruti Bhargava, Andrew Miller, Pramod Viswanath.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin network partitioning &amp; network-level privacy attacks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-residency/2019-06-12-ethan-heilman-network-partitioning-attacks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-residency/2019-06-12-ethan-heilman-network-partitioning-attacks/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs 2019 Residency
Slides: https://residency.chaincode.com/presentations/bitcoin/ethan_heilman_p2p.pdf
Eclipse attack paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2015/263.pdf
Bitcoin’s P2P Network Please interrupt me. I&amp;rsquo;m going to go through this stuff a little bit quickly because I hear that you&amp;rsquo;ve already read Eclipse attack paper and you&amp;rsquo;ve already looked at some of the peer to peer stuff.
Bitcoin uses a peer-to-peer network to announce transactions and blocks. It makes 8 outgoing connections. These are TCP connections initiated by the node.</description></item><item><title>Advances In Block Propagation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2017-11-27-gmaxwell-advances-in-block-propagation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2017-11-27-gmaxwell-advances-in-block-propagation/</guid><description>slides: https://web.archive.org/web/20190416113003/https://people.xiph.org/~greg/gmaxwell-sf-prop-2017.pdf
https://en.bitcoin.it/wiki/User:Gmaxwell/block_network_coding
efficient block transfer: https://web.archive.org/web/20170912171304/https://people.xiph.org/~greg/efficient.block.xfer.txt
low latency block xfer: https://web.archive.org/web/20160607023347/https://people.xiph.org/~greg/lowlatency.block.xfer.txt
https://web.archive.org/web/20160607023408/https://people.xiph.org/~greg/mempool_sync_relay.txt
https://web.archive.org/web/20160607023359/http://people.xiph.org/~greg/weakblocks.txt
compact blocks FAQ https://bitcoincore.org/en/2016/06/07/compact-blocks-faq/
some history https://www.reddit.com/r/btc/comments/557ihg/what_are_the_arguments_against_xthin_blocks/d88q5l4/
more history https://www.reddit.com/r/btc/comments/6p076l/segwit_only_allows_170_of_current_transactions/dkmugw5/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/944656354307919873
Introduction I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about some recent advances in block propagation and why this stuff is important. I am going to talk about how the original bitcoin p2p protocol works, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work that way for the most part anymore. I will talk about the history of this, including fast block relay protocol, block network coding, and then building up to where the state of the art is today.</description></item><item><title>Measuring maximum sustained transaction throughput on a global network of Bitcoin nodes</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/measuring-network-maximum-sustained-transaction-throughput/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/measuring-network-maximum-sustained-transaction-throughput/</guid><description>Andrew Stone, Bitcoin Unlimited
We are 25 minutes behind schedule.
We have the rest of the team wathcing remotely. I think the motivation for this project is clear. Transaction volume on the bitcoin network could be growing exponentially except that there is a limit on the number of confirmed transactions. Transaction fees have increased and confirmation times are not reliable, and bitcoin is unusable for some applications.
Some people want to see the max blokc size limit lifted.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Block Propagation and IBLT</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/bitcoin-block-propagation-iblt-rusty-russell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/bitcoin-block-propagation-iblt-rusty-russell/</guid><description>This is not what I do. But I was doing it anyway.
The problem is that blocks are transmitted in their entirety. If you have a 1 MB uplink and you&amp;rsquo;re connecting to 8 peers, your first peer will see a 1MB block in about 66.8 seconds. And the last one will get it in 76.4 seconds, because we basically blast out blocks in parallel to our peers. Miners can solve this problem of slow block transmission by centralizing and all using the same pool.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Peer-to-Peer Network and Mempool</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2017/p2p-john-newbery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2017/p2p-john-newbery/</guid><description>John Newbery covers the primitives and functionality that comprises Bitcoin peer-to-peer network. This includes types of nodes that comprise the network, message format, control messages, transaction and block propagation, mempool, fee estimation, compact blocks etc.</description></item><item><title>Erlay</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/erlay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/erlay/</guid><description>Erlay: Bandwidth-efficient transaction relay for bitcoin
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171744449396953090
paper: https://arxiv.org/abs/1905.10518
Introduction Hi, my name is Gleb. I work at Chaincode Labs. I am working on making nodes better and stronger and make the network more robust. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on erlay with Pieter and Greg and some other guys.
Bitcoin p2p network There are private nodes that are behind firewalls like ones run at home. If your node is connected to a router, your router tries to protect you from the internet accessing your endpoint.</description></item><item><title>Graphene Set Reconciliation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/graphene-set-reconciliation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/graphene-set-reconciliation/</guid><description>Brian N. Levine, College of Information and Computer Sciences, UMass Amherst
This is joint work with some people I work with at UMass, including Gavin Andresen.
The problem I am going to focus on in this presentation is how to relay information to a new block, to a neighbor, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t know about next. This would be on the fast relay network or on the regular p2p network. It&amp;rsquo;s about avoiding a situation where, the naieve situation is to send the entire block data.</description></item><item><title>Issues Impacting Block Size Proposals</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/issues-impacting-block-size-proposals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/issues-impacting-block-size-proposals/</guid><description>Bitcoin was introduced as a p2p electronic cash system. That&amp;rsquo;s what it says in the whitepaper. That&amp;rsquo;s what the users were exposed to. The 1 MB block size was set for anti-spam purposes. Otherwise when bitcoin value is low, it&amp;rsquo;s trivial to DOS the network with large blocks.
Moving on to some observations. The process of finding distributed ocnsensus takes time; it&amp;rsquo;s a settlement system. The core service that bitcoin provides is censorship resistance.</description></item><item><title>Reworking Bitcoin Core P2P Code For Robustness And Event Driven</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/reworking-bitcoin-core-p2p-code-for-robustness-and-event-driven/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/reworking-bitcoin-core-p2p-code-for-robustness-and-event-driven/</guid><description>That is me. I want to apologize right off. I am here to talk about reworking Bitcoin Core p2p code. This is a Bitcoin Core specific topic. I have been working on some software for the past few weeks to talk about working things rather than theory. The presentation is going to suffer because of this.
Bitcoin Core has a networking stack that dates back all the way to the initial implementation from Satoshi or at least it&amp;rsquo;s been patched and hacked on ever since.</description></item><item><title>Validation Costs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/validation-costs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/validation-costs/</guid><description>Validation costs and incentives
How many of you have read the Satoshi whitepaper? It&amp;rsquo;s a good paper. As we have discovered, it has some serious limitations that we think can be fixed but they are serious challenges for scaling. Amongst these are, it was really built as a single code base which was meant to be run in its entirety. All machines were going to participate equally in this p2p network.</description></item></channel></rss>