<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Elizabeth Stark on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/elizabeth-stark/</link><description>Recent content in Elizabeth Stark on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/elizabeth-stark/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>State Of Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/state-of-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/state-of-lightning-network/</guid><description>Fireside chat on the state of the lightning network
Introduction WP: We have a fireside chat with Stacy Herbert from Kaiser Report and Elizabeth Stark. Some people say she is the CEO of Lightning Network, but she is the CEO of Lightning Labs. Let&amp;rsquo;s invite them on stage.
SH: Did anyone notice the bitcoin price today? How many here are reckless? How many of you have used lightning? Alright, how many are torchbearers?</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin- Native Currency of the Internet</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2019-02-11-jack-dorsey-elizabeth-stark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2019-02-11-jack-dorsey-elizabeth-stark/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/52/
Stephan Livera: Welcome to the Stephan Livera podcast, focused on Bitcoin and Austrian economics. Learn the technology and economics of Bitcoin by listening in to interviews with the best and brightest. It’s a very special episode today with Jack Dorsey, CEO of Twitter and Square, and also Elizabeth Stark, CEO of Lightning Labs.
Stephan Livera: I’ve been very impressed with Jack’s commentary on Bitcoin as potentially the native currency of the internet, and the way he’s been managing Square and one of Square’s products in particular, the Cash App, which allows for Bitcoin purchases and sales.</description></item><item><title>Interview Adam Back Elizabeth Stark</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/interview-adam-back-elizabeth-stark/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/interview-adam-back-elizabeth-stark/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005842855271784449
stark: Thank you Giacomo. Who here had too much fun at the party last night? My voice is going. Hopefully it will stay for this interview. We are lucky to have Adam Back here today, co-founder of Blockstream and inventor of Hashcash (history). He just happened to appear and there was an available spot. Thank you for making this work.
adam3us: Thank you for inviting me.
stark: I&amp;rsquo;m a co-organizer of this event.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Regulation Landscape</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/bitcoin-regulation-landscape/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/bitcoin-regulation-landscape/</guid><description>Elizabeth Stark Jerry Brito Constance Choi Christian Catalini (moderator) MIT Compton Labs - Building 26, room 100
http://mitbitcoinexpo.org/
Okay guys, we are getting close to the time for the next panel. Head back to your seats. You may bring food in with you. We also started 15 minutes late. People have 15 minutes .. we ended lunch on time. One of our speakers literally only came for 30 minutes today, 2 to 230.</description></item><item><title>Day 1 Closing Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/day-1-closing-panel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/day-1-closing-panel/</guid><description>Closing panel
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043517333640241152
RS: Thanks guys for joining the panel. We just need to get one more chair. I am going to introduce Alex Petrov here because everyone else was on stage. The closing panel is going to be an overview of what&amp;rsquo;s happening in bitcoin. I want to start with the question I started with last year. What is the current state of bitcoin compared to last year? What has happened?</description></item><item><title>The Future Of Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/the-future-of-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/the-future-of-lightning/</guid><description>The future of lightning
The year of #craeful and the future of lightning
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043501348606693379
It&amp;rsquo;s great to be back here in Riga. Let&amp;rsquo;s give a round of applause to the event organizers and everyone brought us back here. This is the warmest time I&amp;rsquo;ve ever been in Riga. It&amp;rsquo;s been great. I want to come back in the summers.
Introduction I am here to talk about what has happened in the past year and the future of what we&amp;rsquo;re going to see with lightning.</description></item></channel></rss>