<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Aviv Zohar on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/aviv-zohar/</link><description>Recent content in Aviv Zohar on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/aviv-zohar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ghostdag</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/ghostdag/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/ghostdag/</guid><description>The GHOSTDAG protocol
Yonatan Sompolinsky and Aviv Zohar (The Hebrew University of Jerusalem)
paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/104.pdf
Introduction This is joint work with Yonatan. I am going to talk about a DAG-based protocol to scale on-chain. The reason why I like this protocol is because it&amp;rsquo;s a very simple generalization of the longest-chain protocol that we all know and love. It gives some insight into what the role of proof-of-work is in these protocols.</description></item><item><title>How To Charge Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/how-to-charge-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/how-to-charge-lightning/</guid><description>Our next talk is getting into layer 2. Leaving what needs to done at th&amp;hellip;
I am going to start with maybe a simple beginning talking about a single channel between Alice and Bob. We heard about channels yesterday so I am not going to go into details. Alice is not going to cheat Bob in my scenario. Everything is going to run as if everyone honest and doing their best effort, for my example.</description></item><item><title>Introduction (2019)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/introduction/</guid><description>Introduction to DFA Workshop
We are an international conference that focuses on the latest development in software and its scalability in the bitcoin ecosystem. We have come here to Israel. We are running 5 days of events, including this current workshop. Over the next 4 days following today, we&amp;rsquo;re running Bitcoin Edge Dev++ workshop at Tel Aviv University for 2 days, and then Scaling Bitcoin for 2 days which is compromised of over 44 high tech sessions on complex scalability and security related topics in the bitcoin ecosystem, mainly for developers.</description></item></channel></rss>