<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Contract Protocols on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/contract-protocols/</link><description>Recent content in Contract Protocols on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/contract-protocols/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Developing secure Bitcoin contracts using BitML</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/bitml/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/bitml/</guid><description>paper: https://arxiv.org/abs/1905.07639
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171695588116746240
This is shared work with my collaborators and coauthors.
Smart contracts I am sure everyone here knows what a smart contract is. It&amp;rsquo;s a program that can move cryptoassets. It&amp;rsquo;s executed in a decentralized environment. Generally speaking, we can say there&amp;rsquo;s two classes of smart contracts. A smart contract is a program. While in blockchain like bitcoin, smart contracts are cryptographic protocols. This effects how we can reason about a blockchain; bitcoin has many more security proofs for script than ethereum.</description></item><item><title>Taproot, Schnorr signatures, and SIGHASH_NOINPUT</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2018-07-09-taproot-schnorr-signatures-and-sighash-noinput-oh-my/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2018-07-09-taproot-schnorr-signatures-and-sighash-noinput-oh-my/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1021880538020368385
slides: https://prezi.com/view/YkJwE7LYJzAzJw9g1bWV/
Introduction I am Pieter Wuille. I will just dive in. Today I want to talk about improvements to the bitcoin scripting language. There is feedback in the microphone. Okay.
I will mostly be talking about improvements to the bitcoin scripting language. This is by no means an exhaustive list of all the things that are going on. It&amp;rsquo;s more my personal focus in the things that I am interested in and excited about seeing happen.</description></item><item><title>Taproot, Graftroot, Etc</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-03/2018-03-06-taproot-graftroot-etc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-03/2018-03-06-taproot-graftroot-etc/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/972468121046061056
Graftroot The idea of graftroot is that in every contract there is a superset of people that can spend the money. This assumption is not always true but it&amp;rsquo;s almost always true. Say you want to lock up these coins for a year, without any conditionals to it, then it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. But assume you have&amp;ndash; pubkey recovery? No&amp;hellip; pubkey recovery is inherently incompatible with any form of aggregation, and aggregation is far superior.</description></item><item><title>Scalable Smart Contracts Via Proofs And Single Use Seals</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/scalable-smart-contracts-via-proofs-and-single-use-seals/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/scalable-smart-contracts-via-proofs-and-single-use-seals/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/957660108137418752
slides: https://cyber.stanford.edu/sites/default/files/petertodd.pdf
https://petertodd.org/2016/commitments-and-single-use-seals
https://petertodd.org/2016/closed-seal-sets-and-truth-lists-for-privacy
Introduction I am petertodd and I am here to break your blockchain. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of interesting following a talk like that, in some ways I&amp;rsquo;m going in a more extreme direcion for consensus. Do we actually need consensus at all? Can we make a more robust system by eliminating it to the maximum extent possible? I think for some use case at least I have some techniques that will let you go do this.</description></item><item><title>Ivy: A Declarative Predicate Language for Smart Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/2017-01-26-dan-robinson-ivy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/2017-01-26-dan-robinson-ivy/</guid><description>Intro Hi I’m Dan Robinson, I’m one of the Product Architects at Chain which is an enterprise blockchain infrastructure company for financial institutions. We have a full stack blockchain protocol and what I am going to talk about is part of that that also can be used for other applications including as I am going to demo here, make it easier to write scripts for Bitcoin Script.
Introduction: Two Blockchain Models To start out I want to talk about two blockchain models.</description></item><item><title>Privacy-Preserving Smart Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/privacy-preserving-smart-contracts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/privacy-preserving-smart-contracts/</guid><description>ranjit@csail.mit.edu
http://people.csail.mit.edu/ranjit/
We have been looking at how much we can support or what limitations we might encounter. There are also efficiency issues and privacy guarantees. And then there are some potential relaxations that will help with removing the fundamental limitations and express the power and make smart contracts more useful.
The point of this talk is off-chain transactions and secure computation. I will also highlight the relationship of secure computation and bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Formal verification: the road to complete security of smart contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/formal-verification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/formal-verification/</guid><description>slides: https://twitter.com/MartinLundfall/status/1091119463276064769
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1091103595016085504
Introduction Thank you everyone. It&amp;rsquo;s exciting to be here speaking about formal verification. The road to complete security of smart contracts is a sensationalist title. I&amp;rsquo;ll be spending a few moments making a huge disclaimer.
Disclaimer This can only be interpreted as a very long road or a very narrow sense in which complete security is actually cheap. There&amp;rsquo;s still a sense of completeness, which is one of the aspects I want to focus on in this talk.</description></item><item><title>Improving Bitcoin Smart Contract Efficiency</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2018/improving-bitcoin-smart-contract-efficiency/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2018/improving-bitcoin-smart-contract-efficiency/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/980545280973201410
Introduction I will be talking about discreet log contracts, taproot, and graftroot. Not in that order, the order will actually be taproot, graftroot, and then discreet log contracts.
Quick intro: I&amp;rsquo;m Tadge Dryja. I work here at MIT down the street at Digital Currency Initiative. I was coauthor on the lightning network paper, and I worked on lightning. I also was the author of a paper introducing discreet log contracts.</description></item><item><title>Present And Future Tech Challenges In Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/present-and-future-tech-challenges-in-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/present-and-future-tech-challenges-in-bitcoin/</guid><description>1 on 1: Present and future tech challenges in bitcoin
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043484879210668032
PR: Hi everybody. I think I have the great fortune to moderate this panel in the sense that we have really great questions thought by the organizers. Essentially we want to ask Adam and Peter what are their thoughts on the current and the future tech challenges for bitcoin. I&amp;rsquo;m just going to start with that question, starting with Peter.</description></item><item><title>Self Reproducing Coins As Universal Turing Machine</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/self-reproducing-coins-as-universal-turing-machine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/self-reproducing-coins-as-universal-turing-machine/</guid><description>paper: https://arxiv.org/abs/1806.10116
Introduction This is joint work with my colleagues. I am Alexander Chepurnoy. We work for Ergo Platform. Vasily is an external member. This talk is about turing completeness in the blockchain. This talk will be pretty high-level. This talk is based on already-published paper, which was presented at the CBT conference. Because of copyright agreements with Springer, you will not find the latest version on arxiv.
The general question of scalability is how can we do more with less until we can do everything with nothing?</description></item><item><title>Step by Step Towards Writing a Safe Contract: Insights from an Undergraduate Ethereum Lab</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/andrew-miller/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/andrew-miller/</guid><description>Next up I want to introduce Elaine Shi and Andrew Miller from University of Maryland. Andrew is also on the zerocash team.
Okay. I am an assistant professor at the University of Maryland. We all believe that cryptocurrency is the way of the future and smart contracts. So students in the future have to program smart contracts.
So that&amp;rsquo;s what I did. I asked some students to program some smart contracts.</description></item><item><title>The Future Of Bitcoin Smart Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/the-future-of-bitcoin-smart-contracts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/the-future-of-bitcoin-smart-contracts/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043419056492228608
Hey guys, next talk in 5 minutes. In five minutes.
Introduction Hello everyone. If you&amp;rsquo;re walking, please do it in silence. I am a bit nervous. I was too busy organizing this conference and didn&amp;rsquo;t get time for this talk. If you had high expectatoins for this presentation, then please lower them for the next 20 minutes. I was going to talk about the traditional VC models and why it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work in the bitcoin industry.</description></item></channel></rss>