<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ethan Heilman on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/ethan-heilman/</link><description>Recent content in Ethan Heilman on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/ethan-heilman/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Network Partitioning Attacks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-12-ethan-heilman-network-partitioning-attacks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-12-ethan-heilman-network-partitioning-attacks/</guid><description>Bitcoin network partitioning &amp;amp; network-level privacy attacks
Location: Chaincode Labs 2019 Residency
Slides: https://residency.chaincode.com/presentations/bitcoin/ethan_heilman_p2p.pdf
Eclipse attack paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2015/263.pdf
Bitcoin’s P2P Network Please interrupt me. I&amp;rsquo;m going to go through this stuff a little bit quickly because I hear that you&amp;rsquo;ve already read Eclipse attack paper and you&amp;rsquo;ve already looked at some of the peer to peer stuff.
Bitcoin uses a peer-to-peer network to announce transactions and blocks. It makes 8 outgoing connections.</description></item><item><title>Cross-Chain Swaps</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/cross-chain-swaps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/cross-chain-swaps/</guid><description>Ethan and Nicolas describe atomic cross-chain swaps - a protocol where two parties can exchange coins as a single operation. The exchange does not require any trusted third party and neither of the parties involved can cheat each other. They describe how this can be used on a single blockchain as a privacy protocol or “cross-chain” as a trading protocol.</description></item><item><title>Blind Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/blind-signatures/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/blind-signatures/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1047648050234060800
See also http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/building-on-bitcoin/2018/blind-signatures-and-scriptless-scripts/
Introduction Hi everyone. I work at Commonwealth Crypto. Today I am going to be talking to you about blind signatures. I&amp;rsquo;d like to encourage people to ask questions. Please think of questions. I&amp;rsquo;ll give time and pause for people to ask questions.
What are blind signatures? A very informal definition of blind signatures is that they are a signature scheme that allows one party to sign a message without learning the message they signed.</description></item><item><title>Atomically Trading With Roger Gambling On The Success Of A Hard Fork</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/atomically-trading-with-roger-gambling-on-the-success-of-a-hard-fork/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/atomically-trading-with-roger-gambling-on-the-success-of-a-hard-fork/</guid><description>Atomically Trading with Roger: Gambling on the success of a hard-fork
paper: http://homepages.cs.ncl.ac.uk/patrick.mc-corry/atomically-trading-roger.pdf
This is joint work with Patrick McCorry, Andrew Miller and myslef. Patrick was originally going to give this talk but he was unable to make it. I&amp;rsquo;ll give the talk with his slides. I want to acknowledge Roger Ver for permission to use his name in the title of the talk. We asked permission.
I will only be talking about some of the information in the paper.</description></item><item><title>Near Misses</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/near-misses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/near-misses/</guid><description>Near misses: What could have gone wrong
Introduction Thank you. I am Ethan Heilman. I am a research whose has done a bunch of work in security of cryptocurrencies. I am also CTO of Arwen which does secure atomic swaps. I am a little sick today so please excuse my coughing, wheezing and drinking lots of water.
Bitcoin scary stories The general outline of this talk is going to be &amp;ldquo;scary stories in bitcoin&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Tumblebit</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/tumblebit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/tumblebit/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784686167052709888
Hi. So I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking about tumblebit. It&amp;rsquo;s our untrusted private bitcoin payment system. Tumblebit provides payments which are private. They provide set anonymity when used as a classic tumbler. They are untrusted. The tumbler can&amp;rsquo;t violate your privacy, and can&amp;rsquo;t steal your coins. It&amp;rsquo;s also scalable. It&amp;rsquo;s compatible and works with today&amp;rsquo;s bitcoin. There are no malleability concerns. We&amp;rsquo;re going to rely on the constrained opcodes that currently exist in bitcoin.</description></item></channel></rss>