<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Josibake on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/josibake/</link><description>Recent content in Josibake on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/josibake/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Newsletter #292 Recap</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinops/newsletter-292-recap/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinops/newsletter-292-recap/</guid><description>Mark Erhardt: 00:03:57
We are complete. Maybe we can start. So good morning. This is Optech Newsletter #292 Recap. And as you can hear, Mike is not here today and I&amp;rsquo;m filling in as the main host. Today we have four news items, two releases and release candidates, and four PRs to talk about in our notable code and documentation changes. I&amp;rsquo;m Merch and I work at Chaincode Labs and bring you weekly this OpTec newsletter recap.</description></item><item><title>Silent Payments</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-design/learning-bitcoin-and-design/silent-payments/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-design/learning-bitcoin-and-design/silent-payments/</guid><description>Josi gave us a great introduction to silent payments in this conversation. We talked about the history of similar efforts, benefits and drawbacks, how it works, status of the project, adoption path, and lots more.</description></item><item><title>Silent Payments</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2023-04/2023-04-26-silent-payments/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2023-04/2023-04-26-silent-payments/</guid><description>BIP Overview Scanning key and spending key are different: better security. Silent payment transactions are indistinguishable from transactions with taproot outputs on-chain.
Q: Address labeling, why not create two silent payment addresses?
A: It doubles scanning costs.
Limited to taproot UTXOs (currently about 3% of transactions) but when it increases we should find ways to optimize scanning, even though it currently does not seem to be an issue.
Q: Why no P2PK</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Developer Education Overview</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2023-01-18-josibake/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2023-01-18-josibake/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/450/
Josi, welcome to the show.
Josibake – 00:02:32:
Thanks for having me.
Stephan- 00:02:33:
So, Josi, I know you were keen to chat about I know you’ve been doing a bit of work in the bitcoin development world, doing some mentoring as well, and keen to chat a bit about the process of Bitcoin developer education. Why is it important, all of that. But let’s first start with a little bit about you.</description></item><item><title>The Bitcoin Core wallet and wrangling bitcoin data</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/the-bitcoin-core-wallet-and-wrangling-bitcoin-data/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/the-bitcoin-core-wallet-and-wrangling-bitcoin-data/</guid><description>In this conversation, Adam Jonas and Mark Erhardt discuss their work with Josie Baker on Bitcoin data analysis, focusing on mempool data collection and Bitcoin Core wallet improvements. Josie explains his work in standardizing and cleaning mempool data to create a comprehensive, open-source dataset. This dataset will facilitate research and development in areas such as fee estimation and transaction propagation. They also delve into Bitcoin Core wallet enhancements, including privacy improvements and efficient coin selection methods. The conversation highlights the importance of reproducibility, empirical analysis, and open-source collaboration in advancing Bitcoin technology. Josie’s efforts emphasize the value of making Bitcoin data accessible and fostering a community of contributors in the Bitcoin development ecosystem.</description></item></channel></rss>