<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Oliver Gugger on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/oliver-gugger/</link><description>Recent content in Oliver Gugger on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/oliver-gugger/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lightning Network Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2022-03-01-lightning-panel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2022-03-01-lightning-panel/</guid><description>Topic: The Lightning Network in 2022
Location: London Bitcoin Devs
Introductions Ali Taylor-Cipolla (ATC): Ali coming in from Coinbase Recruiting. I’d like to introduce to my friend Tiago who is on the Europe side.
Tiago Schmidt (TS): Hello everyone. Quick introduction, sitting in the recruiting team here in London and leading the expansion for engineering hiring across UK and Ireland. Coinbase is in hyper-growth at the moment and we will be looking to hire loads of the people.</description></item><item><title>Oliver Gugger, LSAT</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/vr-bitcoin/2020-05-16-oliver-gugger-lsat/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/vr-bitcoin/2020-05-16-oliver-gugger-lsat/</guid><description>Topic: LSAT - Your Ticket Aboard The Lightning Native Web
Location: Reckless VR
Intro Happy to be here to talk about LSAT, let’s jump right in. We are going to have a look at LSAT. What the motivation was to come up with this? What the use cases for and we are going to jump into the technical detail. This is going to be a technical talk. There will be some low level details.</description></item><item><title>Laolu, Joost, Oliver - Lnd0.10</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/vr-bitcoin/2020-04-18-laolu-joost-oliver-lnd0.10/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/vr-bitcoin/2020-04-18-laolu-joost-oliver-lnd0.10/</guid><description>Topic: lnd v0.10
Location: Virtual Reality (VR Bitcoin)
Intro (Laolu Osuntokun) Thanks everyone for coming. This is my first time doing a VR presentation, really cool. I am going to be talking about lnd 0.10. Right now we are on rc2, the next major lnd release, it has a bunch of cool features, bug fixes, optimizations. I am going to talk about some big ticket features in 0.10. There are a bunch of other features that you are going to want to check out in the release notes.</description></item></channel></rss>