<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Montreal (2015) on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/</link><description>Recent content in Montreal (2015) on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Alternatives To Block Size As Aggregate Resource Limits</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/alternatives-to-block-size-as-aggregate-resource-limits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/alternatives-to-block-size-as-aggregate-resource-limits/</guid><description>I am talking about block size, but not any particular proposal. Why do we have the block size limit and is it a good thing in the first place? The block size exists as a denial-of-service limiter. It limits the amount of resources that a node validating the blockchain can exhaust when validating a block. We want to do this because in the early days of bitcoin there are often certain kinds of transactions there are ways to slow down a validator by using a non-standard transaction or filling up a block with tons of spam.</description></item><item><title>Amiko Pay</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/amiko-pay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/amiko-pay/</guid><description>Amiko Pay aims to become an implementation of the lightning network. So that previous presentation was a great setup. There&amp;rsquo;s a little bit more to Amiko Pay. If you look through the basic design of the lightning network, there&amp;rsquo;s a network of payment channels. There have been several variations of this idea. Lightning Network happens to be the best so far. What Amiko Pay aims to do is to focus on the nodes, and do the routing between nodes.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Block Propagation and IBLT</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/bitcoin-block-propagation-iblt-rusty-russell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/bitcoin-block-propagation-iblt-rusty-russell/</guid><description>This is not what I do. But I was doing it anyway.
The problem is that blocks are transmitted in their entirety. If you have a 1 MB uplink and you&amp;rsquo;re connecting to 8 peers, your first peer will see a 1MB block in about 66.8 seconds. And the last one will get it in 76.4 seconds, because we basically blast out blocks in parallel to our peers. Miners can solve this problem of slow block transmission by centralizing and all using the same pool.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Failure Modes And The Role Of The Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/bitcoin-failure-modes-and-the-role-of-the-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/bitcoin-failure-modes-and-the-role-of-the-lightning-network/</guid><description>I am going to be talking about bitcoin failure modes, and Joseph will talk about how the lightning network can help. I&amp;rsquo;ll start. We&amp;rsquo;ll start off by saying that bitcoin is working, which is really cool. Blocks starts with lots of zeroes, coins stay put, they move when you tell them to. That&amp;rsquo;s really cool and it works. That&amp;rsquo;s great. This is a good starting place. We should acknowledge that bitcoin can fail.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Load Spike Simulation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/bitcoin-load-spike-simulation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/bitcoin-load-spike-simulation/</guid><description>Our goal for this project, our rationale of what we&amp;rsquo;re interesting is when many transactions arrive in a short period of time. This could be because of denial of service attacks where few entities are creating a large number of transactions, or many people wanting to create transactions, like a shopping spree. We wanted to answer two questions, how does the temporary spike in transaction rate affect confirmation delay distribution? For a given spike shape, can we change the block size and how would that effect the evolution of the system?</description></item><item><title>Block Synchronization Time</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/block-synchronization-time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/block-synchronization-time/</guid><description>Initial Block Synchronization Time Complexity
slides: http://strateman.ninja/initial_block_synchronization.pdf
Block synchronization is how nodes join the market. New nodes download the blockchain and validate everything. This is how the security of the network works. Who is responsible for doing this? Everyone must be doing a full block synchronization. If you are not doing this, you&amp;rsquo;re not on the bitcoin network. As a simple hypothesis, the block size growth is related to initial block synchronization as a simple function of the integral.</description></item><item><title>Blockchain Testbed</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/blockchain-testbed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/blockchain-testbed/</guid><description>A testbed for bitcoin scaling
I want to talk today about how to scale bitcoin. We want lower latency, we want higher throughput, more bandwidth and more transactions per second, and we want security. We can try to tune the parameters. In all of the plots, I have time going from left to right and these are blocks in rectangles. We have larger blocks which might give us more throughput. We could have shorter block length, and transactions would come faster on the chain and we have better throughput but we get forks and orphans when that happens.</description></item><item><title>Coinscope</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/coinscope-andrew-miller/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/coinscope-andrew-miller/</guid><description>http://cs.umd.edu/projects/coinscope/
I am going to talk about a pair of tools, one is a simulator and another one is a measurement station for the bitcoin network. So let me start with the bitcoin simulator framework. The easiest approach is to create a customized model that is a simplified abstraction of what you care about- which is like simbit, to show off how selfish-mining works. What you put in is what you get, so the model is actually different from the actual behavior of the bitcoin network means that you don&amp;rsquo;t learn anything really.</description></item><item><title>Competitive Fee Market Urgency</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/competitive-fee-market-urgency/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/competitive-fee-market-urgency/</guid><description>The urgency of a competitive fee market to ensure a scalable future
I am Marshall. I run Firehash. CTO Cryptsy also. Some people have higher cost, some people have lower cost. I think those were some good estimates for true costs. I am going to be talking about why fees are going to be very important very soon. We&amp;rsquo;ll talk about what happens without fees, talk about why bitcoin really isn&amp;rsquo;t free but how we can do things like microtransactions, real microtransactions, talk about the cost and talk about solutions.</description></item><item><title>Fee markets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/peter-r/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/peter-r/</guid><description>((Note that there is a more accurate transcript from Peter-R himself below.))
Miners have another job as well. Miners are commodity producers, they produce something that the world has never seen. They produce block space, which is room for transactional debt. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore what the field of economics tells us. We&amp;rsquo;ll plot the total number of bytes per block. On the vertical we will plot the unit cost of the commodity, or the price of 1 transaction worth of blockspace.</description></item><item><title>Future Of Spv Tech</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/future-of-spv-tech/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/future-of-spv-tech/</guid><description>https://docs.google.com/document/d/1t0bSZj5b66xBdW7xrjHlcvfqYAbTaQDB4-_T0Jvs3T4/edit#heading=h.5lm45oa6kuri
issues with current SPV wallets
Existing clients and their status
bitcoinj electrum ** they are doing SPV proofs ** bloom filters utxo commitments need to get in need to pick which type of utxo commitments
Number of nodes to connect to for more SPV clients
1 header from each peer to verify that we are all getting the same thing what block does each peer think is the best? very cheap to poll a huge number of peers</description></item><item><title>How To Mine Bitcoin Profitably</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/how-to-mine-bitcoin-profitably/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/how-to-mine-bitcoin-profitably/</guid><description>How to mine bitcoin profitability
Minting money with megawatts
Thank you for the introduction. We thought bitcoin was really a good idea for an unstable and inefficient financial world. I am going to dive and talk about this presentation which is how to mine bitcoin profitably. This is a short talk, it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be a short talk, so let&amp;rsquo;s get straight to the crux of the matter.
Bitcoin mining is the lowest part of the transaction stack.</description></item><item><title>Issues Impacting Block Size Proposals</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/issues-impacting-block-size-proposals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/issues-impacting-block-size-proposals/</guid><description>Issues impacting block size proposals
Jeff Garzik (jgarzik)
Bitcoin was introduced as a p2p electronic cash system. That&amp;rsquo;s what it says in the whitepaper. That&amp;rsquo;s what the users were exposed to. The 1 MB block size was set for anti-spam purposes. Otherwise when bitcoin value is low, it&amp;rsquo;s trivial to DOS the network with large blocks.
Moving on to some observations. The process of finding distributed ocnsensus takes time; it&amp;rsquo;s a settlement system.</description></item><item><title>More Core Devs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/more-core-devs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/more-core-devs/</guid><description>10x the number of core devs
Objectives:
10x would only be like &amp;lt;1000 bitcoin developers 7000 fedora developers how do we grow developers? how many tor developers? how many linux developers?
poaching from each other is not cool
There&amp;rsquo;s not enough people with the necessary skills. There&amp;rsquo;s no clear way to train new people. Apprenticeship works, but it scales very very poorly. It&amp;rsquo;s better than a static fixed number of developers.</description></item><item><title>Non Currency Applications</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/non-currency-applications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/non-currency-applications/</guid><description>Scalability of non-currency applications
I am from Princeton University. I am here to talk about the scalability issues that non-currency applications of bitcoin have that might be a little different than regular payments that go through the bitcoin network. I put this together with my advisor, Arvind. The reason why I want to talk about this is because when people talk about how bitcoin will have to scale is that people throw out a thing about Visa processing 20,000 transactions per second or something.</description></item><item><title>Overview Of Security Concerns</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/overview-of-security-concerns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/overview-of-security-concerns/</guid><description>Overview of Security Concerns
I am going to talk about scale-related security issues. Scale-related security issues. I said scale, not scalability. We are not talking about scalability. We&amp;rsquo;re talking about changing numbers, and what are the implications, what attacks are easier or harder by changing the block size number. What are we trying to accomplish? What is the system meant to be? Nobody really agrees of course. What&amp;rsquo;s interesting is that as much as we disagree about what was meant to be, there are a lot of key things about what bitcoin could be, these visions share some details.</description></item><item><title>Privacy And Fungibility</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/privacy-and-fungibility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/privacy-and-fungibility/</guid><description>Privacy and scalability
Even though Bitcoin is the worst privacy system ever, everyone in the community very strongly values privacy.
There are at least three things: privacy censorship resistance fungibility
The easiest way to censor things is to punish communication, not prevent communication. Privacy is the weakest link in censorship resistance. Fungibility is an absolute necessity for any medium of exchange. The properties of money include fungibility. Without privacy you may not be able to have fungibility.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Preserving Smart Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/privacy-preserving-smart-contracts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/privacy-preserving-smart-contracts/</guid><description>ranjit@csail.mit.edu
http://people.csail.mit.edu/ranjit/
We have been looking at how much we can support or what limitations we might encounter. There are also efficiency issues and privacy guarantees. And then there are some potential relaxations that will help with removing the fundamental limitations and express the power and make smart contracts more useful.
The point of this talk is off-chain transactions and secure computation. I will also highlight the relationship of secure computation and bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Relay Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/relay-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/relay-network/</guid><description>It was indicative of two issues. A lot of people were reducing their security model by not validating their bitcoin. It was potentially less secure. That&amp;rsquo;s not something that relay networks try to address. The big issue with the decreasing number of nodes, which the relay network doesn&amp;rsquo;t address, is that it reduces the resilience against attack. If there&amp;rsquo;s only 100 nodes, there&amp;rsquo;s really only some 100 VPses that you have to knock offline before the bitcoin network stops working.</description></item><item><title>Reworking Bitcoin Core P2P Code For Robustness And Event Driven</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/reworking-bitcoin-core-p2p-code-for-robustness-and-event-driven/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/reworking-bitcoin-core-p2p-code-for-robustness-and-event-driven/</guid><description>That is me. I want to apologize right off. I am here to talk about reworking Bitcoin Core p2p code. This is a Bitcoin Core specific topic. I have been working on some software for the past few weeks to talk about working things rather than theory. The presentation is going to suffer because of this.
Bitcoin Core has a networking stack that dates back all the way to the initial implementation from Satoshi or at least it&amp;rsquo;s been patched and hacked on ever since.</description></item><item><title>Roundgroup Roundup 1</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/roundgroup-roundup-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/roundgroup-roundup-1/</guid><description>Roundtable roundup review 1
Future of SPV Technology So hopefully I summarized this reasonably. There were a number of things that came up in our discussion. It would help SPV a lot if there were UTXO commitments in blocks. This can be done with a soft-fork. It has implementation cost difficulties. There are some ugly things you could do about how the trees are formed, so that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to repopulate the whole thing every single block.</description></item><item><title>Roundgroup Roundup 2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/roundgroup-roundup-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/roundgroup-roundup-2/</guid><description>Communicating without official structures Roundgroup roundup day 2
Hi guys, okay I am going to try to find my voice here. I am losing it. I ran the session on communication without official structures. We went through the various channels through which people are communicating in this community like forums, blogs, irc, reddit, twitter, email, and we talked a little about them each. There&amp;rsquo;s also the conferences and meetings. There are different forms of communication in text than in person.</description></item><item><title>Security Of Diminishing Block Subsidy</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/security-of-diminishing-block-subsidy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/security-of-diminishing-block-subsidy/</guid><description>Miners no longer incentivized to mine all the time. The future of mining hardware. Impact on the bitcoin ecosystem. Implications and assumptions of the model.
Are minting rewards and transaction fees the same? Transaction fees are time-dependent. A miner can only claim transaction fees as transactions are added to their block. As transaction fees start to dominate the block reward, they become time-dependent. We are modeling this block reward as a linear function of time, we have this factor B which might be initial minting reward, and we have some scaling factor, the block reward is like &amp;ldquo;b + at&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Sharding The Blockchain</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/sharding-the-blockchain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/sharding-the-blockchain/</guid><description>I am going to talk about blockchain sharding. This is one of the scaling solutions that I like the most. I have done the most work on it. In case you don&amp;rsquo;t know who I am, I am a researcher mostly with the ethereum project. Basically the basics of sharding is that in non-sharding, every node does every validation. In a sharding solution, nodes hold a subset of the state, and a subset of the blockchain.</description></item><item><title>Snarks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/snarks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/snarks/</guid><description>some setup motivating topics:
practicality pcp theorem trustless setup magic away the trusted setup schemes without trusted setup pcp theorem is the existent proof that the spherical cow exists. people:
Andrew Miller (AM) Madars Virza (MV) Andrew Poelstra (AP) Bryan Bishop (BB) Nathan Wilcox ZZZZZ: zooko gmaxwell&amp;rsquo;s ghost (only in spirit) SNARKs always require some sort of setup. PCP-based SNARKs can use random oracle assumption instantiated by hash function, sha256 acts as the random oracle.</description></item><item><title>Stroem Payment Channels</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/stroem-payment-channels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/stroem-payment-channels/</guid><description>Stroem
Jarl Fransson (Strawpay)
7 transactions per second, or is it 3? That&amp;rsquo;s about what we can do with bitcoin. What if you need 100,000 transactions per second? I come from Strawpay, we&amp;rsquo;ve been looking into bitcoin for a long time. When we learned about scripting and the power of contracts, like payment channels, we thought maybe it&amp;rsquo;s time to do micropayments and microtransactions. To give you some perspective on scale, let&amp;rsquo;s say that 1 billion people make 25 transactions per day.</description></item><item><title>Systematizing Knowledge</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/systematizing-knowledge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/systematizing-knowledge/</guid><description>There should be a SNARK wiki. Any website that is better than someone saying &amp;ldquo;you know, check the June July 2014 bitcoin-wizard logs&amp;rdquo;. We need to research gmaxwell scalability. We should probably fix that.
Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about what some of the goals are that we might get out of this. We have some different ideas for approaches to systematizing knowledge. There are at least three camps here. I think Bryan&amp;rsquo;s paper repositories.</description></item><item><title>Transaction Fee Estimation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/transaction-fee-estimation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/transaction-fee-estimation/</guid><description>How wallets can handle real transaction fees
You should have a market at this point, where some number of transactions never happen because they aren&amp;rsquo;t willing to pay a fee. So you get some equilibrium of price going on. I proactively want to see this happen because we don&amp;rsquo;t know what fees should be until we run the experiment and see what prices end up being. For this to happen, wallets have to do price setting in some way.</description></item><item><title>Validation Costs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/validation-costs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/validation-costs/</guid><description>Validation costs and incentives
How many of you have read the Satoshi whitepaper? It&amp;rsquo;s a good paper. As we have discovered, it has some serious limitations that we think can be fixed but they are serious challenges for scaling. Amongst these are, it was really built as a single code base which was meant to be run in its entirety. All machines were going to participate equally in this p2p network.</description></item></channel></rss>