<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pierre Rochard on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/pierre-rochard/</link><description>Recent content in Pierre Rochard on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/pierre-rochard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Excel In Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2018-10-27-pierre-rochard-excel-in-lightning/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2018-10-27-pierre-rochard-excel-in-lightning/</guid><description>Excel in Lightning - Lightning Hack Day NYC
Demo I want to present a project I’ve been hacking on for the past month which is getting lnd inside of Excel. I’ll explain why someone would ever do that. I want to bring Lightning to the most popular business platform in existence today which is Microsoft Office Excel. It’s installed on hundreds of millions of computers around the world. It is used day-to-day by all sorts of business people who are doing adhoc data analysis.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Excel Plugin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-26-pierre-rochard-lightning-excel-plugin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2018-10-26-pierre-rochard-lightning-excel-plugin/</guid><description>Demo My project is to create a user interface for lightning that might appeal to a different crowd than ours. We’re kind of used to Linux, open source, free software so being in a proprietary environment like Excel is unfamiliar territory for us. And yet I think that there is a large demographic of people who are interested in Bitcoin who work in the business world where they use Excel day to day.</description></item><item><title>Accumulating Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/accumulating-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/accumulating-bitcoin/</guid><description>Accumulating bitcoin
Introduction Today I am going to be preaching to the choir I think. Hopefully I will be reiterating and reinforcing some points that you already know but maybe forgot to bring up with your nocoiner friends, or learning something new. I hope there&amp;rsquo;s something for everyone in here.
Q: Should I buy bitcoin?
A: Yes.
Q: Are you going to troll a journalist?
A: Today? Already done.
Misconceptions One of the biggest misconceptions I heard when I first learned about bitcoin was that bitcoin was just a payments system.</description></item></channel></rss>