<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Justin Moon on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/justin-moon/</link><description>Recent content in Justin Moon on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/justin-moon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Q A</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/dallas-bitcoin-symposium/q-a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/dallas-bitcoin-symposium/q-a/</guid><description>Q&amp;amp;A session
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1162436437687623684
MB: I have a podcast called Tales from the Crypt where I interview people working on and around bitcoin. I have spoken to many of these gentlemen on the podcast as well. I want to focus on, many of these presentations were focused on history and prehistory of bitcoin. For this Q&amp;amp;A session, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the future of the bitcoin standard. Michael, I want you to talk about the future of the bitcoin standard on a sound money point standpoint, like not having to chase for a store of value like houses.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Developers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/dallas-bitcoin-symposium/bitcoin-developers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/dallas-bitcoin-symposium/bitcoin-developers/</guid><description>Introduction I am going to talk about a programmer&amp;rsquo;s perspective. As investors, you might find this interesting, but at the same time it&amp;rsquo;s not entirely actionable. As a programmer, the bitcoin ecosystem is very attractive. This is true of cryptocurrencies in general. I&amp;rsquo;ll make a distinction for bitcoin at the end. One of the interesting things is that you see some of the most talented hackers in the world are extremely attracted to bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>State Of Multisig</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/state-of-multisig/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/state-of-multisig/</guid><description>State of multisig for bitcoin hodlers: Better wallets with PSBT
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1162769521993834496
Introduction I am going to be talking about the state of multisig. It&amp;rsquo;s a way of creating a transaction output that requires multiple keys to sign. This is a focus for people holding bitcoin. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about some of the benefits and some of the issues. I am not a security expert, though.
Perspective Multisig is an emphasis on saving and not spending a lot.</description></item></channel></rss>