<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Building On Bitcoin 2018 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/</link><description>Recent content in Building On Bitcoin 2018 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ant routing for the Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/lightning-routing-ants-pheromones/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/lightning-routing-ants-pheromones/</guid><description>Building on Bitcoin 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014530761398145025
https://twitter.com/rperezmarco/status/1013938984718884866
Introduction I wanted to present some ideas for alternative ideas for routing on LN. This was published on arxiv: 1807.00151 (July 2018).
http://webusers.imj-prg.fr/~ricardo.perez-marco
Overview I am going to talk about what I understand to be decentralized network. Fabrice has already explained most of what is LN about and some history about it. I will just recall a few properties that I need in order to address the mathematical problem of routing.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Assets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/bitcoin-assets/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/bitcoin-assets/</guid><description>Assets on bitcoin
Building on Bitcoin 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014483345026289664
Good morning everybody. In the mean time, while my presentation loads, I am Giacomo Zucco. I am the founder of BHB network and a consulting company. We do bitcoin consulting for institutional customers especially in Switzerland. We also like development on top of bitcoin and things like that.
My talk today is about assets on bitcoin. The subtitlte is &amp;ldquo;Yes, ok, financial sovereignity and cryptoanarchy are cool, but what about those cryptokitties?</description></item><item><title>Bootstrapping Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/bootstrapping-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/bootstrapping-lightning-network/</guid><description>Bootstrapping LN: What have we learned?
Building on Bitcoin 2018
acinq
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014531050503065601
My name is Fabrice Drouin. I work with ACINQ. We are a comapny working on printing LN. I am going to talk about what happens, what was the process of bootstrapping and developing lightning and what happened on mainnet.
Timeline Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t know what lightning is? And who has used lightning? Okay, almost everyone. It&amp;rsquo;s an evolution on the idea of payment channels.</description></item><item><title>Crypto Castles</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/crypto-castles/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/crypto-castles/</guid><description>Building your own bank and constructing crypto castles
Building on Bitcoin 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014483571946508288
I am going to do a brain dump of basically anything that people who are building systems protecting private keys are thinking about. Hopefully you can ingest this for when you decide to build one of these systems.
If you have been in this space for long at all, you should be well aware that there are risks for trusting third-parties.</description></item><item><title>Libbitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/libbitcoin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/libbitcoin/</guid><description>libbitcoin Building on Bitcoin 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014483126817521665
This is me. When I first suggested giving a talk here on libbitcoin, &amp;hellip;. one of the pieces of feedback I got was that bitcoin is libbitcoin, what are you building on bitcoin? libbitcoin is actually more. I will also talk about what it is going on underneath. It&amp;rsquo;s an implementation of bitcoin as well.
Most of the talks I give are around cryptoeconomics. Up until recently, libbitcoin hasn&amp;rsquo;t been mature enough to go and promote.</description></item><item><title>Anonymous Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/anonymous-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/anonymous-bitcoin/</guid><description>Building on Bitcoin 2018
Anonymous bitcoin
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014128850765303808
https://github.com/zkSNACKs/WalletWasabi
One year ago I was standing here at this conference and Igave a talk. Today I am standing here and I titled my talk &amp;ldquo;Anonymous bitcoin&amp;rdquo;. One year ago at this conference, the conference was named &amp;ldquo;breaking bitcoin&amp;rdquo;. I did not break bitcoin. Someone else did, you might remember.
Today I want to present how I build on bitcoin. I have two goals with this presentation.</description></item><item><title>Binary Transparency</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/binary-transparency/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/binary-transparency/</guid><description>Contours for binary transparency
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014167797205815297
I am going to talk about binary transparency. What is it? Let&amp;rsquo;s suppose that you have an android phone or iphone and you download some software from the app store or Google Play. How do you know that the apk or that software that you&amp;rsquo;re being given is the same piece of software that is being given to everyone else and google or apple hasn&amp;rsquo;t specifically given you a bad version of that software because they were threatened or compelled to do so in a court order or because their keys were compromised?</description></item><item><title>Blind Signatures And Scriptless Scripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/blind-signatures-and-scriptless-scripts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/blind-signatures-and-scriptless-scripts/</guid><description>Blind signatures in scriptless scripts
Building on Bitcoin 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014197255593603072
My name is Jonas. I work at Blockstream as an engineer. I am going to talk about some primitives about blind signatures, scriptless scripts, and blind coin swap, and I will explain how to trustlessly exchange ecash tokens using bitcoin.
I want to introduce the blind Schnorr signature in a few moments.
Schnorr signature My assumption is not that you will completely understand Schnorr signatures, but maybe you will at least agree that if you can understand Schnorr signatures then the step to blind Schnorr signatures is not a big step.</description></item><item><title>Btcpay</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/btcpay/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/btcpay/</guid><description>How to make everyone run their own full node
Building on Bitcoin, 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014166857958461440
I am the maintainer of Nbitcoin and btcpay. I am a dot net fanboy. I am happy that the number of people working on bitcoin in C# has spread from one about four years ago to about ten in this room toay. That&amp;rsquo;s great. I work at DG Lab in Japan.
The goal of my talk is to continue what Jonas Schnelli was talking about.</description></item><item><title>Coinjoinxt</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/coinjoinxt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/coinjoinxt/</guid><description>CoinjoinXT and other techniques for deniable transfers.
Building on Bitcoin 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014197088979226625
https://joinmarket.me/blog/blog/coinjoinxt/
Introduction My talk today is about what I&amp;rsquo;m calling CoinjoinXT which is kind of a new proposal. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t say it&amp;rsquo;s a new technology, but perhaps a new combination of technologies. My name is Adam Gibson. Yes, another Adam, sorry about that. I have been working on privacy tech for the last number of years, mostly on joinmarket.</description></item><item><title>Current And Future State Of Wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/current-and-future-state-of-wallets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/current-and-future-state-of-wallets/</guid><description>Current and future state of wallets
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014127893495021568
Introduction I started to contribute to Bitcoin Core about 5 years ago. Since then, I have managed to get 450 commits merged. I am also the co-founder of a wallet hardware company based in Switzerland called Shift+ Cryptocurrency.
Wallets is not rocket science. It&amp;rsquo;s mostly about pointing the figure to things that we can do better. I prepared a lot of content.
Privacy, security and trust When I look at existing wallets, I see the triangle of privacy, security and trust.</description></item><item><title>Dandelion</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/dandelion/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/dandelion/</guid><description>Dandelion: Privacy-preserving transaction propagation in bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s p2p network
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014196927062249472
Today I will be talking to you about privacy in bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s p2p layer. This was joint work with some talented colleagues.
Bitcoin p2p layer I want to give a brief overview of the p2p layer. Users in bitcoin are connected over a p2p network with tcp links. Users are identified by ip address and port number. Users have a second identity, which is their address or public key or however you want to think about it.</description></item><item><title>Single Use Seals</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/single-use-seals/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/single-use-seals/</guid><description>Single use seals
Building on Bitcoin 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014168068447195136
I am going to talk about single use seals and ways to use them. They are a concept of building consensus applications and things that need consensus. I want to mention why that matters. What problem are we trying to solve? Imagine my cell phone and I open up my banking app or the banking app or lightning app&amp;hellip; I want to make sure that what I see on my screen is the same as what you see on your screen.</description></item><item><title>Tooling</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/tooling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/tooling/</guid><description>Building on Bitcoin 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014167542422822913
What kind of tools do we need to create, in order to facilitate building on bitcoin? We are going to open questions to the floor. The guys will be there to get your questions. The panel will be about 20 minutes long, and then we will go for food.
eric voskuil nicolasdorier kevin loaec lawrence nahum
LN: I work at Blockstream. I work on low-level wallets and tooling for wallets.</description></item><item><title>Working On Scripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/working-on-scripts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/working-on-scripts/</guid><description>Working on scripts with logical opcodes
Building on Bitcoin 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014167120417091584
Bitcoin has logical opcodes in bitcoin script. Depending on whose is trying to spend coins or what information they have, they interact with logical opcodes. We could see a simple example here taken from one of the lightning network commitment transcraction scripts. It pushes a key on to the stack so that a checksig can run later. It adds a relative timelock as well.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Wallet Design</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/lightning-wallet-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/lightning-wallet-design/</guid><description>Designing lightning wallets for the bitcoin user
Building on Bitcoin 2018
Good morning everyone. Thank you for being here. Thank you to the organizers for this event. My talk is about designing lightning wallets for bitcoin users. I am talking about UX. But really, UX is a lot more than what wallets look like. It&amp;rsquo;s from bip39 and making backups much easier, to anything you cna imagine, to make it easier for bitcoin to use bitcoin.</description></item></channel></rss>