<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Splicing on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/splicing/</link><description>Recent content in Splicing on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/splicing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What is splicing?</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/what-is-splicing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/what-is-splicing/</guid><description>Stephan Livera 00:02:14
Dusty welcome to the show hey thanks for having me yeah I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of what you got what you&amp;rsquo;re doing with splicing and obviously it&amp;rsquo;s been great to see you over the years kind of or in and around the Bitcoin and Lightning circles and yeah I love what you&amp;rsquo;re doing with flashing so let&amp;rsquo;s hear a little bit about you just for people who don&amp;rsquo;t know you just a little bit on you</description></item><item><title>Lightning Privacy &amp; Splice Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/lightning-privacy-splice-panel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/lightning-privacy-splice-panel/</guid><description>Housekeeping Speaker 0: 00:01:17
Today we&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking about Lightning privacy, splicing and other very cool things with an absolute amazing panel here. Just before that, I have a couple of things that I want to set out some updates. So OpenSats is now taking grants for a Bitcoin application, sorry, taking grant applications for Bitcoin projects and Nostra projects and Lightning projects. And there is about five mil for an OSTER, five mil for Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Splicing, Lightning's Multiparty Future</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/splicing-lightnings-multiparty-future/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/splicing-lightnings-multiparty-future/</guid><description>Introduction Thanks for coming. It&amp;rsquo;s exciting to be in Mexico City, talking about Lightning, splicing, and privacy. I&amp;rsquo;m Dusty. This is a photo of me when I was much younger—a little bit younger, but that number is growing every year, it turns out. So, a little bit about me: I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing Bitcoin development stuff for probably five years, and about a year or change ago, I decided to focus on doing lightning stuff, and my first big project has been splicing.</description></item><item><title>Splicing</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-residency/2019-06-26-rene-pickhardt-splicing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-residency/2019-06-26-rene-pickhardt-splicing/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs Lightning Residency 2019
Transcript by: Caralie Chrisco
Introduction So splicing basically means you have a payment channel, you have a certain capacity of a payment channel and you want to change the capacity on the payment channel. But you don&amp;rsquo;t want to change your balance right? For balance change,(inaudible) we&amp;rsquo;ll get some money on it. But splicing really means you want to change the capacity.
I mean the obvious way of doing this is close the channel, make a new channel with the design capacity and you could.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Overview</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/layer2-summit/2018/lightning-overview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/layer2-summit/2018/lightning-overview/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005913055333675009
https://lightning.network/
Introduction First I am going to give a brief overview of how lightning works for those of who you may not be so familiar. Then I am going to discuss three technologies we&amp;rsquo;ll be working on in the next year at Lightning Labs and pushing forward.
Philosophical perspective and scalability Before I do that though, following up on what Neha was saying, I want to give a philosophical perspective on how I think about layer 2 as a scalability solution.</description></item></channel></rss>