<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jonas Schnelli on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/jonas-schnelli/</link><description>Recent content in Jonas Schnelli on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/jonas-schnelli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Maintaining Bitcoin Core-Contributions, Consensus, Conflict</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2021-01-14-jonas-schnelli-maintaining-bitcoin-core/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2021-01-14-jonas-schnelli-maintaining-bitcoin-core/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/242/
Stephan Livera:
Jonas. Welcome back to the show.
Jonas Schnelli:
Hey! Hi, Stephan. Thanks for having me.
Stephan Livera:
Jonas, Its been a while since we spoke on the show and I was excited to get another opportunity to chat with you and learn a little bit more and obviously talk about this on behalf of some of the newer listeners who are coming in and they may not be familiar with how does Bitcoin Core work.</description></item><item><title>P2P Encryption</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/p2p-encryption/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/p2p-encryption/</guid><description>bip324: v2 message transport protocol
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137312478373851136
slides: https://twitter.com/_jonasschnelli_/status/1137389541512351749
Previous talks https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/bip151-peer-encryption/
https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-09-04-jonas-schenlli-bip150-bip151/
https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06-07-p2p-encryption/
Introduction This will be a technical talk. I hope you&amp;rsquo;re prepared for some cryptography. By the way, this now has a bip number as of this morning. This is bip324. I call it v2 message transport protocol. It&amp;rsquo;s not a consensus change, it&amp;rsquo;s purely a p2p network layer change. It&amp;rsquo;s not all about encryption, but mainly about encryption.</description></item><item><title>Hardware Wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06/2019-06-07-hardware-wallets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06/2019-06-07-hardware-wallets/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1136924010955104257
How much should Bitcoin Core do, and how much should other libraries do? Andrew Chow wrote the wonderful HWI tool. Right now we have a pull request to support external signers. The HWI script can talk to most major hardware wallets because it has all the drivers built in now, and it can get keys from it, and sign arbitrary transactions. That&amp;rsquo;s roughly what it does. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of manual, though.</description></item><item><title>Current And Future State Of Wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/current-and-future-state-of-wallets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/current-and-future-state-of-wallets/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014127893495021568
Introduction I started to contribute to Bitcoin Core about 5 years ago. Since then, I have managed to get 450 commits merged. I am also the co-founder of a wallet hardware company based in Switzerland called Shift+ Cryptocurrency.
Wallets is not rocket science. It&amp;rsquo;s mostly about pointing the figure to things that we can do better. I prepared a lot of content.
Privacy, security and trust When I look at existing wallets, I see the triangle of privacy, security and trust.</description></item><item><title>Bip150 Bip151</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-09-04-jonas-schnelli-bip150-bip151/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-09-04-jonas-schnelli-bip150-bip151/</guid><description>bip150 and bip151: Bitcoin p2p network encryption and authentication
https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/master/bip-0150.mediawiki
https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/master/bip-0151.mediawiki
https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/bip151-peer-encryption/
Introduction Alright guys.. take a seat. ((various mumblings)) Want to thank our sponsors, Digital Garage (applause). Second order of business, if you guys could&amp;hellip; trash away.. that would be awesome. There are trash cans in the back and right there and right next to the drinks. So at the end of the night, that would be great. Jonas Schnelli is a bitcoin core developer and he is here to talk about bitcoin encryption and authentication on the p2p network.</description></item><item><title>BIP151 Peer Encryption</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/bip151-peer-encryption/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/bip151-peer-encryption/</guid><description>BIP151: Peer-to-peer encryption and authentication from the perspective of end-users
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785046960705339392
Good morning. Thanks for having me here. I would like to talk about the end-user perspective of p2p authentication. I would like to start with a little example of how difficult it is to be aware of end-user issues that they are facing at the front. Who is using a thin client? An &amp;ldquo;SPV&amp;rdquo; wallet on your smartphone? Yeah. Who of you are on iOS?</description></item><item><title>Improvements to Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/maaku-panel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/maaku-panel/</guid><description>This can be a broad range of topics for improvements. I am Mark Friedenbach, I have worked on Bitcoin protocol research, but I also do Core tech engineering at Blockstream. We also have Jonas, an independent Bitcoin Core developer. We also have Andrew Poelstra, who has been core to the crypto work which has been incoporated into Bitcoin, such as libsecp256k1 which we recently integrated in the 0.12 release. It speeds up Bitcoin validation by 7-8x.</description></item></channel></rss>