<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Olaoluwa Osuntokun on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/olaoluwa-osuntokun/</link><description>Recent content in Olaoluwa Osuntokun on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/olaoluwa-osuntokun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Laolu, Joost, Oliver - Lnd0.10</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/vr-bitcoin/2020-04-18-laolu-joost-oliver-lnd0.10/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/vr-bitcoin/2020-04-18-laolu-joost-oliver-lnd0.10/</guid><description>Topic: lnd v0.10
Location: Virtual Reality (VR Bitcoin)
Intro (Laolu Osuntokun) Thanks everyone for coming. This is my first time doing a VR presentation, really cool. I am going to be talking about lnd 0.10. Right now we are on rc2, the next major lnd release, it has a bunch of cool features, bug fixes, optimizations. I am going to talk about some big ticket features in 0.10. There are a bunch of other features that you are going to want to check out in the release notes.</description></item><item><title>SIGHASH_NOINPUT, ANYPREVOUT</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06/2019-06-06-noinput-etc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06/2019-06-06-noinput-etc/</guid><description>SIGHASH_NOINPUT, ANYPREVOUT, OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACK, OP_CHECKOUTPUTSHASHVERIFY, and OP_SECURETHEBAG
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1136636856093876225
There&amp;rsquo;s apparently some political messaging around OP_SECURETHEBAG and &amp;ldquo;secure the bag&amp;rdquo; might be an Andrew Yang thing.
SIGHASH_NOINPUT A bunch of us are familiar with NOINPUT. Does anyone need an explainer? What&amp;rsquo;s the difference from the original NOINPUT and the new one? NOINPUT is kind of scary to at least some people. If we just do NOINPUT, does that start causing problems in bitcoin?</description></item><item><title>Lnd</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/noded-podcast/2018-12-14-laolu-conner-lnd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/noded-podcast/2018-12-14-laolu-conner-lnd/</guid><description>Noded podcast with Laolu Osuntokun and Conner Fromknecht - December 14th 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1089187758931890178
Podcast: https://noded.org/podcast/noded-0360-with-olaoluwa-osuntokun-and-conner-fromknecht/
Pierre: Welcome to the Noded Bitcoin podcast. This is episode 36. We’re joined with Laolu and Conner from Lightning Labs as well as my co-host Michael Goldstein. How’s it going guys?
roasbeef: Not bad
Pierre: So I listened to Laolu on Stephan Livera’s podcast and I would encourage any of our listeners to go listen to that first so that they can hear all about some of the latest developments in lightning.</description></item><item><title>Laolu Osuntokun - Stephan Livera</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2018-12-11-laolu-osuntokun-stephan-livera/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2018-12-11-laolu-osuntokun-stephan-livera/</guid><description>Stephan Livera podcast with Laolu Osuntokun - December 11th 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1090640881873387525
Podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/39
Stephan: Hi Laolu. Thank you very much for coming on the show.
roasbeef: It’s good to be here.
Stephan: It’s been a while since the Lighting Summit was on and now you’re back home. How’s things back home?
roasbeef: Not bad, just the usual back to work, just the regular stuff. Australia was great. I had never been.</description></item><item><title>Exploring Lnd0.4</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2018-04-20-laolu-osuntokun-exploring-lnd0.4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2018-04-20-laolu-osuntokun-exploring-lnd0.4/</guid><description>Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1pyQgGDUcB29r8DnTaS0GQS6usjw4CpgciQx_-XBVOwU/
The Genesis of lnd First, the genesis of lnd. Here is the first commit of lnd. It was October 27 2015. This is when I was in school still. This was done when I went on break and it was the first major…. we had in terms of code. We talked about the language we’re using, the licensing, the architecture of the daemon. A fun fact, the original name of lnd was actually called Plasma.</description></item><item><title>Hardening Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/hardening-lightning/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/hardening-lightning/</guid><description>Hardening lightning network
Olaoluwa Osuntokun (roasbeef), Lightning Labs
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/959155562134102016
slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/14NuX5LTDSmmfYbAn0NupuXnXpfoZE0nXsG7CjzPXdlA/edit
previous talk (2017): http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/lightning-network-security-analysis/
previous slides (2017): https://cyber.stanford.edu/sites/default/files/olaoluwaosuntokun.pdf
Introduction I am basically going to go over some ways that I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about basically hardening lightning network, in terms of making security better and making the client more scalable itself, and then I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about some issues and pain points that come up when you&amp;rsquo;re doing fees on mainnet. And there&amp;rsquo;s going to be some relatively minor changes that I propose to Bitcoin in this talk.</description></item><item><title>Neutrino</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-06-06-laolu-osuntokun-neutrino/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-06-06-laolu-osuntokun-neutrino/</guid><description>Neutrino: The Privacy Preserving Bitcoin Light Client
Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1vjJUWOZIaPshjx1svfE6rFZ2lC07n47ifOdzpKWqpb4/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1054031024085258240
Introduction My name is Laolu or Roasbeef on the internet. I’m going to talk about light clients in general and then also what we’re working on in terms of light clients and then also how that factors into the lightning network itself. The talk is called Neutrino because that is the name of our new light client that has been released.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Security Analysis</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/lightning-network-security-analysis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/lightning-network-security-analysis/</guid><description>Security analysis of the lightning network
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/957978915515092992
slides: https://cyber.stanford.edu/sites/default/files/olaoluwaosuntokun.pdf
Introduction My name is Laolu Osuntokun and I work on lightning stuff. I go by roasbeef on the internet. I work at Lightning Labs. I am going to be giving an overview of some security properties and privacy properties of lightning.
State of the hash-lock Before I start, I want to go over the state of the hash-lock which is the current progress to completion and design of lightning.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-07-18-laolu-osuntokun-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-07-18-laolu-osuntokun-lightning-network/</guid><description>Lightning Network Deep Dive
Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1OPijcjzadKkbxvGU6VcVnAeSD_DKb7gjnevBcqhPCW0/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1052238088913788928
Introduction My name is Laolu Osuntokun and I work with Lightning guys and you know me as maybe Roasbeef from the internet, on GitHub, Twitter, everything else. I’ve been Roasbeef for the past 8 years and I’m still Roasbeef that’s how it works. I’m going to give you a deep dive into the lightning network. I remember like 2 years ago when I was learning about Bitcoin initially and I went to these Bitcoin dev meetups in Mission and there was a deep dive and Taariq was the MC there, super friendly guy.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Script</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/bitcoin-script/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/bitcoin-script/</guid><description>Featuring roasbeef
Agenda opcodes OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACK sighash flags keytree sigs MAST graftroot, taproot covenants, reverse covenants (input restrictions: this input has to be spent with tihs other input, or can only be spent if this other one doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist) stack manipulation script languages (simplicity) tx formats, serialization? what would we change with hard-fork changes to the transaction format? Segwit transaction encoding format sucks; the witnesses are at the end and inline with all the scriptsigs and that should be changed.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Script V2.0 And Strengthened Payment Channels</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/bitcoin-script-v2.0-and-strengthened-payment-channels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/bitcoin-script-v2.0-and-strengthened-payment-channels/</guid><description>This is a brief history of bitcoin script evolution. Since bitcoin was active in 2009, there was a lot of emergency fixes for the first 2 years done by Satoshi. He found that people could skpi the signature check using OP_RETURN and malformed scriptSigs. So those functions were removed. OP_VER and OP_VERIF were intended for script upgrades but it was found that after every release of bitcoin, it would become a hard-fork because of the design.</description></item><item><title>Flare Routing In Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/flare-routing-in-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/flare-routing-in-lightning/</guid><description>Flare: An approach to routing in lightning network
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784745976170999810
I will not be as technical as Olaoluwa was. You have nodes that open up payment channels. This scheme is actually developed at the moment in great detail. So how do you find the channels through which to send payments? So we wanted to propose some initial solution to this.
Routing requirements It should be source routing because we need the privacy.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Security Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-security-panel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-security-panel/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137758233865703424
Introduction MF: I will start by thanking Kevin and Lea and the organizers. It&amp;rsquo;s been an awesome event. Thanks also to the sponsors. Without their assistance we couldn&amp;rsquo;t have had the event. I&amp;rsquo;d also like to make some plugs before we start the conversation. One, I run the London Bitcoin developers group. If you&amp;rsquo;re ever in London or interested in speaking, please look up London Bitcoin Devs on Twitter or Meetup.</description></item><item><title>Multi Party Channels In The Utxo Model Challenges And Opportunities</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-party-channels-in-the-utxo-model-challenges-and-opportunities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-party-channels-in-the-utxo-model-challenges-and-opportunities/</guid><description>Multi-party channels in the UTXO model: Challenges and opportunities
Olaoluwa Osuntokun (Lightning Labs) (roasbeef)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048468663089618944
Introductions Hi. So my name is Laolu. I am also known as roasbeef and I am co-founder of Lightning Labs. I am going to go over some cool research and science fiction. In the actual implementation for these things and cool to discuss and get some discussions around this. first I am going to talk about single-party channels and multi-party channels.</description></item><item><title>Onion Routing In Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/onion-routing-in-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/onion-routing-in-lightning/</guid><description>http://lightning.network/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784742298089299969
Privacy-preserving decentralized micropayments
We&amp;rsquo;re excited about lightning because the second layer could be an important opportunity to improve privacy and fungibility. Also, there might be timing information in the payments themselves.
Distributed set of onion routers (OR, cite OG onionrouting paper). Users create circuits with sub-set of nodes. Difficult for oion routers to gain more info than predecessor+successor in path. Low latency - usable within greater internet. Notable success is tor, notable success of routing nodes.</description></item></channel></rss>