<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rusty Russell on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/rusty-russell/</link><description>Recent content in Rusty Russell on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/rusty-russell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lightning Offers / BOLT12 -The next big thing in Lightning?</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2021-08-09-rusty-russell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2021-08-09-rusty-russell/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/298/
Stephan Livera:
Rusty welcome back to the show.
Rusty Russell:
Thanks. It’s always good to be here, Stephan.
Stephan Livera:
So Rusty, I know you’ve been making progress on this whole offers idea. Now you’ve mentioned this on the show in the past. And in fact, I recall at the Lightning conference and I think it was October, 2019 is when you actually first put this idea out there into the wild.</description></item><item><title>Improving the Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi-research-club/2021-05-30-rusty-russell-improving-lightning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi-research-club/2021-05-30-rusty-russell-improving-lightning/</guid><description>Topic: Improving the Lightning Network
Location: Join the Wasabikas podcast
How Rusty got into Lightning Max Hillebrand (MH): So Rusty, I am very happy that you joined me for this conversation today. You have been a pioneer in Lightning Network. To start off this conversation I am curious, 6 years ago before you got into the Lightning Network what was your understanding of Bitcoin back then and where did you see some of the big problems that needed to be solved at that point?</description></item><item><title>Lightning Multi Part Payments</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2019-12-16-rusty-russelllightning-multi-part-payments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2019-12-16-rusty-russelllightning-multi-part-payments/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/134/
Stephan Livera: Rusty, welcome back to the show.
Rusty Russell: Great to be on again Stephan.
Stephan Livera: So Rusty, I hear there’s been a lot of development around multi-part payment and you’ve got the new c-lightning coming out. Do you want to just give us an update there?
Rusty Russell: Yeah, for sure. So on the, so there’s two sides to this. One is kind of the spec side and the development and interoperability of multi-part payment stuff.</description></item><item><title>Offers and BOLT 12</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-conference/2019/2019-10-19-rusty-russell-offers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-conference/2019/2019-10-19-rusty-russell-offers/</guid><description>Make Me An Offer: Next Level Invoicing
The Lightning Conference Day 1 (Stage 1)
BOLT 11: https://github.com/lightningnetwork/lightning-rfc/blob/master/11-payment-encoding.md
BOLT 12 PR: https://github.com/lightningnetwork/lightning-rfc/pull/798
bolt12.org: https://bolt12.org/
Intro Hi. My name is Rusty Russell and this is actually my official job title at Blockstream, code contributor. It is generic, it is flexible, it is probably a little too humble maybe but that is me. Before we begin the main part of this talk I want to tell you a story.</description></item><item><title>Rusty Russell, Joe Netti</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2019-08-12-rusty-russell-joe-netti/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2019-08-12-rusty-russell-joe-netti/</guid><description>Stephan Livera podcast with Rusty Russell and Joe Netti - August 12th 2019
Podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/98/
Stephan Livera:	Rusty and Joe, welcome to the show.
Joe Netti:	Hi. How’s it going?
Rusty Russell:	Hey, Stephan. Good to be back.
Stephan Livera:	Thanks for rejoining me, Rusty, and thanks for joining me, Joe. So, just a quick intro just for the listeners. Joe, do you want to start?
Joe Netti:	Yeah, sure. So, I got into Bitcoin in around 2013, and took me a while to learn what it was about, and then I just kept diving deeper.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started With C-Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockstream-webinars/2019-07-31-rusty-russell-getting-started-with-c-lightning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockstream-webinars/2019-07-31-rusty-russell-getting-started-with-c-lightning/</guid><description>Getting started with c-lightning
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1231946205380403200
Introduction Hi everyone. We’re actually a couple of minutes early and I think we are going to give a couple of minutes past before we actually start because I think some people will probably be running late particularly with the change in times we had to make after this was announced. While we are waiting it would be interesting to find out a little bit about the attendees’ backgrounds and what they hope to get out of this.</description></item><item><title>JSON Interface</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/boltathon/2019-04-06-rusty-russell-json-interface/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/boltathon/2019-04-06-rusty-russell-json-interface/</guid><description>JSON Interface with c-lightning and Writing Extensions
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230892247345852416
Intro Ok I have top running. We have a plan and we’re going to start from zero. We’re going to clone c-lightning, we’re going to compile it, we’re going to set up a test node. I’m assuming Bitcoin is already installed. We’re going to talk a little about configuring it and stuff like that. All this stuff is useful to see somebody else do.</description></item><item><title>Future Bitcoin Tech Directions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2018-01-24-rusty-russell-future-bitcoin-tech-directions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2018-01-24-rusty-russell-future-bitcoin-tech-directions/</guid><description>Future technological directions in bitcoin: An unreliable guide
notes: https://docs.google.com/document/d/1iNzJtJRq9-0vdILQAe9Bcj7r1a7xYVf8CSY0_oFrH9c/edit or http://diyhpl.us/~bryan/papers2/bitcoin/Future%20technological%20directions%20in%20bitcoin%20-%202018-01-24.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/957318453181939712
Introduction Thank you very much for that introduction. Alright, well polished machine right there. Let&amp;rsquo;s try that again. Thank you for that introduction. My talk today is all about this. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to be talking about this. If you see me reaching for the red hat, please stop me. Before I begin, I want to apologize in advance: this talk is a summary of things coming up in bitcoin that some people are workin on, which means first I need to apologize to the people whose work I am about to compress into about 85 second segments each, because I am going to gloss over a lot of things.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Block Propagation and IBLT</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/bitcoin-block-propagation-iblt-rusty-russell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/bitcoin-block-propagation-iblt-rusty-russell/</guid><description>This is not what I do. But I was doing it anyway.
The problem is that blocks are transmitted in their entirety. If you have a 1 MB uplink and you&amp;rsquo;re connecting to 8 peers, your first peer will see a 1MB block in about 66.8 seconds. And the last one will get it in 76.4 seconds, because we basically blast out blocks in parallel to our peers. Miners can solve this problem of slow block transmission by centralizing and all using the same pool.</description></item><item><title>Invertible Bloom Lookup Tables And Weak Block Propagation Performance</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/invertible-bloom-lookup-tables-and-weak-block-propagation-performance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/invertible-bloom-lookup-tables-and-weak-block-propagation-performance/</guid><description>IBLT and weak block propagation performance
slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY1/3_block_propagation_1_rosenbaum.pdf
IBLT - invertible bloom lookup tables
Before we get started, for privacy reasons, and for reasons of zero attribution, please do not take pictures of attendees. Do not have pictures of attendees in the photographs. Taking pictures of the stage and slides are OK, since they are being broadcasted. No photographs of any attendees, please let them remain anonymous and private. For Chinese speakers, please ask in Chinese and I will use American English to translate.</description></item></channel></rss>