<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mark Friedenbach on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/mark-friedenbach/</link><description>Recent content in Mark Friedenbach on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/mark-friedenbach/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Flexible Limit Trading Subsidy For Larger Blocks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/a-flexible-limit-trading-subsidy-for-larger-blocks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/a-flexible-limit-trading-subsidy-for-larger-blocks/</guid><description>slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY2/3_tweaking_the_chain_2_friedenbach.pdf
I really want to thank jgarzik for that interesting talk. Who picks what block size? My talk is going to be about a category of dynamic block size proposals that attach the block size limit to the fee in such a way that as there is more demand for block size, through users that want to pay fees, the block size will increase or decrease as necessary. The need for a dynamic block size is so that the block size can increase.</description></item><item><title>Alternatives To Block Size As Aggregate Resource Limits</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/alternatives-to-block-size-as-aggregate-resource-limits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/alternatives-to-block-size-as-aggregate-resource-limits/</guid><description>I am talking about block size, but not any particular proposal. Why do we have the block size limit and is it a good thing in the first place? The block size exists as a denial-of-service limiter. It limits the amount of resources that a node validating the blockchain can exhaust when validating a block. We want to do this because in the early days of bitcoin there are often certain kinds of transactions there are ways to slow down a validator by using a non-standard transaction or filling up a block with tons of spam.</description></item><item><title>Fast Difficulty Adjustment</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/fast-difficulty-adjustment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/fast-difficulty-adjustment/</guid><description>Fast difficulty adjustment using a low-pass finite impulse response filter
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785107422323085312
slides https://scalingbitcoin.org/milan2016/presentations/Scaling%20Bitcoin%203%20-%20Mark%20Friedenbach.pdf
Introductions I work at Blockstream Labs. This work is based on work I did in 2013 which is now only being presented. If there are any control engineers, I would encourage you. I am going to cover some mistakes that have been covered in the industry on alternative networks and proposals.
Difficulty adjustment Difficulty adjustment happens every 2016 blocks in bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Forward Blocks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/forward-blocks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/forward-blocks/</guid><description>Forward blocks: On-chain settlement capacity increases without the hard-fork
Mark Friedenbach (maaku)
paper: http://freico.in/forward-blocks-scalingbitcoin-paper.pdf
slides: http://freico.in/forward-blocks-scalingbitcoin-slides.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048416249791668225
Introduction I know that we&amp;rsquo;re running late in this session so I&amp;rsquo;ll try to keep this fast and get everyone to lunch. I have presented at Scaling Bitcoin four times now so I won&amp;rsquo;t dwell on the introduction. I wanted to talk about scaling bitcoin directly on chain in a way that is compatible with all existing node deployments.</description></item><item><title>Improvements to Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/maaku-panel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/maaku-panel/</guid><description>This can be a broad range of topics for improvements. I am Mark Friedenbach, I have worked on Bitcoin protocol research, but I also do Core tech engineering at Blockstream. We also have Jonas, an independent Bitcoin Core developer. We also have Andrew Poelstra, who has been core to the crypto work which has been incoporated into Bitcoin, such as libsecp256k1 which we recently integrated in the 0.12 release. It speeds up Bitcoin validation by 7-8x.</description></item></channel></rss>