<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blockchain Protocol Analysis Security Engineering 2017 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/</link><description>Recent content in Blockchain Protocol Analysis Security Engineering 2017 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lightning Network Security Analysis</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/lightning-network-security-analysis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/lightning-network-security-analysis/</guid><description>Security analysis of the lightning network
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/957978915515092992
slides: https://cyber.stanford.edu/sites/default/files/olaoluwaosuntokun.pdf
Introduction My name is Laolu Osuntokun and I work on lightning stuff. I go by roasbeef on the internet. I work at Lightning Labs. I am going to be giving an overview of some security properties and privacy properties of lightning.
State of the hash-lock Before I start, I want to go over the state of the hash-lock which is the current progress to completion and design of lightning.</description></item><item><title>Scalable Smart Contracts Via Proofs And Single Use Seals</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/scalable-smart-contracts-via-proofs-and-single-use-seals/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/scalable-smart-contracts-via-proofs-and-single-use-seals/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/957660108137418752
slides: https://cyber.stanford.edu/sites/default/files/petertodd.pdf
https://petertodd.org/2016/commitments-and-single-use-seals
https://petertodd.org/2016/closed-seal-sets-and-truth-lists-for-privacy
Introduction I am petertodd and I am here to break your blockchain. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of interesting following a talk like that, in some ways I&amp;rsquo;m going in a more extreme direcion for consensus. Do we actually need consensus at all? Can we make a more robust system by eliminating it to the maximum extent possible? I think for some use case at least I have some techniques that will let you go do this.</description></item><item><title>Covenants - Structuring Multi Transaction Contracts in Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/2017-01-26-jeremy-rubin-covenants/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/2017-01-26-jeremy-rubin-covenants/</guid><description>Structuring Multi Transaction Contracts in Bitcoin
Location: BPASE 2017, Stanford University
Slides: https://rubin.io/public/pdfs/multi-txn-contracts.pdf
Intro Hey everyone. How is it going? Happy to be going last right now given that I had all these wonderful speakers before me to explain so much of what I am about to tell you. I’m going to talk to you today about structuring multi-transaction contracts in Bitcoin. I think there is a lot of great work that happens in Bitcoin at the script level, at the individual input and output.</description></item><item><title>Ivy - A Declarative Predicate Language for Smart Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/2017-01-26-dan-robinson-ivy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/2017-01-26-dan-robinson-ivy/</guid><description>Ivy: A Declarative Predicate Language for Smart Contracts
Location: BPASE 2017, Stanford University
Intro Hi I’m Dan Robinson, I’m one of the Product Architects at Chain which is an enterprise blockchain infrastructure company for financial institutions. We have a full stack blockchain protocol and what I am going to talk about is part of that that also can be used for other applications including as I am going to demo here, make it easier to write scripts for Bitcoin Script.</description></item><item><title>Posts Theorem</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/2017-01-26-russell-oconnor-posts-theorem/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/2017-01-26-russell-oconnor-posts-theorem/</guid><description>Post’s Theorem and Blockchain Languages: A Short Course in the Theory of Computation
Location: BPASE 2017, Stanford University
Intro Hi. My name is Russell O’Connor. I am here to talk to you about Post’s theorem, the theory of computation and its applications to blockchain languages. There is a bit of a debate about whether Turing complete languages are appropriate or not for doing computations, whether the DAO fiasco is related to the Turing completeness problem or is it an unrelated issue?</description></item></channel></rss>