<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Harry Kalodner on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/harry-kalodner/</link><description>Recent content in Harry Kalodner on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/harry-kalodner/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blocksci Platform</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/blocksci-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/blocksci-platform/</guid><description>BlockSci: a Platform for Blockchain Science and Exploration
Harry Kalodner, Princeton University (Arvind Narayanan etc.)
Alright well, my name is Harry Kalodner, I am a student at Princeton University and I am here to tell you about a tool I built alon with some colleagues at Princeton which could be used for analyzing the blockchain in different ways. So far most of the talks today have been constructive about new ways to use the blockchain and protocols to slightly modify bitcoin in roder to improve privacy or scaling.</description></item><item><title>Non Currency Applications</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/non-currency-applications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/non-currency-applications/</guid><description>Scalability of non-currency applications
I am from Princeton University. I am here to talk about the scalability issues that non-currency applications of bitcoin have that might be a little different than regular payments that go through the bitcoin network. I put this together with my advisor, Arvind. The reason why I want to talk about this is because when people talk about how bitcoin will have to scale is that people throw out a thing about Visa processing 20,000 transactions per second or something.</description></item><item><title>Security Of Diminishing Block Subsidy</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/security-of-diminishing-block-subsidy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/security-of-diminishing-block-subsidy/</guid><description>Miners no longer incentivized to mine all the time. The future of mining hardware. Impact on the bitcoin ecosystem. Implications and assumptions of the model.
Are minting rewards and transaction fees the same? Transaction fees are time-dependent. A miner can only claim transaction fees as transactions are added to their block. As transaction fees start to dominate the block reward, they become time-dependent. We are modeling this block reward as a linear function of time, we have this factor B which might be initial minting reward, and we have some scaling factor, the block reward is like &amp;ldquo;b + at&amp;rdquo;.</description></item></channel></rss>