<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Decentralized Financial Architecture Workshop on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/</link><description>Recent content in Decentralized Financial Architecture Workshop on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Custody Group</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/custody-group/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/custody-group/</guid><description>Custody working group
One of the problems in the ecosystem was nomenclature. We started working on a report about what features a nomenclature would have. Airgaps, constant-time software, sidechannel resistance, Faraday cage, deterministic software, entropy, blind signatures, proof-of-reserve, multi-vendor hardware to minimize compromise. Multi-location and multi-sig. Insurance guarantee scheme. Canaries, dead man switches, tripwires, heartbeat mechanisms. Shamir&amp;rsquo;s secret sharing vs multisig. The second part of this report was going to be market analysis.</description></item><item><title>Compliance And Confidentiality</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/compliance-and-confidentiality/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/compliance-and-confidentiality/</guid><description>Compliance and confidentiality: can they co-exist?
Alexander Zaidelson, Beam
Introduction Hi everyone. It&amp;rsquo;s a great pleasure to be here. I&amp;rsquo;m Alexander Zaidelson, CEO of Beam. I&amp;rsquo;ll be presenting our view on the regulation and how we live with it as a project. I&amp;rsquo;m not an expert in regulation. Whatever I&amp;rsquo;m showing here is how we see the landscape from what we understand.
Beam is a confidential transaction. The question is, how can confidential cryptocurrency co-exist with regulation?</description></item><item><title>G20 Discussion</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/g20-discussion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/g20-discussion/</guid><description>Why do we need a multi-stakeholder discussion in a blockchain world? A report from G20 discussions.
https://bsafe.network
Introduction I am the cofounder of the bsafe.network which focuses on blockchain research. I was a program co-chair for Scaling Bitcoin at Keio University last year. I also work with IEEE, ACM conferences, Ledger Journal, and more. My background is engagement with Bank of Japan NTT internet cash in 1998-2000.
Several huge incidents From a regulatory point of view, there are many big events that have occurred: MtGox, the DAO attack, coincheck, monacoin, and Zaif.</description></item><item><title>Implications</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/implications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/implications/</guid><description>Implications on regulation and governance of blockchain-based finance
Yuta Takanashi (Financial Services Agency, Japan)
Disclaimer First, please note that the opinions presented here belong to myself and don&amp;rsquo;t represent the organizations to which I belong.
Major goals for financial regulators The primary goals of financial regulators are to maintain financial stability, protect investors and consumers, and prevent financial crimes. These goals are public interests and are needed to be achieved regardless of the technology used in the financial systems.</description></item><item><title>Introduction (2019)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/introduction/</guid><description>Introduction to DFA Workshop
We are an international conference that focuses on the latest development in software and its scalability in the bitcoin ecosystem. We have come here to Israel. We are running 5 days of events, including this current workshop. Over the next 4 days following today, we&amp;rsquo;re running Bitcoin Edge Dev++ workshop at Tel Aviv University for 2 days, and then Scaling Bitcoin for 2 days which is compromised of over 44 high tech sessions on complex scalability and security related topics in the bitcoin ecosystem, mainly for developers.</description></item><item><title>Metadata</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/metadata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/metadata/</guid><description>website: https://dfa2019.bitcoinedge.org/
twitter: https://twitter.com/thebitcoinedge
https://gnso.icann.org/sites/default/files/file/field-file-attach/presentation-pre-icann65-policy-report-13jun19-en.pdf</description></item><item><title>Perspective</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/perspective/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/decentralized-financial-architecture-workshop/perspective/</guid><description>Regulators should focus on consumer protection
Regulators should focus on operating (or overseeing) rating agencies, and formal review of proposed standards
Fungibility is important, and many regulatory goals are contrary to fungibility, indicating that their forms of money will be inferior and their economy will be left behind.
Anonymity should be a core value&amp;ndash; the society with the most privacy will have the most advantages.
The importance of regulatory sandboxes (which should be optional).</description></item></channel></rss>