<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/op-checktemplateverify/</link><description>Recent content in OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/op-checktemplateverify/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OP_VAULT Round 2 &amp; OP_CTV</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/op_vault-round-2-op_ctv/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/op_vault-round-2-op_ctv/</guid><description>The podcast episode discusses the OP_VAULT proposal for enhancing Bitcoin self-custody and security. NVK hosts a panel with James O&amp;rsquo;Beirne, Rijndael, Greg Sanders, and Ben Carman, who delve into the technical aspects and benefits of OP_VAULT. The proposal aims to improve Bitcoin custody by introducing vaults, allowing users to lock their coins with predetermined spend conditions, enhancing security against theft and accidental loss. They compare OP_VAULT with other proposals like CTV and ANYPREVOUT, highlighting its simplicity and operational efficiency. The conversation also addresses potential concerns about covenants and the importance of community engagement and education to facilitate the proposal&amp;rsquo;s acceptance and activation. The episode emphasizes the need for better custody solutions to secure large amounts of Bitcoin, especially as the user base grows and the value of Bitcoin increases.</description></item><item><title>Sydney Socratic Seminar</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-06-01-socratic-seminar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-06-01-socratic-seminar/</guid><description>Google Doc of the resources discussed: https://docs.google.com/document/d/1E9mzB7fmzPxZ74WZg0PsJfLwjpVZ7OClmRdGQQFlzoY/
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Bitcoin Problems (Lloyd Fournier) https://bitcoin-problems.github.io/
This is Bitcoin Problems, it is a Jekyll website I put on GitHub. I am very bad at making things look nice but it is functional at least.</description></item><item><title>Socratic Seminar - Vaults and OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-05-19-socratic-seminar-vaults/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-05-19-socratic-seminar-vaults/</guid><description>Pastebin of the resources discussed: https://pastebin.com/3Q8MSwky
Twitter announcement: https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1262821838654255104?s=20
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who would prefer their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Introductions Michael Folkson (MF): This is a London BitDevs Socratic Seminar. We are live-streaming on YouTube so please be aware of that for the guys and girls on the call.</description></item></channel></rss>