<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tokyo (2018) on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/</link><description>Recent content in Tokyo (2018) on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Accumulators</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/accumulators/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/accumulators/</guid><description>A scalable drop-in replacement for merkle trees
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048454406755168257
Introduction Hello. Test. Okay. I am going to talk about accumulators for UTXOs. The previous two talks were a great setup for this. This is joint work with Ben Fisch who is also here today and Dan Boneh. I first want to advertise the Stanford Blockchain Conference (formerly known as BPASE) happening at the end of January 2019 at Stanford. Whether you give a talk or not, you should try to attend.</description></item><item><title>Analysis Of Dust In Utxo Based Cryptocurrencies</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/analysis-of-dust-in-utxo-based-cryptocurrencies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/analysis-of-dust-in-utxo-based-cryptocurrencies/</guid><description>An analysis of dust in UTXO-based cryptocurrencies
Cristina Pérez-Solà, Sergi Delgado Segura, Guillermo Navarro-Arribas and Jordi Herrera (Universitat Autònoma de Barcelona)
Sergi Delgado Segura
https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/513.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048380094446632961
Introduction Thank you everyone. I am glad to be here today to tell you about our analysis of the UTXO set in different cryptocurrencies. This is shared work with the other coauthors listed. The outline is that I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the UTXO set, then I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about definitions, our results, and our conclusions.</description></item><item><title>Atomic Swaps</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/atomic-swaps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/atomic-swaps/</guid><description>The state of atomic swaps
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048790167283068929
History This should be easy to follow. I want to start off with some history. The first mention of atomic swap concepts was in 2013 in a bitcointalk.org thread where people were wondering how to exchange coins between independent ledgers in a trustless way. There were a few comments on the thread every now and then asking has anyone implemented this. It was quiet until last year when people started doing atomic swaps last year.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Script</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/bitcoin-script/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/bitcoin-script/</guid><description>Featuring roasbeef
Agenda opcodes OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACK sighash flags keytree sigs MAST graftroot, taproot covenants, reverse covenants (input restrictions: this input has to be spent with tihs other input, or can only be spent if this other one doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist) stack manipulation script languages (simplicity) tx formats, serialization? what would we change with hard-fork changes to the transaction format? Segwit transaction encoding format sucks; the witnesses are at the end and inline with all the scriptsigs and that should be changed.</description></item><item><title>Compact Multi Signatures For Smaller Blockchains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/compact-multi-signatures-for-smaller-blockchains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/compact-multi-signatures-for-smaller-blockchains/</guid><description>Compact multi-signatures for smaller blockchains
Dan Boneh (Stanford University), Manu Drijvers and Gregory Neven (DFINITY)
paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/483.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048441176024469504
Introduction Hi. Thanks a lot for coming in after lunch. This slot is often known as &amp;ldquo;the slot of death&amp;rdquo;. Some of us are jetlagged, this is the perfect time to doze off and only wake up at the end of the talk. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to prevent that from happening. I think the best way to do that is to start about what this talk can do for you.</description></item><item><title>Deploying Blockchain At Scale Lessons From The Internet Deployment In Japan</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/deploying-blockchain-at-scale-lessons-from-the-internet-deployment-in-japan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/deploying-blockchain-at-scale-lessons-from-the-internet-deployment-in-japan/</guid><description>Deploying blockchain at scale: Lessons learned from the Internet deployment in Japan
Jun Muai (Keio University)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048373339826188288
Okay. Good morning everybody. Good morning? I am from Keio University. Welcome to Keio University.
Let me introduce something about our university. This is very old. It&amp;rsquo;s from 1858. It&amp;rsquo;s the oldest university in Japan. It was founded in 1858. The highest bill in this country is 10,000 yen on paper. This person is the founder of Keio University.</description></item><item><title>Forward Blocks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/forward-blocks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/forward-blocks/</guid><description>Forward blocks: On-chain settlement capacity increases without the hard-fork
Mark Friedenbach (maaku)
paper: http://freico.in/forward-blocks-scalingbitcoin-paper.pdf
slides: http://freico.in/forward-blocks-scalingbitcoin-slides.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048416249791668225
Introduction I know that we&amp;rsquo;re running late in this session so I&amp;rsquo;ll try to keep this fast and get everyone to lunch. I have presented at Scaling Bitcoin four times now so I won&amp;rsquo;t dwell on the introduction. I wanted to talk about scaling bitcoin directly on chain in a way that is compatible with all existing node deployments.</description></item><item><title>Fraud Proofs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/fraud-proofs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/fraud-proofs/</guid><description>Improving SPV client validation and security with fraud proofs
Mustafa Al-Bassam (University College London)
paper: https://arxiv.org/pdf/1809.09044.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048446183004233731
Introduction I am going to be talking about fraud proofs. It allows lite clients to have a leve lof security of almost the level of a full node. Before I describe fraud proofs, how about we talk about motivations.
Motivations There&amp;rsquo;s a large tradeoff between blockchain decentralization and how much on-chain throughput you can get.</description></item><item><title>Ghostdag</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/ghostdag/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/ghostdag/</guid><description>The GHOSTDAG protocol
Yonatan Sompolinsky and Aviv Zohar (The Hebrew University of Jerusalem)
paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/104.pdf
Introduction This is joint work with Yonatan. I am going to talk about a DAG-based protocol to scale on-chain. The reason why I like this protocol is because it&amp;rsquo;s a very simple generalization of the longest-chain protocol that we all know and love. It gives some insight into what the role of proof-of-work is in these protocols.</description></item><item><title>How Much Privacy Is Enough</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/how-much-privacy-is-enough/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/how-much-privacy-is-enough/</guid><description>How much privacy is enough? Threats, scaling, and trade-offs in blockchain privacy protocols
Ian Miers (secparam)
unrelated, https://arxiv.org/pdf/1706.00916.pdf
Introductions Hi everybody. This is a talk on how much privacy is enough, evaluating trade-offs in privacy and scalability. This is going to be unusual for this conference because I will not be presenting new technical content. I am going to be talking about evaluating the tradeoffs between these scalability and privacy. As context, my name is Ian Miers.</description></item><item><title>Incentivizing Payment Channel Watchtowers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/incentivizing-payment-channel-watchtowers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/incentivizing-payment-channel-watchtowers/</guid><description>Incentivizing payment channel watchtowers
Georgia Avarikioti, Felix Laufenberg, Jakub Sliwinski, Yuyi Wang and Roger Wattenhofer (ETH Zurich)
Zeta Avarikioti
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048767166823071746
Introduction Hi. Good morning. I am Zeta. I am going to talk about how to incentivize payment channel watchtowers. This is joint work with my collaborators.
Micropayment channels There are many ways to construct channels such as lightning channels and duplex channels. There&amp;rsquo;s hops, you can route payments, and other proposals more recent ones for doing channels in payment networks like sprites, eltoo, all of them although they are different they all share the fundamental nature of channels.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/introduction/</guid><description>Anton Yemelyanov
Introduction
slides: https://tokyo2018.scalingbitcoin.org/presentations
Welcome to scaling bitcoin. This is an international conference. We run the event every year in a different geographical location. We run this event as a strictly academic and engineering conference. The mentality that we take behind the event is think global, act local. It&amp;rsquo;s a well known bitcoin additive. Our goal is to stimulate the bitcoin ecosystem. The best way to do this is to stimulate the engineering community, because that&amp;rsquo;s what drives this magnificent technology for the last almost 10 years now.</description></item><item><title>Multi Hop Locks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-hop-locks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-hop-locks/</guid><description>Multi-hop locks for secure, privacy-preserving and interoperable payment-channel networks
Giulio Malavolta (Friedrich-Alexander-University Erlangen-Nuernberg), Pedro Moreno-Sanchez (Purdue University), Clara Schneidewind (Vienna University of Technology), Aniket Kate (Purdue University) and Matteo Maffei (Vienna University of Technology)
https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/472.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048476273259900928
This is joint work with my colleagues. I promise I will talk slower than the last talk. In a multi-hop network, the security tool is a hash-time lock contract (HTLC) where the payment is conditioned on revealing the pre-image of a hash function.</description></item><item><title>Multi Party Channels In The Utxo Model Challenges And Opportunities</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-party-channels-in-the-utxo-model-challenges-and-opportunities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-party-channels-in-the-utxo-model-challenges-and-opportunities/</guid><description>Multi-party channels in the UTXO model: Challenges and opportunities
Olaoluwa Osuntokun (Lightning Labs) (roasbeef)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048468663089618944
Introductions Hi. So my name is Laolu. I am also known as roasbeef and I am co-founder of Lightning Labs. I am going to go over some cool research and science fiction. In the actual implementation for these things and cool to discuss and get some discussions around this. first I am going to talk about single-party channels and multi-party channels.</description></item><item><title>Omniledger</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/omniledger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/omniledger/</guid><description>Omniledger: A secure, scale-out, decentralized ledger via sharding
Eleftherios Kokoris-Kogias, Philipp Jovanovic, Linus Gasser, Nicolas Gailly, Ewa Syta and Bryan Ford (Ecole Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne)
(LefKok)
paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2017/406.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048733316839432192
Introduction I am Lefteris. I am a 4th year PhD student. I am here to talk about omniledger. It&amp;rsquo;s our architecture for a blockchain. It&amp;rsquo;s not directly related to bitcoin because it&amp;rsquo;s a different architecture. To begin, I would like to acknowledge my coauthors who collaborated on this project.</description></item><item><title>Playing With Fire Adjusting Bitcoin Block Subsidy</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/playing-with-fire-adjusting-bitcoin-block-subsidy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/playing-with-fire-adjusting-bitcoin-block-subsidy/</guid><description>slides: https://github.com/ajtowns/sc-btc-2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048401029148991488
Introduction First an apology about the title. I saw some comments on twitter after the talk was announced and they were speculating that I was going to break the 21 million coin limit. But that&amp;rsquo;s not the case. Rusty has a civil war thesis: the third era will start with the civil war, the mathematics of this situation seem einevitable. As the miners and businesses with large transaction volume will both decide to reintroduce inflation so that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to pay fees, fees just magically happen.</description></item><item><title>Rebalancing Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/rebalancing-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/rebalancing-lightning/</guid><description>Rebalancing in the lightning network: Analysis and implications
Sebastián Reca (Muun)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048753406628655105
Introduction This talk is going to be about rebalancing in the lightning network. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the implications and about running a lightning node.
Financial costs In the lightning network, routing nodes will incur in financial costs by having their money locked inside channels. They can&amp;rsquo;t use that money elsewhere. They incur a financial cost to doing this activity, at least an opportunity cost.</description></item><item><title>Reproducible Lightning Benchmark</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/reproducible-lightning-benchmark/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/reproducible-lightning-benchmark/</guid><description>Reproducible lightning benchmark
https://github.com/dgarage/LightningBenchmarks
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048760545699016705
Introduction Thanks for the introduction, Jameson. I feel like a rock star now. So yeah, I won&amp;rsquo;t introduce myself. I call myself a code monkey the reason is that a lot of the talks in scaling bitcoin can surprise people but I understood very few of them. The reason is that I am more of an application developer. Basically, I try to understand a lot of the talks but if it&amp;rsquo;s too complex then I just wait until some crypto guy makes a proof-of-concept, then I just make something in C# that other people can use.</description></item><item><title>Scriptless Ecdsa</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/scriptless-ecdsa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/scriptless-ecdsa/</guid><description>Instantiating scriptless 2p-ECDSA: fungible 2-of-2 multisigs for bitcoin today
Conner Fromknecht (Lightning Labs)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048483254087573504
maybe https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/472.pdf and https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/lightning-dev/2018-April/001221.html
Introduction Alright. Thank you very much. Thank you Pedro, that was a great segue into what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about. He has been doing work on formalizing multi-hop locks. I want to also talk about what changes might be necessary to deploy this on the lightning network.
History For what it&amp;rsquo;s worth, these dates are rough.</description></item><item><title>Self Reproducing Coins As Universal Turing Machine</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/self-reproducing-coins-as-universal-turing-machine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/self-reproducing-coins-as-universal-turing-machine/</guid><description>paper: https://arxiv.org/abs/1806.10116
Introduction This is joint work with my colleagues. I am Alexander Chepurnoy. We work for Ergo Platform. Vasily is an external member. This talk is about turing completeness in the blockchain. This talk will be pretty high-level. This talk is based on already-published paper, which was presented at the CBT conference. Because of copyright agreements with Springer, you will not find the latest version on arxiv.
The general question of scalability is how can we do more with less until we can do everything with nothing?</description></item><item><title>Statechains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/statechains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/statechains/</guid><description>Statechains: Off-chain transfer of UTXOs
I am the education director of readingbitcoin.org, and I am going to be talking about statechains for off-chain transfer of UTXOs.
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048799338703376385
Statechains This is another layer 2 scaling solution, by avoiding on-chain transactions. It&amp;rsquo;s similar to lightning network. The difference is that coin movement is not restricted. You deon&amp;rsquo;t have these channels where you have to have a path and send an exact amount. There&amp;rsquo;s some synergy with lightning; it&amp;rsquo;s not a replacement for lightning.</description></item></channel></rss>