<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bitcoin Edge Dev++ 2018 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/</link><description>Recent content in Bitcoin Edge Dev++ 2018 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Abstract Thinking About Consensus Systems</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/abstract-thinking-about-consensus-systems/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/abstract-thinking-about-consensus-systems/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048039485550690304
slides: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1LiGzgFXMI2zq8o9skErLcO3ET2YeQbyx/view?usp=sharing
Serialization Blocks are usually thought of as a serialized data stream. But really these are only true on the network serialization or over the network. A different implementation of bitcoin could in theory use a different format. The format is only used on the network and the disk, not the consensus protocol. The format could actually be completely different.
Each block is identified by a single cryptographic hash and it commits to various abstract information.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Toolchain, Unit Testing And Deterministic Builds</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/bitcoin-toolchain-unit-testing-and-deterministic-builds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/bitcoin-toolchain-unit-testing-and-deterministic-builds/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048103693885759489
Introduction Just to continue on what James said about the build system on Bitcoin Core&amp;hellip; I am going to talk about deterministic builds. I am MarcoFalke and I also work at Chaincode Labs in NYC.
Bitcoin Core Build System The build system is based on autotools, so it should just work anywhere where autotools runs. Just run ./autogen.sh ./configure and then make, that&amp;rsquo;s it.
We recently added support for MSVC builds mostly for Windows developers to do native builds not having to switch between Linux and Windows all the time.</description></item><item><title>Cross-Chain Swaps</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/cross-chain-swaps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/cross-chain-swaps/</guid><description>Ethan and Nicolas describe atomic cross-chain swaps - a protocol where two parties can exchange coins as a single operation. The exchange does not require any trusted third party and neither of the parties involved can cheat each other. They describe how this can be used on a single blockchain as a privacy protocol or “cross-chain” as a trading protocol.</description></item><item><title>Federated Chains, Sidechains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/sidechains-and-federation-models/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/sidechains-and-federation-models/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048008467871666178
Introduction The name &amp;ldquo;sidechain&amp;rdquo; is overloaded. My favorite private sidechain is my coach. That&amp;rsquo;s my private sidechain. Hopefully I can explain the high-level concepts of a sidechain, at a 10,000 foot view. What are these? What do they give you?
Sidechain components First you need a blockchain. It has to be something that builds a consensus history. The state of the ledger has to be recorded, or the account model, or whatever you&amp;rsquo;re doing.</description></item><item><title>Handling Reorgs &amp; Forks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/reorgs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/reorgs/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1052344700554960896
Introduction Good morning, my name is Bryan. I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking about reorganizations and forks in the bitcoin blockchain. First, I want to define what a reorganization is and what a fork is.
Definitions You might have heard that the bitcoin blockchain is a permanent data structure that records everything from all time and that is actually somewhat false. Instead, actually the bitcoin blockchain can be modified and changed, and some of these changes are called reorgs and some of these changes are called forks.</description></item><item><title>Interfacing with Python via python-bitcoinlib</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/python-bitcoinlib/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/python-bitcoinlib/</guid><description>python-bitcoinlib repo: https://github.com/petertodd/python-bitcoinlib
Bitcoin Edge schedule: https://keio-devplusplus-2018.bitcoinedge.org/#schedule
Twitter announcement: https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1052927707888189442
Transcript completed by: Bryan Bishop Edited by: Michael Folkson
Intro I will be talking about python-bitcoinlib.
whoami First I am going to start with an introduction slide. This is because I keep forgetting who I am so I have to write it down in all of my presentations. (Joke)
Before I get started, there is a presentation right after mine that is about libbitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Overview, Channel Factories, Discreet Log Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/lightning-network/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048039589837852672
Introduction I have quite a while to speak. I hope it&amp;rsquo;s not too boring. I&amp;rsquo;ll have an intermission half way through. It&amp;rsquo;s not going to be two hours. It will be more like 80 minutes or something. We are going to talk about payment channels, unidirectional payment channels, lightning channels, homomorphic keys, hash trees, watchtowers, discreet log contracts, oracles, anticipated signatures, DLCS within channels, etc.
I am Tadge Dryja. I work at MIT Digital Currency Initiative.</description></item><item><title>Overview Bitcoin Core Architecture</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/overview-bitcoin-core-architecture/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/overview-bitcoin-core-architecture/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048098034234445824
slides: http://jameso.be/dev++2018/
Introduction Alright guys, how are you guys doing? You guys look tired. Given your brains are probably fried, I am delighted to tell you that this talk will be pretty high level. I am James O&amp;rsquo;Beirne, I work at Chaincode Labs. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on Bitcoin Core since 2015. I am in New York most of the time.
Agenda Today we are going to talk about Bitcoin Core.</description></item><item><title>Protecting Yourself And Your Business</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/protecting-yourself-and-your-business/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/protecting-yourself-and-your-business/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048087226742071296
Introduction Hello. My name is Warren Togami and I will be talking about exchange security. Not only protecting the people but also the business. This has been a topic of interest recently.
Warren&amp;rsquo;s security background I have some credibility when it comes to security due to my previous career in open-source software. I have been working on the Linux operating system first with Fedora then with Red Hat for many years.</description></item><item><title>Blind Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/blind-signatures/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/blind-signatures/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1047648050234060800
See also http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/building-on-bitcoin/2018/blind-signatures-and-scriptless-scripts/
Introduction Hi everyone. I work at Commonwealth Crypto. Today I am going to be talking to you about blind signatures. I&amp;rsquo;d like to encourage people to ask questions. Please think of questions. I&amp;rsquo;ll give time and pause for people to ask questions.
What are blind signatures? A very informal definition of blind signatures is that they are a signature scheme that allows one party to sign a message without learning the message they signed.</description></item><item><title>Block Structure And Headers Utxos Merkle Trees Segwit Bip141</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/block-structure-and-headers-utxos-merkle-trees-segwit-bip141/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/block-structure-and-headers-utxos-merkle-trees-segwit-bip141/</guid><description>Block structure &amp;amp; headers, UTXO, Merkle Trees, Address, Proof-of-Work &amp;amp; Difficulty, SegWit (BIP141)
This presentation was spoken in Japanese. I don&amp;rsquo;t speak Japanese, but I made a live translation as I listened anyway: https://docs.google.com/document/d/1ngqP9_Ep4x7iwTqF6Vvqm1Ob97A_a1irXMUc2ZHsEt4/edit</description></item><item><title>Bulletproofs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/bulletproofs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/bulletproofs/</guid><description>Overview of Bullet Proofs - a new zero-knowledge cryptographical solution for confidential transactions</description></item><item><title>Coin Selection</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/coin-selection/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/coin-selection/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1047708247333859328
Introduction I am going to do a short talk on coin selection. Everyone calls me kalle. In Japanese, my name is kalle. Coin selection, what it is, how it works, and interestingly enough- in the latest version of Bitcoin Core released yesterday, they have changed the coin selection algorithm for the first time since a long time. They are now using something with more scientific rigor behind it (branch-and-bound coin selection), which is good news.</description></item><item><title>Finite fields, Elliptic curves, ECDSA, Schnorr</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/digital-signatures/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/digital-signatures/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1047634593619181568
Introduction Thank you to Anton and to everyone at Keio University and Digital Garage. I have an hour to talk about digital signatures, finite fields, ECDSA, Schnorr signatures, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of ground to cover. I&amp;rsquo;m going to move quickly and start from a high level.
My name is John. I live in New York. I work at a company called Chaincode Labs. Most of the time, I contribute to Bitcoin Core.</description></item><item><title>Hierarchical Deterministic Wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/hierarchical-deterministic-wallets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/hierarchical-deterministic-wallets/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1047714436889235456
https://teachbitcoin.io/presentations/wallets.html
Introduction My name is James Chiang. Quick introduction about myself. My contributions to bitcoin have been on the project libbitcoin where I do documentation. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working through the APIs and libraries. I think it&amp;rsquo;s a great toolkit. Eric Voskuil is speaking later today and he also works on libbitcoin. I also volunteered to talk about hierarchical deterministic wallets.
When we talk about bitcoin wallets, you always have some kind of secret or entropy you want to keep safe.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Bitcoin Edge Dev++ and Bc2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/introduction/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/introduction/</guid><description>We will be using two screens. The english will be on the front screen and the japanese will be on the other screen to the side here. We will also be sharing a google docs file for each one in slack. We should help each other and teach better and learn these things. Without further adue, here&amp;rsquo;s Anton from Bitcoin Edge.
Hi everybody. Welcome to Dev++. It started last year at Stanford 2017 where we trained 100 people.</description></item><item><title>P2PKH, P2WPKH, P2SH, P2WSH</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/p2pkh-p2wpkh-p2h-p2wsh/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/p2pkh-p2wpkh-p2h-p2wsh/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1047697572444270592
Introduction This is going to be a bit of a re-tread I think. I am going to be talking about common bitcoin script templates used in bitcoin today.
Addresses do not exist on the blockchain. But scripts do. You&amp;rsquo;ve heard about p2pk, p2pkh, p2sh, and others. I&amp;rsquo;m going to go over these anyway.
Pay-to-pubkey (p2pk) This was the first type. It had no address format actually. Nodes connected to each other over IP address, with no authentication.</description></item><item><title>Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions (BIP174)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/partially-signed-bitcoin-transactions-bip174/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/partially-signed-bitcoin-transactions-bip174/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1047730297242935296
Introduction Bryan briefly mentioned partially-signed bitcoin transactions (PSBT). I can give more depth on this. There&amp;rsquo;s history and motivation, a background of why this is important, what these things are doing. What is the software doing?
History and motivation Historically, there was no standard for this. Armory had its own format. Bitcoin Core had network-serialized transactions. This ensures fragmentation and it&amp;rsquo;s incomplete and bad that there was no standard. For segwit, a transaction to a legacy node looks like a zero-input transaction, which is a way to flag it as a segwit transaction.</description></item><item><title>Scripts (general &amp; simple)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/scripts-general-and-simple/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/scripts-general-and-simple/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1047679223115083777
Introduction I am going to talk about why we have scripts in bitcoin. I&amp;rsquo;ll give some examples and the design philosophy. I am not going to talk about the semantics of bitcoin script, though. Why do we have bitcoin script? I&amp;rsquo;ll show how to lock and unlock coins. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about pay-to-pubkey, multisig, and computing vs verification in the blockchain.
Why have script at all? In my first talk, I talked about digital signatures to transfer coins from one person to another.</description></item><item><title>SIGHASH_NOINPUT (BIP118)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/sighash-noinput/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/sighash-noinput/</guid><description>SIGHASH_NOINPUT (BIP118)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1049510702384173057
Hi, my name is Bryan, I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking about SIGHASH NOINPUT. It was something that I was asked to speak about. It is currently not deployed, but it is an active proposal.
So, just really brief about who I am. I have a software development background. I just left LedgerX last week, so that is an exciting change in my life. Also, I contribute to bitcoin core, usually as code review.</description></item><item><title>Taproot and Graftroot</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/taproot-and-graftroot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/taproot-and-graftroot/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1047764770265284608
Introduction Taproot and graftroot are recent proposals in the bitcoin world. Every script type looks different and they are distinct. From a privacy perspective, that&amp;rsquo;s pretty bad. You watermark or fingerprint yourself all the time by showing unique scripts on the blockchain or in your transactions. This causes censorship risks and other problems for fungibility. Often you are paying for contigencies that are never used, like the whoopsies branches in your scripts.</description></item><item><title>Wallet Security, Key Management &amp; Hardware Security Modules (HSMs)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/wallet-security/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/wallet-security/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1049813559750746112
Intro Alright, I’m now going to talk about bitcoin wallet security. And I was asked to talk about key management and hardware security modules and a bunch of other topics all in one talk. This will be a bit broader than some of the other talks because this is an important subject about how do you actually store bitcoin and then some of the developments around the actual storage of bitcoin in a secure way.</description></item></channel></rss>