<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Point Time Locked Contracts (PTLCs) on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/ptlc/</link><description>Recent content in Point Time Locked Contracts (PTLCs) on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/ptlc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Simple Taproot Channels</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/simple-taproot-channels/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/simple-taproot-channels/</guid><description>Elle Mouton and Oliver Gugger explained the transition from 2-of-2 Pay-to-Witness-Script-Hash funding outputs to MuSig2 key funding outputs in Taproot channels. This upgrade aims to enhance privacy and chain space savings. The spec for Taproot channels, proposed by Roasbeef, is nearing completion with notable progress from LND and LDK implementations. The podcast also delved into potential updates to the gossip protocol, distinguishing between Gossip 1.5 and 2.0. Gossip 2.0 proposes tying proofs to node announcements rather than individual channels, significantly boosting privacy. The discussion extended to PTLCs (Point Time-Locked Contracts), which promise enhanced privacy and security but require further adoption and development. The iterative approach to these upgrades emphasizes gradual implementation to mitigate risks and ensure stability</description></item><item><title>Coinjoin Done Right: the onchain offchain mix (and anti-Sybil with RIDDLE)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/coinjoin-done-right-the-onchain-offchain-mix-and-anti-sybil-with-riddles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/coinjoin-done-right-the-onchain-offchain-mix-and-anti-sybil-with-riddles/</guid><description>NOTE: Slides of the talk can be found here
Introduction My name&amp;rsquo;s Adam Gibson, also known as waxwing on the internet. Though the title might suggest that I have the solution to the problem of implementing CoinJoin, it&amp;rsquo;s not exactly true. It&amp;rsquo;s a clickbait. I haven&amp;rsquo;t, but I suppose what I can say in a more serious way is that I&amp;rsquo;m proposing what I consider to be a meaningfully different alternative way of looking at the concept of CoinJoin and therefore at the concept of on-chain privacy because the conversation nowadays about on-chain privacy tends to be dominated by CoinJoin.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2022/lightning-panel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2022/lightning-panel/</guid><description>The discussion primarily revolved around the Lightning Network, a scaling solution for Bitcoin designed to enable faster, decentralized transactions. Rene Pickhardt and Lisa Neigut shared their insights, highlighting Lightning&amp;rsquo;s potential as a peer-to-peer electronic cash system and a future payment infrastructure. They emphasized its efficiency for frequent transactions between trusted parties but noted challenges in its current infrastructure, such as the need for continuous online operation and the risk of losing funds if a node is compromised. The panelists discussed the scalability of the network, indicating that while millions could use it self-sovereignly, larger-scale adoption would likely involve centralized service providers. The conversation also touched on the impact of Taproot on privacy and channel efficiency, and the technical intricacies of maintaining state and preventing fraud within the network.</description></item><item><title>Sydney Socratic Seminar</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-02-23-socratic-seminar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-02-23-socratic-seminar/</guid><description>Topic: Agenda in Google Doc below
Video: No video posted online
Google Doc of the resources discussed: https://docs.google.com/document/d/1VAP4LNjHHVLy9RJwpQ8LqXEUw79z5TTZxr9du_Z0-9A/
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
PoDLEs revisited (Lloyd Fournier) https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/lightning-dev/2021-January/002929.html
We’ll start with me talking about my research into UTXO probing attacks on Lightning in the dual funding proposal.</description></item><item><title>Payment Points</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/payment-points/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/payment-points/</guid><description>Nadav Kohen: 00:00:00
Right now in the Lightning Network, if I were to make a payment every single hop along that route, they would know that they&amp;rsquo;re on the same route, because every single HTLC uses the same hash. It&amp;rsquo;s a bad privacy leak. It&amp;rsquo;s actually a much worse privacy leak now that we have multi-path payments, because every single path along your multi-path payment uses the same hash as well.</description></item><item><title>A Schnorr-Taproot’ed Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-06-antoine-riard-taproot-lightning/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-06-antoine-riard-taproot-lightning/</guid><description>Slides: https://www.dropbox.com/s/9vs54e9bqf317u0/Schnorr-Taproot%27ed-LN.pdf
Intro Today Schnorr and Taproot for Lightning, it is a really exciting topic.
Lightning architecture The Lightning architecture for those who are not familiar with it. You have the blockchain as the underlying layer. On top of it you are going to build a channel, you have a HTLC and people are going to spend onions to you. If you want to be paid you are going to send an invoice to the sender.</description></item><item><title>Replacing Payment Hashes with Payment Points</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-conference/2019/2019-10-20-nadav-kohen-payment-points/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-conference/2019/2019-10-20-nadav-kohen-payment-points/</guid><description>Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/15l4h2_zEY4zXC6n1NqsImcjgA0fovl_lkgkKu1O3QT0/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1220453531683115020
Intro My name is Nadav Kohen. I’m a software engineer at Suredbits. I’m going to talk about payment points which have been alluded to throughout the conference by various talks.
Hash Timelocked Contract (HTLC) Routing First of all, some preliminaries, HTLCs. I don’t think I’m going to spend much time on this slide. We all know what they are. For every hop forward you add a hash timelocked contract.</description></item></channel></rss>