<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Learning Bitcoin and Design on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/learning-bitcoin-and-design/</link><description>Recent content in Learning Bitcoin and Design on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/learning-bitcoin-and-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Covenants Part 2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/learning-bitcoin-and-design/covenants-part-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/learning-bitcoin-and-design/covenants-part-2/</guid><description>Introduction Christoph Ono: 00:00:01
All right, welcome to our second learning Bitcoin and Design call about covenants. Today, the idea was to go deeper into covenants use cases, right? Last time, the first call was more about just generally what it is and what it does. Now we wanted to go deeper. I think on the web, on the GitHub issue, there was one request about congestion control. But the other big one was scaling, I think.</description></item><item><title>Silent Payments</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/learning-bitcoin-and-design/silent-payments/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/learning-bitcoin-and-design/silent-payments/</guid><description>Silent payments are introduced as a method to enhance Bitcoin transactions&amp;rsquo; privacy and usability by addressing the issue of address reuse. Unlike traditional methods, silent payments use elliptic curve Diffie-Hellman (ECDH) to generate unique addresses for each transaction without interaction. This preserves user privacy and simplifies the process. Josibake explains the design rationale, technical challenges, and implementation strategies. He emphasizes the need for widespread adoption of sending capabilities and highlights the potential applications in exchanges and other services. The discussion also covers the trade-offs between privacy and computational overhead, proposing solutions to ensure efficient implementation and user education.</description></item><item><title>Covenants</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/learning-bitcoin-and-design/covenants/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/learning-bitcoin-and-design/covenants/</guid><description>Introductions Christoph Ono: 00:00:01
Welcome to our first Learning Bitcoin and Design call of 2024. We haven&amp;rsquo;t had one of these in a while, but we&amp;rsquo;re picking them back up again. The first topic is a really tough one, I think at least, it&amp;rsquo;s covenants. The reason, one of the reasons why this came up is because on Bitcoin Design, we have this new design challenge. We have a page with design challenges that are meant to be kind of take home challenges.</description></item><item><title>FediMint</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/learning-bitcoin-and-design/fedimint/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/learning-bitcoin-and-design/fedimint/</guid><description>Introduction Stephen DeLorme: 00:00:04
All right. Welcome, everybody. This is the Learning Bitcoin and Design Call. It&amp;rsquo;s July 26, 2022. And our topic this week is FediMint. And we have Justin Moon here with us and several designers and product folks in the room here that are interested in learning about this. So I&amp;rsquo;ve got a FigJam open here where we can toss images, ideas, text, links, whatever we want to consolidate during the call.</description></item></channel></rss>