<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Developers-Miners Meeting on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-developers-miners-meeting-2016/</link><description>Recent content in Developers-Miners Meeting on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-developers-miners-meeting-2016/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cali 2016</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-developers-miners-meeting-2016/cali2016/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-developers-miners-meeting-2016/cali2016/</guid><description>California Gathering 2016
Transcription introduction Some Bitcoin developers and miners gathered together during the end of the July to socialize and become better acquainted with each other. The following discussions were live transcribed by an untrained volunteer with attribution removed as per Chatham House rules. In bitcoin, discussions can move very quickly, which can cause an increase in errors, including semantic errors, when typing in real time. This text was not produced from an audio recording.</description></item><item><title>Dan Boneh</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-developers-miners-meeting-2016/dan-boneh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-developers-miners-meeting-2016/dan-boneh/</guid><description>A conversation with Dan Boneh
2016-08-01
Part of the challenge was that the Google Maps directions in the email were going down some roads that had construction&amp;hellip;. been here 10 minutes, and some arriving in another 10 minutes. They are building a new biology building. Large campus here. In whatever direction you walk, there are buildings and more buildings. In two years there will be a new biology building, and two years later there will be a new computer science building.</description></item><item><title>Jihan Wu Google Tech Talk (2016)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-developers-miners-meeting-2016/jihan-wu-google-tech-talk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-developers-miners-meeting-2016/jihan-wu-google-tech-talk/</guid><description>Jihan Wu
Bitcoin
Google Tech Talk
Okay so maybe we will start. Thank you for coming. We have about 25 folks here from the Bitcoin community, both miners and Core developers. Don&amp;rsquo;t know exactly what the definition of a Core developer is, but I guess I know one when I see one. So anyway, we&amp;rsquo;re lucky here to have Jihan Wu. He&amp;rsquo;s the co-founder of Bitmain, a leading Chinese bitcoin technology company and mining pool.</description></item></channel></rss>