<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Carla Kirk-Cohen on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/carla-kirk-cohen/</link><description>Recent content in Carla Kirk-Cohen on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/carla-kirk-cohen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Routing Problems and Solutions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/edgedevplusplus/2019-09-09-carla-kirk-cohen-routing-problems-and-solutions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/edgedevplusplus/2019-09-09-carla-kirk-cohen-routing-problems-and-solutions/</guid><description>Topic: Routing Problems and Solutions
Location: Tel-Aviv 2019
Introduction I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking about routing in the Lightning Network now. So I&amp;rsquo;m going to touch on how it&amp;rsquo;s currently operating, some issues that you run into when you are routing, and then some potential expansions to the spec which are going to address some of these issues.
We ran through the Lightning Network graph: the nodes of vertices, the channels in this graph of edges.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Layer By Layer</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/edgedevplusplus/lightning-network-layer-by-layer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/edgedevplusplus/lightning-network-layer-by-layer/</guid><description>Topic: The Lightning Network Layer by Layer
Location: Dev++ O3-19 Tel Aviv
Introduction Good afternoon everyone. My name is Carla. I&amp;rsquo;m one of the Chaincode residents from the summer residency that they ran in New York this year and this afternoon I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking about Lightning. In this talk, I&amp;rsquo;m gonna be walking you through the protocol layer by layer and having a look at the different components that make up the Lightning Network.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Routing</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/edgedevplusplus/lightning-network-routing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/edgedevplusplus/lightning-network-routing/</guid><description>Introduction Good afternoon everyone. My name is Carla. I am one of the chaincode residents this summer. This talk is going to walk through the protocol layer by layer and look at the different components that make up the network. Lightning is an off-chain scaling solution which consists of a p2p network of payment channels. It allows payments to be forwarded by nodes in exchange for fees.
Scaling with payment channels This involves a payment channel.</description></item><item><title>Lightning network topology, its creation and maintenance</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/edgedevplusplus/lightning-network-topology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/edgedevplusplus/lightning-network-topology/</guid><description>Carla Kirk-Cohen
Introduction Alright. Give me a second to test this. Alright. Antoine has taken you through the routing layer. I&amp;rsquo;m going to take you through what the lightning network looks like today. This is the current topology of the network and how this came about, and some approaches for maintaining the network and making the graph look like we want it to look.
Lightning brief overview There&amp;rsquo;s ideally only two transactions involved in any lightning channel, the commitment transaction and the closure transaction.</description></item></channel></rss>