<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kalle Alm on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/kalle-alm/</link><description>Recent content in Kalle Alm on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/kalle-alm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Signet Workshop</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-07-kalle-alm-signet-workshop/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-07-kalle-alm-signet-workshop/</guid><description>Topic: Signet Workshop
Location: Advancing Bitcoin
Video: No video posted online
Let’s prepare mkdir workspace cd workspace git clone https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin.git cd bitcoin git remote add kallewoof https://github.com/kallewoof/bitcoin.git git fetch kallewoof git checkout signet ./autogen.sh ./configure -C --disable-bench --disable-test --without-gui make -j5 When you try to run the configure part you are going to have some problems if you don’t have the dependencies. If you don’t have the dependencies Google your OS and “Bitcoin build”.</description></item><item><title>Signet Integration</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-06-kalle-alm-signet-integration/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-06-kalle-alm-signet-integration/</guid><description>Topic: Signet Integration
Location: Advancing Bitcoin
Date: February 6th 2020
Slides: https://www.dropbox.com/s/6fqwhx7ugr3ppsg/Signet%20Integration%20V2.pdf
BIP 325: https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/master/bip-0325.mediawiki
Signet on Bitcoin Wiki: https://en.bitcoin.it/wiki/Signet
Bitcoin dev mailing list: https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2019-March/016734.html
Bitcoin Core PR 16411 (closed): https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/16411
Bitcoin Core PR 18267 (open): https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/pull/18267
Intro I am going to talk about Signet. Do you guys know what Signet is? A few people know. I will explain it briefly. I have an elevator pitch, I have three actually depending on the height of the elevator.</description></item><item><title>Signet annd its uses for development</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/signet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/signet/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171310731100381184
https://explorer.bc-2.jp/
Introduction I was going to talk about signet yesterday but people had some delay downloading docker images. How many of you have signet right now? How many think you have signet right now? How many downloaded something yesterday? How many docker users? And how many people have compiled it themselves? Okay. I think we have like 10 people. The people that compiled it yourself, I think you&amp;rsquo;re going to be able to do this.</description></item><item><title>Mempool Analysis &amp; Simulation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/2019-06-08-mempool-analysis-simulation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/2019-06-08-mempool-analysis-simulation/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137342023063744512
slides: https://breaking-bitcoin.com/docs/slides/2019/mempoolAnalysis.pdf
Introduction Fun fact: I don&amp;rsquo;t think anyone knows this fact, but antpool is a miner and antpool is not mining replace-by-fee transactions. What I mean by that is that if you do a replace-by-fee transaction, they will ignore the second high fee transaction. There are cases where transactions are RBF-bumped to increase the fee to make it mined faster, so you RBF bump it, and then you have people spending the unconfirmed RBF version and then have a chain of transactions but then the original transaction is mined and not the other chained transactions.</description></item><item><title>Signmessage</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-10/2018-10-10-signmessage/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-10/2018-10-10-signmessage/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1049834659306061829
signmessage kallewoof and others
I am trying to make a new signmessage to do other things. Just use the signature system inside bitcoin to sign a message. Sign a message that someone wants. You can use proof-of-funds or whatever.
You could just have a signature and it&amp;rsquo;s a signature inside of a package and it&amp;rsquo;s small and easy. Another option is to have a .. that is invalid somehow. You do a transaction with some input, where the txid is the message hash or something.</description></item><item><title>Bulletproofs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/bulletproofs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/bulletproofs/</guid><description>Overview of Bullet Proofs - a new zero-knowledge cryptographical solution for confidential transactions</description></item><item><title>Coin Selection</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/coin-selection/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/coin-selection/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1047708247333859328
Introduction I am going to do a short talk on coin selection. Everyone calls me kalle. In Japanese, my name is kalle. Coin selection, what it is, how it works, and interestingly enough- in the latest version of Bitcoin Core released yesterday, they have changed the coin selection algorithm for the first time since a long time. They are now using something with more scientific rigor behind it (branch-and-bound coin selection), which is good news.</description></item><item><title>Optimizing Fee Estimation Via Mempool State</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/optimizing-fee-estimation-via-mempool-state/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/optimizing-fee-estimation-via-mempool-state/</guid><description>I am a Bitcoin Core developer and I work at DG Lab. Today I would like to talk about fees. There&amp;rsquo;s this weird gap between&amp;ndash; there are two things going on. People complain about high fees. But people are confused about why Bitcoin Core is giving high fees but if you set fees manually you can get a much lower fee and get a transaction mined pretty fast. I started to look into this in detail and did simulations and a bunch of stuff.</description></item></channel></rss>