<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sidechains on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/sidechains/</link><description>Recent content in sidechains on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/sidechains/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bitcoin Sidechains - Unchained Epicenter Adam3Us, Gmaxwell (2015-02-03)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/bitcoin-sidechains-unchained-epicenter-adam3us-gmaxwell/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/bitcoin-sidechains-unchained-epicenter-adam3us-gmaxwell/</guid><description>EB65 – Adam Back &amp;amp; Greg Maxwell: Sidechains Unchained
2015-02-03
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jE_elgnIw3M
people:
Sebastien Couture Brian Fabian Crain Adam Back (adam3us) Greg Maxwell (gmaxwell) Brian: We are here today we have Adam Back and Greg Maxwell, to anyone who is following bitcoin and bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s development, you will have probably heard of these two gentlemen. I was fortunate enough that the first time that I went to a bitcoin conference at the beginning of my involvement in this space, it was in Amsterdam 2013 and I somehow randomly ended up having dinner twice with Adam which really was super fascinating talking to him about bitcoin, and so I&amp;rsquo;m really exciting to have them on today, especially since we are going to have a chance to talk about a project we have talked about many times on this show before, with different people, which is sidechains, because sidechains I think that everyone is in agreement that it is one of the more interesting projects in the space, and a lot of people have many questions about it.</description></item><item><title>Epicenter Bitcoin Adam3Us Scalability (2015-09-07)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2015-09-07-epicenter-bitcoin-adam3us-scalability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2015-09-07-epicenter-bitcoin-adam3us-scalability/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Why bitcoin needs a measured approach to scaling&amp;rdquo;
video: https://youtube.com/watch?v=wYHyR2E5Pic
Adam Back (adam3us) Epicenter (EC)
Sebastien Couture (SC) Brian Fabian Crain (BC)
BC: Adam Back is here for the second time on this show. Some of you will be familiar that Adam Back is the inventor of proof-of-work or hashcash as it was then. He was one of the few people cited in the original Bitcoin whitepaper. More recently he has been involved in sidechains and Blockstream where he is a founder.</description></item><item><title>Plasma Cash</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/plasma-cash/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/plasma-cash/</guid><description>Plasma Cash: Towards more efficient plasma constructions
Non-custodial sidechains for bitcoin utilizing plasma cash and covenants
Georgios Konstantopoulos
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1172108023705284609
paper: https://github.com/loomnetwork/plasma-paper/blob/master/plasma_cash.pdf
slides: https://gakonst.com/scalingbitcoin2019.pdf
Introduction We have known how to do these things for at least a year, but the question is how can we find the minimum changes that we can figure out to do in bitcoin if any on how to explore the layer 2 space in a better sense rather than just accepting that lightning network is the dominant solution?</description></item><item><title>Provenance Groups</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/provenance-groups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/provenance-groups/</guid><description>Give the name of your tech topic table. You have three minutes to summarize. When you have one minute to summarize, I will give you the one minute warning. When you have zero minutes left, you will be thrown out the window.
Media rights We talked about media rights and payments. The ability to figure out the incentive structure for whether we can compensate people who create page views with people who have view rights and how that all works.</description></item><item><title>Russell Oconnor Simplicity (2019-10-15)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/2019-10-15-russell-oconnor-simplicity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/2019-10-15-russell-oconnor-simplicity/</guid><description>Name: Russell O’Connor
Topic: Simplicity
Location: CES Summit 2019
Date: October 15th 2019
Video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Pn5rySgyTQ0
Slides: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1FivYGQzOYfM0JGl4SS3VR1UGKsyMn_L5/
Simplicity white paper: https://blockstream.com/simplicity.pdf
Intro So Simplicity is a programming language that I have been working on at Blockstream. I call it an alternative or reimagination of Bitcoin Script as it would have been if I had invented Bitcoin. An alternative or new instruction set that is compatible with Bitcoin. It could be soft forked in.</description></item><item><title>Secure Protocols Bip Taproot</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/secure-protocols-bip-taproot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/secure-protocols-bip-taproot/</guid><description>Secure protocols on BIP-taproot
Jonas Nick
36C7 1A37 C9D9 88BD E825 08D9 B1A7 0E4F 8DCD 0366
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137358557584793600
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06-06-taproot/
slides: https://nickler.ninja/slides/2019-breaking.pdf
Introduction I am going to tlak about something that is a collaboration of many people in the bitcoin community including my colleagues at Blockstream. The bip-taproot proposal was recently posted to the bitcoin-dev mailing list which proposes an improvement for bitcoin.
Disclaimer It&amp;rsquo;s not at all certain that a bip-taproot soft-fork will activate in its current form or at all.</description></item><item><title>Statechains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/statechains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/statechains/</guid><description>Statechains: Off-chain transfer of UTXOs
Ruben Somsen
I am the education director of readingbitcoin.org, and I am going to be talking about statechains for off-chain transfer of UTXOs.
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048799338703376385
Statechains This is another layer 2 scaling solution, by avoiding on-chain transactions. It&amp;rsquo;s similar to lightning network. The difference is that coin movement is not restricted. You deon&amp;rsquo;t have these channels where you have to have a path and send an exact amount.</description></item></channel></rss>