<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sidechains on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/sidechains/</link><description>Recent content in sidechains on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/sidechains/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Simplicity</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/2019-10-15-russell-oconnor-simplicity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/2019-10-15-russell-oconnor-simplicity/</guid><description>Topic: Simplicity
Location: CES Summit 2019
Slides: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1FivYGQzOYfM0JGl4SS3VR1UGKsyMn_L5/
Simplicity white paper: https://blockstream.com/simplicity.pdf
Intro So Simplicity is a programming language that I have been working on at Blockstream. I call it an alternative or reimagination of Bitcoin Script as it would have been if I had invented Bitcoin. An alternative or new instruction set that is compatible with Bitcoin. It could be soft forked in. We’ve experimented with it on sidechains such as Elements or Liquid.</description></item><item><title>Statechains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/statechains/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/statechains/</guid><description>Schnorr signatures, adaptor signatures and statechains
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171345418237685760
Introduction If you want to know the details of statechains, I recommend checking out my talk from Breaking Bitcoin 2019 Amsterdam. I&amp;rsquo;ll give a quick recap of Schnorr signatures and adaptor signatures and then statechains. I think it&amp;rsquo;s important to understand Schnorr signatures to the point where you&amp;rsquo;re really comfortable with it. A lot of the cool stuff in bitcoin right now is related to or using Schnorr signatures.</description></item><item><title>Secure Protocols Bip Taproot</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/secure-protocols-bip-taproot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/secure-protocols-bip-taproot/</guid><description>36C7 1A37 C9D9 88BD E825 08D9 B1A7 0E4F 8DCD 0366
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137358557584793600
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06-06-taproot/
slides: https://nickler.ninja/slides/2019-breaking.pdf
Introduction I am going to tlak about something that is a collaboration of many people in the bitcoin community including my colleagues at Blockstream. The bip-taproot proposal was recently posted to the bitcoin-dev mailing list which proposes an improvement for bitcoin.
Disclaimer It&amp;rsquo;s not at all certain that a bip-taproot soft-fork will activate in its current form or at all.</description></item><item><title>Drivechain</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/austin-bitcoin-developers/2019-05-27-drivechain-paul-sztorc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/austin-bitcoin-developers/2019-05-27-drivechain-paul-sztorc/</guid><description>Drivechain: An interoperability layer-2, Described in terms of the lightning network- something you already understand
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1133202672570519552
About me Okay. So here&amp;rsquo;s some things about myself. I&amp;rsquo;ve been a bitcoiner since 2012. I&amp;rsquo;ve published bitcoin research on truthcoin.info blog. I&amp;rsquo;ve presented at Scaling Bitcoin 1, 2, 3, 4, tabconf, and Building on Bitcoin. My background is in economics and statistics. I worked at Yale Econ Department as a statistician for 2.5 years.</description></item><item><title>Federated Chains, Sidechains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/sidechains-and-federation-models/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/sidechains-and-federation-models/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048008467871666178
Introduction The name &amp;ldquo;sidechain&amp;rdquo; is overloaded. My favorite private sidechain is my coach. That&amp;rsquo;s my private sidechain. Hopefully I can explain the high-level concepts of a sidechain, at a 10,000 foot view. What are these? What do they give you?
Sidechain components First you need a blockchain. It has to be something that builds a consensus history. The state of the ledger has to be recorded, or the account model, or whatever you&amp;rsquo;re doing.</description></item><item><title>Epicenter Bitcoin - Scalability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2015-09-07-epicenter-bitcoin-adam3us-scalability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2015-09-07-epicenter-bitcoin-adam3us-scalability/</guid><description>Why bitcoin needs a measured approach to scaling
Name: Adam Back (adam3us) Epicenter (EC)
Sebastien Couture (SC) Brian Fabian Crain (BC)
BC: Adam Back is here for the second time on this show. Some of you will be familiar that Adam Back is the inventor of proof-of-work or hashcash as it was then. He was one of the few people cited in the original Bitcoin whitepaper. More recently he has been involved in sidechains and Blockstream where he is a founder.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Sidechains - Unchained Epicenter</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/bitcoin-sidechains-unchained-epicenter-adam3us-gmaxwell/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/bitcoin-sidechains-unchained-epicenter-adam3us-gmaxwell/</guid><description>EB65 – Adam Back &amp;amp; Greg Maxwell: Sidechains Unchained
people:
Sebastien Couture Brian Fabian Crain Adam Back (adam3us) Greg Maxwell (gmaxwell) Brian: We are here today we have Adam Back and Greg Maxwell, to anyone who is following bitcoin and bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s development, you will have probably heard of these two gentlemen. I was fortunate enough that the first time that I went to a bitcoin conference at the beginning of my involvement in this space, it was in Amsterdam 2013 and I somehow randomly ended up having dinner twice with Adam which really was super fascinating talking to him about bitcoin, and so I&amp;rsquo;m really exciting to have them on today, especially since we are going to have a chance to talk about a project we have talked about many times on this show before, with different people, which is sidechains, because sidechains I think that everyone is in agreement that it is one of the more interesting projects in the space, and a lot of people have many questions about it.</description></item><item><title>Plasma Cash</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/plasma-cash/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/plasma-cash/</guid><description>Plasma Cash: Towards more efficient plasma constructions
Non-custodial sidechains for bitcoin utilizing plasma cash and covenants
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1172108023705284609
paper: https://github.com/loomnetwork/plasma-paper/blob/master/plasma_cash.pdf
slides: https://gakonst.com/scalingbitcoin2019.pdf
Introduction We have known how to do these things for at least a year, but the question is how can we find the minimum changes that we can figure out to do in bitcoin if any on how to explore the layer 2 space in a better sense rather than just accepting that lightning network is the dominant solution?</description></item><item><title>Provenance Groups</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/provenance-groups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/provenance-groups/</guid><description>Give the name of your tech topic table. You have three minutes to summarize. When you have one minute to summarize, I will give you the one minute warning. When you have zero minutes left, you will be thrown out the window.
Media rights We talked about media rights and payments. The ability to figure out the incentive structure for whether we can compensate people who create page views with people who have view rights and how that all works.</description></item><item><title>Sidechains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/matt-corallo-sidechains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/matt-corallo-sidechains/</guid><description>Sidechains, Blockstream
One second. Technical difficulties. Okay, sorry about that. Okay. Hi. I am Matt or BlueMatt for those of you know me. I swear it&amp;rsquo;s not related to my hair. Nobody believes me.
I got into Bitcoin three or four years ago because I was interested in the programming and computer science aspects and as well as my interest in large-scale economic incentive structures and macroeconomics and how we create incentive structures that create actions on a low level by rational actors.</description></item><item><title>Sidechains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/sidechains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/sidechains/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784767020290150400
slides https://scalingbitcoin.org/milan2016/presentations/D1%20-%209%20-%20Paul.pdf
Before we begin, we will explain how the workshops will work upstairs. There will be some topics and room numbers. Now we will start the next presentation on sidechain scaling with Paul Sztorc. Thank you everyone.
Thanks a lot. So this talk will be a little different. Scaling via strategy, not physics. This will not change the kilobytes sent over&amp;ndash; it will, just not in the literal sense.</description></item><item><title>Statechains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/statechains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/statechains/</guid><description>Statechains: Off-chain transfer of UTXOs
I am the education director of readingbitcoin.org, and I am going to be talking about statechains for off-chain transfer of UTXOs.
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048799338703376385
Statechains This is another layer 2 scaling solution, by avoiding on-chain transactions. It&amp;rsquo;s similar to lightning network. The difference is that coin movement is not restricted. You deon&amp;rsquo;t have these channels where you have to have a path and send an exact amount. There&amp;rsquo;s some synergy with lightning; it&amp;rsquo;s not a replacement for lightning.</description></item></channel></rss>