<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sidechains on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/sidechains/</link><description>Recent content in Sidechains on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/sidechains/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Scaling to Billions of Users</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/scaling-to-billions-of-users/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/scaling-to-billions-of-users/</guid><description>In this episode, Aaron and Sjors discuss a recent blog post by Bitcoin Core developer Anthony Towns, “Putting the B in BTC”, in which he outlines a vision for scaling Bitcoin to facilitate billions of users. As Aaron and Sjors walk through the article, they explain what some of Towns’ proposed solutions are, and which tradeoffs they entail.</description></item><item><title>Building Trustless Bridges</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/layer-2/building-trustless-bridges/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/layer-2/building-trustless-bridges/</guid><description>Many mechanisms have been created that enable users to lock BTC on the mainchain, transfer a claim on the BTC in some offchain system, and then later redeem the claim and take ownership of the underlying BTC. Colloquially known as &amp;ldquo;bridges&amp;rdquo;, these mechanisms offer a diverse range of security and usability properties for users to choose from depending on their risk tolerance and cost preferences. This talk will give an overview of the different types of BTC bridges that exist, how they work, and how they can be improved.</description></item><item><title>RSK, Federated Sidechains And Powpeg</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/rsk-federated-sidechains-and-powpeg/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/rsk-federated-sidechains-and-powpeg/</guid><description>In this episode of The Van Wirdum Sjorsnado, hosts Aaron van Wirdum and Sjors Provoost discuss RSK’s shift from a federated sidechain model to the project’s new Powpeg solution. They explain how this works exactly, and discuss some of Powpeg’s security tradeoffs.</description></item><item><title>Plasma Cash: Towards more efficient Plasma Constructions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/plasma-cash/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/plasma-cash/</guid><description>Non-custodial sidechains for bitcoin utilizing plasma cash and covenants
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1172108023705284609
paper: https://github.com/loomnetwork/plasma-paper/blob/master/plasma_cash.pdf
slides: https://gakonst.com/scalingbitcoin2019.pdf
Introduction We have known how to do these things for at least a year, but the question is how can we find the minimum changes that we can figure out to do in bitcoin if any on how to explore the layer 2 space in a better sense rather than just accepting that lightning network is the dominant solution?</description></item><item><title>Statechains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/statechains/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/statechains/</guid><description>Schnorr signatures, adaptor signatures and statechains
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171345418237685760
Introduction If you want to know the details of statechains, I recommend checking out my talk from Breaking Bitcoin 2019 Amsterdam. I&amp;rsquo;ll give a quick recap of Schnorr signatures and adaptor signatures and then statechains. I think it&amp;rsquo;s important to understand Schnorr signatures to the point where you&amp;rsquo;re really comfortable with it. A lot of the cool stuff in bitcoin right now is related to or using Schnorr signatures.</description></item><item><title>Drivechain</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/austin-bitcoin-developers/2019-05-27-drivechain-paul-sztorc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/austin-bitcoin-developers/2019-05-27-drivechain-paul-sztorc/</guid><description>Drivechain: An interoperability layer-2, Described in terms of the lightning network- something you already understand
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1133202672570519552
About me Okay. So here&amp;rsquo;s some things about myself. I&amp;rsquo;ve been a bitcoiner since 2012. I&amp;rsquo;ve published bitcoin research on truthcoin.info blog. I&amp;rsquo;ve presented at Scaling Bitcoin 1, 2, 3, 4, tabconf, and Building on Bitcoin. My background is in economics and statistics. I worked at Yale Econ Department as a statistician for 2.5 years.</description></item><item><title>Federated Chains, Sidechains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/sidechains-and-federation-models/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/sidechains-and-federation-models/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048008467871666178
Introduction The name &amp;ldquo;sidechain&amp;rdquo; is overloaded. My favorite private sidechain is my coach. That&amp;rsquo;s my private sidechain. Hopefully I can explain the high-level concepts of a sidechain, at a 10,000 foot view. What are these? What do they give you?
Sidechain components First you need a blockchain. It has to be something that builds a consensus history. The state of the ledger has to be recorded, or the account model, or whatever you&amp;rsquo;re doing.</description></item><item><title>Mimblewimble And Scriptless Scripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/realworldcrypto/2018/mimblewimble-and-scriptless-scripts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/realworldcrypto/2018/mimblewimble-and-scriptless-scripts/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/954531580848082944
We&amp;rsquo;re about ready for the second session of RWC. We are going to move on to cryptocurrencies. So we have 3 talks lined up in this session. The first one is on mimblewimble and scriptless scripts, delivered by Andrew Poelstra from Blockstream.
Introduction Thank you. Cool. Hello. My name is Andrew Poelstra. I am the research director at Blockstream and I&amp;rsquo;m here to talk about a couple of things that I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about over the past year, called mimblewimble, and also scriptless scripts.</description></item><item><title>Microchains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/microchains/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/microchains/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/927257690685939712
I would like to see a blockchain ecosystem with 1000s of transactions/second at layer 1 with full security. And so, we have to look at blockchain differently if we are going to achieve this.
A brief introduction&amp;hellip; my name is David Vorick. I have been studying bitcoin since 2011. My primary gig is Sia. I have been spending a lot of time on consensus algorithms and proof-of-work. If we could start over what sorts of things could we do today that we didnt know about in 2008?</description></item><item><title>Mimblewimble And Scriptless Scripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/mimblewimble-and-scriptless-scripts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/mimblewimble-and-scriptless-scripts/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/838480912396533760
Up next we have Andrew Poelstra and he is going to be talking about a really interesting new concept for a cryptocurrency. It&amp;rsquo;s called mimblewimble, after a spell from Harry Potter, because it prevents characters from speaking. Try speaking? Hello, test. We also have a&amp;hellip; hello? hello? Can you guys hear me?
I am going to talk about the concept of scriptless scripts. It&amp;rsquo;s a way of describing what mimblewimble does, in a way that shows the conceptual details, and maybe give the ability to take the lessons we learned from mimblewimble and apply to other projects.</description></item><item><title>Mimblewimble</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-11-21-mimblewimble/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-11-21-mimblewimble/</guid><description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aHTRlbCaUyM
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/801990263543648256
History As Denise said, I gave a talk in Milan about mimblewimble about a month ago (slides). This is more or less the same talk, but rebalanced a bit to try to emphasize what I think is important and add some history that has happened in the intervening time. I&amp;rsquo;ll get started.
Many of you have heard of mimblewimble. It&amp;rsquo;s been in the news. It has a catchy name.</description></item><item><title>Mimblewimble: Private, Massively-Prunable Blockchains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/mimblewimble/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/mimblewimble/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784696648597405696
slides: http://diyhpl.us/~bryan/papers2/bitcoin/mimblewimble-2016-scaling-bitcoin-slides.pdf
Hi, I am from Blockstream. I am here to talk about Mimblewimble. Mimblewimble is not mine. It&amp;rsquo;s from the dark lord. I am going to start with the history of the paper. It has been in the news a little bit. I will talk about the transaction structure, the block structure, try to explain the trust model and argue that it&amp;rsquo;s almost as strong as bitcoin. There&amp;rsquo;s less data to verify than in bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Mimblewimble Podcast</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/mimblewimble-podcast/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/mimblewimble-podcast/</guid><description>Andrew Poelstra (andytoshi) Pieter Wuille (sipa) Brian Deery Chris Odom Starts at 26min.
I am going to introduce our guests here in just a minute.
Launch of zcash might be delayed in order to allow the code to be analyzed by multiple third-party auditors. Zooko stated, &amp;ldquo;I feel bad that we didn&amp;rsquo;t do a better job of making TheDAO disaster-like problems harder for people&amp;rdquo;.
Our guests on the line are Andrew Poelstra and Pieter Wuille.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Sidechains - Unchained Epicenter</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/bitcoin-sidechains-unchained-epicenter-adam3us-gmaxwell/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/bitcoin-sidechains-unchained-epicenter-adam3us-gmaxwell/</guid><description>EB65 – Adam Back &amp;amp; Greg Maxwell: Sidechains Unchained
people:
Sebastien Couture Brian Fabian Crain Adam Back (adam3us) Greg Maxwell (gmaxwell) Brian: We are here today we have Adam Back and Greg Maxwell, to anyone who is following bitcoin and bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s development, you will have probably heard of these two gentlemen. I was fortunate enough that the first time that I went to a bitcoin conference at the beginning of my involvement in this space, it was in Amsterdam 2013 and I somehow randomly ended up having dinner twice with Adam which really was super fascinating talking to him about bitcoin, and so I&amp;rsquo;m really exciting to have them on today, especially since we are going to have a chance to talk about a project we have talked about many times on this show before, with different people, which is sidechains, because sidechains I think that everyone is in agreement that it is one of the more interesting projects in the space, and a lot of people have many questions about it.</description></item><item><title>Lower Bounds for Off-Chain Protocols: Exploring the Limits of Plasma</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/lower-bounds-limits-plasma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/lower-bounds-limits-plasma/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230183338746335233
Introduction Okay, thank you. The title of my talk is exploring the limits of plasma. This is joint work with others.
Plasma Let me start by telling you about Plasma. It&amp;rsquo;s a family of layer 2 solutions for scaling blockchain. It was proposed in 2017 by Poon and Buterin. It&amp;rsquo;s a family of protocols. There&amp;rsquo;s plenty of different plasmas. This is a diagram from more than a year ago. There are many variants.</description></item><item><title>Provenance Groups</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/provenance-groups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/provenance-groups/</guid><description>Give the name of your tech topic table. You have three minutes to summarize. When you have one minute to summarize, I will give you the one minute warning. When you have zero minutes left, you will be thrown out the window.
Media rights We talked about media rights and payments. The ability to figure out the incentive structure for whether we can compensate people who create page views with people who have view rights and how that all works.</description></item><item><title>Rootstock</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/rootstock/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/rootstock/</guid><description>Sergio is co-founder and chief scientist at RSK Labs. The whitepaper was pretty good. I am happy that he is here. Thank you. Just give me a minute.
Alicia Bendhan Lous Parker BitDevsNYC
Yes, I use powerpoint. Please don&amp;rsquo;t read my emails.
Thanks everyone for staying here and not going to the next room. Thanks for the organizers for inviting me. Today I am going to talk about Rootstock. It&amp;rsquo;s a codename for a smart contracting platform that we are developing for SKY labs, which is a company we founded in 2015.</description></item><item><title>Sidechains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/matt-corallo-sidechains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/matt-corallo-sidechains/</guid><description>One second. Technical difficulties. Okay, sorry about that. Okay. Hi. I am Matt or BlueMatt for those of you know me. I swear it&amp;rsquo;s not related to my hair. Nobody believes me.
I got into Bitcoin three or four years ago because I was interested in the programming and computer science aspects and as well as my interest in large-scale economic incentive structures and macroeconomics and how we create incentive structures that create actions on a low level by rational actors.</description></item><item><title>Sidechains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/sidechains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/sidechains/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784767020290150400
slides https://scalingbitcoin.org/milan2016/presentations/D1%20-%209%20-%20Paul.pdf
Before we begin, we will explain how the workshops will work upstairs. There will be some topics and room numbers. Now we will start the next presentation on sidechain scaling with Paul Sztorc. Thank you everyone.
Thanks a lot. So this talk will be a little different. Scaling via strategy, not physics. This will not change the kilobytes sent over&amp;ndash; it will, just not in the literal sense.</description></item></channel></rss>