<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>scalability on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/scalability/</link><description>Recent content in scalability on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/scalability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Scaling to Billions of Users</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/scaling-to-billions-of-users/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/scaling-to-billions-of-users/</guid><description>In this episode, Aaron and Sjors discuss a recent blog post by Bitcoin Core developer Anthony Towns, “Putting the B in BTC”, in which he outlines a vision for scaling Bitcoin to facilitate billions of users. As Aaron and Sjors walk through the article, they explain what some of Towns’ proposed solutions are, and which tradeoffs they entail.</description></item><item><title>Building Trustless Bridges</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/layer-2/building-trustless-bridges/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/layer-2/building-trustless-bridges/</guid><description>Many mechanisms have been created that enable users to lock BTC on the mainchain, transfer a claim on the BTC in some offchain system, and then later redeem the claim and take ownership of the underlying BTC. Colloquially known as &amp;ldquo;bridges&amp;rdquo;, these mechanisms offer a diverse range of security and usability properties for users to choose from depending on their risk tolerance and cost preferences. This talk will give an overview of the different types of BTC bridges that exist, how they work, and how they can be improved.</description></item><item><title>Blockchain Design Patterns: Layers and scaling approaches</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/blockchain-design-patterns/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/blockchain-design-patterns/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171400374336536576
Introduction Alright. Are we ready to get going? Thumbs up? Alright. Cool. I am Andrew and this is David. We&amp;rsquo;re here to talk about blockchain design patterns: layers and scaling approaches. This will be a tour of a bunch of different scaling approaches in bitcoin in particular but it&amp;rsquo;s probably applicable to other blockchains out there. Our talk is in 3 parts. We&amp;rsquo;ll talk about some existing scaling tech and related things like caching transactions and mempool propagation.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Scaling Tradeoffs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/adam3us-bitcoin-scaling-tradeoffs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/adam3us-bitcoin-scaling-tradeoffs/</guid><description>Bitcoin scaling tradeoffs with Adam Back (adam3us) at Paralelni Polis
Institute of Cryptoanarchy http://www.paralelnipolis.cz/
slides: http://www.slideshare.net/paralelnipolis/bitcoin-scaling-tradeoffs-with-adam-back
description: &amp;ldquo;In this talk, Adam Back overviews the Bitcoin scaling and discuses his personal view about its tradeoffs and future development.&amp;rdquo;
Intro fluff And now I would like to introduce you to a great guest from the U.K. or Malta, Adam Back. Adam is long-time professional cryptologist and also he&amp;rsquo;s a Bitcoin expert. He&amp;rsquo;s the inventor of hashcash, which was used for example by Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Non Currency Applications</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/non-currency-applications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/non-currency-applications/</guid><description>Scalability of non-currency applications
I am from Princeton University. I am here to talk about the scalability issues that non-currency applications of bitcoin have that might be a little different than regular payments that go through the bitcoin network. I put this together with my advisor, Arvind. The reason why I want to talk about this is because when people talk about how bitcoin will have to scale is that people throw out a thing about Visa processing 20,000 transactions per second or something.</description></item><item><title>Scalability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/peter-todd-scalability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/peter-todd-scalability/</guid><description>There we go. Yeah. Looks good. Thank you.
So I wanted to talk about scalability and I wanted to give two opposing views of it. The first is really, scaling Bitcoin up is really really easy. The underlying architecture of Bitcoin is designed in a way that makes it easy to scale. You have your blockchain, and you have your blocks at the top which are 80 bytes data structures. They form a massive long chain all the way back to the genesis block when Bitcoin was created.</description></item><item><title>Trustlessness Scalability And Directions In Security Models</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/trustlessness-scalability-and-directions-in-security-models/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/trustlessness-scalability-and-directions-in-security-models/</guid><description>Trustlessness, scalability and directions in security models
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043397023846883329
&amp;hellip; Is everyone awake? Sure. Jumping jacks. Wow, that&amp;rsquo;s bright. I am more idealistic than Eric. I am going to talk about utility and why people use bitcoin and let&amp;rsquo;s see how that goes.
Trustlessness is much better than decentralization. I want to talk about trustlessness. People use the word decentralization a lot and I find that to be kind of useless because decentralization is a means to an end.</description></item><item><title>Validation Cost Metric</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/validation-cost-metric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/validation-cost-metric/</guid><description>slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY2/3_tweaking_the_chain_3_nick.pdf
Motivation As we&amp;rsquo;ve seen over the last two days scalability is a multidimensional problem. One of the main topics of research is increasing the blocksize to increase transaction throughput. The assumption is that as technological progress is continuing and transaction throughput is increased accordingly, the cost for runnning a fully validating node stays constant.
However, blocksize proposals usually only directly change one aspect of full node costs - the blocksize.</description></item></channel></rss>