<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ben Fisch on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/ben-fisch/</link><description>Recent content in Ben Fisch on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/ben-fisch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Proofs Of Space And Replication</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/proofs-of-space-and-replication/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/proofs-of-space-and-replication/</guid><description>Tight proofs of space and and replication
Ben Fisch (Stanford University)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1091064672831234048
paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/702.pdf
Introduction This talk is about proofs of space and tight proofs of space.
Proof of Space A proof-of-space is an alternative to proof-of-work. Applications have been proposed like spam prevention, DoS attack prevention, sybil resistance in consensus networks which is most relevant to this conference. In proof-of-space, it&amp;rsquo;s an interactive protocol between a miner and a prover who has some disk storage and claims that hey I am storing 1 gigabyte of data.</description></item><item><title>Survey Of Progress In Zero Knowledge Proofs Towards Trustless Snarks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/survey-of-progress-in-zero-knowledge-proofs-towards-trustless-snarks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/survey-of-progress-in-zero-knowledge-proofs-towards-trustless-snarks/</guid><description>Ben Fisch (Stanford University) (benafisch)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171683484382957568
Introduction I am going to be giving a survey of recent progress into succinct zero-knowledge proofs. I&amp;rsquo;ll survey recent developments, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to start with what zero-knowledge proofs are. This is towards SNARKs without trusted setup. I want to help you get up to date on what&amp;rsquo;s happening on with SNARKs. There&amp;rsquo;s an explosion of manuscripts and it&amp;rsquo;s hard to keep track.
One theme is the emergence of polynomial commitment schemes which is an efficient tool for building transparent SNARKs without trusted setup.</description></item><item><title>Transparent Snarks From Dark Compilers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/transparent-snarks-from-dark-compilers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/transparent-snarks-from-dark-compilers/</guid><description>Transparent SNARKs from DARK compilers
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230561492254089224
paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2019/1229.pdf
Introduction Our next speaker is Ben Fisch, part of the Stanford Applied Crypto team and he has done a lot of work that is relevant to the blockchain space. Proofs of replication, proofs of space, he is also one of the coauthors of a paper that defined the notion of verifiable delay functions. He has also worked on accumulators, batching techniques, vector commitments, and one of his latest works is exciting which is DARKs which he is going to talk about today.</description></item></channel></rss>