<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Segwit on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/segwit/</link><description>Recent content in Segwit on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/segwit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Challenges in implementing coinjoin in hardware wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2022/challenges-in-implementing-coinjoin-in-hardware-wallets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2022/challenges-in-implementing-coinjoin-in-hardware-wallets/</guid><description>Introduction Hi everyone. I&amp;rsquo;m Pavel Rusnak, known as Stik in the Bitcoin community. I&amp;rsquo;m the co-founder of Satoshi Labs, the company that brought Trezor. Today I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking about the challenges of implementing CoinJoin in hardware wallets.
Why Privacy Let&amp;rsquo;s summarize why privacy matters. Among all reasons I consider these reasons as most important.
Autonomy: Privacy allows individuals to have control over their personal information, enabling them to make independent choices and decisions.</description></item><item><title>Misconceptions about segwit vbytes</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-15-segwit-vbytes-misconceptions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-15-segwit-vbytes-misconceptions/</guid><description>Weighing transactions: The witness discount You&amp;rsquo;ve already heard from someone that this presentation will be more interactive. I probably won&amp;rsquo;t get through all of my material. If you have questions during the talk, please feel free to raise your hand and we can cover it right away. I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to walk you through a transaction serialization for both a non-segwit transaction and a segwit transaction. By the end of the talk, I hope you understand how the transaction weight is calculated and how the witness discount works.</description></item><item><title>Weighing Transactions, The Witness Discount</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/weighing-transactions-the-witness-discount/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/weighing-transactions-the-witness-discount/</guid><description>In this talk Mark Erhardt: 0:00:25
I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to walk with you through a transaction serialization, the Bitcoin transaction serialization. And we&amp;rsquo;ll try to understand a non-SegWit transaction and then a SegWit transaction to compare it to. And I hope by the end of this talk, you understand how the transaction weight is calculated and how the witness discount works. And if we get to it, we may take a look at a few different output types in the end as well.</description></item><item><title>Explaining Segregated Witness</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-magazine/bitcoin-explained/explaining-segregated-witness/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-magazine/bitcoin-explained/explaining-segregated-witness/</guid><description>Aaron: 00:01:46
Live from Utrecht. This is The Van Wirdum Sjorsnado. Hello. Sjors, we&amp;rsquo;re going to talk about a classic today.
Sjors: 00:01:52
Yeah. We&amp;rsquo;re going to party like it&amp;rsquo;s 2015.
Aaron: 00:01:55
SegWit.
Segregated Witness Sjors: 00:01:56
That&amp;rsquo;s right.
Aaron: 00:01:57
Segregated Witness, which was the previous soft fork, well, was the last soft fork. We&amp;rsquo;re working towards a Taproot soft fork now.
Sjors: 00:02:06
It&amp;rsquo;s the last soft fork we know of.</description></item><item><title>Enterprise Wallets/UTXO Management</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2020-11-09-enterprise-walletsutxo-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/2020-11-09-enterprise-walletsutxo-management/</guid><description>Mark Erhardt: 00:00:00
Just to throw out a few numbers there, non-SegWit inputs cost almost 300 bytes, and native SegWit inputs cost slightly more than 100 bytes. There&amp;rsquo;s almost a reduction by two-thirds in fees if you switch from non-SegWit to native SegWit.
Introduction Caralie Chrisco: 00:00:29
Hi, everyone, welcome to the Chaincode podcast. My name is Caralie.
Adam Jonas: 00:00:32
And it&amp;rsquo;s Jonas.
Caralie Chrisco: 00:00:33
And we&amp;rsquo;re back!</description></item><item><title>Segwit, PSBT Vulnerability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/la-bitdevs/2020-06-18-luke-dashjr-segwit-psbt-vulnerability/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/la-bitdevs/2020-06-18-luke-dashjr-segwit-psbt-vulnerability/</guid><description>SegWit/PSBT vulnerability (CVE-2020-14199)
Location: LA BitDevs (online)
CVE: https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2020-14199
Trezor blog post on the vulnerability: https://blog.trezor.io/latest-firmware-updates-correct-possible-segwit-transaction-vulnerability-266df0d2860
Greg Sanders Bitcoin dev mailing list post in April 2017: https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2017-August/014843.html
The vulnerability The way Bitcoin transactions are encoded in the software is there is a list of coins essentially and then there is a list of destinations and the amount being sent to each destination. The destinations do not include the fee. Nothing in the transaction tells you what the fee of the transaction is.</description></item><item><title>Advanced Segwit</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-18-james-obeirne-advanced-segwit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-18-james-obeirne-advanced-segwit/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs 2019 Residency
Slides: https://residency.chaincode.com/presentations/bitcoin/Advanced_segwit.pdf
James O&amp;rsquo;Beirne: To sort of vamp off of Jonas&amp;rsquo;s preamble, I&amp;rsquo;m not that smart. I&amp;rsquo;m a decent programmer, but compared to a lot of people who work on Bitcoin, I barely know what I&amp;rsquo;m doing. I kind of consider myself like a carpenter, a digital carpenter equivalent. I&amp;rsquo;m a steady hand. I can get things done. I&amp;rsquo;m fairly patient, which i s key when it comes to Bitcoin Core development because, trust me, you&amp;rsquo;re gonna be doing a lot of waiting around and a lot of rebasing.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Optech</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-10/2018-10-09-bitcoin-optech/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-10/2018-10-09-bitcoin-optech/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1049527415767101440
https://bitcoinops.org/
Bitcoin Optech is trying to encourage bitcoin businesses to adopt better scaling techniques and technologies, things like batching, segwit, down the line maybe Schnorr signatures, aggregatable signatures, maybe lightning. Right now we&amp;rsquo;re focusing on things that businesses could be doing right now. Exchanges could be batching, and some aren&amp;rsquo;t. We&amp;rsquo;re talking to those companies and listening to their concerns and what they&amp;rsquo;re doing, and just trying to nudge them in the right direction.</description></item><item><title>Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions (BIP174)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/partially-signed-bitcoin-transactions-bip174/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/partially-signed-bitcoin-transactions-bip174/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1047730297242935296
Introduction Bryan briefly mentioned partially-signed bitcoin transactions (PSBT). I can give more depth on this. There&amp;rsquo;s history and motivation, a background of why this is important, what these things are doing. What is the software doing?
History and motivation Historically, there was no standard for this. Armory had its own format. Bitcoin Core had network-serialized transactions. This ensures fragmentation and it&amp;rsquo;s incomplete and bad that there was no standard. For segwit, a transaction to a legacy node looks like a zero-input transaction, which is a way to flag it as a segwit transaction.</description></item><item><title>Advances In Block Propagation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2017-11-27-gmaxwell-advances-in-block-propagation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2017-11-27-gmaxwell-advances-in-block-propagation/</guid><description>slides: https://web.archive.org/web/20190416113003/https://people.xiph.org/~greg/gmaxwell-sf-prop-2017.pdf
https://en.bitcoin.it/wiki/User:Gmaxwell/block_network_coding
efficient block transfer: https://web.archive.org/web/20170912171304/https://people.xiph.org/~greg/efficient.block.xfer.txt
low latency block xfer: https://web.archive.org/web/20160607023347/https://people.xiph.org/~greg/lowlatency.block.xfer.txt
https://web.archive.org/web/20160607023408/https://people.xiph.org/~greg/mempool_sync_relay.txt
https://web.archive.org/web/20160607023359/http://people.xiph.org/~greg/weakblocks.txt
compact blocks FAQ https://bitcoincore.org/en/2016/06/07/compact-blocks-faq/
some history https://www.reddit.com/r/btc/comments/557ihg/what_are_the_arguments_against_xthin_blocks/d88q5l4/
more history https://www.reddit.com/r/btc/comments/6p076l/segwit_only_allows_170_of_current_transactions/dkmugw5/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/944656354307919873
Introduction I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about some recent advances in block propagation and why this stuff is important. I am going to talk about how the original bitcoin p2p protocol works, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work that way for the most part anymore. I will talk about the history of this, including fast block relay protocol, block network coding, and then building up to where the state of the art is today.</description></item><item><title>Light Clients During 2017 Interfork Period</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/light-clients-during-2017-interfork-period/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/light-clients-during-2017-interfork-period/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005617123287289857
Next up is Thomas.
Introduction Alright. Hello everyone. Thank you for having me. I&amp;rsquo;m the developer of the Electrum wallet. I started this project in 2011. I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about lite clients and the implication of the 2017 hard-fork. We might be in the middle of two forks at the moment.
So we have segwit and we are very happy about that. ((applause)) This graph was taken from Pieter Wuille&amp;rsquo;s website.</description></item><item><title>Whalepool</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2016-12-14-whalepool/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2016-12-14-whalepool/</guid><description>Whalepool segwit transcript
https://soundcloud.com/elux-2/the-great-stakehodler-debate-lombroso-petrov-potter-ver
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/809174512105295872
Host: Mr. Ver, can you hear this?
RV: Yes, I can.
Host: Welcome to Whalepool.
Gavin: Hey Roger, it&amp;rsquo;s Gavin. I heard about this.
RV: Hey Eric. I see lots of familiar names in here.
RV: Who was that? I don&amp;rsquo;t know whose voice that was.
Hodl: Mr. Hodl
RV: Thanks for organizing this. Hello Mr. Hodl.
Host: Okay, ready to go. Here we have Eric Lombrozo who is a developer who has committed code to Bitcoin Core.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network As A Directed Graph Single Funded Channel Network Topology</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-04-11-lightning-network-as-a-directed-graph-single-funded-channel-network-topology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-04-11-lightning-network-as-a-directed-graph-single-funded-channel-network-topology/</guid><description>http://lightning.network/
slides: http://diyhpl.us/~bryan/papers2/bitcoin/Lightning%20Network%20as%20Directed%20Graph%20Single-Funded%20Channel%20Topology%20-%20Tadge%20Dryja%20-%202016-04-11.pdf
Okay. Hello everyone. Yes, okay, great. Yes. Yeah, I&amp;rsquo;m working on Lightning Network. Bitcoin is great and fun to work on.
Basic super quick summary of Lightning I am going to re-cap lightning network real quick. The basic idea is to have channels between two nodes. A channel, from the perspective of the rest of the world, is just a 2-of-2 multisig output. You can&amp;rsquo;t even tell it&amp;rsquo;s multisig, you just see an address with a 3 in front of the address.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Script</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/bitcoin-script/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/bitcoin-script/</guid><description>Featuring roasbeef
Agenda opcodes OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACK sighash flags keytree sigs MAST graftroot, taproot covenants, reverse covenants (input restrictions: this input has to be spent with tihs other input, or can only be spent if this other one doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist) stack manipulation script languages (simplicity) tx formats, serialization? what would we change with hard-fork changes to the transaction format? Segwit transaction encoding format sucks; the witnesses are at the end and inline with all the scriptsigs and that should be changed.</description></item><item><title>Bloxroute</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/bloxroute/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/bloxroute/</guid><description>bloXroute: A network for tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s blockchain
Introduction Hi. I am Souyma and I am here to talk with you about Bloxroute. The elephant in the room is that blockchains have been claimed to solve everything like credit cards, social media, and global micropayments. To handle credit card payment volumes, blockchains need like 5000 transactions per second, for microtransactions you need 70000 transactions per second, and for social media even more. Blockchains today do about 10 transactions/second.</description></item><item><title>Segregated Witness And Its Impact On Scalability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/segregated-witness-and-its-impact-on-scalability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/segregated-witness-and-its-impact-on-scalability/</guid><description>slides: https://prezi.com/lyghixkrguao/segregated-witness-and-deploying-it-for-bitcoin/
code: https://github.com/sipa/bitcoin/commits/segwit
SPV = simplified payment verification
CSV = checksequenceverify
CLTV = checklocktimeverify
Segregated witness (segwit) and deploying it for Bitcoin
Okay. So I am Pieter Wuille. I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about segregated witness for Bitcoin. Before I can explain this, I want to give some context. We all know how bitcoin transactions work. Every bitcoin transaction gets inputs, which refer to previous outputs being spent. Every input has the txid and the signature to prove that it is allowed, plus an amount and script in every output.</description></item><item><title>Segwit Lessons Learned</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/segwit-lessons-learned/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/segwit-lessons-learned/</guid><description>Lessons learned with segwit in Bitcoin
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785034301272420353
Hi. My name is Greg Sanders. I will be giving a talk about segwit in bitcoin lessons learned. I will also give some takeaways that I think are important. A little bit about myself. I work on Elements Project at Blockstream. I was a reviewer on segwit for Bitcoin Core. How do we scale protocol development? How do we scale review and keep things safe?</description></item></channel></rss>