<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Anthony Towns on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/anthony-towns/</link><description>Recent content in Anthony Towns on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/anthony-towns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Schnorr and Taproot</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2019-12-27-aj-towns-schnorr-taproot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2019-12-27-aj-towns-schnorr-taproot/</guid><description>Topic: Schnorr Taproot Tapscript BIPs
Location: Stephan Livera Podcast
Transcript Stephan Livera: AJ, welcome to the show.
AJ Towns: Howdy.
Stephan Livera: Thanks for joining me AJ. I know you’re doing a lot of really cool work with the Schnorr and Taproot proposal and the review club. But let’s start with a bit of your background and I know you’re working at Xapo as well.
AJ Towns: Yeah so I’m working at Xapo on Bitcoin Core dev, which means that I get to do open source work full time and get paid for it and it’s pretty freaking awesome.</description></item><item><title>Schnorr Taproot Tapscript BIPs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2019-12-27-aj-townsschnorr-taproot-tapscript-bips/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2019-12-27-aj-townsschnorr-taproot-tapscript-bips/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/137/
Stephan Livera: AJ, welcome to the show.
AJ Towns: Howdy.
Stephan Livera: Thanks for joining me AJ. I know you’re doing a lot of really cool work with the Schnorr and Taproot proposal and the review club. But let’s start with a bit of your background and I know you’re working at Xapo as well.
AJ Towns: Yeah, so I, I’m working at Xapo on Bitcoin core dev, which basically just means that I get to do open source work full time and get paid for it and it’s pretty freaking awesome.</description></item><item><title>Changes Without Unanimous Consent</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/changes-without-unanimous-consent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/changes-without-unanimous-consent/</guid><description>I want to talk about dealing with consensus changes without so-called consensus. I am using consensus in terms of the social aspect, not in terms of the software algorithm consensus for databases. &amp;ldquo;Consensus changes without consensus&amp;rdquo;. If you don&amp;rsquo;t consensus on consensus, then some people are going to follow one chain and another another chain.
If you have unanimous consensus, then new upgrades work just fine. Developers write software, miners run the same stuff, and then there are no splits because PoW builds on other blocks and we&amp;rsquo;re all happy and the economy is all in agreement as well and everyone wins.</description></item><item><title>Playing With Fire Adjusting Bitcoin Block Subsidy</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/playing-with-fire-adjusting-bitcoin-block-subsidy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/playing-with-fire-adjusting-bitcoin-block-subsidy/</guid><description>slides: https://github.com/ajtowns/sc-btc-2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048401029148991488
Introduction First an apology about the title. I saw some comments on twitter after the talk was announced and they were speculating that I was going to break the 21 million coin limit. But that&amp;rsquo;s not the case. Rusty has a civil war thesis: the third era will start with the civil war, the mathematics of this situation seem einevitable. As the miners and businesses with large transaction volume will both decide to reintroduce inflation so that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to pay fees, fees just magically happen.</description></item></channel></rss>