<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2020 Stanford on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/</link><description>Recent content in 2020 Stanford on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Consensus Protocol Risks And Vulnerabilities</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/consensus-protocol-risks-and-vulnerabilities/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/consensus-protocol-risks-and-vulnerabilities/</guid><description>Consensus protocol risks and vulnerabilities
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229906447808360450
Introduction I am going to talk about why cryptocurrencies matter. I am going to take the skeptics side. I am going to start from a banker&amp;rsquo;s standpoint why a lot of the things that cryptocurrency people land say don&amp;rsquo;t make any sense.
Where are the engineers coming from? An engineer will look at something like Visa and say this is horrible. These are systems from 50-100 years ago.</description></item><item><title>Communication With Regulators</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/communication-with-regulators/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/communication-with-regulators/</guid><description>Communication with regulators
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229856579324760064
Backgrounds NTT JFSA SEC (enforcement division) celo compliance gold reserves, central bank digital currencies (monetary policy controls) soc1/soc2 audits engineer Developers and regulators: lawfulness questions Are software developers liable from a regulatory perspective for software that they write? There was a case against EtherDelta. He was receiving income from it. In any crime, for enforcement agencies&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s a line between regulators and criminal enforcement. Regulators create rules.</description></item><item><title>Opening Remarks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/opening-remarks/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/opening-remarks/</guid><description>Opening remarks
http://bsafe.network/events/codefi_stanford_2020/
https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229833591716102144
Good morning. Let us start this workshop. I am a researcher at Georgetown University and it is my pleasure to host this workshop. CoDeFi is a workshop about coordination of decentralized finance. This unfortunately shares a name with a Consensys product. CoDeFi contains CoDe and DeFi. This is a multi-stakeholder workshop to discuss stakeholders that have never met before. I think we have regulators here, and engineers here, and researchers here, and business people here.</description></item><item><title>Regulatory Pain Points</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/regulatory-pain-points/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/regulatory-pain-points/</guid><description>Regulatory pain points
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229838162827993088
Introduction Hi, good morning everyone. I am a Japanese financial regulator at JFSA. My goal is to promote financial innovations and still ensure the financial stability and various regulatory goals. I have nearly 10 years experience as a regulator. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a strong background in technology, so I hope I can rely on the other stakeholders on this. I am now in Washington DC doing research on blockchain and governance policy.</description></item><item><title>Risk Overview</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/risk-overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/risk-overview/</guid><description>Overview of risk in decentralized financial systems
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229878346709782528
Introduction This is an overview of catastrophic failure risk in decentralized systems. There are certain degrees of risk in this system where losses can be moderate but not entirely destructive, but also potential failure modes where losses can be serious and ruinous equivalent to the global financial crisis.
From a regulator&amp;rsquo;s perspective, there&amp;rsquo;s a couple of primary mandates that regulators are tasked with making rules for.</description></item><item><title>Stress Testing Decentralized Finance</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/stress-testing-decentralized-finance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/stress-testing-decentralized-finance/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229844754990370816
Introduction More quantitatively, I think coming up with stress tests is akin to Bryan&amp;rsquo;s question&amp;hellip;. stress testing is something that people in this space kind of do, and I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about what that looks like and what an actuarial analysis should look like.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to go through three examples of where an actuarial analysis shows certain weaknesses that need to be monitored and understood. They are going to be more on the scifi end of cryptocurrency.</description></item><item><title>Technological Stability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/technological-stability/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/technological-stability/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229891596688052226
Controversial thesis: the primary source of economic instability is unreasonable demands (from regulators, but really from the general public) for violating certain cryptocurrency tech design principles, like on sound money- privacy and confidentiality (like confidential transactions and confidential assets), monetary policy (like scarcity economics), identity vs anonymity, AML/KYC requirements, censorship, sanctions requirements and discrimination (e.g. denying money to certain parties), and issues of fungibility (like mixing and history-indistinguishability).
Financial stability goals- like avoiding global economic crashes- might be at odds with goals like producing sound money and privacy for everyone.</description></item><item><title>Economic Risks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/economic-risks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/economic-risks/</guid><description>We looked at economic risks, and how to build a social safety net while allowing innovations. We talked about a bunch of different projects and looked at different systemic risk views from different countries. So the idea was to understand it from an economic perspective. I don&amp;rsquo;t think we came to any great conclusions. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of economic risk, and people don&amp;rsquo;t really understand it yet. One idea is to have more forums for central banks and regulators to understand what the technology can do, so that they can give insights for what the ramifications might be.</description></item></channel></rss>