<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rene Pickhardt on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/rene-pickhardt/</link><description>Recent content in Rene Pickhardt on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/rene-pickhardt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Path Finding in the Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-26-rene-pickhardt-path-finding-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-26-rene-pickhardt-path-finding-lightning-network/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Residency 2019
Introduction Today I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk a little bit about path finding on the Lightning Network and some part of it will be about the gossip protocol which is like a little bit of a review of what the gossip messages are going to look like. So it&amp;rsquo;s a little bit basic again. But other than that, I&amp;rsquo;ve been told that you seek more for like opinionated talks and recent ideas instead of, like, how the bolts work because you already know all of that.</description></item><item><title>Splicing</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-26-rene-pickhardt-splicing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-26-rene-pickhardt-splicing/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs Lightning Residency 2019
Transcript by: Caralie Chrisco
Introduction So splicing basically means you have a payment channel, you have a certain capacity of a payment channel and you want to change the capacity on the payment channel. But you don&amp;rsquo;t want to change your balance right? For balance change,(inaudible) we&amp;rsquo;ll get some money on it. But splicing really means you want to change the capacity.
I mean the obvious way of doing this is close the channel, make a new channel with the design capacity and you could.</description></item><item><title>The Update Layer</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-26-rene-pickhardt-update-layer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-26-rene-pickhardt-update-layer/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs Lightning Residency 2019
Introduction Maybe we had a wrong impression, you can ask, like in Christian’s talk, as many questions as you want while the presentation is there. So, it&amp;rsquo;s a small disclaimer just saying: these slides are part of a much larger slide set which is open-source and you find notes and, I think, we share slides in the Google Docs anyway.
The outline of the talk is, I’m going to talk about the construction of payment channels in Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Multihop of the Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-24-rene-pickhardt-multihop-in-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-24-rene-pickhardt-multihop-in-lightning/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs Lightning Residency 2019
Slides: https://residency.chaincode.com/presentations/lightning/Multihop_Layer.pdf
Introduction I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about Lightning Network payment channels and the update layer which is basically multihop payments and the outline of this talk is one slide myths about routing that are floating around and I just want to discuss them in the beginning very briefly. Then I will talk about the payment process on the Lightning Network and compare it a little bit with the payment process on Bitcoin.</description></item></channel></rss>