<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cory Fields on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/cory-fields/</link><description>Recent content in Cory Fields on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/cory-fields/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cory Fields</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/cory-fields/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/cory-fields/</guid><description>MIT Bitcoin Expo 2016 transcript
last year- http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/ this year- http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/
Welcome everyone to MIT Bitcoin Expo 2016. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of Bitcoin by now, then I am not sure how you got here. My name is nchinda. I am the reigning Bitcoin club president. I am going to have some fun. The club is hijacking the #mit-dci IRC channel. You can twitter with #mitbitcoinexpo. There&amp;rsquo;s a link up on our website for livestreaming.</description></item><item><title>Everything Is Broken</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/everything-is-broken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/everything-is-broken/</guid><description>Everything is broken
This is a clickbaity title, I realize. But the reason I say it is because it&amp;rsquo;s become a mantra for at least myself but for the people who hear me banging my hands on the desk all the time. I am Cory Fields and I work here at the MIT DCI. I am also a Bitcoin Core developer. I am less active these days there because I have been spending some time looking at some higher layer stuff.</description></item><item><title>Research And Development Goals</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/bitcoin-devcore-2015/research-and-development-goals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/bitcoin-devcore-2015/research-and-development-goals/</guid><description>R&amp;amp;D Goals &amp;amp; Challenges
We often see people saying they are testing the waters, they fixed a typo, they made a tiny little fix that doesn&amp;rsquo;t impact much, they are getting used to the process. They are finding that it&amp;rsquo;s really easy to contribut to Bitcoin Core. You code your changes, you submit your changes, there&amp;rsquo;s not much to it.
There&amp;rsquo;s a difference, and the lines are fuzzy and undefined, and you cna make a change to Core that changes a spelling error or a change to policy or consensus rules, for those high-level things, for ecosystem-level things, there&amp;rsquo;s several mailing lists, the dev list gets the most traffic.</description></item><item><title>Reworking Bitcoin Core P2P Code For Robustness And Event Driven</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/reworking-bitcoin-core-p2p-code-for-robustness-and-event-driven/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/reworking-bitcoin-core-p2p-code-for-robustness-and-event-driven/</guid><description>That is me. I want to apologize right off. I am here to talk about reworking Bitcoin Core p2p code. This is a Bitcoin Core specific topic. I have been working on some software for the past few weeks to talk about working things rather than theory. The presentation is going to suffer because of this.
Bitcoin Core has a networking stack that dates back all the way to the initial implementation from Satoshi or at least it&amp;rsquo;s been patched and hacked on ever since.</description></item></channel></rss>