<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Erlay on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/erlay/</link><description>Recent content in Erlay on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/erlay/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Erlay</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2024-10/erlay/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2024-10/erlay/</guid><description>Idea from 2018, code since 2021 code-wise, only 20% of the high-level code is merged (not counting low-level minisketch code): The basic structure, plus code for peer signaling has been merged -&amp;gt; good time to join, Review is needed
Open questions mostly concern policies (decisions of nodes) - there are various details still under discussion, such as picking parameters, details in logic etc. BIP330 only defines protocol, but not the policy decisions</description></item><item><title>The P2P network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-podcast/the-p2p-network-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-podcast/the-p2p-network-2/</guid><description>P2P experts Amiti Uttarwar and Pieter Wuille discuss various aspects of peer-to-peer communication in Bitcoin, with Adam Jonas facilitating the conversation. They delve into the challenges and objectives of address relay, highlighting its complexities and the importance of propagating IP addresses to maintain network connectivity and prevent partitioning and eclipse attacks. The discussion covers the design and evolution of AddrMan, introduced in 2012 to manage IP addresses, and the impact of changes like rate-limiting address gossip to mitigate spam. Pieter and Amiti also touch on the significance of maintaining separate network stacks for different network protocols and the potential of employing ASMAP to improve network resilience. The conversation underscores ongoing efforts and future directions for enhancing Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s P2P network.</description></item><item><title>Scaling Bitcoin With The Erlay Protocol</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/scaling-bitcoin-with-the-erlay-protocol/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/scaling-bitcoin-with-the-erlay-protocol/</guid><description>Preamble Aaron van Wirdum: 00:00:07
Live from Utrecht, this is the Van Wirdum Sjorsnado.
Sjors Provoost: 00:00:10
Hello again.
Aaron van Wirdum: 00:00:12
We&amp;rsquo;ve done it again, Sjors.
Sjors Provoost: 00:00:14
We&amp;rsquo;ve done it again.
Aaron van Wirdum: 00:00:15
We recorded the whole episode without actually recording it.
Sjors Provoost: 00:00:18
Yeah.
Aaron van Wirdum: 00:00:19
So we&amp;rsquo;re going to do the whole thing over.
Sjors Provoost: 00:00:20
It&amp;rsquo;s this thing where you press the button, but you don&amp;rsquo;t press it hard enough.</description></item><item><title>Efficient P2P Transaction Relay</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-10/2018-10-08-efficient-p2p-transaction-relay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-10/2018-10-08-efficient-p2p-transaction-relay/</guid><description>p2p transaction relay protocol improvements with set reconciliation gleb
I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I need to motivate this problem. I presented a work in progress session at Scaling. The cost of relaying transactions or announcing a transaction in a network&amp;ndash; how many announcements do you have? Every link has an announcement in either direction right now, and then there&amp;rsquo;s the number of nodes multiplied by the number of connections per node.</description></item></channel></rss>