<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bit Block Boom 2019 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/</link><description>Recent content in Bit Block Boom 2019 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Accumulating Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/accumulating-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/accumulating-bitcoin/</guid><description>Accumulating bitcoin
Pierre Rochard
Introduction Today I am going to be preaching to the choir I think. Hopefully I will be reiterating and reinforcing some points that you already know but maybe forgot to bring up with your nocoiner friends, or learning something new. I hope there&amp;rsquo;s something for everyone in here.
Q: Should I buy bitcoin?
A: Yes.
Q: Are you going to troll a journalist?
A: Today? Already done.</description></item><item><title>Building Vibrant Bitcoin Communities</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/building-vibrant-bitcoin-communities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/building-vibrant-bitcoin-communities/</guid><description>Building vibrant bitcoin communities
Kris Merkel
I am the content manager at Exodus Wallet. I have been helping to build up a userbase over the last few years. We are going to talk about building vibrant bitcoin communities. This is the antithesis of Michael Goldstein&amp;rsquo;s talk.
I want to bring positive dynamics to the communities that we participate in. Bitcoin has a few problems we need to overcome. The problem is Craig Wright.</description></item><item><title>Fiat Money Fiat Food</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/fiat-money-fiat-food/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/fiat-money-fiat-food/</guid><description>Fiat money and fiat food
Saifedean Ammous
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1162734566479728641
Introduction Saife saved my life. Until I met Saife, and had him on my show and talked to him, I was a shitcoiner. Okay? Sorry guys. I am going to lay it out there. He talked to me, he came on my show, he sent me his book, his writings, and before I knew it, I started something I really wanted to share with everyone.</description></item><item><title>How To Meme Bitcoin To The Moon</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/how-to-meme-bitcoin-to-the-moon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/how-to-meme-bitcoin-to-the-moon/</guid><description>How to meme bitcoin to the moon
Michael Goldstein (bitstein)
Introduction How many of y&amp;rsquo;all were at the dinner last night? Okay, great. I had a lot of fun. It was fantastic. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how we will beat it next year, but we will figure something out. I am Michael Goldstein, and welcome to my ridiculous tedtalk. A lot of people talk about price fundamentals, but I am going to talk about how to troll and take the curves hard.</description></item><item><title>State Of Multisig</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/state-of-multisig/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/state-of-multisig/</guid><description>State of multisig for bitcoin hodlers: Better wallets with PSBT
Justin Moon
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1162769521993834496
Introduction I am going to be talking about the state of multisig. It&amp;rsquo;s a way of creating a transaction output that requires multiple keys to sign. This is a focus for people holding bitcoin. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about some of the benefits and some of the issues. I am not a security expert, though.
Perspective Multisig is an emphasis on saving and not spending a lot.</description></item><item><title>Taproot Schnorr Soft Fork</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/taproot-schnorr-soft-fork/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/taproot-schnorr-soft-fork/</guid><description>Taproot, Schnorr, and the next soft-fork
Mike Schmidt
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1162839000811548672
Introduction I am going to speak about this potential next version of bitcoin. Who here has heard of these words? Taproot? Schnorr? Who has heard these buzzwords these days? Yeah, so, the proposed next soft-fork is going to involve both of these technologies sort of interplaying. We want to talk about what are these technologies and how do we use thse things and why is it important that a bitcoin user or holder understands these technologies?</description></item><item><title>There Can Only Be One</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/there-can-only-be-one/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/there-can-only-be-one/</guid><description>Bitcoin: There can only be one
Tone Vays
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1162742007460192256
Introduction I am basically going to talk about why bitcoin will basically eat all the shitcoins and why all of them are going away and I am going to point to some of the details. The big graphic right there is my attempt to categorize all of the altcoins, the ICO space, and so on. Everyone is slowly starting to merge mine with bitcoin, since they can&amp;rsquo;t keep up with the charadde.</description></item></channel></rss>