<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jonathan Harvey Buschel on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/jonathan-harvey-buschel/</link><description>Recent content in Jonathan Harvey Buschel on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/jonathan-harvey-buschel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lightning Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2022/lightning-panel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2022/lightning-panel/</guid><description>The discussion primarily revolved around the Lightning Network, a scaling solution for Bitcoin designed to enable faster, decentralized transactions. Rene Pickhardt and Lisa Neigut shared their insights, highlighting Lightning&amp;rsquo;s potential as a peer-to-peer electronic cash system and a future payment infrastructure. They emphasized its efficiency for frequent transactions between trusted parties but noted challenges in its current infrastructure, such as the need for continuous online operation and the risk of losing funds if a node is compromised. The panelists discussed the scalability of the network, indicating that while millions could use it self-sovereignly, larger-scale adoption would likely involve centralized service providers. The conversation also touched on the impact of Taproot on privacy and channel efficiency, and the technical intricacies of maintaining state and preventing fraud within the network.</description></item><item><title>Welcome</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/welcome/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/welcome/</guid><description>Welcome session
Jonathan Harvey Buschel Jinglan Wang We are going to get started in about two minutes, so please take your seats. We are also testing the mic for the live stream. If you have friends who are not here, feel free to tweet them, email them or post their facebook page or instagram whatever.
(buzzing/feedback continues)
Hey. All y&amp;rsquo;all ready? Alright, awesome. My name is Jing, I am president of the Wossley Bitcoin Club.</description></item></channel></rss>