<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>script on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/script/</link><description>Recent content in script on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/script/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Simplicity: Going Beyond Miniscript</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2023/simplicity-going-beyond-miniscript/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2023/simplicity-going-beyond-miniscript/</guid><description>Can we welcome Christian to the stage? I think I don&amp;rsquo;t have any computer yet. Oh.. It&amp;rsquo;s just okay. All right, I just, I just just read. There&amp;rsquo;s a pointer, okay, great great. I was a bit confused for a second. Can I start? great, so welcome, I&amp;rsquo;m Christian Lewe. I work for Blockstream to research where I mainly work on Simplicity and Miniscript and it&amp;rsquo;s great that we just had a talk on Miniscript so you all know why Miniscript is great, why you should use Miniscript, and in my talk I want to go beyond that.</description></item><item><title>OP_RETURN</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-magazine/bitcoin-explained/op_return/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-magazine/bitcoin-explained/op_return/</guid><description>Intro Aaron van Wirdum: 00:00:19
Live from Utrecht, this is Bitcoin Explained. Hey Sjors.
Sjors Provoost: 00:00:24
What&amp;rsquo;s up?
Aaron van Wirdum: 00:00:25
How exciting. Two weeks ago you told me that maybe you would go to Bitcoin Amsterdam.
Sjors Provoost: 00:00:31
Yes.
Aaron van Wirdum: 00:00:31
And now you&amp;rsquo;re a speaker.
Sjors Provoost: 00:00:33
I&amp;rsquo;m a panelist, probably not a real speaker.
Aaron van Wirdum: 00:00:37
That counts that that&amp;rsquo;s a speaker in my book Sjors.</description></item><item><title>Miniscript</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2022/2022-03-03-sanket-kanjalkar-miniscript/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2022/2022-03-03-sanket-kanjalkar-miniscript/</guid><description>Topic: Miniscript: Composable, Analyzable and Smarter Bitcoin Script
Andrew Poelstra on Miniscript: https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-02-04-andrew-poelstra-miniscript/
Intro (Jeff Gallas) The next speaker is Sanket. He is working at Blockstream and is mostly working on Simplicity and Miniscript and that is also what he is going to talk about, Miniscript. Please welcome Sanket.
Intro (Sanket Kanjalkar) Good morning everyone. Today I will be discussing Miniscript which is a work of Pieter Wuille, Andrew Poelstra and me with input from many Bitcoiners.</description></item><item><title>Sydney Socratic Seminar</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-06-01-socratic-seminar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-06-01-socratic-seminar/</guid><description>Name: Socratic Seminar
Topic: Agenda in Google Doc below
Location: Bitcoin Sydney (online)
Video: No video posted online
Google Doc of the resources discussed: https://docs.google.com/document/d/1E9mzB7fmzPxZ74WZg0PsJfLwjpVZ7OClmRdGQQFlzoY/
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.</description></item><item><title>Explaining Bitcoin Addresses</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-magazine/bitcoin-explained/explaining-bitcoin-addresses/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-magazine/bitcoin-explained/explaining-bitcoin-addresses/</guid><description>Aaron van Wirdum: 00:01:45
Live from Utrecht this is the Van Wirdum Sjorsnado. So the other day I wanted to send Bitcoin to someone, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t.
Sjors Provoost: 00:01:52
Why? Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t you hodl?
Aaron van Wirdum: 00:01:55
I hodl all I can, but sometimes I need to eat, or I need to pay my rent, or I need to buy a new plant for my living room.
Sjors Provoost: 00:02:05</description></item><item><title>P2PKH, P2WPKH, P2SH, P2WSH</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/p2pkh-p2wpkh-p2h-p2wsh/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/p2pkh-p2wpkh-p2h-p2wsh/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1047697572444270592
Introduction This is going to be a bit of a re-tread I think. I am going to be talking about common bitcoin script templates used in bitcoin today.
Addresses do not exist on the blockchain. But scripts do. You&amp;rsquo;ve heard about p2pk, p2pkh, p2sh, and others. I&amp;rsquo;m going to go over these anyway.
Pay-to-pubkey (p2pk) This was the first type. It had no address format actually. Nodes connected to each other over IP address, with no authentication.</description></item><item><title>Scripts (general &amp; simple)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/scripts-general-and-simple/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/scripts-general-and-simple/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1047679223115083777
Introduction I am going to talk about why we have scripts in bitcoin. I&amp;rsquo;ll give some examples and the design philosophy. I am not going to talk about the semantics of bitcoin script, though. Why do we have bitcoin script? I&amp;rsquo;ll show how to lock and unlock coins. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about pay-to-pubkey, multisig, and computing vs verification in the blockchain.
Why have script at all? In my first talk, I talked about digital signatures to transfer coins from one person to another.</description></item><item><title>Working on Scripts with logical opcodes</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/working-on-scripts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/working-on-scripts/</guid><description>Building on Bitcoin 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014167120417091584
Bitcoin has logical opcodes in bitcoin script. Depending on whose is trying to spend coins or what information they have, they interact with logical opcodes. We could see a simple example here taken from one of the lightning network commitment transcraction scripts. It pushes a key on to the stack so that a checksig can run later. It adds a relative timelock as well. Two people can interact with that script and we can set different constraints on those.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Scripting</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-04-03-andreas-antonopoulos-bitcoin-scripting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2017-04-03-andreas-antonopoulos-bitcoin-scripting/</guid><description>Topic: Advanced Bitcoin Scripting
Location: SF Bitcoin Devs
Mastering Bitcoin on GitHub: https://github.com/bitcoinbook/bitcoinbook
Intro Today’s talk is different from some of the other talks I’ve done so bear with me. We are going to do this slowly in a very casual manner. This is not one of my usual talks where I am going to tell you about big picture vision and stuff like that. What I want to do is talk about some interesting features of Bitcoin Script and explain them.</description></item></channel></rss>