<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>stratum-v2 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/stratum-v2/</link><description>Recent content in stratum-v2 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/stratum-v2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Stratum V2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2022-10/2022-10-11-stratum-v2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2022-10/2022-10-11-stratum-v2/</guid><description>Introduction There was an announcement earlier this morning that announced the open-source project implementing Stratum v2 is ready for testing now. Spiral has been contributing to this project for a few years. There&amp;rsquo;s a few other companies funding it as well. It&amp;rsquo;s finally ready for testing.
History About 4 years ago or so, Matt proposed BetterHash which focused on enabling miners to be able to do their own transaction selection. There was an independent effort from Braaains that they called stratum v2 which added encryption and authentication between miners and pools and other improvements over stratum v1 like switching from JSON to binary and some other optimizations that were needed over the past 10 years.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Mining Firmware and Stratum v2 - Rachel Rybarczyk - TABConf 2021</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/bitcoin-mining-firmware-and-stratum-v2-rachel-rybarczyk-tabconf-2021/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2021/bitcoin-mining-firmware-and-stratum-v2-rachel-rybarczyk-tabconf-2021/</guid><description>Introduction Coming to the stage next, she is the VP of Mining at Galaxy Digital. Everybody please welcome to the stage Rachel Rybarczyk, everyone. My name is Rachel, I&amp;rsquo;m VP of Mining at Galaxy Digital. I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the space for a few years now and I recently started developing on Stratum V2, which is a new mining protocol. So I want to talk today about Stratum V2, how it compares to Stratum V1, the adoption efforts, some adoption hurdles, and how it all fits in together.</description></item></channel></rss>