<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MuSig on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/musig/</link><description>Recent content in MuSig on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/musig/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>MuSig2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2022-08-11-tim-ruffing-musig2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2022-08-11-tim-ruffing-musig2/</guid><description>Reading list: https://gist.github.com/michaelfolkson/5bfffa71a93426b57d518b09ebd0998c
Introduction Michael Folkson (MF): This is a Socratic Seminar, we are going to be discussing MuSig2 and we’ll move onto adjacent topics such as FROST and libsecp256k1 later. We have a few people on the call including Tim (Ruffing). If you want to do short intros, you don’t have to, for the people on the call.
Tim Ruffing (TR): Hi. Thanks for having me. I am Tim Ruffing, my work is at Blockstream.</description></item><item><title>Taproot multisig</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2022/2022-03-03-jimmy-song-taproot-multisig/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2022/2022-03-03-jimmy-song-taproot-multisig/</guid><description>Slides: https://jimmysong.github.io/taproot-multisig
Pull request adding multisig Taproot support to buidl-python: https://github.com/buidl-bitcoin/buidl-python/pull/109
Intro (Jeff Gallas) The next speaker is Jimmy Song who doesn’t really need an introduction but in any case, he has been, which is important for this conference, running the Programming Blockchain workshops for 5 years now. Leon is one of his alumni so there is a direct connection to this conference. He has also just released a new book which is a bit more political than technical, it is called “Bitcoin and the American Dream”.</description></item><item><title>MuSig2: Simple Two-Round Schnorr Multi-Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/iacr/2021-08-16-jonas-nick-musig2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/iacr/2021-08-16-jonas-nick-musig2/</guid><description>MuSig2 paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/1261.pdf
Introduction This is a talk about MuSig2, simple two round Schnorr multisignatures. I am Jonas Nick and this work is a collaboration with my colleague Tim Ruffing at Blockstream and Yannick Seurin.
Multi-Signatures Multisignatures allow n signers to produce a single signature on a single message. The signing protocol can be interactive and require multiple communication rounds. We distinguish between multisignatures where n-of-n signers can produce a signature and threshold signatures where any subset of size t out of n signers can produce a signature.</description></item><item><title>MuSig2: Simple Two-Round Schnorr Multi-Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/realworldcrypto/2021/2021-01-12-tim-ruffing-musig2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/realworldcrypto/2021/2021-01-12-tim-ruffing-musig2/</guid><description>MuSig2 paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/1261.pdf
Introduction This is about MuSig2, simple two round Schnorr multisignatures. This is joint work with Jonas Nick and Yannick Seurin. Jonas will be available to answer questions as I will be of course.
Multi-Signatures The idea that with multisignatures is that n signers can get together and produce a single signature on a single message. To be clear for this talk when I talk about multisignatures what I mean is n-of-n signatures and not the more general setting of threshold signatures where you can have a threshold t that is smaller than n and have something like a t-of-n signatures.</description></item><item><title>MuSig, MuSig-DN and MuSig2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-10-27-jonas-nick-tim-ruffing-musig2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-10-27-jonas-nick-tim-ruffing-musig2/</guid><description>Tim Ruffing on Schnorr multisig at London Bitcoin Devs: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-17-tim-ruffing-schnorr-multisig/
MuSig paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/068.pdf
MuSig blog post: https://blockstream.com/2019/02/18/en-musig-a-new-multisignature-standard/
Insecure shortcuts in MuSig: https://medium.com/blockstream/insecure-shortcuts-in-musig-2ad0d38a97da
MuSig-DN paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/1057.pdf
MuSig-DN blog post: https://medium.com/blockstream/musig-dn-schnorr-multisignatures-with-verifiably-deterministic-nonces-27424b5df9d6
MuSig2 paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/1261.pdf
MuSig2 blog post: https://medium.com/blockstream/musig2-simple-two-round-schnorr-multisignatures-bf9582e99295
Transcript completed by: Stephan Livera Edited by: Michael Folkson
Intro Stephan Livera (SL): Jonas and Tim, welcome to the show.
Jonas Nick (JN): Hello.
Tim Ruffing (TR): Hey.
SL: So thanks guys for joining me today.</description></item><item><title>Taproot and Schnorr Multisignatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-17-tim-ruffing-schnorr-multisig/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-17-tim-ruffing-schnorr-multisig/</guid><description>Location: London Bitcoin Devs (online)
Slides: https://slides.com/real-or-random/taproot-and-schnorr-multisig
Transcript of the previous day’s Socratic Seminar on BIP-Schnorr: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-16-socratic-seminar-bip-schnorr/
Intro (Michael Folkson) We are now live. This is London Bitcoin Devs with Tim Ruffing. We had the Socratic Seminar yesterday, I think we have some people on the call that were at the Socratic Seminar. That was brilliant. Thanks to Tim, Pieter, Greg, waxwing and everyone for showing up and taking 2 and a half hours out of their day.</description></item><item><title>Schnorr and Taproot workshop</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinops/2019-09-27-schnorr-taproot-workshop/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinops/2019-09-27-schnorr-taproot-workshop/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs, NYC
https://github.com/bitcoinops/taproot-workshop
https://bitcoinops.slack.com
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1177697093462482949
Run: jupyter notebook
See also Schnorr signatures and taproot: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2018-07-09-taproot-schnorr-signatures-and-sighash-noinput-oh-my/
https://github.com/sipa/bips/blob/bip-schnorr/bip-schnorr.mediawiki
https://github.com/sipa/bips/blob/bip-schnorr/bip-taproot.mediawiki
https://github.com/sipa/bips/blob/bip-schnorr/bip-tapscript.mediawiki
Why Schnorr and why taproot? Who here already feels comfortbale with Schnorr/Taproot? This is a proposed consensus change to bitcoin. When we talk about consensus changes, we often talk about tradeoffs and compromises. It would be irresponsible to say taproot has no downsides, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s important to mention it&amp;rsquo;s a clear win for bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>ZkVM: zero-knowledge virtual machine for fast confidential smart contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/zkvm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/zkvm/</guid><description>https://medium.com/stellar-developers-blog/zkvm-a-new-design-for-fast-confidential-smart-contracts-d1122890d9ae and https://twitter.com/oleganza/status/1126612382728372224
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171711553512583169
Introduction Okay, welcome. What is zkvm? It&amp;rsquo;s a multi-asset blockchain architecture that combines smart contracts and confidentiality features. It&amp;rsquo;s written in pure rust from top to bottom.
https://github.com/stellar/slingshot
Agenda I&amp;rsquo;ll explain the good parts, and then I&amp;rsquo;ll explain away the bad parts. Sounds like a good time.
What does this have to do with bitcoin? zkvm is a unique combination of the best ideas in the blockchain space.</description></item><item><title>Tales from the Crypt with Andrew Poelstra</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tftc-podcast/2019-06-18-andrew-poelstra-tftc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tftc-podcast/2019-06-18-andrew-poelstra-tftc/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1160178010986876928
Podcast: https://talesfromthecrypt.libsyn.com/tales-from-the-crypt-80-andrew-poelstra
How the idea of Taproot was formed Andrew: There are some small off suit IRC channels of bitcoin-wizards where people discuss some specific topics such as Minisketch which is a set reconciliation protocol that was developed by Greg Maxwell, Pieter Wuille and Gleb Naumenko among a couple of others. It was mostly those three. They have a channel where they talk about things. There is one where there was a whole bunch of discussion leading up to the Taproot BIP proposal.</description></item><item><title>Secure protocols on BIP taproot</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/secure-protocols-bip-taproot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/secure-protocols-bip-taproot/</guid><description>36C7 1A37 C9D9 88BD E825 08D9 B1A7 0E4F 8DCD 0366
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137358557584793600
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06-06-taproot/
slides: https://nickler.ninja/slides/2019-breaking.pdf
Introduction I am going to tlak about something that is a collaboration of many people in the bitcoin community including my colleagues at Blockstream. The bip-taproot proposal was recently posted to the bitcoin-dev mailing list which proposes an improvement for bitcoin.
Disclaimer It&amp;rsquo;s not at all certain that a bip-taproot soft-fork will activate in its current form or at all.</description></item><item><title>Taproot, Schnorr, and the next soft-fork</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/taproot-schnorr-soft-fork/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/taproot-schnorr-soft-fork/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1162839000811548672
Introduction I am going to speak about this potential next version of bitcoin. Who here has heard of these words? Taproot? Schnorr? Who has heard these buzzwords these days? Yeah, so, the proposed next soft-fork is going to involve both of these technologies sort of interplaying. We want to talk about what are these technologies and how do we use thse things and why is it important that a bitcoin user or holder understands these technologies?</description></item></channel></rss>