<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>altcoins on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/altcoins/</link><description>Recent content in altcoins on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/altcoins/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Monero and the Privacy Doom Principle</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/monero-and-the-privacy-doom-principle/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/monero-and-the-privacy-doom-principle/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a blockchain researcher and developer. I&amp;rsquo;ve built the Sia blockchain ecosystem and I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the space for a while and today I&amp;rsquo;m talking about Monero and privacy models that ended up being explained in analytical techniques that we can use to beat error in privacy.
The Concept of Privacy in Cryptocurrencies So my name is David Vork. I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the blockchain space for about a decade. I&amp;rsquo;ve been between researching and launching blockchains, doing a lot of engineering, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the space for a while and studying things.</description></item><item><title>Why do hardware wallets not support altcoins?</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2020-11-01-greg-maxwell-hardware-wallets-altcoins/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2020-11-01-greg-maxwell-hardware-wallets-altcoins/</guid><description>They&amp;rsquo;re an enormous distraction and hazard to software development. It&amp;rsquo;s hard enough to correctly and safely write software to support one system. Every minute spent creating and testing the software for some alternative is a minute taken away from supporting Bitcoin.
I can say first hand that my efforts to review hardware wallet code against possible vulnerabilities have been actively thwarted by hardware wallet codebases being crapped up with support for altcoins.</description></item><item><title>Socratic Seminar</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chicago-bitdevs/2020-08-12-socratic-seminar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chicago-bitdevs/2020-08-12-socratic-seminar/</guid><description>BitDevs Solo Socratic 4 agenda: https://bitdevs.org/2020-07-31-solo-socratic-4
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have given permission for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Bitcoin Core P2P IRC Meetings https://github.com/bitcoin-core/bitcoin-devwiki/wiki/P2P-IRC-meetings
They are starting P2P meetings for the Bitcoin protocol now. The trend for organizing backbone development for Bitcoin is starting to become more modular.</description></item><item><title>Proof-of-Stake Longest Chain Protocols Revisited</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/proof-of-stake/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/proof-of-stake/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230646529230163968
Introduction Thanks. I am the last talk of the session so I better make it interesting, and if not interesting then short at least. I am going to talk about proof-of-stake. This is collaboration with a few people. Vivek Bagaria, &amp;hellip; et al.
Proof-of-stake prism The starting point of this project was to come up with a proof-of-stake version of prism, which we just saw in the last talk. Prism has good latency and very high throughput and it also inherits the simplicity of the longest-chain protocol because its security is maintained by the longest chain protocol on each of the 1000 voting chains.</description></item><item><title>Linking Anonymous Transactions via Remote Side-Channel Attacks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/linking-anonymous-transactions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/linking-anonymous-transactions/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230214874908655617
paper: https://crypto.stanford.edu/timings/paper.pdf
Introduction This is going to be talking about linking anonymous transactions in zcash and monero. Thanks for the introduction. I am going to be talking about remote side-channel attacks on anonymous transactions. This will be with respect to zcash and monero. Full disclosure, we disclosed all of the things I am talking about here today and everything has been fixed. No need to worry.
This is joint work with Dan Boneh and Kenny Paterson.</description></item><item><title>Stress Testing Decentralized Finance</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/stress-testing-decentralized-finance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/stress-testing-decentralized-finance/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229844754990370816
Introduction More quantitatively, I think coming up with stress tests is akin to Bryan&amp;rsquo;s question&amp;hellip;. stress testing is something that people in this space kind of do, and I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about what that looks like and what an actuarial analysis should look like.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to go through three examples of where an actuarial analysis shows certain weaknesses that need to be monitored and understood. They are going to be more on the scifi end of cryptocurrency.</description></item><item><title>Grin update</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/lehnberg/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/lehnberg/</guid><description>Mimblewimble pros and cons There are no amounts, no addresses, and improved scaling. But one of hte problems is that it requires interactive transactions. But this is a pro because of this you have to participate in mining. You can send money to addresses without having to accept the money. Just as you saw here, you can identify the blue box as an output or an input. You could build up a transaction graph.</description></item><item><title>Quisquis: A New Design for Anonymous Cryptocurrencies</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/quisquis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/quisquis/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1090677466216128512
https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/990
Introduction Good morning. I am here to talk to you about Quisquis which is a new design for an anonymous cryptocurrency. This talk is going to focus on the transaction layer. We don&amp;rsquo;t talk about consensus or smart contracts or higher applications.
Outline I am going to talk about bitcoin and anonymity. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about existing cryptocurrencies that claim to have anonymity and about their limitations. Then I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about our basic solution, where one public key is one coin, updateable public keys, and N-to-N transactions without interactions.</description></item><item><title>Arbitrum 2.0: Faster Off-Chain Contracts with On-Chain Security</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/arbitrum-v2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/arbitrum-v2/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230191734375628802
Introduction Thank you, good morning everybody. I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about our latest version of our Abitrum system. The first version was discussed in a paper in 2018. Since then, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of advances in my technology and a real running system has been made. This is the first working roll-up system for general smart contracts.
First I will set the scene to provide some context on what we&amp;rsquo;re talking about and how what we&amp;rsquo;re doing fits into the larger picture.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin: There Can Only Be One</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/there-can-only-be-one/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/there-can-only-be-one/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1162742007460192256
Introduction I am basically going to talk about why bitcoin will basically eat all the shitcoins and why all of them are going away and I am going to point to some of the details. The big graphic right there is my attempt to categorize all of the altcoins, the ICO space, and so on. Everyone is slowly starting to merge mine with bitcoin, since they can&amp;rsquo;t keep up with the charadde.</description></item><item><title>Celo Ultralight Client</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/celo-ultralight-client/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/celo-ultralight-client/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230261714039398402
Introduction Hello everyone. My name is Marek Olszewski. We are going to be talking about Plumo which is Celo&amp;rsquo;s ultralightweight client protocol. This is joint work with a number of collaborators.
Plumo Plumo sands for &amp;ldquo;feather&amp;rdquo; in esperanto. I hope most people here are familiar with this graph. Chain sizes are growing. This is a graph of the bitcoin chain size over time. It has continued to grow. We&amp;rsquo;re now at 256 megabytes.</description></item><item><title>Cryptographic Hocus-Pocus Meaning Nothing: The Zcash Trusted Setup MPC</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/cryptographic-hocus-pocus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/cryptographic-hocus-pocus/</guid><description>or: &amp;ldquo;Peter Todd&amp;rsquo;s secret love letter to Zooko&amp;rdquo;
Background See http://web.archive.org/web/20170717025249/https://petertodd.org/2016/cypherpunk-desert-bus-zcash-trusted-setup-ceremony
and later it was then redacted: https://petertodd.org/2016/cypherpunk-desert-bus-zcash-trusted-setup-ceremony
Introduction Alright. Hopefully you guys are all awake ish or something. I am going to give a talk about the zcash trusted setup. As many of you know, I was involved in it. The way to start is to answer, what is it?
What is the zcash trusted setup? It&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of toxic waste, basically.</description></item><item><title>Mixicles: Simple Private Decentralized Finance</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/mixicles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/mixicles/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230666545803563008
https://chain.link/mixicles.pdf
Introduction This work was done in my capacity as technical advisor to Chainlink, and not my Cornell or IC3 affiliation. Mixicle is a combination of the words mixers and oracles. You will see why in a moment.
DeFi and privacy As of a couple of weeks ago, DeFi passed the $1 billion mark which is to say there&amp;rsquo;s over $1 billion of cryptocurrency in DeFi smart contracts today. This is great, but wait just a minute.</description></item><item><title>Motoko, the language for the Internet Computer</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/motoko-language/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/motoko-language/</guid><description>Introduction Thanks, Byron. Glad to be here. My name is Dominic Williams. I am founder of the internet computer project at Dfinity Foundation. Last year we talked about consensus protocols. Today we are talking about tools for building on top of the internet computer which is great news and shows the progress we have made. I&amp;rsquo;m going to give some introductory context, and then our senior researcher from our languages division will talk about Motoko.</description></item><item><title>Siacoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/siacoin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/siacoin/</guid><description>I have been working on a decentralized cloud storage platform. Before I go into that, I wanted to mention that I have been working on Bitcoin since 2011. Since 2013 I have been in the wizards channel. In 2014 a friend and myself founded a company to build Siacoin. The team has grown to 3 people. Sia is the name of our decentralized storage protocol. We are trying to emulate Amazon S3.</description></item><item><title>Sound Money</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/dallas-bitcoin-symposium/sound-money/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/dallas-bitcoin-symposium/sound-money/</guid><description>Introduction In 2014, Michael appeared on MSNBC and gave this quote: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;d only recommend using altcoins for speculation purposes if you really love risk, you&amp;rsquo;re absolutely in love with risk, and you&amp;rsquo;re interested in watching money disappear.&amp;rdquo; Today my talk is on sound money for the digital age. The concept of monetary economics is the reason why I got interested in bitcoin back in 2012. I still tihnk that&amp;rsquo;s the important thing that makes bitcoin important in the first place.</description></item><item><title>The Libra Blockchain &amp; Move: A technical introduction</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/libra-blockchain-intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/libra-blockchain-intro/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230248685319024641
Introduction We&amp;rsquo;re building a new wallet for the system, Calibre, which we are launching. A bit about myself before we get started. I have been at Facebook for about 10 years now. Before Facebook, I was one of the co-founders of reCaptcha- the squiggly letters you type in before you login and register. I have been working at Facebook on performance, reliability, and working with web standards to make the web faster.</description></item><item><title>Transparent Dishonesty: front-running attacks on Blockchain</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/transparent-dishonesty/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/transparent-dishonesty/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1231005309310627841
Introduction The last two talks are going to be about frontrunning. One of the features of blockchain is that they are slow but this also opens them up to vulnerabilities such that I can insert my transactions before other people and this could have bad consequences and Shayan is going to explore this a little bit.
My talk will not be as intense as the previous talk, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to have more pictures.</description></item><item><title>Visa &amp; Chain</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coindesk-consensus-2016/visa-chain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coindesk-consensus-2016/visa-chain/</guid><description>Preliminary notes:
Contact me- https://twitter.com/kanzure
Visa &amp;amp; Chain
My name is Adam Ludwin. We are here to talk about blockchain database technology networks. Chain.com is a blockchain database technology company. We do one thing. We partner with financia leaders like Visa to launch blockchain database technology networks. I want to talk about why. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of hype in blockchain database technology. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of attention in blockchain database technology.</description></item></channel></rss>