<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Adaptor signatures on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/adaptor-signatures/</link><description>Recent content in Adaptor signatures on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/adaptor-signatures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nesting, ROAST, Half-Aggregation, Adaptor Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/nesting-roast-half-aggregation-adaptor-signatures/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/nesting-roast-half-aggregation-adaptor-signatures/</guid><description>Speaker 1: 00:00:00
Just as a warning, so don&amp;rsquo;t do this at home.
Speaker 0: 00:00:01
Yes, of course. Still have your friendly neighborhood cryptographer have a look at it.
Speaker 2: 00:00:16
This is the second half of the conversation with Tim and Peter. If you have not listened to the first half, I&amp;rsquo;d suggest going back and listening to that episode. We cover all sorts of fun things, including when to roll your own cryptography, why we prefer Schnorr signatures over ECDSA, Schnorr efficiency improvements, multi-sig, mu-sig, interactive versus non-interactive signing, Frost, and more.</description></item><item><title>Coinjoin Done Right: the onchain offchain mix (and anti-Sybil with RIDDLE)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/coinjoin-done-right-the-onchain-offchain-mix-and-anti-sybil-with-riddles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/coinjoin-done-right-the-onchain-offchain-mix-and-anti-sybil-with-riddles/</guid><description>NOTE: Slides of the talk can be found here
Introduction My name&amp;rsquo;s Adam Gibson, also known as waxwing on the internet. Though the title might suggest that I have the solution to the problem of implementing CoinJoin, it&amp;rsquo;s not exactly true. It&amp;rsquo;s a clickbait. I haven&amp;rsquo;t, but I suppose what I can say in a more serious way is that I&amp;rsquo;m proposing what I consider to be a meaningfully different alternative way of looking at the concept of CoinJoin and therefore at the concept of on-chain privacy because the conversation nowadays about on-chain privacy tends to be dominated by CoinJoin.</description></item><item><title>Socratic Seminar - Discreet Log Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2021-08-10-socratic-seminar-dlcs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2021-08-10-socratic-seminar-dlcs/</guid><description>Gist of resources discussed: https://gist.github.com/michaelfolkson/f5da6774c24f99dba5c6c16ec8d499e9
This event was livestreamed on YouTube and so comments are attributed to specific individuals by the name or pseudonym that was visible on the livestream. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be anonymized please get in touch.
Intro Michael Folkson (MF): Welcome to everyone on the call, welcome to people watching on YouTube. This is a Socratic Seminar, we’ve got a Zoom call and it is being livestreamed on YouTube.</description></item><item><title>A2L: Anonymous Atomic Locks for Scalability and Interoperability in Payment Channel Hubs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/anonymous-atomic-locks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/anonymous-atomic-locks/</guid><description>paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2019/589.pdf
https://github.com/etairi/A2L
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1172116189742546945
Introduction I am going ot talk about anonymous atomic locks for scalability and interoperability in payment-channel hubs. This is joint work with my colleagues.
Scalability I will try to keep this section as short as possible. This talk is also about scalability in bitcoin. You&amp;rsquo;re probably aware of the scalability issues. There is decentralized data structure recording each transaction in order to provide public verifiability. Global consensus is required, such that everyone checks the whole blockchain.</description></item><item><title>Secure protocols on BIP taproot</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/secure-protocols-bip-taproot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/secure-protocols-bip-taproot/</guid><description>36C7 1A37 C9D9 88BD E825 08D9 B1A7 0E4F 8DCD 0366
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137358557584793600
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06-06-taproot/
slides: https://nickler.ninja/slides/2019-breaking.pdf
Introduction I am going to tlak about something that is a collaboration of many people in the bitcoin community including my colleagues at Blockstream. The bip-taproot proposal was recently posted to the bitcoin-dev mailing list which proposes an improvement for bitcoin.
Disclaimer It&amp;rsquo;s not at all certain that a bip-taproot soft-fork will activate in its current form or at all.</description></item><item><title>Grin update</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/lehnberg/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/lehnberg/</guid><description>Mimblewimble pros and cons There are no amounts, no addresses, and improved scaling. But one of hte problems is that it requires interactive transactions. But this is a pro because of this you have to participate in mining. You can send money to addresses without having to accept the money. Just as you saw here, you can identify the blue box as an output or an input. You could build up a transaction graph.</description></item><item><title>Building Mimblewimble/Grin, an implementation for privacy and scalability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/building-mimblewimble-and-grin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/building-mimblewimble-and-grin/</guid><description>Quentin Le Sceller (Grin Dev Team), Ignotus Peverell (Grin Dev Team), Yeastplume (Grin Dev Team), Antioch Peverell (Grin Dev Team), HashMap (Grin Dev Team), John Tromp (Grin Dev Team), Daniel Lehnberg (Grin Dev Team)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1090662484275384320
Our first talk is from the Grin project. It was just launched a few weeks ago. Okay, let&amp;rsquo;s get started.
Introduction Hi everyone. My name is Quentin Le Sceller. I&amp;rsquo;m a developer at Blockcypher. I am here to talk about grin, specifically about building mimblewimble and grin an implementation for privacy and scalability.</description></item><item><title>The State of Atomic Swaps</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/atomic-swaps/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/atomic-swaps/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048790167283068929
History This should be easy to follow. I want to start off with some history. The first mention of atomic swap concepts was in 2013 in a bitcointalk.org thread where people were wondering how to exchange coins between independent ledgers in a trustless way. There were a few comments on the thread every now and then asking has anyone implemented this. It was quiet until last year when people started doing atomic swaps last year.</description></item><item><title>Taproot, Schnorr signatures, and SIGHASH_NOINPUT</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2018-07-09-taproot-schnorr-signatures-and-sighash-noinput-oh-my/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2018-07-09-taproot-schnorr-signatures-and-sighash-noinput-oh-my/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1021880538020368385
slides: https://prezi.com/view/YkJwE7LYJzAzJw9g1bWV/
Introduction I am Pieter Wuille. I will just dive in. Today I want to talk about improvements to the bitcoin scripting language. There is feedback in the microphone. Okay.
I will mostly be talking about improvements to the bitcoin scripting language. This is by no means an exhaustive list of all the things that are going on. It&amp;rsquo;s more my personal focus in the things that I am interested in and excited about seeing happen.</description></item><item><title>Blind Signatures in Scriptless Scripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/blind-signatures-and-scriptless-scripts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/blind-signatures-and-scriptless-scripts/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014197255593603072
My name is Jonas. I work at Blockstream as an engineer. I am going to talk about some primitives about blind signatures, scriptless scripts, and blind coin swap, and I will explain how to trustlessly exchange ecash tokens using bitcoin.
I want to introduce the blind Schnorr signature in a few moments.
Schnorr signature My assumption is not that you will completely understand Schnorr signatures, but maybe you will at least agree that if you can understand Schnorr signatures then the step to blind Schnorr signatures is not a big step.</description></item><item><title>Cross Curve Atomic Swaps</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-03/2018-03-05-cross-curve-atomic-swaps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-03/2018-03-05-cross-curve-atomic-swaps/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/971827042223345664
Draft of an upcoming scriptless scripts paper. This was at the beginning of 2017. But now an entire year has gone by.
post-schnorr lightning transactions https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/lightning-dev/2018-February/001031.html
An adaptor signature.. if you have different generators, then the two secrets to reveal, you just give someone both of them, plus a proof of a discrete log, and then you say learn the secret to one that gets the reveal to be the same.</description></item><item><title>Schnorr Signatures For Bitcoin: Challenges and Opportunities</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/schnorr-signatures-for-bitcoin-challenges-opportunities/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/schnorr-signatures-for-bitcoin-challenges-opportunities/</guid><description>slides: https://prezi.com/bihvorormznd/schnorr-signatures-for-bitcoin/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/958776403977220098
https://blockstream.com/2018/02/15/schnorr-signatures-bpase.html
Introduction My name is Pieter Wuille. I work at Blockstream. I contribute to Bitcoin Core and bitcoin research in general. I work on various proposals for the bitcoin system for some time now. Today I will be talking about Schnorr signatures for bitcoin, which is a project we&amp;rsquo;ve been working on, on-and-off, for a couple of years now. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the cool things that we can do that might be non-obvious, and also some non-obvious challenges that we ran into while doing this.</description></item><item><title>Mimblewimble And Scriptless Scripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/realworldcrypto/2018/mimblewimble-and-scriptless-scripts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/realworldcrypto/2018/mimblewimble-and-scriptless-scripts/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/954531580848082944
We&amp;rsquo;re about ready for the second session of RWC. We are going to move on to cryptocurrencies. So we have 3 talks lined up in this session. The first one is on mimblewimble and scriptless scripts, delivered by Andrew Poelstra from Blockstream.
Introduction Thank you. Cool. Hello. My name is Andrew Poelstra. I am the research director at Blockstream and I&amp;rsquo;m here to talk about a couple of things that I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about over the past year, called mimblewimble, and also scriptless scripts.</description></item><item><title>Mimblewimble And Scriptless Scripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/mimblewimble-and-scriptless-scripts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/mimblewimble-and-scriptless-scripts/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/838480912396533760
Up next we have Andrew Poelstra and he is going to be talking about a really interesting new concept for a cryptocurrency. It&amp;rsquo;s called mimblewimble, after a spell from Harry Potter, because it prevents characters from speaking. Try speaking? Hello, test. We also have a&amp;hellip; hello? hello? Can you guys hear me?
I am going to talk about the concept of scriptless scripts. It&amp;rsquo;s a way of describing what mimblewimble does, in a way that shows the conceptual details, and maybe give the ability to take the lessons we learned from mimblewimble and apply to other projects.</description></item><item><title>Mimblewimble</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-11-21-mimblewimble/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-11-21-mimblewimble/</guid><description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aHTRlbCaUyM
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/801990263543648256
History As Denise said, I gave a talk in Milan about mimblewimble about a month ago (slides). This is more or less the same talk, but rebalanced a bit to try to emphasize what I think is important and add some history that has happened in the intervening time. I&amp;rsquo;ll get started.
Many of you have heard of mimblewimble. It&amp;rsquo;s been in the news. It has a catchy name.</description></item><item><title>Mimblewimble: Private, Massively-Prunable Blockchains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/mimblewimble/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/mimblewimble/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784696648597405696
slides: http://diyhpl.us/~bryan/papers2/bitcoin/mimblewimble-2016-scaling-bitcoin-slides.pdf
Hi, I am from Blockstream. I am here to talk about Mimblewimble. Mimblewimble is not mine. It&amp;rsquo;s from the dark lord. I am going to start with the history of the paper. It has been in the news a little bit. I will talk about the transaction structure, the block structure, try to explain the trust model and argue that it&amp;rsquo;s almost as strong as bitcoin. There&amp;rsquo;s less data to verify than in bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Mimblewimble Podcast</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/mimblewimble-podcast/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/mimblewimble-podcast/</guid><description>Andrew Poelstra (andytoshi) Pieter Wuille (sipa) Brian Deery Chris Odom Starts at 26min.
I am going to introduce our guests here in just a minute.
Launch of zcash might be delayed in order to allow the code to be analyzed by multiple third-party auditors. Zooko stated, &amp;ldquo;I feel bad that we didn&amp;rsquo;t do a better job of making TheDAO disaster-like problems harder for people&amp;rdquo;.
Our guests on the line are Andrew Poelstra and Pieter Wuille.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Preserving Multi Hop Locks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/privacy-preserving-multi-hop-locks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/privacy-preserving-multi-hop-locks/</guid><description>Privacy preserving multi-hop locks for blockchain scalability and interoperability
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1091026195032924160
paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/472.pdf
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-hop-locks/
Introduction This is joint work with my collaborators. Permissionless blockchains have some issues. The permissionless nature leads to the transaction rate that they have. This limits widespread adoption of blockchain technology like bitcoin or ethereum. Scalability approaches can be roughly grouped into two groups, one is on-chain layer 1 solutions. The other group is off-chain layer 2, which is the focus of this talk today.</description></item><item><title>Scriptless Scripts With Mimblewimble</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/scriptless-scripts-with-mimblewimble/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/scriptless-scripts-with-mimblewimble/</guid><description>Introduction Hi everyone. I am Andrew Poelstra. I am the research director at Blockstream. I want to talk about deploying scriptless scripts, wihch is something I haven&amp;rsquo;t talked much about over the past year or two.
History Let me give a bit of history about mimblewimble. As many of you know, this was dead-dropped anonymously in the middle of 2016 by someone named Tom Elvis Jedusor which is the French name for Voldemort.</description></item><item><title>Taproot, Schnorr, and the next soft-fork</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/taproot-schnorr-soft-fork/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/taproot-schnorr-soft-fork/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1162839000811548672
Introduction I am going to speak about this potential next version of bitcoin. Who here has heard of these words? Taproot? Schnorr? Who has heard these buzzwords these days? Yeah, so, the proposed next soft-fork is going to involve both of these technologies sort of interplaying. We want to talk about what are these technologies and how do we use thse things and why is it important that a bitcoin user or holder understands these technologies?</description></item><item><title>Threshold Scriptless Scripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/threshold-scriptless-scripts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/threshold-scriptless-scripts/</guid><description>Omer Shlomovits (KZen Research) (omershlomovits, zengo)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171690582445580288
Scriptless scripts We can write smart contracts in bitcoin today, but there&amp;rsquo;s some limitations. We can do a lot of great things. We can do atomic swaps, multisig, payment channels, etc. There&amp;rsquo;s a cost, though. Transactions become bigger with bigger scripts. Also, it&amp;rsquo;s kind of heavy on the verifiers. The verifiers now need to verify more things. There&amp;rsquo;s also privacy issues because you put your contract publicly on chain.</description></item><item><title>Using Chains for what They're Good For</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/using-the-chain-for-what-chains-are-good-for/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/using-the-chain-for-what-chains-are-good-for/</guid><description>I am Andrew Poelstra, a cryptographer at Blockstream. I am going to talk about scriptless scripts. But this is a specific example of a more general theme, which is using the blockchain as a trust anchor or commitment layer for smart contracts whose real contents don&amp;rsquo;t really hit the blockchain. I&amp;rsquo;ll elaborate on what I mean by that, and I&amp;rsquo;ll show what the benefits are for that.
To give some context, in Bitcoin script, the scripting language which is used to encode smart contracts, which go on to the blockchain and everyone verifies the chain and downloads and executes all of this contract code.</description></item></channel></rss>