<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Consensus Enforcement on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/consensus-enforcement/</link><description>Recent content in Consensus Enforcement on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/consensus-enforcement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bitcoin Q&amp;A: Initial Blockchain Download</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/andreas-antonopoulos/2018-10-23-andreas-antonopoulos-initial-blockchain-download/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/andreas-antonopoulos/2018-10-23-andreas-antonopoulos-initial-blockchain-download/</guid><description>Becca asks why does it take it so long to download the blockchain? I do have a fast internet connection and I could download 200GB in less than a hour. What Becca is talking about is what’s called the initial blockchain download or IBD which is the first synchronization of the Bitcoin node or any kind of blockchain node to its blockchain. The answer is that while the amount of data you need to download in order to get the full blockchain is about 200GB or so you’re not simply downloading that and storing it on disk.</description></item><item><title>Abstract Thinking About Consensus Systems</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/abstract-thinking-about-consensus-systems/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/abstract-thinking-about-consensus-systems/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048039485550690304
slides: https://drive.google.com/file/d/1LiGzgFXMI2zq8o9skErLcO3ET2YeQbyx/view?usp=sharing
Serialization Blocks are usually thought of as a serialized data stream. But really these are only true on the network serialization or over the network. A different implementation of bitcoin could in theory use a different format. The format is only used on the network and the disk, not the consensus protocol. The format could actually be completely different.
Each block is identified by a single cryptographic hash and it commits to various abstract information.</description></item><item><title>Consensus Barnacles</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lets-talk-bitcoin-podcast/2016-12-25-christopher-jeffrey-consensus-barnacles/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lets-talk-bitcoin-podcast/2016-12-25-christopher-jeffrey-consensus-barnacles/</guid><description>SF Bitcoin Devs presentation on Bcoin: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-09-28-christopher-jeffrey-bcoin/
Breaking Bitcoin presentation on consensus pitfalls: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/breaking-bitcoin/2017/2017-09-10-christopher-jeffrey-consensus-pitfalls/
History of Bcoin Adam Levine (AL): JJ thanks for being here today.
Christopher Jeffrey (JJ): Thanks man. Glad to be here.
AL: We are going to jump right into it with the elephant in the room on all this stuff. Bcoin is effectively an alternative implementation of the Nakamoto client including consensus code. That is kind of a controversial thing.</description></item><item><title>Bcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-09-28-christopher-jeffrey-bcoin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2016-09-28-christopher-jeffrey-bcoin/</guid><description>Bcoin repo: https://github.com/bcoin-org/bcoin
Intro Hey everyone. I’m JJ with Purse. Tonight I want to talk to you about full nodes and full node implementations in general. In particular my project and the project we’ve been working on at Purse which is bcoin. A little history about me. I’ve actually given a presentation here before two years ago at the dev meetup. What I gave my talk on two years ago was actually the process of turning bitcoind into a shared object, into a library so you could link to it and call functions directly and call consensus code.</description></item><item><title>Reaching Consensus on Open Blockchains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coindesk-consensus-2016/reaching-consensus-open-blockchains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coindesk-consensus-2016/reaching-consensus-open-blockchains/</guid><description>Preliminary notes:
Contact me- https://twitter.com/kanzure
Reaching consensus on open blockchains
Moderator- Pindar Wong
Gavin Andresen, MIT Digital Currency Initiative
Vitalik Buterin, Ethereum Foundation
Eric Lombrozo, Ciphrex and Bitcoin Core
Neha Narula, MIT Media Lab Digital Currency Initiative
Please silence your cell phone during this session. Thank you. Please silence your cell phones during this session. Thank you. Ladies and gentlemen, please take your seats. The session is about to begin.</description></item></channel></rss>