<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>attacks on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/attacks/</link><description>Recent content in attacks on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/attacks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sydney Socratic Seminar</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-02-23-socratic-seminar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-02-23-socratic-seminar/</guid><description>Name: Socratic Seminar
Topic: Agenda in Google Doc below
Location: Bitcoin Sydney (online)
Video: No video posted online
Google Doc of the resources discussed: https://docs.google.com/document/d/1VAP4LNjHHVLy9RJwpQ8LqXEUw79z5TTZxr9du_Z0-9A/
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.</description></item><item><title>Erebus Attacks And How To Stop Them With ASMAP</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-magazine/bitcoin-explained/erebus-attacks-and-how-to-stop-them-with-asmap/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-magazine/bitcoin-explained/erebus-attacks-and-how-to-stop-them-with-asmap/</guid><description>Aaron van Wirdum: 00:00:07
Live from Utrecht, this is The Van Wirdum Sjorsnado.
Sjors Provoost: 00:00:10
Hello!
Aaron van Wirdum: 00:00:10
Hey Sjors. What&amp;rsquo;s up? We got a market cap all time high, did you celebrate?
Sjors Provoost: 00:00:14
No, I did not because it&amp;rsquo;s just dilution.
Aaron van Wirdum: 00:00:16
What do you mean?
Sjors Provoost: 00:00:17
I mean somebody&amp;rsquo;s making more Bitcoin. So it&amp;rsquo;s fun that the market cap goes up, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter unless you&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Lightning Topics</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-08-13-christian-decker-lightning-topics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-08-13-christian-decker-lightning-topics/</guid><description>Topic: ANYPREVOUT, MPP, Mitigating Lightning Attacks
Location: Stephan Livera Podcast
Transcript completed by: Stephan Livera Edited by: Michael Folkson
Latest ANYPREVOUT update ANYPREVOUT BIP (BIP 118): https://github.com/ajtowns/bips/blob/bip-anyprevout/bip-0118.mediawiki
Stephan Livera (SL): Christian welcome back to the show.
Christian Decker (CD): Hey Stephan, thanks for having me.
SL: I wanted to chat with you about a bunch of stuff that you’ve been doing. We’ve got a couple of things that I was really interested to chat with you about: ANYPREVOUT, MPP, Lightning attacks, the latest with Lightning Network.</description></item><item><title>Revault</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/honey-badger-diaries/2020-04-24-kevin-loaec-antoine-poinsot-revault/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/honey-badger-diaries/2020-04-24-kevin-loaec-antoine-poinsot-revault/</guid><description>Revault Bitcoin vaults
Location: Honey Badger Diaries (podcast)
Transcript (abridged) Aaron: So you guys built something. First tell me are you a company? Is this a startup? What is the story here?
Kevin: My personal interest in vaults started last year when Bryan Bishop published his email on the mailing list. I was like “That is an interesting concept.” After that I started engaging with him on Twitter proposing a few different ideas.</description></item><item><title>Stress Testing Decentralized Finance</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/stress-testing-decentralized-finance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/stress-testing-decentralized-finance/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229844754990370816
Introduction More quantitatively, I think coming up with stress tests is akin to Bryan&amp;rsquo;s question&amp;hellip;. stress testing is something that people in this space kind of do, and I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about what that looks like and what an actuarial analysis should look like.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to go through three examples of where an actuarial analysis shows certain weaknesses that need to be monitored and understood. They are going to be more on the scifi end of cryptocurrency.</description></item><item><title>P2P Privacy Attacks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-10-09-giulia-fanti-p2p-privacy-attacks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-10-09-giulia-fanti-p2p-privacy-attacks/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs 2019 Residency
Slides: https://residency.chaincode.com/presentations/bitcoin/giulia_fanti_bitcoin_p2p.pdf
Giulia: So today I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk to you about some work that my collaborators and I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on for the last three years now. So this was joint work with a bunch of people who are now spread across a few different universities but it started at the University of Illinois: Shaileshh Bojja Venkatakrishnan, Surya Bakshi, Brad Denby, Shruti Bhargava, Andrew Miller, Pramod Viswanath.</description></item><item><title>Attack Vectors of Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-fabrice-drouin-attack-vectors-of-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-fabrice-drouin-attack-vectors-of-lightning-network/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Residency – Summer 2019
Introduction All right so I&amp;rsquo;m going to introduce really quickly attack vectors on Lightning. I focus on first what you can do with the Lightning protocol, but I will mostly speak about how attacks will probably happen in real life. It&amp;rsquo;s probably not going to be direct attacks on the protocol itself.
Denial of Service So the basic attacks you can have when you&amp;rsquo;re running lightning nodes are denial of service attacks basically.</description></item><item><title>Network Partitioning Attacks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-12-ethan-heilman-network-partitioning-attacks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-12-ethan-heilman-network-partitioning-attacks/</guid><description>Bitcoin network partitioning &amp;amp; network-level privacy attacks
Location: Chaincode Labs 2019 Residency
Slides: https://residency.chaincode.com/presentations/bitcoin/ethan_heilman_p2p.pdf
Eclipse attack paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2015/263.pdf
Bitcoin’s P2P Network Please interrupt me. I&amp;rsquo;m going to go through this stuff a little bit quickly because I hear that you&amp;rsquo;ve already read Eclipse attack paper and you&amp;rsquo;ve already looked at some of the peer to peer stuff.
Bitcoin uses a peer-to-peer network to announce transactions and blocks. It makes 8 outgoing connections.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Topological Analysis</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-topological-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-topological-analysis/</guid><description>Topological analysis of the lightning network
paper: https://arxiv.org/abs/1901.04972
https://github.com/seresistvanandras/LNTopology
Introduction Knowing the topology is not necessarily a vulnerability, but it gives you a lot of information. If I know Bryan&amp;rsquo;s full node is connected to some other nodes, I will have an easier time to cut Bryan out of the network or launch attacks against him. Knowing the topology is not necessarily a vulnerability, but it&amp;rsquo;s really strong information.
Recent research There were some recent papers published on this topic:</description></item><item><title>Breaking Hardware Wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/breaking-hardware-wallets/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/breaking-hardware-wallets/</guid><description>Breaking hardware wallets: Tales from the trenches and glimpses into the future
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005627960160849920
Hello. Nobody cares? Ah. So next up is Nicolas. And he will talk about hardware attacks. Thank you.
Introduction Hi everybody. Thanks for making a great conference so far. I am Nicolas from Ledger hardware wallet. Today I am going to be talking about breaking hardware wallets. I don&amp;rsquo;t mean physically breaking them. If you expected to come steal a hardware wallet and be able to break it, then you will be disappointed.</description></item><item><title>Spam Attacks Analysis</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/spam-attacks-analysis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/spam-attacks-analysis/</guid><description>Hunting moby dick, an analysis of 2015-2016 spam attacks
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005525351517360129
Introduction Hi. Thanks for Breaking Bitcoin to invite me to speak and to present this research on Moby Dick.
Moby Dick and spam attacks&amp;ndash; let me explain, Moby Dick is an entity that spammed or sent a lot of transactions in bitcoin in 2015. We did some analysis on who this person is or what they were doing. This is bitcoin archaeology, where we analyze past activities and try to analyze what happened and get insight into what could happen.</description></item><item><title>Beyond Hashrate Majority Attacks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/beyond-hashrate-majority-attacks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/beyond-hashrate-majority-attacks/</guid><description>Beyond 51% attacks
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230624835996250112
Introduction Alright let&amp;rsquo;s get started with the next session. Vitalik is from Canada. He is a former writer for Bitcoin Magazine and can often be seen wearing unicorn shirts. He will be telling us about &amp;ldquo;Beyond 51% attacks&amp;rdquo;. Take it away.
Okay, so hello everyone. Hi. Okay. I will start by reminding everyone that 51% attacks are in fact bad. Bear with me for a few minutes.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Load Spike Simulation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/bitcoin-load-spike-simulation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/bitcoin-load-spike-simulation/</guid><description>Our goal for this project, our rationale of what we&amp;rsquo;re interesting is when many transactions arrive in a short period of time. This could be because of denial of service attacks where few entities are creating a large number of transactions, or many people wanting to create transactions, like a shopping spree. We wanted to answer two questions, how does the temporary spike in transaction rate affect confirmation delay distribution? For a given spike shape, can we change the block size and how would that effect the evolution of the system?</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Script V2.0 And Strengthened Payment Channels</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/bitcoin-script-v2.0-and-strengthened-payment-channels/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/bitcoin-script-v2.0-and-strengthened-payment-channels/</guid><description>This is a brief history of bitcoin script evolution. Since bitcoin was active in 2009, there was a lot of emergency fixes for the first 2 years done by Satoshi. He found that people could skpi the signature check using OP_RETURN and malformed scriptSigs. So those functions were removed. OP_VER and OP_VERIF were intended for script upgrades but it was found that after every release of bitcoin, it would become a hard-fork because of the design.</description></item><item><title>Competitive Equilibria Staking Lending</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/competitive-equilibria-staking-lending/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/competitive-equilibria-staking-lending/</guid><description>Competitive equilibria between staking and on-chain lending
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230581977289379840
https://arxiv.org/pdf/2001.00919v1.pdf
See also &amp;ldquo;Stress testing decentralized finance&amp;rdquo; https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/stress-testing-decentralized-finance/
Introduction There have been some odd finanical attacks in the DeFi space and also on staking. This talk aims to show that the threat model for staking is definitively different from that of proof-of-work, and these financial attacks need to be part of the threat model.
Agenda I&amp;rsquo;ll go over some high level overview of intuitive market dynamics, then we will build up an agent-based model that correctly goes across multiple participants to stress test staking situations, then we go through the various assumptions, and at a high-level I&amp;rsquo;ll give some formal probability statements without proofs, and finally I have simulation results to discuss which can give you some idea about how to design a monetary policy.</description></item><item><title>Covenants</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/covenants/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/covenants/</guid><description>Bitcoin covenants: Opportunities and challenges
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785071789705728000
We published this last February at an academic workshop. The work itself has interesting ramifications. My real goal here is to start a conversation and then do a follow-up blog post where we collate feedback from the community. We would like to add this to Bitcoin Core. Covenants.
This all started from a very basic and simple observation about the current status of our computing infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>Day 1 Group Summaries</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/day-1-group-summaries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/day-1-group-summaries/</guid><description>Day 1 group summaries
We need two to three minute report backs from each session. Also, note takers. Please email your notes to contact@scalingbitcoin.org so that we can add notes to the wiki. Come join us. Okay, so.
Lightning We discussed routing and several aspects of routing algorithms in the lightning network. We talked about the tradeoff between privacy aspects and reliability in routing. We quickly discovered that after some of the things were already resolved by the papers&amp;ndash; the way how we deal with a general separation and channel transaction fees, is actually quite an interesting discussion topic.</description></item><item><title>Extracting Seeds From Hardware Wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/extracting-seeds-from-hardware-wallets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/extracting-seeds-from-hardware-wallets/</guid><description>7DC5A359D0D5B5AB6728&amp;hellip;
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137672946435198976
Introduction My talk is about extracting seeds from hardware wallets. I am chief security officer at Ledger. I joined Ledger a bit more than one year ago. I built the Ledger Donjon which is an independent red team. Our mission is to help secure Ledger&amp;rsquo;s products. So what we do day to do is try to break all the hardware wallets. We continuously challenge the security of our products.</description></item><item><title>Failures Of Secret Key Cryptography (2013)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/failures-of-secret-key-cryptography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/failures-of-secret-key-cryptography/</guid><description>FSE 2013
Welcome to the second invited talk, to be given by Dan Bernstein. Dan is one of the few members of our community who does not need an introduction. It&amp;rsquo;s a great honor and pleasure that he has agreed to give a talk here. Dan comes from UC Berkeley and from Chicago. Just a few things you might know Dan from&amp;ndash; he sued the U.S. government about export controls. In 2004, .</description></item><item><title>Lehnberg</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/lehnberg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/lehnberg/</guid><description>daniel/lehberg
Mimblewimble pros and cons There are no amounts, no addresses, and improved scaling. But one of hte problems is that it requires interactive transactions. But this is a pro because of this you have to participate in mining. You can send money to addresses without having to accept the money. Just as you saw here, you can identify the blue box as an output or an input. You could build up a transaction graph.</description></item><item><title>Linking Anonymous Transactions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/linking-anonymous-transactions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/linking-anonymous-transactions/</guid><description>Linking anonymous transactions via remote side-channel attacks
Florian Tramer
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230214874908655617
paper: https://crypto.stanford.edu/timings/paper.pdf
Introduction This is going to be talking about linking anonymous transactions in zcash and monero. Thanks for the introduction. I am going to be talking about remote side-channel attacks on anonymous transactions. This will be with respect to zcash and monero. Full disclosure, we disclosed all of the things I am talking about here today and everything has been fixed.</description></item><item><title>Overview Of Security Concerns</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/overview-of-security-concerns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/overview-of-security-concerns/</guid><description>Overview of Security Concerns
I am going to talk about scale-related security issues. Scale-related security issues. I said scale, not scalability. We are not talking about scalability. We&amp;rsquo;re talking about changing numbers, and what are the implications, what attacks are easier or harder by changing the block size number. What are we trying to accomplish? What is the system meant to be? Nobody really agrees of course. What&amp;rsquo;s interesting is that as much as we disagree about what was meant to be, there are a lot of key things about what bitcoin could be, these visions share some details.</description></item><item><title>Security Attacks Decentralized Mining Pools</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/security-attacks-decentralized-mining-pools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/security-attacks-decentralized-mining-pools/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137373752038240262
Introduction Hi, I am Alexei. I am a research student at Imperial College London and I will be talking about the security of decentralized mining pools.
Motivation The motivation behind this talk is straightforward. I think we can all agree that to some extent the hashrate in bitcoin has seen some centralization around large mining pools, which undermines the base properties of censorship resistance in bitcoin which I think bitcoin solves in a nice matter.</description></item><item><title>Sybilquorum</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/sybilquorum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/sybilquorum/</guid><description>SybilQuorum: Open distributed ledgers through trust networks
Alberto Sonnino from UCL and chainspace.io
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1090777875253407745
Introduction This is joint work with George Danezis who couldn&amp;rsquo;t be here today and also cofounded Chainspace. Among all the possible challenges we may have on a blockchain, this talk will be about how to build strong sybil resistance. We would consider a subset of the problem, how will we bootstrap a federated agreement system?
Sybil attacks I am sure everyone knows about sybil attacks.</description></item><item><title>Transparent Dishonesty</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/transparent-dishonesty/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/transparent-dishonesty/</guid><description>Transparent dishonesty: frontrunning attacks on blockchain
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1231005309310627841
Introduction The last two talks are going to be about frontrunning. One of the features of blockchain is that they are slow but this also opens them up to vulnerabilities such that I can insert my transactions before other people and this could have bad consequences and Shayan is going to explore this a little bit.
My talk will not be as intense as the previous talk, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to have more pictures.</description></item><item><title>Vulnerability Detection</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/vulnerability-detection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/vulnerability-detection/</guid><description>Automatic detection of vulnerabilities in smart contracts
Mooly Sagiv
Introduction If you find a bug in a smart contract, it&amp;rsquo;s really hard to mitigate that bug. In formal verification, we really look for bugs. We can identify subtle bugs, like reentrancy attacks, ownership violation, incorrect transactions, bugs due to updated code. We also want to assure the absence of bugs.
Device drivers I come from the domain of Windows device drivers.</description></item><item><title>Why Block Sizes Should Not Be Too Big</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/why-block-sizes-should-not-be-too-big/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/why-block-sizes-should-not-be-too-big/</guid><description>Briefly, why block sizes shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too big
slides: https://luke.dashjr.org/tmp/code/block-sizes-mcc.pdf
I am luke-jr. I am going to go over why block size shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be too big.
How does bitcoin work? Miners put transactrions into blocks. Users verify that the blocks are valid. If the users don&amp;rsquo;t verify this, then miners can do basically anything. Because the users do this, 51% attacks are limited to reorgs which is undoing transactions. If there&amp;rsquo;s no users verifying this, then miners have no incentive to do this.</description></item></channel></rss>