<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Adam Back on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/adam-back/</link><description>Recent content in Adam Back on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/adam-back/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Simplicity - Next-Gen Smart Contracting</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockstream-webinars/2020-04-08-adam-back-simplicity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockstream-webinars/2020-04-08-adam-back-simplicity/</guid><description>Location: Blockstream webinar
Slides: https://docsend.com/view/svs27jr
Blockstream blog post on the Jets release: https://medium.com/blockstream/simplicity-jets-release-803db10fd589
Simplicity GitHub repo: https://github.com/elementsproject/simplicity
Asciinema video used in the presentation: https://asciinema.org/a/rhIsJBixoB3k8yuFQQr2UGAQN
Join the Simplicity mailing list here: https://lists.ozlabs.org/listinfo/simplicity
Intro I am going to describe Simplicity which we made an announcement recently. It is a next generation script language for Bitcoin and Bitcoin-like networks which include Elements and Liquid. It is primarily the work of Russell O’Connor but Andrew Poelstra has been helping also since Fall of last year where we made a previous release.</description></item><item><title>Block Reorgs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/what-bitcoin-did-podcast/2019-05-14-adam-back-bryan-bishop-block-reorgs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/what-bitcoin-did-podcast/2019-05-14-adam-back-bryan-bishop-block-reorgs/</guid><description>Topic: Bitcoin Block Re-orgs
Location: What Bitcoin Did Podcast
Bitcoin Stack Exchange on blockchain rollbacks: https://bitcoin.stackexchange.com/questions/87652/51-attack-apparently-very-easy-refering-to-czs-rollback-btc-chain-how-t
Transcript completed by: Peter McCormack Edited by: Michael Folkson
Bitcoin Block Re-orgs Peter McCormack (PM): Adam, how are you?
Adam Back (AB): Good!
PM: How you doing Bryan?
Bryan Bishop (BB): Doing good!
PM: So we&amp;rsquo;re here to talk about re-orgs. Something I&amp;rsquo;d heard about before because didn&amp;rsquo;t the BSV chain have a couple of re-orgs recently?</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Satellite Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/bitcoin-satellite-network/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/bitcoin-satellite-network/</guid><description>Bitcoin in Spaaace! I am going to be talking about the bitcoin satellite service that Blockstream has been offering for a few years now. I am going to talk about what it does and why that&amp;rsquo;s interesting to users.
Satellite infrastructure There are 4 satellites, 2 uplinks with base stations sending data up to the satellites, and then 5 transponders. It&amp;rsquo;s covering both Asia and Australia with one satellite with two transponders.</description></item><item><title>Interview Adam Back Elizabeth Stark</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/interview-adam-back-elizabeth-stark/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/interview-adam-back-elizabeth-stark/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005842855271784449
stark: Thank you Giacomo. Who here had too much fun at the party last night? My voice is going. Hopefully it will stay for this interview. We are lucky to have Adam Back here today, co-founder of Blockstream and inventor of Hashcash (history). He just happened to appear and there was an available spot. Thank you for making this work.
adam3us: Thank you for inviting me.
stark: I&amp;rsquo;m a co-organizer of this event.</description></item><item><title>Implications of Blockchain</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2016-adam-back/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2016-adam-back/</guid><description>New Context Conference 2016 http://dg717.com/ncc/en/
We are using a hashtag to organize the information today. The hashtag we&amp;rsquo;re using is nccblockchain. Ncc stands for new conference context. That&amp;rsquo;s where we are. Blockchain is what we&amp;rsquo;re talkin gabout. Can I ask the people in the back to take a seat? We&amp;rsquo;re about to get ready. Meet the neighbor near your seat. Switch your cellphone off. I am going to demonstrate. The toilets squirt you.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Scaling Tradeoffs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/adam3us-bitcoin-scaling-tradeoffs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/adam3us-bitcoin-scaling-tradeoffs/</guid><description>Bitcoin scaling tradeoffs with Adam Back (adam3us) at Paralelni Polis
Institute of Cryptoanarchy http://www.paralelnipolis.cz/
slides: http://www.slideshare.net/paralelnipolis/bitcoin-scaling-tradeoffs-with-adam-back
description: &amp;ldquo;In this talk, Adam Back overviews the Bitcoin scaling and discuses his personal view about its tradeoffs and future development.&amp;rdquo;
Intro fluff And now I would like to introduce you to a great guest from the U.K. or Malta, Adam Back. Adam is long-time professional cryptologist and also he&amp;rsquo;s a Bitcoin expert. He&amp;rsquo;s the inventor of hashcash, which was used for example by Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Epicenter Bitcoin - Scalability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2015-09-07-epicenter-bitcoin-adam3us-scalability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2015-09-07-epicenter-bitcoin-adam3us-scalability/</guid><description>Why bitcoin needs a measured approach to scaling
Name: Adam Back (adam3us) Epicenter (EC)
Sebastien Couture (SC) Brian Fabian Crain (BC)
BC: Adam Back is here for the second time on this show. Some of you will be familiar that Adam Back is the inventor of proof-of-work or hashcash as it was then. He was one of the few people cited in the original Bitcoin whitepaper. More recently he has been involved in sidechains and Blockstream where he is a founder.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Sidechains - Unchained Epicenter</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/bitcoin-sidechains-unchained-epicenter-adam3us-gmaxwell/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/bitcoin-sidechains-unchained-epicenter-adam3us-gmaxwell/</guid><description>EB65 – Adam Back &amp;amp; Greg Maxwell: Sidechains Unchained
people:
Sebastien Couture Brian Fabian Crain Adam Back (adam3us) Greg Maxwell (gmaxwell) Brian: We are here today we have Adam Back and Greg Maxwell, to anyone who is following bitcoin and bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s development, you will have probably heard of these two gentlemen. I was fortunate enough that the first time that I went to a bitcoin conference at the beginning of my involvement in this space, it was in Amsterdam 2013 and I somehow randomly ended up having dinner twice with Adam which really was super fascinating talking to him about bitcoin, and so I&amp;rsquo;m really exciting to have them on today, especially since we are going to have a chance to talk about a project we have talked about many times on this show before, with different people, which is sidechains, because sidechains I think that everyone is in agreement that it is one of the more interesting projects in the space, and a lot of people have many questions about it.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Without Internet</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/bitcoin-without-internet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/bitcoin-without-internet/</guid><description>SM: We have a special announcement to make. Let me kick it over to Richard right now.
RM: We completed a project that will integrate the GoTenna mesh radio system with Blockstream&amp;rsquo;s blocksat satellite system. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty exciting. It&amp;rsquo;s called txtenna. It will allow anybody to send a signed bitcoin transaction from an off-grid full node that is receiving blockchain data from the blocksat network, and then relay it over the GoTenna mesh network.</description></item><item><title>Fungibility and Privacy</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/bitcoin-adam3us-fungibility-privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/bitcoin-adam3us-fungibility-privacy/</guid><description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3dAdI3Gzodo
First of all I was going to explain what we mean by fungibility before bitcoin and ecash. It&amp;rsquo;s an old legal concept in fact, about paper currency. It&amp;rsquo;s the idea that a one ten dollar note is the same as any other ten dollar note. If you receive a note that was involved in a theft, 10 transactions ago, and the police investigate the theft, they have no right to remove the ten dollar note from your pocket.</description></item><item><title>Fungibility And Scalability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/fungibility-and-scalability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/fungibility-and-scalability/</guid><description>slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY1/1_overviews_2_back.pdf
I think everyone knows what fungibility is, it&amp;rsquo;s when coins are equal and interchangeable. It&amp;rsquo;s an important property for an electronic cash system. All bitcoin users would have a problem if fungability goes away.
Bitcoin has fungibility without privacy. Previous electronic cash systems had fungibility and cryptographic blinding. In Bitcoin, there&amp;rsquo;s decentralized mining that somebody will process your transaction even if a given miner may not. But there is some privacy, because it&amp;rsquo;s based on pseudonyms.</description></item><item><title>Fungibility Overview</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/fungibility-overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/fungibility-overview/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784676022318952448
Introduction Alright. So let&amp;rsquo;s get started. Okay. Why fungibility? Let&amp;rsquo;s start. What does fungibility mean? Bitcoin is like cash. The hope is that it&amp;rsquo;s for immediate and final payments. To add some nuiance there, you might have to wait for some confirmations. Once you receive a bitcoin, you have a bitcoin and that&amp;rsquo;s final. So even with banks and PayPal, who sometimes shutdown accounts for trivial reasons or sometimes no reason at all, it&amp;rsquo;s typically not the case that it&amp;rsquo;s someone who sent you money&amp;hellip; if you were selling something on ebay, and someone bought an item from you, and that person had an account shutdown, the money you received will not be removed from your account.</description></item><item><title>Present And Future Tech Challenges In Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/present-and-future-tech-challenges-in-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/present-and-future-tech-challenges-in-bitcoin/</guid><description>1 on 1: Present and future tech challenges in bitcoin
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043484879210668032
PR: Hi everybody. I think I have the great fortune to moderate this panel in the sense that we have really great questions thought by the organizers. Essentially we want to ask Adam and Peter what are their thoughts on the current and the future tech challenges for bitcoin. I&amp;rsquo;m just going to start with that question, starting with Peter.</description></item></channel></rss>