<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Output script descriptors on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/descriptors/</link><description>Recent content in Output script descriptors on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/descriptors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Silent Payment Descriptors</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2024-04/silent-payment-descriptors/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2024-04/silent-payment-descriptors/</guid><description>Silent payments properties:
two ECDH with each scan key cost of scanning increases with number of scan keys multiple address = tweak spend key with label We wouldn’t wanna flip that because then the spend key would be common, reducing anonymity and adding extra scanning work
BIP352 recommends NOT using with xpubs, it’s really difficult to have same public key with different chain codes.
Use case question: with silent payments, let&amp;rsquo;s say I make a legacy wallet and want to use one of my existing pubkeys and just combine it with a scan key, is that something that someone could make up.</description></item><item><title>The Bitcoin Development Kit (BDK)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-podcast/the-bitcoin-development-kit-bdk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-podcast/the-bitcoin-development-kit-bdk/</guid><description>The podcast covers the evolution of the Bitcoin Development Kit (BDK), originally known as the Magical Bitcoin Library, from its inception at Blockstream to its current status as a fully-fledged open-source project. Key topics include the renaming of BDK, its foundational use of Rust and descriptors for wallet architecture, and the broad applicability for both individual and enterprise users. Early adopters and contributors to BDK&amp;rsquo;s development are highlighted, alongside discussions on the challenges and technical hurdles such as asynchronous operations and wallet management across multiple descriptors. The conversation also touches on the motivations behind developers preferring to build wallets from scratch and the potential advantages of adopting BDK for future-proofing wallet applications. Upcoming features in BDK 1.0 promise further enhancements, particularly in syncing mechanisms and transaction planning.</description></item><item><title>The Bitcoin Core Wallet</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-podcast/the-bitcoin-core-wallet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-podcast/the-bitcoin-core-wallet/</guid><description>The discussion with Andrew Chow explores the evolution of the Bitcoin Core wallet, emphasizing significant developments like descriptor wallets and PSBT for enhancing functionality and interoperability. The conversation highlights the continuous efforts to refactor and improve the wallet&amp;rsquo;s codebase, addressing challenges and introducing innovations in coin selection and transaction management. The importance of maintaining high security and review standards is underscored, reflecting the wallet&amp;rsquo;s role in supporting Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s core principles. Future directions include improving the wallet&amp;rsquo;s performance, user experience, and GUI.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Core 24.0</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/bitcoin-core-v24/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/bitcoin-core-v24/</guid><description>Intro Aaron van Wirdum: 00:00:20
Live from Utrecht, this is Bitcoin
Sjors Provoost: 00:00:23
Explained.
Aaron van Wirdum: 00:00:24
Hey Sjors.
Sjors Provoost: 00:00:25
What&amp;rsquo;s up?
Aaron van Wirdum: 00:00:26
I&amp;rsquo;m good.
Sjors Provoost: 00:00:27
How do you like the weather?
Aaron van Wirdum: 00:00:29
It was too hot all summer and then it was nice for about a week and now we&amp;rsquo;re back to too cold.
Sjors Provoost: 00:00:36</description></item><item><title>Miniscript</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-podcast/miniscript/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-podcast/miniscript/</guid><description>Sanket describes to Murch his work on Miniscript. We explore uses for Miniscript, learn about intersections with PSBTs, Output Descriptors, and Taproot, and suss out the difference between Miniscript and Miniscript Policy.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Core 0.21.0</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/bitcoin-core-v0-21/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/bitcoin-core-v0-21/</guid><description>Intro Aaron van Wirdum: 00:01:35
Live from Utrecht, this is The Van Wirdum Sjorsnado. Episode 24, we&amp;rsquo;re going to discuss Bitcoin Core 21.
Sjors Provost: 00:01:46
Hooray. Well, 0.21. We&amp;rsquo;re still in the age of the zero point releases.
Aaron van Wirdum: 00:01:51
Yes, which is ending now.
Sjors Provost: 00:01:53
Probably yes.
Aaron van Wirdum: 00:01:54
That&amp;rsquo;s what I understand. The next one, the 22 will actually be Bitcoin Core 22.</description></item><item><title>Wallet Architecture and Descriptors</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06/2019-06-05-wallet-architecture/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06/2019-06-05-wallet-architecture/</guid><description>Bitcoin Core wallet architecture + descriptors
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1136282460675878915
writeup: https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/issues/16165
Wallet architecture discussion There are three main areas here. One is IsMine: how do I determine a particular output is affecting my wallet? What about asking for a new address, where is it coming from? That&amp;rsquo;s not just get new address, it&amp;rsquo;s get raw change address, it&amp;rsquo;s also change being created in fundrawtransaction. The third issue is wallet signing. Storage is not an entrypoint, it&amp;rsquo;s just a way of implementing these things.</description></item><item><title>Script Descriptors</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-10/2018-10-08-script-descriptors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-10/2018-10-08-script-descriptors/</guid><description>https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/blob/master/doc/descriptors.md
I would like to talk about script descriptors. There&amp;rsquo;s a number of projects we&amp;rsquo;re working on and they are all kind of related. I&amp;rsquo;d like to clarify how things fit together.
Note: there is an earlier transcript that has not been published (needs review) about script descriptors.
Agenda History of script descriptors and how we came to this. What&amp;rsquo;s currently in Bitcoin Core v0.17 Wallet integration DESCRIPT About script descriptors The problem that I wanted to tackle was that currently in Bitcoin Core wallet we have a blob of public keys and private keys and HD chains and scripts and a bunch of other metadata and keypools.</description></item></channel></rss>