<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>smart contracts on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/smart-contracts/</link><description>Recent content in smart contracts on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/smart-contracts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bitcoin R&amp;D Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2022/bitcoin-randd-panel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2022/bitcoin-randd-panel/</guid><description>Ayush: 00:00:07
My name is Ayush Khandelwal. I am a software engineer at Google. I run a tech crypto-focused podcast on the side. And I have some amazing guests with me. So if you want to introduce yourself, what do you work on? And yeah, just get us started.
Jeremy: 00:00:31
I am Jeremy Rubin. I am a class of 2016 MIT alumni, so it&amp;rsquo;s good to be back on campus.</description></item><item><title>Socratic Seminar - Discreet Log Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2021-08-10-socratic-seminar-dlcs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2021-08-10-socratic-seminar-dlcs/</guid><description>Name: Socratic Seminar
Topic: Discreet Log Contracts
Location: London BitDevs (online)
Gist of resources discussed: https://gist.github.com/michaelfolkson/f5da6774c24f99dba5c6c16ec8d499e9
This event was livestreamed on YouTube and so comments are attributed to specific individuals by the name or pseudonym that was visible on the livestream. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be anonymized please get in touch.
Intro Michael Folkson (MF): Welcome to everyone on the call, welcome to people watching on YouTube.</description></item><item><title>Jeremy Rubin - Sapio 101</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/vr-bitcoin/2020-07-11-jeremy-rubin-sapio-101/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/vr-bitcoin/2020-07-11-jeremy-rubin-sapio-101/</guid><description>Topic: Sapio Programming 101: Stateful Smart Contracts for Bitcoin with OP_CTV
Location: Reckless VR
Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1X4AGNXJ5yCeHRrf5sa9DarWfDyEkm6fFUlrcIRQtUw4/
utxos.org website: https://utxos.org/
Intro (Udi Wertheimer) Today we are joined by Jeremy Rubin who is a Bitcoin Core contributor and the co-founder of the MIT Bitcoin Project. He is involved in a tonne of other cool stuff. He is also championing BIP 119 which is OP_CHECKTEMPLATEVERIFY. He is going to tell us about that and how it allows for new types of smart contracts.</description></item><item><title>Simplicity</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/2018-01-25-russell-oconnor-simplicity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/2018-01-25-russell-oconnor-simplicity/</guid><description>Simplicity: A New Language for Blockchains
Location: BPASE 2018, Stanford University
Slides: https://cyber.stanford.edu/sites/g/files/sbiybj9936/f/slides-bpase-2018.pdf
Simplicity white paper: https://blockstream.com/simplicity.pdf
Intro Good morning everyone. I have been working on a new language for the consensus layer of blockchains and I am here to present that to you today.
Blockchains and Smart Contracts I know everyone is familiar with this in the audience but I want to make sure that I’m on the same page with you guys.</description></item><item><title>Scalable Smart Contracts Via Proofs And Single Use Seals</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/scalable-smart-contracts-via-proofs-and-single-use-seals/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/scalable-smart-contracts-via-proofs-and-single-use-seals/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/957660108137418752
slides: https://cyber.stanford.edu/sites/default/files/petertodd.pdf
https://petertodd.org/2016/commitments-and-single-use-seals
https://petertodd.org/2016/closed-seal-sets-and-truth-lists-for-privacy
Introduction I am petertodd and I am here to break your blockchain. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of interesting following a talk like that, in some ways I&amp;rsquo;m going in a more extreme direcion for consensus. Do we actually need consensus at all? Can we make a more robust system by eliminating it to the maximum extent possible? I think for some use case at least I have some techniques that will let you go do this.</description></item><item><title>Ivy - A Declarative Predicate Language for Smart Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/2017-01-26-dan-robinson-ivy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/2017-01-26-dan-robinson-ivy/</guid><description>Ivy: A Declarative Predicate Language for Smart Contracts
Location: BPASE 2017, Stanford University
Intro Hi I’m Dan Robinson, I’m one of the Product Architects at Chain which is an enterprise blockchain infrastructure company for financial institutions. We have a full stack blockchain protocol and what I am going to talk about is part of that that also can be used for other applications including as I am going to demo here, make it easier to write scripts for Bitcoin Script.</description></item><item><title>Arbitrum V2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/arbitrum-v2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/arbitrum-v2/</guid><description>Arbitrum 2.0: Faster Off-Chain Contracts with On-Chain Security
Ed Felten, Off-chain Labs
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230191734375628802
Introduction Thank you, good morning everybody. I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about our latest version of our Abitrum system. The first version was discussed in a paper in 2018. Since then, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of advances in my technology and a real running system has been made. This is the first working roll-up system for general smart contracts.</description></item><item><title>Bitml</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/bitml/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/bitml/</guid><description>Developing secure bitcoin contracts using BitML
Stefano Lande
paper: https://arxiv.org/abs/1905.07639
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171695588116746240
This is shared work with my collaborators and coauthors.
Smart contracts I am sure everyone here knows what a smart contract is. It&amp;rsquo;s a program that can move cryptoassets. It&amp;rsquo;s executed in a decentralized environment. Generally speaking, we can say there&amp;rsquo;s two classes of smart contracts. A smart contract is a program. While in blockchain like bitcoin, smart contracts are cryptographic protocols.</description></item><item><title>Discreet Log Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/discreet-log-contracts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/discreet-log-contracts/</guid><description>http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/discreet-log-contracts/
paper: https://adiabat.github.io/dlc.pdf
Hello everyone. I am going to give a talk about discreet log contracts. I am from MIT DCI. I work on lightning network software and discreet log contracts. A quick intro: these are pretty new. I am not sure if they work. This presentation is part of the peer review process. Maybe the math doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. Please let me know. It might also work, though.
It&amp;rsquo;s a system of smart contracts using bitcoin which is similar to lightning network.</description></item><item><title>Formal Verification</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/formal-verification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/formal-verification/</guid><description>Formal verification: The road to complete security of smart contracts
slides: https://twitter.com/MartinLundfall/status/1091119463276064769
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1091103595016085504
Introduction Thank you everyone. It&amp;rsquo;s exciting to be here speaking about formal verification. The road to complete security of smart contracts is a sensationalist title. I&amp;rsquo;ll be spending a few moments making a huge disclaimer.
Disclaimer This can only be interpreted as a very long road or a very narrow sense in which complete security is actually cheap.</description></item><item><title>Improving Bitcoin Smart Contract Efficiency</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2018/improving-bitcoin-smart-contract-efficiency/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2018/improving-bitcoin-smart-contract-efficiency/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/980545280973201410
Introduction I will be talking about discreet log contracts, taproot, and graftroot. Not in that order, the order will actually be taproot, graftroot, and then discreet log contracts.
Quick intro: I&amp;rsquo;m Tadge Dryja. I work here at MIT down the street at Digital Currency Initiative. I was coauthor on the lightning network paper, and I worked on lightning. I also was the author of a paper introducing discreet log contracts.</description></item><item><title>Mixicles</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/mixicles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/mixicles/</guid><description>Mixicles: Simple Private Decentralized Finance
Ari Juels
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230666545803563008
https://chain.link/mixicles.pdf
Introduction This work was done in my capacity as technical advisor to Chainlink, and not my Cornell or IC3 affiliation. Mixicle is a combination of the words mixers and oracles. You will see why in a moment.
DeFi and privacy As of a couple of weeks ago, DeFi passed the $1 billion mark which is to say there&amp;rsquo;s over $1 billion of cryptocurrency in DeFi smart contracts today.</description></item><item><title>Present And Future Tech Challenges In Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/present-and-future-tech-challenges-in-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/present-and-future-tech-challenges-in-bitcoin/</guid><description>1 on 1: Present and future tech challenges in bitcoin
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043484879210668032
PR: Hi everybody. I think I have the great fortune to moderate this panel in the sense that we have really great questions thought by the organizers. Essentially we want to ask Adam and Peter what are their thoughts on the current and the future tech challenges for bitcoin. I&amp;rsquo;m just going to start with that question, starting with Peter.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Preserving Smart Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/privacy-preserving-smart-contracts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/privacy-preserving-smart-contracts/</guid><description>ranjit@csail.mit.edu
http://people.csail.mit.edu/ranjit/
We have been looking at how much we can support or what limitations we might encounter. There are also efficiency issues and privacy guarantees. And then there are some potential relaxations that will help with removing the fundamental limitations and express the power and make smart contracts more useful.
The point of this talk is off-chain transactions and secure computation. I will also highlight the relationship of secure computation and bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Quisquis - A new design for anonymous cryptocurrencies</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/quisquis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/quisquis/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1090677466216128512
https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/990
Introduction Good morning. I am here to talk to you about Quisquis which is a new design for an anonymous cryptocurrency. This talk is going to focus on the transaction layer. We don&amp;rsquo;t talk about consensus or smart contracts or higher applications.
Outline I am going to talk about bitcoin and anonymity. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about existing cryptocurrencies that claim to have anonymity and about their limitations. Then I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about our basic solution, where one public key is one coin, updateable public keys, and N-to-N transactions without interactions.</description></item><item><title>Rootstock</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/rootstock/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/rootstock/</guid><description>Rootstock
Sergio is co-founder and chief scientist at RSK Labs. The whitepaper was pretty good. I am happy that he is here. Thank you. Just give me a minute.
Alicia Bendhan Lous Parker BitDevsNYC
Yes, I use powerpoint. Please don&amp;rsquo;t read my emails.
Thanks everyone for staying here and not going to the next room. Thanks for the organizers for inviting me. Today I am going to talk about Rootstock. It&amp;rsquo;s a codename for a smart contracting platform that we are developing for SKY labs, which is a company we founded in 2015.</description></item><item><title>Self Reproducing Coins As Universal Turing Machine</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/self-reproducing-coins-as-universal-turing-machine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/self-reproducing-coins-as-universal-turing-machine/</guid><description>paper: https://arxiv.org/abs/1806.10116
Introduction This is joint work with my colleagues. I am Alexander Chepurnoy. We work for Ergo Platform. Vasily is an external member. This talk is about turing completeness in the blockchain. This talk will be pretty high-level. This talk is based on already-published paper, which was presented at the CBT conference. Because of copyright agreements with Springer, you will not find the latest version on arxiv.
The general question of scalability is how can we do more with less until we can do everything with nothing?</description></item><item><title>Step by Step Towards Writing a Safe Contract - Insights from an Undergraduate Ethereum Lab</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/andrew-miller/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/andrew-miller/</guid><description>Next up I want to introduce Elaine Shi and Andrew Miller from University of Maryland. Andrew is also on the zerocash team.
Okay. I am an assistant professor at the University of Maryland. We all believe that cryptocurrency is the way of the future and smart contracts. So students in the future have to program smart contracts.
So that&amp;rsquo;s what I did. I asked some students to program some smart contracts.</description></item><item><title>The Future Of Bitcoin Smart Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/the-future-of-bitcoin-smart-contracts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/the-future-of-bitcoin-smart-contracts/</guid><description>The future of bitcoin smart contracts
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043419056492228608
Hey guys, next talk in 5 minutes. In five minutes.
Introduction Hello everyone. If you&amp;rsquo;re walking, please do it in silence. I am a bit nervous. I was too busy organizing this conference and didn&amp;rsquo;t get time for this talk. If you had high expectatoins for this presentation, then please lower them for the next 20 minutes. I was going to talk about the traditional VC models and why it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work in the bitcoin industry.</description></item><item><title>Threshold Scriptless Scripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/threshold-scriptless-scripts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/threshold-scriptless-scripts/</guid><description>Omer Shlomovits (KZen Research) (omershlomovits, zengo)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171690582445580288
Scriptless scripts We can write smart contracts in bitcoin today, but there&amp;rsquo;s some limitations. We can do a lot of great things. We can do atomic swaps, multisig, payment channels, etc. There&amp;rsquo;s a cost, though. Transactions become bigger with bigger scripts. Also, it&amp;rsquo;s kind of heavy on the verifiers. The verifiers now need to verify more things. There&amp;rsquo;s also privacy issues because you put your contract publicly on chain.</description></item><item><title>Using The Chain For What Chains Are Good For</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/using-the-chain-for-what-chains-are-good-for/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/using-the-chain-for-what-chains-are-good-for/</guid><description>I am Andrew Poelstra, a cryptographer at Blockstream. I am going to talk about scriptless scripts. But this is a specific example of a more general theme, which is using the blockchain as a trust anchor or commitment layer for smart contracts whose real contents don&amp;rsquo;t really hit the blockchain. I&amp;rsquo;ll elaborate on what I mean by that, and I&amp;rsquo;ll show what the benefits are for that.
To give some context, in Bitcoin script, the scripting language which is used to encode smart contracts, which go on to the blockchain and everyone verifies the chain and downloads and executes all of this contract code.</description></item><item><title>Vulnerability Detection</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/vulnerability-detection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/vulnerability-detection/</guid><description>Automatic detection of vulnerabilities in smart contracts
Mooly Sagiv
Introduction If you find a bug in a smart contract, it&amp;rsquo;s really hard to mitigate that bug. In formal verification, we really look for bugs. We can identify subtle bugs, like reentrancy attacks, ownership violation, incorrect transactions, bugs due to updated code. We also want to assure the absence of bugs.
Device drivers I come from the domain of Windows device drivers.</description></item><item><title>Zkvm - zero-knowledge virtual machine for fast confidential smart contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/zkvm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/zkvm/</guid><description>Fats, private, flexible blockchain contracts
Oleg Andreev (Stellar) (oleganza)
https://medium.com/stellar-developers-blog/zkvm-a-new-design-for-fast-confidential-smart-contracts-d1122890d9ae and https://twitter.com/oleganza/status/1126612382728372224
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171711553512583169
Introduction Okay, welcome. What is zkvm? It&amp;rsquo;s a multi-asset blockchain architecture that combines smart contracts and confidentiality features. It&amp;rsquo;s written in pure rust from top to bottom.
https://github.com/stellar/slingshot
Agenda I&amp;rsquo;ll explain the good parts, and then I&amp;rsquo;ll explain away the bad parts. Sounds like a good time.
What does this have to do with bitcoin? zkvm is a unique combination of the best ideas in the blockchain space.</description></item></channel></rss>