<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Christopher Allen on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/christopher-allen/</link><description>Recent content in Christopher Allen on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/christopher-allen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Smart Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/2018-01-24-christopher-allen-smart-signatures/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/2018-01-24-christopher-allen-smart-signatures/</guid><description>Smart Signatures: Experiments in Authorization
Location: BPASE 2018, Stanford University
Slides: https://www.slideshare.net/ChristopherA/smart-signaturesexperiments-in-authentication-stanford-bpase-2018-final
Intro Good afternoon. My name is Christopher Allen, I am with Blockstream and today I wanted to give you an introduction to something that isn’t about consensus, isn’t about proof of stake and other things. I want to pop up a level. I want to talk about smart signatures. These are a number of experiments in authorization.
Digital Signatures First we need to recap, what is a digital signature?</description></item><item><title>Christopher Allen</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/christopher-allen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/christopher-allen/</guid><description>Whta makes for a great wonderful magical calliberation? Collaboration? Grab one card randomly. Keep it with you. What is this particular pattern of greatness? See if you can&amp;rsquo;t embody it or can&amp;rsquo;t recommend it ofr find it in the next two days. I would like each of you to tell a story about a collaboration that was really meaningful to you. It could be a business effort, it could be another team in your company, or it could be a personal collaboration that you found really powerful.</description></item><item><title>Self Sovereign Identity Ideology And Architecture</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/rebooting-web-of-trust/2019-prague/self-sovereign-identity-ideology-and-architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/rebooting-web-of-trust/2019-prague/self-sovereign-identity-ideology-and-architecture/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1168566218040762369
Paralelni Polis First I&amp;rsquo;d like to introduce the space we&amp;rsquo;re in right now. Welcome to Paralelni Polis. It is an education organization. It&amp;rsquo;s a first organization in the world that is running fully on crypto. It is running solely on cryptoeconomics and donations. I&amp;rsquo;d like to welcome you to the event called Rebooting the Web of Trust. This is the 9th event. This is its first time in Prague. We want to spread awareness and get communities around the world to focus on digital identity and to think differently about digital identity.</description></item><item><title>Smart Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/smart-signatures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/smart-signatures/</guid><description>Christopher Allen
Smart signatures and smarter signatures
Signatures are a 50+ year old technology. I am talking about the digital signature. It&amp;rsquo;s a hash of an object that has been encrypted by private key and verified by a public key against the hash of the object. All of our systems are using this in a varity of complex ways at high level to either do identity, sign a block, or do a variety of different things.</description></item></channel></rss>