<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>BLS signatures on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/bls-signatures/</link><description>Recent content in BLS signatures on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/bls-signatures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Anonymous Credentials</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/anonymous-credentials/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/anonymous-credentials/</guid><description>Jonas Nick discusses anonymous credentials and their applications in this section. Anonymous credentials involve getting a blinded token signed by a server, where the server does not see the message being signed. These tokens contain attributes that can be selectively revealed, and range proofs can be used to verify attributes without revealing additional information. The speaker highlights the flexibility and security of anonymous credentials and how they improve on traditional signatures. They also discuss advancements in these credentials, such as mercurial signatures and delegateable anonymous credentials. The speaker mentions the work of Del Tauri and their solution for creating a divisible e-cash system using homomorphic cryptographic commitments, range proofs, and blind signature schemes. They also discuss the merging and breaking of anonymous credentials, as well as reissuing tokens without exposing the individual values. The implementation and linkability of credentials are also explored in the conversation. Overall, the participants express the need for further study and propose focusing on the cryptography part of the scheme in the next session.</description></item><item><title>Handel: Practical Multi-Signature Aggregation for Large Byzantine Committees</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/handel-practical-multisig-aggregation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/handel-practical-multisig-aggregation/</guid><description>Introduction Handle is a aggregation protocol for large scale byzantine committees. This is work with my colleagues in addition to myself.
Why aggregate? Distributed systems often require gathering statements about large subsets of nodes. However, processing (filtering, aggregating&amp;hellip;) measurements can be a bottleneck. We want to apply some processing while collecting the measurements.
Why byzantine? A byzantine node is a node that can be arbitrary. It can be offline and it can be anything it wants and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to respect the protocol specification.</description></item><item><title>Compact Multi-Signatures For Smaller Blockchains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/compact-multi-signatures-for-smaller-blockchains/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/compact-multi-signatures-for-smaller-blockchains/</guid><description>Dan Boneh (Stanford University), Manu Drijvers and Gregory Neven (DFINITY)
paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/483.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048441176024469504
Introduction Hi. Thanks a lot for coming in after lunch. This slot is often known as &amp;ldquo;the slot of death&amp;rdquo;. Some of us are jetlagged, this is the perfect time to doze off and only wake up at the end of the talk. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to prevent that from happening. I think the best way to do that is to start about what this talk can do for you.</description></item></channel></rss>