<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Giacomo Zucco on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/giacomo-zucco/</link><description>Recent content in Giacomo Zucco on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/giacomo-zucco/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Assets on Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/bitcoin-assets/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/bitcoin-assets/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014483345026289664
Good morning everybody. In the mean time, while my presentation loads, I am Giacomo Zucco. I am the founder of BHB network and a consulting company. We do bitcoin consulting for institutional customers especially in Switzerland. We also like development on top of bitcoin and things like that.
My talk today is about assets on bitcoin. The subtitlte is &amp;ldquo;Yes, ok, financial sovereignity and cryptoanarchy are cool, but what about those cryptokitties?</description></item><item><title>Banks As Bitcoin Custodians</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/banks-as-bitcoin-custodians/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/banks-as-bitcoin-custodians/</guid><description>Traditional banks as bitcoin custodians: Security challenges and implications
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005545022559866880
Our next speaker is Giacomo Zucco. Yeah, have fun.
categories: [&amp;lsquo;conference&amp;rsquo;] tags: [&amp;lsquo;security&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;research&amp;rsquo;] As you can hear, there are a lot of italians here. Okay. So, good afternoon everyone. I am Giacomo Zucco.
I am a theoretical physicist. I worked at Accenture as a technology consultant and now I work at BHB Network which is a bridge between free open-source development and research on the bitcoin protocol, and the world of the incumbents.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Maximalism Dissected</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/bitcoin-maximalism-dissected/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/bitcoin-maximalism-dissected/</guid><description>Bitcoin maximalism dissected
Good morning everyone. I am very happy to be here at Baltic Honeybadger. Last year I gave a scaling presentation. I opened the conference with a scaling presentation. This year in order to compensate, I will be super serious. This will be the most boring presentation at the conference. I am going to try to dissect and formalize bitcoin maximalism.
This is the scarriest font I found on prezi.</description></item><item><title>The Future Of Bitcoin Wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/the-future-of-bitcoin-wallets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/the-future-of-bitcoin-wallets/</guid><description>1 on 1: The future of bitcoin wallets
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043445104827084800
GZ: Thank you very much. We&amp;rsquo;re going to talk about the future of bitcoin wallets. As you know, it&amp;rsquo;s a very central topic. We always compare bitcoin to the internet. Wallets are basically like browsers like back at the beginning of the web. They are the first gateway to a user experience for users on bitcoin. It&amp;rsquo;s important to see how they will evolve.</description></item></channel></rss>