<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ruben Somsen on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/ruben-somsen/</link><description>Recent content in Ruben Somsen on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/ruben-somsen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Silent Payments part 2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/silent-payments-part-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/silent-payments-part-2/</guid><description>In this episode of Bitcoin, Explained, Aaron and Sjors welcome Ruben Somsen and Josie to the show to discuss BIP 352, their now-finalized Bitcoin Improvement Proposal for Silent Payments.</description></item><item><title>Silent Payments</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2023-04/2023-04-26-silent-payments/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2023-04/2023-04-26-silent-payments/</guid><description>BIP Overview Scanning key and spending key are different: better security. Silent payment transactions are indistinguishable from transactions with taproot outputs on-chain.
Q: Address labeling, why not create two silent payment addresses?
A: It doubles scanning costs.
Limited to taproot UTXOs (currently about 3% of transactions) but when it increases we should find ways to optimize scanning, even though it currently does not seem to be an issue.
Q: Why no P2PK</description></item><item><title>Silent Payments and Alternatives</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-15-silent-payments/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-15-silent-payments/</guid><description>Introduction I will talk about silent payments but also in general the design space around what kind of constructs you can have to pay people in a non-interactive way. In the bitcoin world, there are a couple common ways of paying someone. Making a payment is such a basic thing. &amp;hellip; The alternative we have is that you can generate a single address and put it in your twitter profile and everyone can pay you, but that&amp;rsquo;s not private.</description></item><item><title>Silent Payments</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/silent-payments/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/silent-payments/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this episode of Bitcoin, Explained, hosts Aaron van Wirdum and Sjors Provoost welcome Ruben Somsen back on the show to talk about a recent proposal of his called “Silent Payments”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Silent Payments resemble earlier ideas like Stealth Addresses and Reusable Payment Codes, in that they allow users to publish a static “address”, while this is not the actual Bitcoin address they will be paid on. Instead, senders of a transaction can use this static address to generate new Bitcoin addresses for the recipient, for which the recipient — and only the recipient — can in turn generate the corresponding private keys.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like Stealth Addresses and Reusable Payment Codes, the benefit of Silent Payments is that addresses can be posted publicly without harming users’ privacy; snoops cannot link the publicly posted address to the actual Bitcoin addresses that the recipient is paid on. Meanwhile, unlike Stealth Addresses and Reusable Payment Codes, Silent Payments do not require any additional blockchain data— though this does come at a computational cost for the recipient.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The podcast episode details all this in roughly two parts. In the first half of the episode, Ruben, Aaron and Sjors break down how Silent Payments work, and in the second half of the episode they discuss how Silent Payments compare to Stealth Addresses and Reusable Payment Codes, as well as some potential implementation issues.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Explaining RGB Tokens</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/explaining-rgb-tokens/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/explaining-rgb-tokens/</guid><description>Intro Aaron van Wirdum: 00:01:45
Live, from Utrecht, this is The Van Wirdum Sjorsnado. Hello.
Ruben Somsen: 00:01:48
Hello.
Sjors Provoost: 00:01:49
Hey, who&amp;rsquo;s there?
Ruben Somsen: 00:01:51
It&amp;rsquo;s another Dutch guy.
Sjors Provoost: 00:01:53
Welcome to the show, Ruben.
Ruben Somsen: 00:01:54
Thank you.
Aaron van Wirdum: 00:01:56
Welcome back Ruben. Ruben, did you start selling your tweets yet?
Ruben Somsen: 00:01:59
I tried to sell one of my tweets to my sister but she said, &amp;ldquo;What the hell are you doing?</description></item><item><title>What Is Utreexo?</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/what-is-utreexo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/what-is-utreexo/</guid><description>The discussion revolves around Utreexo, a novel proposal aimed at enhancing Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s scalability by optimizing the UTXO set storage through a compact, Merkle tree-based structure. Utreexo seeks to address the challenges of node synchronization speeds and RAM usage by allowing nodes to store a much smaller representation of the UTXO set, thus potentially accelerating the syncing process and making the network more efficient. The conversation delves into the technical mechanisms of Utreexo, its implementation challenges, and the practical benefits it offers, including reduced memory requirements and the facilitation of faster node operations. While acknowledging Utreexo&amp;rsquo;s promising advantages for Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s scalability, the participants also weigh its potential downsides, such as increased bandwidth for block transmission and the necessity for significant network adoption to realize its full benefits.</description></item><item><title>Socratic Seminar - Coinswap</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-23-socratic-seminar-coinswap/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-06-23-socratic-seminar-coinswap/</guid><description>Pastebin of the resources discussed: https://pastebin.com/zbegGmb8
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have given permission for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Introductions Michael Folkson (MF): This is London BitDevs, this is a Socratic Seminar. We had two events last week so it is great to see so many people on the call.</description></item><item><title>Succinct Atomic Swap</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/ruben-somsen/2020-05-11-ruben-somsen-succinct-atomic-swap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/ruben-somsen/2020-05-11-ruben-somsen-succinct-atomic-swap/</guid><description>Topic: Succinct Atomic Swap (SAS)
Location: Ruben Somsen YouTube channel
SAS resources: https://gist.github.com/RubenSomsen/8853a66a64825716f51b409be528355f
Intro Happy halvening. Today I have a special technical presentation for you. Basically what we are going to do is cut atomic swaps in half. I call this succinct atomic swaps.
Motivation First let me tell you my motivation. I think Bitcoin is a very important technology. We need to find ways to utilize it at its maximum potential without sacrificing decentralization.</description></item><item><title>Statechains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/statechains/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/statechains/</guid><description>Schnorr signatures, adaptor signatures and statechains
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171345418237685760
Introduction If you want to know the details of statechains, I recommend checking out my talk from Breaking Bitcoin 2019 Amsterdam. I&amp;rsquo;ll give a quick recap of Schnorr signatures and adaptor signatures and then statechains. I think it&amp;rsquo;s important to understand Schnorr signatures to the point where you&amp;rsquo;re really comfortable with it. A lot of the cool stuff in bitcoin right now is related to or using Schnorr signatures.</description></item><item><title>Blind statechains: UTXO transfer with a blind signing server</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06/2019-06-07-statechains/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06/2019-06-07-statechains/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1136992734953299970
&amp;ldquo;Formalizing Blind Statechains as a minimalistic blind signing server&amp;rdquo; https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2019-June/017005.html
overview: https://medium.com/@RubenSomsen/statechains-non-custodial-off-chain-bitcoin-transfer-1ae4845a4a39
statechains paper: https://github.com/RubenSomsen/rubensomsen.github.io/blob/master/img/statechains.pdf
previous transcript: http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/statechains/
Introduction I am going to talk casually through the whole statechains thing. If you want to interject, please do. I&amp;rsquo;ll get started. The current idea is to make it completely blind. It&amp;rsquo;s blinded statechains. The goal is to allow people to transfer a UTXO without changing anything on-chain. The concept I use to describe it is a blind signing server.</description></item><item><title>Statechains: Off-chain transfer of UTXOs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/statechains/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/statechains/</guid><description>I am the education director of readingbitcoin.org, and I am going to be talking about statechains for off-chain transfer of UTXOs.
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048799338703376385
Statechains This is another layer 2 scaling solution, by avoiding on-chain transactions. It&amp;rsquo;s similar to lightning network. The difference is that coin movement is not restricted. You deon&amp;rsquo;t have these channels where you have to have a path and send an exact amount. There&amp;rsquo;s some synergy with lightning; it&amp;rsquo;s not a replacement for lightning.</description></item></channel></rss>