<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Anton Yemelyanov on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/anton-yemelyanov/</link><description>Recent content in Anton Yemelyanov on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/anton-yemelyanov/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Intro</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/intro/</guid><description>Introduction
Good morning. Glad to see many of you again. My name is Anton Yemelyanov. I am one of the organizers of this event. On behalf of Scaling Bitcoin planning committee, I would like to welcome everybody here to the third scaling event. We&amp;rsquo;re holding this event here in Milan. Milan has a really vibrant community. It has been a real pleasure working with everyone here to create this event. The goal of Scaling as everybody knows is to get everyone together in a single place, all engineers and academic community so that we can discuss different scaling approaches and see how they can be applied to bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Intro</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/intro/</guid><description>Introduction Stanford 2017
https://scalingbitcoin.org/
https://scalingbitcoin.org/event/stanford2017
Sorry that we&amp;rsquo;re running a little bit late. My name is Anton Yemelyanov. I am one of the organizers running this event. Welcome everybody. It&amp;rsquo;s great to have a lot of familiar faces here. First of all, as you may know, we have ran over the last 2 days, Bitcoin Edge Dev++ where we have trained over 80 new developers that have joined our ecosystem. They have covered a number of topics including ECDSA and discreet log contracts.</description></item><item><title>Intro</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/intro/</guid><description>Introduction to Scaling Bitcoin Tel Aviv 2019
https://telaviv2019.scalingbitcoin.org/
https://telaviv2019.scalingbitcoin.org/#schedule
Freenode IRC: #bitcoin-workshops
https://telaviv2019.scalingbitcoin.org/live/
Everybody please take your seats. Just to let you know, there&amp;rsquo;s electrical plugs in the center of row 1 and row 6. Otherwise, there are extension cords connected on the sides.
Good morning. Welcome to Israel. My name is Anton Yemelyanov. I am the chair of the Scaling Bitcoin program committee and one of the organizers of these events.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/introduction/</guid><description>Anton Yemelyanov
Introduction
slides: https://tokyo2018.scalingbitcoin.org/presentations
Welcome to scaling bitcoin. This is an international conference. We run the event every year in a different geographical location. We run this event as a strictly academic and engineering conference. The mentality that we take behind the event is think global, act local. It&amp;rsquo;s a well known bitcoin additive. Our goal is to stimulate the bitcoin ecosystem. The best way to do this is to stimulate the engineering community, because that&amp;rsquo;s what drives this magnificent technology for the last almost 10 years now.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Bitcoin Edge Dev++ and Bc2</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/edgedevplusplus/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/edgedevplusplus/introduction/</guid><description>We will be using two screens. The english will be on the front screen and the japanese will be on the other screen to the side here. We will also be sharing a google docs file for each one in slack. We should help each other and teach better and learn these things. Without further adue, here&amp;rsquo;s Anton from Bitcoin Edge.
Hi everybody. Welcome to Dev++. It started last year at Stanford 2017 where we trained 100 people.</description></item></channel></rss>