<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>W3 Blockchain Workshop 2016 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/</link><description>Recent content in W3 Blockchain Workshop 2016 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Archival Science</title><link>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/archival-science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/archival-science/</guid><description>{% if page.transcript_by %} Transcript by: {{ page.transcript_by }}{% endif %} Blockchain is a memory transfer sytsem. These memories are moving through space and time. This is something that I recognized. As a type of record, a ledger is a type of record traditionally. There are a number of international standards. One of them is ISO 15489, international records amangemetn. You will see this idea of memory of transactions as evidence.</description></item><item><title>Arvind Narayanan</title><link>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/arvind-narayanan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/arvind-narayanan/</guid><description>{% if page.transcript_by %} Transcript by: {{ page.transcript_by }}{% endif %} I would like to introduce Arvind. He is a professor at Princeton. He has talked about this in a number of different forums.
Hi everyone. My name is Arvind. This is turning out to be one of the more unusual and interesting events that I have been to. Someone at my table called the first session a quasi-religious experience. Not sure whether that was a good thing or not.</description></item><item><title>Blockchain Hub</title><link>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/blockchain-hub/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/blockchain-hub/</guid><description>{% if page.transcript_by %} Transcript by: {{ page.transcript_by }}{% endif %} Kenji Saito
BlockchainHub
My understanding is that there is application logic, consensus mechanism, distributed timestamp and ledger structure. With these layers, the blockchain can give total control of assets to the end. This materializes the attitude and philosophy of the internet. The intention is I think great. There is a missing link, though. It would be nice if these blockchain could manage the digital representational of physical assets.</description></item><item><title>Christopher Allen</title><link>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/christopher-allen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/christopher-allen/</guid><description>{% if page.transcript_by %} Transcript by: {{ page.transcript_by }}{% endif %} Christopher Allen
Whta makes for a great wonderful magical calliberation? Collaboration? Grab one card randomly. Keep it with you. What is this particular pattern of greatness? See if you can&amp;rsquo;t embody it or can&amp;rsquo;t recommend it ofr find it in the next two days. I would like each of you to tell a story about a collaboration that was really meaningful to you.</description></item><item><title>Day 2 Groups</title><link>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/day-2-groups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/day-2-groups/</guid><description>{% if page.transcript_by %} Transcript by: {{ page.transcript_by }}{% endif %}
Browsers One was creating a new API or updating an existing API for Web Auth or an expansion to the web auth spec, where the browser would understand blockchain-based identity. We want to resolve and display blockchain identity in the browser, anything identified as an identity in a blockchain in a browser. Request payload signature. Apps receiving payloads could check from the user.</description></item><item><title>Deterministic Signatures Group</title><link>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/deterministic-signatures-group/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/deterministic-signatures-group/</guid><description>{% if page.transcript_by %} Transcript by: {{ page.transcript_by }}{% endif %} Deterministic expressions (group)
So please give your name and organization and what would you like to hear in the next twenty or thirty minutes.
ECDSA threshold signatures. Signature systems. Multisig predicate expressions.
new crypto systems build pipeline things, gitian things git signatures interop smart signatures &amp;ldquo;crypto conditions&amp;rdquo; ECDSA threshold signatures https://github.com/WebOfTrustInfo/ID2020DesignWorkshop/blob/master/topics-and-advance-readings/DexPredicatesForSmarterSigs.md
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/christopher-allen/
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/petertodd-dex/
https://petertodd.org/2016/talks-dex-arnhem-dev-workshop
http://www.weboftrust.info/downloads/smart-signatures.pdf
Probably what people are least familiar with is crypto conditions.</description></item><item><title>Ethcore</title><link>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/ethcore/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/ethcore/</guid><description>{% if page.transcript_by %} Transcript by: {{ page.transcript_by }}{% endif %} ethcore
At ethcore, we are building the infrastructure for the future of the decentralized web. Unless we get distracted by TheDAO and soft-forks and hard-forks. Maybe decentralization is not the most important thing. We want to build a p2p secure serverless web. Why is decentralization such an important notion? There&amp;rsquo;s no intrinsic value in being decentralized. There&amp;rsquo;s intrinsic value in being utilized and secure by people.</description></item><item><title>Groups Identity</title><link>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/groups-identity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/groups-identity/</guid><description>{% if page.transcript_by %} Transcript by: {{ page.transcript_by }}{% endif %}
The topic that we have been working on is identity for everyone. In terms of trusted set of parties if you will, that can potentially provide some level of attestation to the identity and that can be provided in a digitized manner as to what levels of service an be provided to that level of identity as well.
What belongs in a blockchain?</description></item><item><title>Intro</title><link>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/intro/</guid><description>{% if page.transcript_by %} Transcript by: {{ page.transcript_by }}{% endif %} Blockhains and standards
W3C Workshop
29-30 June 2016
Cambridge, Massachusetts
Doug Schepers schepers@w3.org
@shepazu
https://www.w3.org/2016/04/blockchain-workshop/
irc.w3.org #blockchain
https://etherpad.w3ctag.org/p/blockchain
My name is Doug. I am ostensibly the organizer. Along with my chairs, Neha, where are you? Please stand up so that everyone can embarras you. She is with DCI here at MIT, the Digital Currency Initiative. Daza, also with MIT, he is the guy who grbabed the space for us, and he is going to do video stuff later.</description></item><item><title>Ipfs</title><link>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/ipfs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/ipfs/</guid><description>{% if page.transcript_by %} Transcript by: {{ page.transcript_by }}{% endif %} I will not have time to describe IPFS. We have multiformats that allow protocol agility, interop and avoid lock-in. Multihash, multiaddr, multibase, multicodec, multistream, multikey. What do you do with cryptographic hashes? When you have four different hashes all the same length that happen to be coming from different functions, what are those functions? sha256? sha512? sha3? blake2b? How do you know which hash type it is?</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network</title><link>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/lightning-network/</guid><description>{% if page.transcript_by %} Transcript by: {{ page.transcript_by }}{% endif %} Lightning network
Tadge Dryja
I am going to talk about blockchain scalability using payment channel networks. I am working on Lightning Network. It&amp;rsquo;s currently being built in bitcoin but it can support other things. One of the fundamental problems with blockchain is scalability. How can you have millions of users and rapid transactions?
Fundamentally, the blockchain is shared. You can call it a DLT but it&amp;rsquo;s really a copied ledger.</description></item><item><title>Matsuo</title><link>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/matsuo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/matsuo/</guid><description>{% if page.transcript_by %} Transcript by: {{ page.transcript_by }}{% endif %} Shinichiro Matsuo
bsafe.network
Giving trust by security evaluation and bsafe.network
This is a severe problem. How can we trust the output of blockchain technology? We have several security issues. There was the huge DAO attack from two weeks ago. We also have other problems, such as protocol specification, key management, implementation, operation, and vulnerability handling. Also key renewal and key revocation issues.</description></item><item><title>Petertodd Dex</title><link>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/petertodd-dex/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/petertodd-dex/</guid><description>{% if page.transcript_by %} Transcript by: {{ page.transcript_by }}{% endif %} petertodd
I have been working on deterministic expressions language called DEX. It looks like lambda calculus. But really we&amp;rsquo;re trying to create a way to specify expressions that would return true if a signature is valid. Something like this, which is really just check a signature against a pubkey for a message, is essentially something that would be baked into your software anyway.</description></item><item><title>Physical Assets</title><link>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/physical-assets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/physical-assets/</guid><description>{% if page.transcript_by %} Transcript by: {{ page.transcript_by }}{% endif %} Physical assets, archival science
We are going to spend 20 minutes talkign about the topics. Then we will spend 10 minutes getting summaries. Then we will spend 20 minutes summarizing everything.
Why is archival science important? I have a background in finance too. Blockchain securitizes things as well. It combines value and memory in one. Also, people have studied archives and how to get records and how to store records.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Anonymity And Identity Group</title><link>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/privacy-anonymity-and-identity-group/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/privacy-anonymity-and-identity-group/</guid><description>{% if page.transcript_by %} Transcript by: {{ page.transcript_by }}{% endif %} Anonymous identity
Another part of it is that all of those IoT things have firmware that can update. The moment that someone gets a key to update this, you can hack the grid by making rapid changes on power usage which actually destroys the &amp;hellip;. do the standards make things less secure? It should be illegal to design broken cryptosystems.</description></item><item><title>Provenance Groups</title><link>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/provenance-groups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/provenance-groups/</guid><description>{% if page.transcript_by %} Transcript by: {{ page.transcript_by }}{% endif %} Give the name of your tech topic table. You have three minutes to summarize. When you have one minute to summarize, I will give you the one minute warning. When you have zero minutes left, you will be thrown out the window.
Media rights We talked about media rights and payments. The ability to figure out the incentive structure for whether we can compensate people who create page views with people who have view rights and how that all works.</description></item><item><title>Royalties</title><link>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/royalties/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/royalties/</guid><description>{% if page.transcript_by %} Transcript by: {{ page.transcript_by }}{% endif %} Chris Tse
Monegraph person
I am going to talk about rights systems. A system that lets us trade rights, like to make movie off of a character, off of the things that Disney makes whenever I buy toys for my two year-old son. This is used in intellectual property. Monegraph is known as the media rights blockchain-ish company. What we discovered about how to model rights, but why is it important, kind of extending and maybe contradicting the point further that the rights are not just the identity mapped to it in the blockchain, it&amp;rsquo;s just, in a lot of cases you are trading, selling or lending rights.</description></item><item><title>Smart Signatures</title><link>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/smart-signatures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/smart-signatures/</guid><description>{% if page.transcript_by %} Transcript by: {{ page.transcript_by }}{% endif %} Christopher Allen
Smart signatures and smarter signatures
Signatures are a 50+ year old technology. I am talking about the digital signature. It&amp;rsquo;s a hash of an object that has been encrypted by private key and verified by a public key against the hash of the object. All of our systems are using this in a varity of complex ways at high level to either do identity, sign a block, or do a variety of different things.</description></item><item><title>Wendy</title><link>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/wendy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>//bitcointranscripts.github.io/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/wendy/</guid><description>{% if page.transcript_by %} Transcript by: {{ page.transcript_by }}{% endif %} 08:45–09:00 - Keynote: “Intro to W3C standards” Wendy Seltzer, W3C.
https://goo.gl/3ZqAuo
We are working to make a web that is global and nteroperable and usable by everyone. If you have tech that you want to work on a global working basis, and distributed manner, then the web is the platform on which to do that. W3C is the consortium and standards body that works to help keep the web open and available.</description></item></channel></rss>