<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fee Management on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/fee-management/</link><description>Recent content in Fee Management on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/fee-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>OP_VAULT for Bitcoin Covenants Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/op_vault-for-bitcoin-covenants-panel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/op_vault-for-bitcoin-covenants-panel/</guid><description>Speaker 0: 00:00:45
Today we have an absolute all-star panel here. We&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking about the Bitcoin Op Vault. It&amp;rsquo;s a new proposal by James. And you know, like any new proposals to Bitcoin, there is a lot to go over. And It&amp;rsquo;s a very big, interesting topic. So today we have Rindell.
Speaker 2: 00:01:05
Hey, good morning. Yeah, I&amp;rsquo;m here talking about vaults, Bitcoin developer, and I work a lot on multi-sig and vaults that don&amp;rsquo;t use covenants.</description></item><item><title>Weighing transactions: The witness discount</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-15-segwit-vbytes-misconceptions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-15-segwit-vbytes-misconceptions/</guid><description>You&amp;rsquo;ve already heard from someone that this presentation will be more interactive. I probably won&amp;rsquo;t get through all of my material. If you have questions during the talk, please feel free to raise your hand and we can cover it right away. I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to walk you through a transaction serialization for both a non-segwit transaction and a segwit transaction. By the end of the talk, I hope you understand how the transaction weight is calculated and how the witness discount works.</description></item><item><title>Fee Market</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2022-10/2022-10-11-fee-market/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2022-10/2022-10-11-fee-market/</guid><description>There are two times we have had sustained fees: late 2017 and early 2021. In late 2017 we saw lots of things break because people hadn&amp;rsquo;t written software to deal with variable fees or anything. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if that was as big of a problem in 2021. I do worry that this will start to become a thing. If you have no variable fee market, and you can just throw in 1 sat/vbyte for several years then it will just work until it doesn&amp;rsquo;t.</description></item><item><title>Socratic Seminar</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2020-05-19-socratic-seminar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2020-05-19-socratic-seminar/</guid><description>Google Doc of the resources discussed: https://docs.google.com/document/d/1hCTlQdt_dK6HerKNt0kl6X8HAeRh16VSAaEtrqcBvlw/
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
0xB10C blog post on mempool observations https://b10c.me/mempool-observations/2-bitmex-broadcast-13-utc/
These 3-of-4 multisig inputs don’t have compressed public keys so they are pretty large in current transaction sizes.</description></item><item><title>Rebalancing in the Lightning Network: Analysis and Implications</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/rebalancing-lightning/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/rebalancing-lightning/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048753406628655105
Introduction This talk is going to be about rebalancing in the lightning network. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the implications and about running a lightning node.
Financial costs In the lightning network, routing nodes will incur in financial costs by having their money locked inside channels. They can&amp;rsquo;t use that money elsewhere. They incur a financial cost to doing this activity, at least an opportunity cost. To recover this, they can charge a fee every time they route a payment.</description></item><item><title>How Wallets Can Handle Real Transaction Fees</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/transaction-fee-estimation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/transaction-fee-estimation/</guid><description>You should have a market at this point, where some number of transactions never happen because they aren&amp;rsquo;t willing to pay a fee. So you get some equilibrium of price going on. I proactively want to see this happen because we don&amp;rsquo;t know what fees should be until we run the experiment and see what prices end up being. For this to happen, wallets have to do price setting in some way.</description></item><item><title>Competitive Fee Market Urgency</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/competitive-fee-market-urgency/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/competitive-fee-market-urgency/</guid><description>The urgency of a competitive fee market to ensure a scalable future
I am Marshall. I run Firehash. CTO Cryptsy also. Some people have higher cost, some people have lower cost. I think those were some good estimates for true costs. I am going to be talking about why fees are going to be very important very soon. We&amp;rsquo;ll talk about what happens without fees, talk about why bitcoin really isn&amp;rsquo;t free but how we can do things like microtransactions, real microtransactions, talk about the cost and talk about solutions.</description></item><item><title>Elastic Block Caps</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/elastic-block-caps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/elastic-block-caps/</guid><description>Introduction Thank you everyone. I am from the Israeli Bitcoin Association. I will start by describing the problem.
The problem The problem is variable transaction fees. The transaction fees shot up. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of fluctuation. To understand why this is a problem, let&amp;rsquo;s go back to the basics.
Block size limit We can have big blocks or small blocks. Each one has advantages and disadvantages. One of the benefits of small blocks is that it&amp;rsquo;s easier to run a node.</description></item><item><title>Fee Management (Lightning Network)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-fabrice-drouin-fee-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-fabrice-drouin-fee-management/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs Lightning Residency 2019
Fabrice: So I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about fee management in Lightning which has been surprisingly one of the biggest operational issues we had when we launched the Lightning Network. So again the idea of Lightning is you have transactions that are not published but publishable, and in our case the problem is what does exactly publishable mean. So it means the UTXO that you’re spending is still spendable.</description></item><item><title>Fee markets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/peter-r/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/peter-r/</guid><description>((Note that there is a more accurate transcript from Peter-R himself below.))
Miners have another job as well. Miners are commodity producers, they produce something that the world has never seen. They produce block space, which is room for transactional debt. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore what the field of economics tells us. We&amp;rsquo;ll plot the total number of bytes per block. On the vertical we will plot the unit cost of the commodity, or the price of 1 transaction worth of blockspace.</description></item><item><title>Optimizing Fee Estimation Via Mempool State</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/optimizing-fee-estimation-via-mempool-state/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/optimizing-fee-estimation-via-mempool-state/</guid><description>I am a Bitcoin Core developer and I work at DG Lab. Today I would like to talk about fees. There&amp;rsquo;s this weird gap between&amp;ndash; there are two things going on. People complain about high fees. But people are confused about why Bitcoin Core is giving high fees but if you set fees manually you can get a much lower fee and get a transaction mined pretty fast. I started to look into this in detail and did simulations and a bunch of stuff.</description></item><item><title>Redesigning Bitcoin Fee Market</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/redesigning-bitcoin-fee-market/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/redesigning-bitcoin-fee-market/</guid><description>https://gnusha.org/url/https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2017-September/015093.html
https://www.reddit.com/r/Bitcoin/comments/72qi2r/redesigning_bitcoins_fee_market_a_new_paper_by/
paper: https://arxiv.org/abs/1709.08881
He will be exploring alternative auction markets.
Hello. This is joint work with Aviv Zohar and I have just moved. And Ron Lavi. And I am going to be talking about tehcniques from&amp;hellip; auction theory.. to rethink how fees in bitcoin are done.
Just a fast recap of how the current mechanism works. Each block has a size. Users are asked to specify the fee they will even pay.</description></item></channel></rss>