<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>halving on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/halving/</link><description>Recent content in halving on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/halving/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Accumulating Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/accumulating-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/accumulating-bitcoin/</guid><description>Accumulating bitcoin
Introduction Today I am going to be preaching to the choir I think. Hopefully I will be reiterating and reinforcing some points that you already know but maybe forgot to bring up with your nocoiner friends, or learning something new. I hope there&amp;rsquo;s something for everyone in here.
Q: Should I buy bitcoin?
A: Yes.
Q: Are you going to troll a journalist?
A: Today? Already done.
Misconceptions One of the biggest misconceptions I heard when I first learned about bitcoin was that bitcoin was just a payments system.</description></item><item><title>Competitive Fee Market Urgency</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/competitive-fee-market-urgency/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/competitive-fee-market-urgency/</guid><description>The urgency of a competitive fee market to ensure a scalable future
I am Marshall. I run Firehash. CTO Cryptsy also. Some people have higher cost, some people have lower cost. I think those were some good estimates for true costs. I am going to be talking about why fees are going to be very important very soon. We&amp;rsquo;ll talk about what happens without fees, talk about why bitcoin really isn&amp;rsquo;t free but how we can do things like microtransactions, real microtransactions, talk about the cost and talk about solutions.</description></item><item><title>How To Meme Bitcoin To The Moon</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/how-to-meme-bitcoin-to-the-moon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/how-to-meme-bitcoin-to-the-moon/</guid><description>How to meme bitcoin to the moon
Introduction How many of y&amp;rsquo;all were at the dinner last night? Okay, great. I had a lot of fun. It was fantastic. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how we will beat it next year, but we will figure something out. I am Michael Goldstein, and welcome to my ridiculous tedtalk. A lot of people talk about price fundamentals, but I am going to talk about how to troll and take the curves hard.</description></item></channel></rss>