<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Eclipse attacks on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/eclipse-attacks/</link><description>Recent content in Eclipse attacks on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/eclipse-attacks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The P2P network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/the-p2p-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/the-p2p-network/</guid><description>Amiti returns to the Chaincode office to discuss all things p2p.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Core 0.21.0</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/bitcoin-core-v0-21/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/bitcoin-core-v0-21/</guid><description>Intro Aaron van Wirdum: 00:01:35
Live from Utrecht, this is The Van Wirdum Sjorsnado. Episode 24, we&amp;rsquo;re going to discuss Bitcoin Core 21.
Sjors Provost: 00:01:46
Hooray. Well, 0.21. We&amp;rsquo;re still in the age of the zero point releases.
Aaron van Wirdum: 00:01:51
Yes, which is ending now.
Sjors Provost: 00:01:53
Probably yes.
Aaron van Wirdum: 00:01:54
That&amp;rsquo;s what I understand. The next one, the 22 will actually be Bitcoin Core 22.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Eclipse Attacks And How To Stop Them</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/bitcoin-eclipse-attacks-and-how-to-stop-them/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/bitcoin-eclipse-attacks-and-how-to-stop-them/</guid><description>The discussion revolves around eclipse attacks against Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s peer-to-peer network, as described in a 2015 paper. Eclipse attacks isolate a node, controlling its network connections to manipulate transaction visibility and block information. The transcript outlines the mechanism of these attacks, including the strategic overflow of a node&amp;rsquo;s address list and inducing node restarts. It also covers the potential for facilitating double-spend attacks and splitting the miner network. Mitigation strategies implemented in Bitcoin Core are discussed, including improvements in peer selection and connection management. These measures increase the resilience of the network against eclipse attacks by reducing attackers&amp;rsquo; ability to monopolize a node&amp;rsquo;s view of the blockchain, showcasing the ongoing efforts to secure Bitcoin against such vulnerabilities.</description></item><item><title>Attacking Bitcoin Core</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/la-bitdevs/2020-04-16-amiti-uttarwar-attacking-bitcoin-core/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/la-bitdevs/2020-04-16-amiti-uttarwar-attacking-bitcoin-core/</guid><description>Intro I’m going to talk to you today about attacking Bitcoin Core.
Bitcoin To start with the fundamentals. As we all know Bitcoin is a money and it is different to our existing centralized solution of money because instead we have nodes that are running all around the world.
Consensus Fundamentally what is required for this to work is the idea of consensus where all the nodes must agree on the same fundamental values.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin network partitioning &amp; network-level privacy attacks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-12-ethan-heilman-network-partitioning-attacks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-residency/2019-06-12-ethan-heilman-network-partitioning-attacks/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Labs 2019 Residency
Slides: https://residency.chaincode.com/presentations/bitcoin/ethan_heilman_p2p.pdf
Eclipse attack paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2015/263.pdf
Bitcoin’s P2P Network Please interrupt me. I&amp;rsquo;m going to go through this stuff a little bit quickly because I hear that you&amp;rsquo;ve already read Eclipse attack paper and you&amp;rsquo;ve already looked at some of the peer to peer stuff.
Bitcoin uses a peer-to-peer network to announce transactions and blocks. It makes 8 outgoing connections. These are TCP connections initiated by the node.</description></item></channel></rss>