<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hong Kong (2015) on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/</link><description>Recent content in Hong Kong (2015) on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Bevy Of Block Size Proposals Bip100 Bip102 And More</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/a-bevy-of-block-size-proposals-bip100-bip102-and-more/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/a-bevy-of-block-size-proposals-bip100-bip102-and-more/</guid><description>slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY2/3_tweaking_the_chain_1_garzik.pdf
slides: http://www.slideshare.net/jgarzik/a-bevy-of-block-size-proposals-scaling-bitcoin-hk-2015
Alternative video: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=37LiYOOevqs&amp;amp;t=1h16m6s
We&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking about every single block size proposal. This is going to be the least technical presentation at the conference. I am not going to go into the proposals htemselves. Changing the block size itself is pretty simple. You change a constant. It&amp;rsquo;s more a discussion of algorithms, roll-out, etc.
What are some of the high level concerns with block size?</description></item><item><title>A Flexible Limit Trading Subsidy For Larger Blocks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/a-flexible-limit-trading-subsidy-for-larger-blocks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/a-flexible-limit-trading-subsidy-for-larger-blocks/</guid><description>slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY2/3_tweaking_the_chain_2_friedenbach.pdf
I really want to thank jgarzik for that interesting talk. Who picks what block size? My talk is going to be about a category of dynamic block size proposals that attach the block size limit to the fee in such a way that as there is more demand for block size, through users that want to pay fees, the block size will increase or decrease as necessary. The need for a dynamic block size is so that the block size can increase.</description></item><item><title>Bip101 Block Propagation Data From Testnet</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/bip101-block-propagation-data-from-testnet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/bip101-block-propagation-data-from-testnet/</guid><description>I am a bitcoin miner. I am a C++ programmer and a scientist. I will be going pretty fast. I have a lot of stuff to cover. Bare with me.
My perspective on this is that scaling bitcoin is an engineer problem. My favorite proposal for how to scale bitcoin is bip101. It&amp;rsquo;s over a 20-year time span. This will give us time to implement fixes to get Bitcoin to a large level.</description></item><item><title>Bip99 And Uncontroversial Hard Forks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/bip99-and-uncontroversial-hard-forks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/bip99-and-uncontroversial-hard-forks/</guid><description>slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY1/1_overview_1_timon.pdf
bip99 https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/master/bip-0099.mediawiki
We are going to focus on consensus rules. I am going to give an introduction and then focus on controversial versus non-controversial hard-forks.
Why do we want to classify consensus changes in the first place? Well, for one, you often have long discussions many times in Bitcoin, we don&amp;rsquo;t always share the same terminology and the same definitions, and this could lead to disagreement. Another advantage of classifying consensus forks is to recommend strategies for them.</description></item><item><title>Braiding The Blockchain</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/braiding-the-blockchain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/braiding-the-blockchain/</guid><description>Bob McElrath (bsm117532)
slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY2/2_breaking_the_chain_1_mcelrath.pdf
I work for SolidX in New York. I am here to tell you about some modifications to the blockchain. All the things we heard yesterday about the block size, come down to the existence of orphans. The reason why we have these problems are orphans. These are consequences of physics and resources. This is not a fundamental property in Bitcoin. ((Transcripter&amp;rsquo;s note: basically, only sharding can make local bandwidth less of an issue.</description></item><item><title>Day 2 Opening</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/day-2-opening/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/day-2-opening/</guid><description>You know exactly what I am going to be saying. Code of Conduct. Code of Conduct. Code of Conduct. I am going to introduce the program chair, Neha. Hi everyone. I hope everyone enjoyed day 1. I thought it was quite fascinating.
We are going to have a few talks happen later. Look out for those. I&amp;rsquo;d like to go ahead and introduce our first speaker, Pieter.</description></item><item><title>Extensibility</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/extensibility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/extensibility/</guid><description>Extensibility, fraud proofs, and security models
Eric Lombrozo (CodeShark)
slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY2/4_extensibility_lombrozo.pdf
Transcript pending, please email link to video to kanzure@gmail.com for transcribing&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Fungibility And Scalability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/fungibility-and-scalability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/fungibility-and-scalability/</guid><description>slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY1/1_overviews_2_back.pdf
I think everyone knows what fungibility is, it&amp;rsquo;s when coins are equal and interchangeable. It&amp;rsquo;s an important property for an electronic cash system. All bitcoin users would have a problem if fungability goes away.
Bitcoin has fungibility without privacy. Previous electronic cash systems had fungibility and cryptographic blinding. In Bitcoin, there&amp;rsquo;s decentralized mining that somebody will process your transaction even if a given miner may not. But there is some privacy, because it&amp;rsquo;s based on pseudonyms.</description></item><item><title>In Adversarial Environments Blockchains Dont Scale</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/in-adversarial-environments-blockchains-dont-scale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/in-adversarial-environments-blockchains-dont-scale/</guid><description>slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY1/2_security_and_incentives_2_todd.pdf
That was a very useful talk (on security assumptions), thank you Andrew.
I am going to start by talking about nitty-gritty applications where adversarial thinking is useful for incentives for decentralization. In an environment where everyone has the data, we are kind of limited as to what we can do. When we talk about scale, I am talking about 5 or 10 orders of magnitude. Do we have a system that has fundamentally different scaling characteristics?</description></item><item><title>Intro</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/intro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/intro/</guid><description>Introduction to event
schedule: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/#schedule
better livestream link: http://www.youtube.com/channel/UCql9h_eXmusjt-f3k8qLwPQ/live
slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/#presentations
paper for the &amp;ldquo;SCP&amp;rdquo; presentation: http://eprint.iacr.org/2015/1168.pdf
slides from &amp;ldquo;SCP&amp;rdquo; presentation: http://www.comp.nus.edu.sg/~loiluu/talks/scp.pptx
irc.freenode.net #bitcoin-workshops
Hello, good morning everyone. Hi welcome to Scaling Bitcoin. My name is Bobbie Lee, my name is Victoria.
We have Pindar Wong coming up. Pindar is the chairman of the organizing committee. Let&amp;rsquo;s give a big round of welcome to Pindar.
Thank you so much. Welcome to Hong Kong.</description></item><item><title>Invertible Bloom Lookup Tables And Weak Block Propagation Performance</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/invertible-bloom-lookup-tables-and-weak-block-propagation-performance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/invertible-bloom-lookup-tables-and-weak-block-propagation-performance/</guid><description>IBLT and weak block propagation performance
slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY1/3_block_propagation_1_rosenbaum.pdf
IBLT - invertible bloom lookup tables
Before we get started, for privacy reasons, and for reasons of zero attribution, please do not take pictures of attendees. Do not have pictures of attendees in the photographs. Taking pictures of the stage and slides are OK, since they are being broadcasted. No photographs of any attendees, please let them remain anonymous and private. For Chinese speakers, please ask in Chinese and I will use American English to translate.</description></item><item><title>Network Topologies And Their Scalability Implications On Decentralized Off Chain Networks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/network-topologies-and-their-scalability-implications-on-decentralized-off-chain-networks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/network-topologies-and-their-scalability-implications-on-decentralized-off-chain-networks/</guid><description>slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY2/1_layer2_3_poon.pdf
LN transactions are real Bitcoin transactions. These are real zero-confirmation transactions. What&amp;rsquo;s interesting is that the original idea behind Bitcoin was solving the double-spending problem. When you move off-chain and off-block, you sort of have this opposite situation where you use double-spends to your advantage, spending from the same output, except you have this global consensus of block but you have this local ordering that you use through this lightning system of penalties through which you can update the balances between two people.</description></item><item><title>Overview Of Bips Necessary For Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/overview-of-bips-necessary-for-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/overview-of-bips-necessary-for-lightning/</guid><description>Scalability of Lightning with different BIPs and some back-of-the-envelope calculations.
slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY2/1_layer2_2_dryja.pdf
I don&amp;rsquo;t have time to introduce the idea of zero-confirmation transactions and lightning. We have given talks about this. There&amp;rsquo;s some documentation available. There&amp;rsquo;s an implementation being worked on. I think it helps a lot with scalability by keeping some transactions off the blockchain. Ideally, many or most transactions. Instead, you would open and close channels. That&amp;rsquo;s all that needs to be on the blockchain.</description></item><item><title>Security Assumptions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/security-assumptions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/security-assumptions/</guid><description>Hi, welcome back.
I am a developer for libsecp256k1. It&amp;rsquo;s a library that does the underlying traditional cryptography used in Bitcoin. I am going to talk about security assumptions, security models and trust models. I am going to give a high-level overview of how we should be thinking about these issues for scaling and efficiency and decentralization. Bitcoin is a crypto system. Everything about it is a crypto system. It needs to be designed with an adversarial mindset, even in an adversarial setting.</description></item><item><title>Segregated Witness And Its Impact On Scalability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/segregated-witness-and-its-impact-on-scalability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/segregated-witness-and-its-impact-on-scalability/</guid><description>slides: https://prezi.com/lyghixkrguao/segregated-witness-and-deploying-it-for-bitcoin/
code: https://github.com/sipa/bitcoin/commits/segwit
SPV = simplified payment verification
CSV = checksequenceverify
CLTV = checklocktimeverify
Segregated witness (segwit) and deploying it for Bitcoin
Okay. So I am Pieter Wuille. I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about segregated witness for Bitcoin. Before I can explain this, I want to give some context. We all know how bitcoin transactions work. Every bitcoin transaction gets inputs, which refer to previous outputs being spent. Every input has the txid and the signature to prove that it is allowed, plus an amount and script in every output.</description></item><item><title>Validation Cost Metric</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/validation-cost-metric/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/validation-cost-metric/</guid><description>slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY2/3_tweaking_the_chain_3_nick.pdf
Motivation As we&amp;rsquo;ve seen over the last two days scalability is a multidimensional problem. One of the main topics of research is increasing the blocksize to increase transaction throughput. The assumption is that as technological progress is continuing and transaction throughput is increased accordingly, the cost for runnning a fully validating node stays constant.
However, blocksize proposals usually only directly change one aspect of full node costs - the blocksize.</description></item><item><title>Why Miners Will Not Voluntarily Individually Produce Smaller Blocks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/why-miners-will-not-voluntarily-individually-produce-smaller-blocks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/why-miners-will-not-voluntarily-individually-produce-smaller-blocks/</guid><description>slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY1/2_security_and_incentives_3_bier.pdf
Marginal cost is very low.
In about 2011, people started discussing the idea of needing an artificial cap for a block size limit to kind of kick up the transaction fees. The orphan risk is a marginal cost the larger the block, the higher the chance of an orphan.
Now I&amp;rsquo;ve got some issues why orphan risk may not be so great. As technology improves, over time the technology cost of orphaning gets lower and lower, so you are relying on driving miner revenue or fees, would become less relevant.</description></item><item><title>Zero Knowledge Proofs For Bitcoin Scalability And Beyond</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/zero-knowledge-proofs-for-bitcoin-scalability-and-beyond/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/zero-knowledge-proofs-for-bitcoin-scalability-and-beyond/</guid><description>I am going to tell you about zero-knowledge proofs for Bitcoin scalability. Even though this is an overview talk, many of the results I will be telling you about are based on work done by people in the slides and also here at the conference.
First I will give a brief introduction to zero knowledge proofs. Then I will try to convince you that if you care about Bitcoin scalability, then you should care about zero-knowledge proofs and you should keep them on your radar.</description></item></channel></rss>