<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hash Time Locked Contract (HTLC) on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/htlc/</link><description>Recent content in Hash Time Locked Contract (HTLC) on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/htlc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lightning Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2022/lightning-panel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2022/lightning-panel/</guid><description>The discussion primarily revolved around the Lightning Network, a scaling solution for Bitcoin designed to enable faster, decentralized transactions. Rene Pickhardt and Lisa Neigut shared their insights, highlighting Lightning&amp;rsquo;s potential as a peer-to-peer electronic cash system and a future payment infrastructure. They emphasized its efficiency for frequent transactions between trusted parties but noted challenges in its current infrastructure, such as the need for continuous online operation and the risk of losing funds if a node is compromised. The panelists discussed the scalability of the network, indicating that while millions could use it self-sovereignly, larger-scale adoption would likely involve centralized service providers. The conversation also touched on the impact of Taproot on privacy and channel efficiency, and the technical intricacies of maintaining state and preventing fraud within the network.</description></item><item><title>Miniscript</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/miniscript/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/miniscript/</guid><description>Sanket describes to Murch his work on Miniscript. We explore uses for Miniscript, learn about intersections with PSBTs, Output Descriptors, and Taproot, and suss out the difference between Miniscript and Miniscript Policy.</description></item><item><title>The State of Atomic Swaps</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/atomic-swaps/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/atomic-swaps/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048790167283068929
History This should be easy to follow. I want to start off with some history. The first mention of atomic swap concepts was in 2013 in a bitcointalk.org thread where people were wondering how to exchange coins between independent ledgers in a trustless way. There were a few comments on the thread every now and then asking has anyone implemented this. It was quiet until last year when people started doing atomic swaps last year.</description></item></channel></rss>