<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Watchtowers on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/watchtowers/</link><description>Recent content in Watchtowers on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/watchtowers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Channel Jamming on the Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-podcast/channel-jamming-on-the-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-podcast/channel-jamming-on-the-lightning-network/</guid><description>Clara and Sergei stop by to chat about their recent proposal on mitigating jamming attacks in the Lightning Network. We talk unconditional fees, local reputation, the impact on decentralization and UX, and the state of Lightning in general.</description></item><item><title>Recovering Payment Channel Midstates Using only The User's Seed</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/payment-channel-recovery-with-seeds/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/payment-channel-recovery-with-seeds/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1172129077765050368
Introduction Cool. This addresses the lightning network which is a scaling technique for the bitcoin network. A big challenge with the lightning network is that you have these midstates that you need to keep. If you lose them, you&amp;rsquo;re out of luck with your counterparty. We had a lot of talks this morning about how to recover midstates but a lot of them used watchtowers. However, this proposal does not require a watchtower and you can restore midstates knowing nothing but your wallet seed.</description></item><item><title>Architecture of LND Watchtowers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/boltathon/2019-04-06-conner-fromknecht-watchtowers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/boltathon/2019-04-06-conner-fromknecht-watchtowers/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1117427512081100800
discussion: https://www.reddit.com/r/lightningdevs/comments/bd33cp/architecture_of_lnd_watchtowers_presentation_from/
Intro Pretty excited today to speak on the topic of watchtowers. It is something that we at Lightning Labs have been working on for almost a year now. Conceptual proof of concept code to really flushing it out into what would be today more of a full on protocol. Hopefully today we’re going to summarize a year of research into this presentation. I’m looking forward to getting into it with you guys so let’s dive right in.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Overview</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/layer2-summit/2018/lightning-overview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/layer2-summit/2018/lightning-overview/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005913055333675009
https://lightning.network/
Introduction First I am going to give a brief overview of how lightning works for those of who you may not be so familiar. Then I am going to discuss three technologies we&amp;rsquo;ll be working on in the next year at Lightning Labs and pushing forward.
Philosophical perspective and scalability Before I do that though, following up on what Neha was saying, I want to give a philosophical perspective on how I think about layer 2 as a scalability solution.</description></item><item><title>Incentivizing Payment Channel Watchtowers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/incentivizing-payment-channel-watchtowers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/incentivizing-payment-channel-watchtowers/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048767166823071746
Introduction Hi. Good morning. I am Zeta. I am going to talk about how to incentivize payment channel watchtowers. This is joint work with my collaborators.
Micropayment channels There are many ways to construct channels such as lightning channels and duplex channels. There&amp;rsquo;s hops, you can route payments, and other proposals more recent ones for doing channels in payment networks like sprites, eltoo, all of them although they are different they all share the fundamental nature of channels.</description></item><item><title>Unlinkable Outsourced Channel Monitoring</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/unlinkable-outsourced-channel-monitoring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/unlinkable-outsourced-channel-monitoring/</guid><description>http://lightning.network/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784752625074012160
Okay. Hi everyone. Check. Wow. Check one two. Okay it&amp;rsquo;s working. And I have 25 minutes. Great. So I am going to talk about unlinkable outsourced channel modeling. Everyone likes channels. You can update states. You can link them together to make a network. This is really great. There are risks. These are additional risks. The price of scalability is eternal vigilance. You have to keep watching your channels.</description></item></channel></rss>