<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Michael Goldstein on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/michael-goldstein/</link><description>Recent content in Michael Goldstein on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/michael-goldstein/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Q A</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/dallas-bitcoin-symposium/q-a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/dallas-bitcoin-symposium/q-a/</guid><description>Q&amp;amp;A session
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1162436437687623684
MB: I have a podcast called Tales from the Crypt where I interview people working on and around bitcoin. I have spoken to many of these gentlemen on the podcast as well. I want to focus on, many of these presentations were focused on history and prehistory of bitcoin. For this Q&amp;amp;A session, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the future of the bitcoin standard. Michael, I want you to talk about the future of the bitcoin standard on a sound money point standpoint, like not having to chase for a store of value like houses.</description></item><item><title>How To Meme Bitcoin To The Moon</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/how-to-meme-bitcoin-to-the-moon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/how-to-meme-bitcoin-to-the-moon/</guid><description>How to meme bitcoin to the moon
Introduction How many of y&amp;rsquo;all were at the dinner last night? Okay, great. I had a lot of fun. It was fantastic. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how we will beat it next year, but we will figure something out. I am Michael Goldstein, and welcome to my ridiculous tedtalk. A lot of people talk about price fundamentals, but I am going to talk about how to troll and take the curves hard.</description></item><item><title>Sound Money</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/dallas-bitcoin-symposium/sound-money/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/dallas-bitcoin-symposium/sound-money/</guid><description>Introduction In 2014, Michael appeared on MSNBC and gave this quote: &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;d only recommend using altcoins for speculation purposes if you really love risk, you&amp;rsquo;re absolutely in love with risk, and you&amp;rsquo;re interested in watching money disappear.&amp;rdquo; Today my talk is on sound money for the digital age. The concept of monetary economics is the reason why I got interested in bitcoin back in 2012. I still tihnk that&amp;rsquo;s the important thing that makes bitcoin important in the first place.</description></item></channel></rss>