<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Anonymity networks on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/anonymity-networks/</link><description>Recent content in Anonymity networks on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/anonymity-networks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bitcoin Core 22.0 Explained</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/bitcoin-core-v22-explained/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/bitcoin-core-v22-explained/</guid><description>Intro Aaron: 00:00:20
Welcome to Bitcoin Explained, the podcast with the most boring name in Bitcoin. Hey Sjors.
Sjors: 00:00:27
What&amp;rsquo;s up? What&amp;rsquo;s with the new name?
Aaron: 00:00:29
So We&amp;rsquo;ve rebranded our podcast. What do you think?
Sjors: 00:00:33
Well, I think, you know, especially if you read it correctly, Bitcoin, explained. I think it&amp;rsquo;s an amazing name. I think the problem was that a lot of people have no idea what the hell a Van Weerdam Shores Nado is.</description></item><item><title>CJDNS</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/cjdns/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/cjdns/</guid><description>This WRC episode shows Caleb DeLisle, the creator of the CJDNS project, discussing the benefits of decentralized mesh networking and its potential impact on the centralized internet controlled by companies. DeLisle explains the adversary tolerance of CJDNS and its use of public keys for communication verification. He also addresses concerns about the environmental impact of crypto mining and argues that it facilitates the transition to renewable energy sources. DeLisle emphasizes the attacks on decentralized finance and crypto by centralized entities and the importance of unity in the crypto community. He highlights the creation of PacketCrypt, a bandwidth-hard proof of work that incentivizes building out large amounts of bandwidth. DeLisle asserts the need to prioritize privacy, robustness, and resilience in the face of attacks and the value of positive engagement with policymakers. He also discusses the differences between CJDNS and other networking solutions, highlighting CJDNS&amp;rsquo;s focus on infrastructure and resilient internet access. In addition, DeLisle mentions the potential for individuals to provide internet access to their neighbors and the financing possibilities for the Packet Network Steward. Finally, he touches on the use of Rust programming language for code review and the productivity improvements it brings in terms of security.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Core 0.21.0</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/bitcoin-core-v0-21/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/bitcoin-core-v0-21/</guid><description>Intro Aaron van Wirdum: 00:01:35
Live from Utrecht, this is The Van Wirdum Sjorsnado. Episode 24, we&amp;rsquo;re going to discuss Bitcoin Core 21.
Sjors Provost: 00:01:46
Hooray. Well, 0.21. We&amp;rsquo;re still in the age of the zero point releases.
Aaron van Wirdum: 00:01:51
Yes, which is ending now.
Sjors Provost: 00:01:53
Probably yes.
Aaron van Wirdum: 00:01:54
That&amp;rsquo;s what I understand. The next one, the 22 will actually be Bitcoin Core 22.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Core 0.21 Supports Tor V3</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/bitcoin-core-v21-supports-tor-v3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/bitcoin-core-v21-supports-tor-v3/</guid><description>Introduction Aaron van Wirdum: 00:00:07
Live from Utrecht, this is the Van Wirdum Sjorsnado. Sjors, you pointed out to me that Bitcoin Core has an amazing new feature merged into its repository.
Sjors Provoost: 00:00:19
Absolutely, we have bigger onions now.
Aaron van Wirdum: 00:00:24
Right, so I had basically no idea what it meant. You figured it out.
Sjors Provoost: 00:00:29
I did.
Aaron van Wirdum: 00:00:34
Yeah so let&amp;rsquo;s start at the beginning.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Network Sphinx And Onion Routing</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/lightning-network-sphinx-and-onion-routing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/lightning-network-sphinx-and-onion-routing/</guid><description>Introduction Hi everyone. I am a developer of rust-lightning, it started in 2018 by BlueMatt. I started contributing about a year ago now. It&amp;rsquo;s a full featured, flexible, spec-compliant lightning library. It targets exchanges, wallet vendors, hardware, meshnet devices, and you can join us on Freenode IRC in the #rust-bitcoin channel which is a really nice one.
Privacy matters Privacy matters on the blockchain. This is the reason why lightning is taking so much time.</description></item></channel></rss>