<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Breaking Bitcoin 2017 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/</link><description>Recent content in Breaking Bitcoin 2017 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Changing Consensus Rules Without Breaking Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/changing-consensus-rules-without-breaking-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/changing-consensus-rules-without-breaking-bitcoin/</guid><description>Changing consensus rules without breaking bitcoin
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005822360321216512
Introduction I&amp;rsquo;d like to talk about &amp;hellip; we actually discovered we can replace the script completely with soft-forks.
It&amp;rsquo;s important to note this quote from satoshi, from summer 2010: &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t believe a second compatible implementation will ever&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;
Comparing open-source development to bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s blockchain &amp;hellip; a lot of the inspiration came from the development of open-source. All source code is public, analogous to all blockchain being public.</description></item><item><title>Consensus Pitfalls</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/2017-09-10-christopher-jeffrey-consensus-pitfalls/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/2017-09-10-christopher-jeffrey-consensus-pitfalls/</guid><description>Pitfalls of Consensus Implementation
Location: Breaking Bitcoin
Intro I’d like to talk about breaking Bitcoin today. Before I do that I’d like to give a short demonstration.
Demo Right now I am SSH’d into a server with a couple of nodes on it. I am going to start up a bitcoind node and I am going to connect to one of these nodes and have it serve me a chain. The chain is kind of big.</description></item><item><title>Interview Adam Back Elizabeth Stark</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/interview-adam-back-elizabeth-stark/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/interview-adam-back-elizabeth-stark/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005842855271784449
stark: Thank you Giacomo. Who here had too much fun at the party last night? My voice is going. Hopefully it will stay for this interview. We are lucky to have Adam Back here today, co-founder of Blockstream and inventor of Hashcash (history). He just happened to appear and there was an available spot. Thank you for making this work.
adam3us: Thank you for inviting me.
stark: I&amp;rsquo;m a co-organizer of this event.</description></item><item><title>Solar Powered Space Pirates</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/solar-powered-space-pirates/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/solar-powered-space-pirates/</guid><description>Solar powered space pirates: A threat to bitcoin?
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005633917356007425
Let&amp;rsquo;s see. How do I make this fullscreen? Alright, anyone who can actually read French know how to make this fullscreen? My french teachers in high school would be very disappointed in me.
My name is Peter Todd. I do cryptography consulting. I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved in Bitcoin Core as well. I want to tell you about whether solar powered space pirates are a threat to bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Banks As Bitcoin Custodians</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/banks-as-bitcoin-custodians/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/banks-as-bitcoin-custodians/</guid><description>Traditional banks as bitcoin custodians: Security challenges and implications
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005545022559866880
Our next speaker is Giacomo Zucco. Yeah, have fun.
categories: [&amp;lsquo;conference&amp;rsquo;] tags: [&amp;lsquo;security&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;research&amp;rsquo;] As you can hear, there are a lot of italians here. Okay. So, good afternoon everyone. I am Giacomo Zucco.
I am a theoretical physicist. I worked at Accenture as a technology consultant and now I work at BHB Network which is a bridge between free open-source development and research on the bitcoin protocol, and the world of the incumbents.</description></item><item><title>Breaking Hardware Wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/breaking-hardware-wallets/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/breaking-hardware-wallets/</guid><description>Breaking hardware wallets: Tales from the trenches and glimpses into the future
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005627960160849920
Hello. Nobody cares? Ah. So next up is Nicolas. And he will talk about hardware attacks. Thank you.
Introduction Hi everybody. Thanks for making a great conference so far. I am Nicolas from Ledger hardware wallet. Today I am going to be talking about breaking hardware wallets. I don&amp;rsquo;t mean physically breaking them. If you expected to come steal a hardware wallet and be able to break it, then you will be disappointed.</description></item><item><title>Light Clients During 2017 Interfork Period</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/light-clients-during-2017-interfork-period/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/light-clients-during-2017-interfork-period/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005617123287289857
Next up is Thomas.
Introduction Alright. Hello everyone. Thank you for having me. I&amp;rsquo;m the developer of the Electrum wallet. I started this project in 2011. I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about lite clients and the implication of the 2017 hard-fork. We might be in the middle of two forks at the moment.
So we have segwit and we are very happy about that. ((applause)) This graph was taken from Pieter Wuille&amp;rsquo;s website.</description></item><item><title>Socialized Costs Of Hard Forks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/socialized-costs-of-hard-forks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/socialized-costs-of-hard-forks/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005518746260262912
KL: Can you hear me? Is it good? Okay. I hope you have practiced your French because.. no, the presentations are in English. Welcome and thank you very much for being here. This conference will very probably be the best we&amp;rsquo;ve had in the bitcoin sphere. The crowd is pretty crazy. I&amp;rsquo;ve had the ticket list and I can say the people in this room, not just the speakers, the attendees are all super amazing.</description></item><item><title>Spam Attacks Analysis</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/spam-attacks-analysis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/spam-attacks-analysis/</guid><description>Hunting moby dick, an analysis of 2015-2016 spam attacks
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005525351517360129
Introduction Hi. Thanks for Breaking Bitcoin to invite me to speak and to present this research on Moby Dick.
Moby Dick and spam attacks&amp;ndash; let me explain, Moby Dick is an entity that spammed or sent a lot of transactions in bitcoin in 2015. We did some analysis on who this person is or what they were doing. This is bitcoin archaeology, where we analyze past activities and try to analyze what happened and get insight into what could happen.</description></item></channel></rss>