<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Andreas Antonopoulos on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/andreas-antonopoulos/</link><description>Recent content in Andreas Antonopoulos on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/andreas-antonopoulos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Seed Splitting</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/andreas-antonopoulos/2020-04-08-andreas-antonopoulos-seed-splitting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/andreas-antonopoulos/2020-04-08-andreas-antonopoulos-seed-splitting/</guid><description>Topic: Why is seed splitting a bad idea?
Location: Andreas Antonopoulos YouTube channel
Why is seed splitting a bad idea? This is something that is being discussed all the time especially on newbie forums. It really needs to be careful very carefully. A friend had the idea to achieve 2 out of 3 protection from my wallet seed by storing the seed in the following way:
Location 1: seed words 1-8 and 9-16 Location 2: seed words 1-8 and 17-24 Location 3: seed words 9-16 and 17-24</description></item><item><title>Hardware Wallet Security</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/andreas-antonopoulos/2019-02-01-andreas-antonopoulos-hardware-wallet-security/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/andreas-antonopoulos/2019-02-01-andreas-antonopoulos-hardware-wallet-security/</guid><description>Topic: Are Hardware Wallets Secure Enough?
Location: Andreas Antonopoulos YouTube channel
Are Hardware Wallets Secure Enough? Q - Hi Andreas. I store my crypto on a Ledger. Listening to Trace Mayer this week has me concerned that this is not safe enough. Trace says you need Bitcoin Core for network validation, Armory for managing the private keys and a Glacier protocol for standard operating procedures and a Purism laptop for hardware.</description></item><item><title>Initial Blockchain Download</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/andreas-antonopoulos/2018-10-23-andreas-antonopoulos-initial-blockchain-download/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/andreas-antonopoulos/2018-10-23-andreas-antonopoulos-initial-blockchain-download/</guid><description>Bitcoin Q&amp;amp;A: Initial blockchain download
Initial blockchain download Becca asks why does it take it so long to download the blockchain? I do have a fast internet connection and I could download 200GB in less than a hour. What Becca is talking about is what’s called the initial blockchain download or IBD which is the first synchronization of the Bitcoin node or any kind of blockchain node to its blockchain. The answer is that while the amount of data you need to download in order to get the full blockchain is about 200GB or so you’re not simply downloading that and storing it on disk.</description></item><item><title>Schnorr Signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/andreas-antonopoulos/2018-10-07-andreas-antonopoulos-schnorr-signatures/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/andreas-antonopoulos/2018-10-07-andreas-antonopoulos-schnorr-signatures/</guid><description>LTB Episode 378 - The Petro inside Venezuela &amp;amp; Schnorr Signatures
Schnorr signatures We’re currently using the elliptic curve digital signature algorithm (ECDSA) which is a specific way of doing digital signatures with elliptic curves but not the only way. Schnorr signatures have some unique characteristics that make them better in many ways than the ECDSA algorithm we use today in Bitcoin.
Schnorr signatures are better because they have certain quirks in the way the mathematics plays out.</description></item><item><title>Full Node and Home Network Security</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/andreas-antonopoulos/2018-08-30-andreas-antonopoulos-home-network-security/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/andreas-antonopoulos/2018-08-30-andreas-antonopoulos-home-network-security/</guid><description>Topic: Full Node and Home Network Security
Location: Andreas Antonopoulos YouTube channel
Does running a Bitcoin full node attract hackers to my home network? Q - Does running a Bitcoin full node and/or a Lightning node at home attract hackers to my IP address and home network? Also could it reveal ownership of Bitcoin and attract physical attacks? Are preconfigured full node starter kits safe to use for non-technical people or is this completely against the point of running a full node and thus non-technical people should abandon the idea?</description></item><item><title>Canada Senate Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/andreas-antonopoulos/2014-10-08-andreas-antonopolous-canada-senate-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/andreas-antonopoulos/2014-10-08-andreas-antonopolous-canada-senate-bitcoin/</guid><description>This is a transcript of submitted evidence to the Parliament of Canada&amp;rsquo;s Senate Committee on Banking, Trade and Commerce. Here is a video. The opening remarks can be found here.
Another transcript may appear here but who knows.
An additional transcript can be found here.
final report: http://www.parl.gc.ca/Content/SEN/Committee/412/banc/rep/rep12jun15-e.pdf
Prepared remarks. My experience is primarily in information security and network architecture. I have a Master’s degree in networks and distributed systems and have worked in this field since 1992.</description></item></channel></rss>