<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>quantum-resistance on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/quantum-resistance/</link><description>Recent content in quantum-resistance on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/quantum-resistance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Taproot</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06/2019-06-06-taproot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06/2019-06-06-taproot/</guid><description>https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/master/bip-0340.mediawiki
https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2019-May/016914.html
https://bitcoinmagazine.com/articles/taproot-coming-what-it-and-how-it-will-benefit-bitcoin/
previously: http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2018-03-06-taproot-graftroot-etc/
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1136616356827283456
Introduction Okay, so, first question- who put my name on that list and what do they want? It wasn&amp;rsquo;t me. I&amp;rsquo;ll ask questions. I can give a summary, but there&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of talk already and I don&amp;rsquo;t know what to focus on. What would sipa like us to review in particular about it? What design decisions do you feel least confident about? Is there anything where you would like other people to investigate design decisions before charging ahead?</description></item><item><title>Fireside chat with Dan Boneh</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/dan-boneh/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/grincon/2019/dan-boneh/</guid><description>TL: I was one of the founders of SF Bitcoin Devs with aantonop. I am also the co-founder of a company called Promise. We sponsor protocols in privacy as well as mimblewimble. If you are mining or actively looking to mine in grin, please say hello to me because we&amp;rsquo;re connected with a lot of mining companies and hosting companies that are looking to host miners very cheaply. I&amp;rsquo;d love to help.</description></item><item><title>Fractal: Post-Quantum and Transparent Recursive Proofs from Holography</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/fractal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/fractal/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230295372909514752
https://eprint.iacr.org/2019/1076.pdf
Introduction One of the most powerful things that you can do with SNARKs is something called recursive proofs where you actually prove that another SNARK was correct. I can give you a proof of a proof of a proof and this is amazing because you can prove an ever-expanding computation like a blockchain is always correct. I can always give you a proof that you have the latest block and you know the entire blockchain and all the transactions in it are correct.</description></item></channel></rss>