<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACK on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/op-checksigfromstack/</link><description>Recent content in OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACK on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/op-checksigfromstack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>General discussion on SIGHASH_NOINPUT, OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACK, and OP_SECURETHEBAG</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06/2019-06-06-noinput-etc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06/2019-06-06-noinput-etc/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1136636856093876225
There&amp;rsquo;s apparently some political messaging around OP_SECURETHEBAG and &amp;ldquo;secure the bag&amp;rdquo; might be an Andrew Yang thing.
SIGHASH_NOINPUT A bunch of us are familiar with NOINPUT. Does anyone need an explainer? What&amp;rsquo;s the difference from the original NOINPUT and the new one? NOINPUT is kind of scary to at least some people. If we just do NOINPUT, does that start causing problems in bitcoin? Does it mean exchanges need to start looking at history of transactions and blacklist NOINPUT in the recent history until it&amp;rsquo;s deeply buried?</description></item><item><title>On-Chain Defense in Depth</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2019-02-09-mcelrath-on-chain-defense-in-depth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2019-02-09-mcelrath-on-chain-defense-in-depth/</guid><description>On-chain defense in depth (UCL CBT seminar)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1159542209584218113
Introduction It seems strange to come to a university and put PhD on my slides because in the finance world that&amp;rsquo;s weird. I put it up there.
Okay, so. I work for Fidelity Digital Assets. Just a couple words about this. Our lawyers make us say this: &amp;ldquo;This presentation is intended to be educational in nature and is not representative of existing products and services from Fidelity Investments or Fidelity Digital Assets.</description></item><item><title>The evolution of bitcoin scripting</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/bitcoin-script/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/bitcoin-script/</guid><description>Agenda opcodes OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACK sighash flags keytree sigs MAST graftroot, taproot covenants, reverse covenants (input restrictions: this input has to be spent with tihs other input, or can only be spent if this other one doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist) stack manipulation script languages (simplicity) tx formats, serialization? what would we change with hard-fork changes to the transaction format? Segwit transaction encoding format sucks; the witnesses are at the end and inline with all the scriptsigs and that should be changed.</description></item></channel></rss>