<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Alekos Filini on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/alekos-filini/</link><description>Recent content in Alekos Filini on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/alekos-filini/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Bitcoin Development Kit (BDK)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/the-bitcoin-development-kit-bdk/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/the-bitcoin-development-kit-bdk/</guid><description>The podcast covers the evolution of the Bitcoin Development Kit (BDK), originally known as the Magical Bitcoin Library, from its inception at Blockstream to its current status as a fully-fledged open-source project. Key topics include the renaming of BDK, its foundational use of Rust and descriptors for wallet architecture, and the broad applicability for both individual and enterprise users. Early adopters and contributors to BDK&amp;rsquo;s development are highlighted, alongside discussions on the challenges and technical hurdles such as asynchronous operations and wallet management across multiple descriptors. The conversation also touches on the motivations behind developers preferring to build wallets from scratch and the potential advantages of adopting BDK for future-proofing wallet applications. Upcoming features in BDK 1.0 promise further enhancements, particularly in syncing mechanisms and transaction planning.</description></item><item><title>Magical Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/la-bitdevs/2020-05-21-alekos-filini-magical-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/la-bitdevs/2020-05-21-alekos-filini-magical-bitcoin/</guid><description>Magical Bitcoin site: https://magicalbitcoin.org/
Magical Bitcoin wallet GitHub: https://github.com/MagicalBitcoin/magical-bitcoin-wallet
sipa’s Miniscript site: http://bitcoin.sipa.be/miniscript/
Andrew Poelstra Miniscript presentation at London Bitcoin Devs: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-02-04-andrew-poelstra-miniscript/
Andrew Poelstra Miniscript workshop at Advancing Bitcoin: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-07-andrew-poelstra-miniscript/
Intro I am a developer, I work on Bitcoin. I came to Bitcoin pretty late compared to the people I work with. I started a couple of years ago working with Giacomo Zucco at BHB Network. I worked for a while at Blockstream and then I left.</description></item></channel></rss>