<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Eric Voskuil on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/eric-voskuil/</link><description>Recent content in Eric Voskuil on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/eric-voskuil/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Libbitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/libbitcoin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/libbitcoin/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014483126817521665
This is me. When I first suggested giving a talk here on libbitcoin, &amp;hellip;. one of the pieces of feedback I got was that bitcoin is libbitcoin, what are you building on bitcoin? libbitcoin is actually more. I will also talk about what it is going on underneath. It&amp;rsquo;s an implementation of bitcoin as well.
Most of the talks I give are around cryptoeconomics. Up until recently, libbitcoin hasn&amp;rsquo;t been mature enough to go and promote.</description></item><item><title>Tooling</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/tooling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/tooling/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014167542422822913
What kind of tools do we need to create, in order to facilitate building on bitcoin? We are going to open questions to the floor. The guys will be there to get your questions. The panel will be about 20 minutes long, and then we will go for food.
LN: I work at Blockstream. I work on low-level wallets and tooling for wallets.
ND: I am working on a library called Nbitcoin for programming bitcoin in C#.</description></item><item><title>Day 1 Closing Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/day-1-closing-panel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/day-1-closing-panel/</guid><description>Closing panel
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043517333640241152
RS: Thanks guys for joining the panel. We just need to get one more chair. I am going to introduce Alex Petrov here because everyone else was on stage. The closing panel is going to be an overview of what&amp;rsquo;s happening in bitcoin. I want to start with the question I started with last year. What is the current state of bitcoin compared to last year? What has happened?</description></item><item><title>Fud Perceived Vs Real Bitcoin Risks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/fud-perceived-vs-real-bitcoin-risks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/fud-perceived-vs-real-bitcoin-risks/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137285873534492672
Eric Voskuil 3CD8 C07F 0B5C E14E
Jimmy FAA6 17E3 2679 E455
Rodolfo 1C9E 033C 6C65 8606
Introduction AW: Some topics might have more agreement between the three of you, and some maybe less. It&amp;rsquo;s up to you guys to say smart things.
JS: Can&amp;rsquo;t guarantee anything there.
FUD: bitcoin too volatile to be used as money AW: What about, bitcoin is too volatile to be used as money?
EV: It is used as money, so.</description></item><item><title>The Reserve Currency Fallacy</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/the-reserve-currency-fallacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/the-reserve-currency-fallacy/</guid><description>The reserve currency fallacy
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043385469134925824
Thank you. Developers, developers, developers, developers. Alright, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t that bad. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of content to explain this concept of the reserve currency fallacy. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to get through it in the amount of available time. I&amp;rsquo;ll be available at the party tonight. I want to go through four slides and talk about the history of this question of scaling, and then the first scaling proposal, second scaling proposal, and so on.</description></item></channel></rss>