<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Baltic Honeybadger 2018 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/</link><description>Recent content in Baltic Honeybadger 2018 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Beyond Bitcoin Decentralized Collaboration</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/beyond-bitcoin-decentralized-collaboration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/beyond-bitcoin-decentralized-collaboration/</guid><description>Beyond bitcoin: Decentralized collaboration
Yurii Rashkovskii (yrashk)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043432684591230976
http://sit.fyi/
Hi everybody. Today I am going to talk about something different than my usual. I am going to talk more about how we can compute and how we collaborate. I&amp;rsquo;ll start with an introduction to the history of how things happened and why are things the way they are today. Many of you probably use cloud SaaS applications. It&amp;rsquo;s often touted as a new thing, something happening in the past 10-15 years.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin As A Novel Market Institution</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/bitcoin-as-a-novel-market-institution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/bitcoin-as-a-novel-market-institution/</guid><description>Bitcoin as a novel market institution
Nic Carter (nic__carter)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043763647498063872
I am going to be talking about bitcoin as an economic system, not as a software or cryptographic system. This talk has two parts. In the first, I&amp;rsquo;m going to take a retrospective of the past 10 years of bitcoin as a functioning economic system. In the second part, I will be looking at bitcoin as it is today and how it will be in the future.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Custody</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/bitcoin-custody/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/bitcoin-custody/</guid><description>Bryan Bishop
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048014038179823617
Bitcoin Custody
Baltic Honey Badger 2018 Bitcoin conference, Riga, Latvia, Day 2
Schedule: https://bh2018.hodlhodl.com/
Transcript
Start time: 6:09:50
Youtube: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D2WXxgZ8h-0&amp;amp;t=22160s
My name is Bryan Bishop, I’m going to be talking about bitcoin custody. Here is my PGP fingerprint, we should be doing that. So who am I, I have a software development background, I don’t just type transcripts. I’m actually no longer at LedgerX as of Friday (Sept 21 2018) when I came here.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Maximalism Dissected</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/bitcoin-maximalism-dissected/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/bitcoin-maximalism-dissected/</guid><description>Bitcoin maximalism dissected
Giacomo Zucco (giacomozucco)
Good morning everyone. I am very happy to be here at Baltic Honeybadger. Last year I gave a scaling presentation. I opened the conference with a scaling presentation. This year in order to compensate, I will be super serious. This will be the most boring presentation at the conference. I am going to try to dissect and formalize bitcoin maximalism.
This is the scarriest font I found on prezi.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Payment Processing And Merchants</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/bitcoin-payment-processing-and-merchants/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/bitcoin-payment-processing-and-merchants/</guid><description>1 on 1: Bitcoin payment processing and merchants
Sergej Kotliar (ziggamon)
Alena Vranova (AlenaSatoshi)
Vortex (theonevortex)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043476967918592003
V: Hello and welcome to this amazing conference. It&amp;rsquo;s a good conference, come on. It&amp;rsquo;s great because you can ask them about UASF and they know what you&amp;rsquo;re talking about. I have some guests with me today. We&amp;rsquo;re going to be talkin gabout merchant processing and talk about regular bitcoin adoption too. The first question I have for Alena is, &amp;hellip; there was a big effort in the early days of bitcoin to onboard merchants and get them on and people thought this was how bitcoin was going to win.</description></item><item><title>Current State Of The Market And Institutional Investors</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/current-state-of-the-market-and-institutional-investors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/current-state-of-the-market-and-institutional-investors/</guid><description>1 on 1: The current state of the market &amp;amp; institutional investors
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043404928935444480
Tone Vays (tonevays)
Bruce Fenton (brucefenton)
Bitcoin Association Guy (BAG)
BAG: I&amp;rsquo;m here with Bruce Fenton and Tone Vays. Bruce is also host of the Satoshi Roundtable and a long-term investor. Tone Vays is a derivatives trader and content creator. We&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking about Wall Street. I believe you&amp;rsquo;re both based in NY? How was the last 12 months?</description></item><item><title>Day 1 Closing Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/day-1-closing-panel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/day-1-closing-panel/</guid><description>Closing panel
Elizabeth Stark (starkness)
Peter Todd (peterktodd)
Jameson Lopp (lopp)
Eric Voskuil (evoskuil)
Alex Petrov (sysmannet)
Roman Snitko (hodlhodl)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043517333640241152
RS: Thanks guys for joining the panel. We just need to get one more chair. I am going to introduce Alex Petrov here because everyone else was on stage. The closing panel is going to be an overview of what&amp;rsquo;s happening in bitcoin. I want to start with the question I started with last year.</description></item><item><title>Extreme Opsec For The Modern Cypherpunk</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/extreme-opsec-for-the-modern-cypherpunk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/extreme-opsec-for-the-modern-cypherpunk/</guid><description>Extreme opsec for the modern cypherpunk
Jameson Lopp (lopp) jameson@team.casa
Jameson is the infrastructure engineer at Casa. Please welcome Jameson Lopp.
Introduction Hi fellow cypherpunks. We&amp;rsquo;re under attack. Corporations and nation states in their quest for omniscience have slowly stripped away our privacy. We are the frog being boiled in the pot called progress. We can&amp;rsquo;t trust that corporations will grant us privacy out of their beneficience. Our failures here are our own.</description></item><item><title>Investing In Bitcoin Businesses</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/investing-in-bitcoin-businesses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/investing-in-bitcoin-businesses/</guid><description>1 on 1: Investing in bitcoin businesses
Nic Carter (nic__carter)
Florian Maier (Marsmensch)
Matthew Mezinskis (crypto_voices) (moderator)
MM: I run a podcast based here in Latvia on bitcoin economics and money. It&amp;rsquo;s American-Latvian. I do it with my partner who is based in Brazil. Today we&amp;rsquo;re going to focus on investing in businesses focused on bitcoin and crypto.
NC: My name is Nic Carter. I work for a venture fund. We&amp;rsquo;re one of the few venture funds that focus on bitcoin and bitcoin-related startups.</description></item><item><title>Opening</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/opening/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/opening/</guid><description>Opening remarks for Baltic Honeybadger 2018
livestream: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=66ZoGUAnY9s
twitter: https://twitter.com/search?f=tweets&amp;amp;vertical=default&amp;amp;q=bh2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043384689321566208
Okay guys, we&amp;rsquo;re going to start in five minutes. So stay here. She is going to introduce speakers and help everyone out. Thanks everyone for coming. It&amp;rsquo;s a huge crowd this year. I wanted to make a few technical announcements. First of all, just remember that we should be excellent to each other. We have people from all over the world here.</description></item><item><title>Present And Future Tech Challenges In Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/present-and-future-tech-challenges-in-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/present-and-future-tech-challenges-in-bitcoin/</guid><description>1 on 1: Present and future tech challenges in bitcoin
Peter Todd (peterktodd)
Adam Back (adam3us)
Pierre Roberge (robep00)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043484879210668032
PR: Hi everybody. I think I have the great fortune to moderate this panel in the sense that we have really great questions thought by the organizers. Essentially we want to ask Adam and Peter what are their thoughts on the current and the future tech challenges for bitcoin. I&amp;rsquo;m just going to start with that question, starting with Peter.</description></item><item><title>The B Foundation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/the-b-foundation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/the-b-foundation/</guid><description>The B Foundation
Alena Vranova (AlenaSatoshi)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043802179004493825
I think most people here have some idea of who I am. I am a long-term bitcoiner. I&amp;rsquo;ve been in bitcoin since 2010. I love bitcoin. I am passionate about it. I want to see it grow and prosper. The positive thing about bitcoin is that it has a resilient ecosystem. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t need any CEO. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t need any centralized organization and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t need any central point to direct where it is going.</description></item><item><title>The Bitcoin Standard</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/the-bitcoin-standard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/the-bitcoin-standard/</guid><description>The bitcoin standard as a layered scaling solution
Saifedean Ammous (via skype) (saifedean)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043425514801844224
Hello, everyone. Can everyone hear me? Okay, wonderful. You can&amp;rsquo;t see my slides, can you. You have to share the screen if you want them to see your slides. How do I do that? Where is that? This is new skype, I&amp;rsquo;m sorry. Thank you everyone for inviting me to speak today. It would be great to join you, but unforutnately I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it.</description></item><item><title>The Future Of Bitcoin Smart Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/the-future-of-bitcoin-smart-contracts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/the-future-of-bitcoin-smart-contracts/</guid><description>The future of bitcoin smart contracts
Max Keidun (keidunm)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043419056492228608
Hey guys, next talk in 5 minutes. In five minutes.
Introduction Hello everyone. If you&amp;rsquo;re walking, please do it in silence. I am a bit nervous. I was too busy organizing this conference and didn&amp;rsquo;t get time for this talk. If you had high expectatoins for this presentation, then please lower them for the next 20 minutes. I was going to talk about the traditional VC models and why it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work in the bitcoin industry.</description></item><item><title>The Future Of Bitcoin Wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/the-future-of-bitcoin-wallets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/the-future-of-bitcoin-wallets/</guid><description>1 on 1: The future of bitcoin wallets
Pavol Rusnak (pavolrusnak)
Lawrence Nahum (larrybitcoin)
Giacomo Zucco (giacomozucco)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043445104827084800
GZ: Thank you very much. We&amp;rsquo;re going to talk about the future of bitcoin wallets. As you know, it&amp;rsquo;s a very central topic. We always compare bitcoin to the internet. Wallets are basically like browsers like back at the beginning of the web. They are the first gateway to a user experience for users on bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>The Future Of Lightning</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/the-future-of-lightning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/the-future-of-lightning/</guid><description>The future of lightning
Elizabeth Stark (starkness)
The year of #craeful and the future of lightning
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043501348606693379
It&amp;rsquo;s great to be back here in Riga. Let&amp;rsquo;s give a round of applause to the event organizers and everyone brought us back here. This is the warmest time I&amp;rsquo;ve ever been in Riga. It&amp;rsquo;s been great. I want to come back in the summers.
Introduction I am here to talk about what has happened in the past year and the future of what we&amp;rsquo;re going to see with lightning.</description></item><item><title>The Reserve Currency Fallacy</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/the-reserve-currency-fallacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/the-reserve-currency-fallacy/</guid><description>The reserve currency fallacy
Eric Voskuil (evoskuil)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043385469134925824
Thank you. Developers, developers, developers, developers. Alright, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t that bad. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of content to explain this concept of the reserve currency fallacy. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to get through it in the amount of available time. I&amp;rsquo;ll be available at the party tonight. I want to go through four slides and talk about the history of this question of scaling, and then the first scaling proposal, second scaling proposal, and so on.</description></item><item><title>Trading Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/trading-panel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/trading-panel/</guid><description>Trading panel
Whalepanda (Whalepanda)
Florian Maier (Marsmensch)
Tone Vays (ToneVays)
Matthew Mezinskis (crypto_voices)
MM: As Trace Mayer says, it&amp;rsquo;s chasing the rabbit. Why not introduce ourselves?
TV: My name is Tone Vays. I come from the traditional Wall Street trading environment. I joined the crypto space in 2013. I spoke at my first conference and wrote my first article in Q1 2014. I was doing some trading. With the popularity of the youtube channel and going to conferences, I went back to trading options in traditional markets.</description></item><item><title>Trustlessness Scalability And Directions In Security Models</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/trustlessness-scalability-and-directions-in-security-models/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/trustlessness-scalability-and-directions-in-security-models/</guid><description>Trustlessness, scalability and directions in security models
Matt Corallo (bluematt)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043397023846883329
&amp;hellip; Is everyone awake? Sure. Jumping jacks. Wow, that&amp;rsquo;s bright. I am more idealistic than Eric. I am going to talk about utility and why people use bitcoin and let&amp;rsquo;s see how that goes.
Trustlessness is much better than decentralization. I want to talk about trustlessness. People use the word decentralization a lot and I find that to be kind of useless because decentralization is a means to an end.</description></item></channel></rss>