<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bitcoin 2024 Nashville on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-2024/</link><description>Recent content in Bitcoin 2024 Nashville on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-2024/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The State of Bitcoin Core Development</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-2024/the-state-of-bitcoin-core-development/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-2024/the-state-of-bitcoin-core-development/</guid><description>Discover the latest developments in Bitcoin Core with our expert panel featuring key contributors to the project. This video delves into recent changes in security vulnerability disclosures, the challenges of funding open-source development, and the careful process of introducing new features to Bitcoin Core. Our panelists offer unique perspectives on the project&amp;rsquo;s priorities and the distinction between Bitcoin Core and protocol development.</description></item><item><title>Making Bitcoin More Private with CISA</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-2024/making-bitcoin-more-private-with-cisa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-2024/making-bitcoin-more-private-with-cisa/</guid><description>Delve into the world of Cross-Input Signature Aggregation (CISA) with our expert panel from Sparrow Wallet, Bitcoin Core, and Casa. This discussion illuminates how CISA could revolutionize Bitcoin transactions by enhancing privacy and reducing fees. Uncover the technical aspects of half and full signature aggregation and understand their potential impact on the Bitcoin network.</description></item><item><title>Discreet Log Contracts, Oracles, Loans, Stablecoins, and More</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-2024/discreet-log-contracts-oracles-loans-stablecoins-and-more/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-2024/discreet-log-contracts-oracles-loans-stablecoins-and-more/</guid><description>In this enlightening discussion, we explore the technical workings of DLCs, their advantages over traditional oracles, and how they compare to other blockchain ecosystems. Our experts also delve into the challenges and future potential of DLCs, making this a must-watch for anyone interested in the cutting edge of Bitcoin technology and decentralized finance.</description></item><item><title>Open Source Mining</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-2024/open-source-mining/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-2024/open-source-mining/</guid><description>Explore the cutting-edge of Bitcoin mining in this insightful panel discussion featuring industry experts. Dive deep into the challenges of mining centralization and discover innovative solutions like Stratum V2, Braid Pool, and open-source hardware projects like Bitx. Learn how these advancements are shaping the future of Bitcoin mining. Join us as we uncover the importance of decentralization in mining, the role of mining pools, and the potential of open-source development in the Bitcoin ecosystem</description></item><item><title>Unlocking Expressivity with OP_CAT</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-2024/unlocking-expressivity-with-op-cat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-2024/unlocking-expressivity-with-op-cat/</guid><description>Explore the exciting world of Bitcoin development with our panel discussion on OpCat, a proposed upgrade that could significantly enhance Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s functionality. Our experts break down the technical aspects of OpCat, explaining how this simple concatenation operation could enable powerful features like covenants, vaults, and more efficient transaction processing.</description></item></channel></rss>