<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Stepan Snigirev on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/stepan-snigirev/</link><description>Recent content in Stepan Snigirev on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/stepan-snigirev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Taproot on hardware wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2022/2022-03-03-stepan-snigirev-taproot-hardware-wallets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/advancing-bitcoin/2022/2022-03-03-stepan-snigirev-taproot-hardware-wallets/</guid><description>Intro (Jeff Gallas) I’m very happy to announce our first speaker for today. It is Stepan Snigirev from Specter, he is the CTO of Specter Solutions and has been working on Bitcoin software and hardware wallets for 3 years now so welcome Stepan.
Overview (Stepan Snigirev) What I want to talk about is Taproot on hardware wallets. We recently got the Taproot upgrade, yay, this is awesome. It activated in November.</description></item><item><title>Specter Desktop Bitcoin Multi Sig</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-08-28-stepan-snigirev-and-ben-kaufman/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2020-08-28-stepan-snigirev-and-ben-kaufman/</guid><description>podcast: https://stephanlivera.com/episode/205/
Stephan Livera:
Stepan and Ben, welcome to the show.
Stepan:
Thank you. Thank you, Stephan. It’s very nice to be here again.
Ben:
Thank you for inviting me.
Stephan Livera:
Stepan I know you’ve been on the show twice before, but perhaps just for any listeners who are a little bit newer, can you tell us a little bit about yourself?
Stepan:
We are doing well originally I came from quantum physics into Bitcoin and started working on hardware stuff mostly.</description></item><item><title>Hardware Wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/austin-bitcoin-developers/2019-06-29-hardware-wallets/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/austin-bitcoin-developers/2019-06-29-hardware-wallets/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1145019634547978240
see also:
Extracting seeds from hardware wallets The future of hardware wallets coredev.tech 2019 hardware wallets discussion Background A bit more than a year ago, I went through Jimmy Song&amp;rsquo;s Programming Blockchain class. That&amp;rsquo;s where I met M where he was the teaching assistant. Basically, you write a python bitcoin library from scratch. The API for this library and the classes and fnuctions that Jimmy uses is very easy to read and understand.</description></item><item><title>Hardware wallet attacks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2019-05-01-stepan-snigirev-hardware-wallet-attacks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2019-05-01-stepan-snigirev-hardware-wallet-attacks/</guid><description>Topic: Hardware Wallets (History of attacks)
Location: London Bitcoin Devs
Slides: https://www.dropbox.com/s/64s3mtmt3efijxo/Stepan%20Snigirev%20on%20hardware%20wallet%20attacks.pdf
Pieter Wuille on anti covert channel signing techniques: https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2020-March/017667.html
Introduction This talk is the second in the series after my previous talk in London a few months ago at the Advancing Bitcoin conference. There I was talking mostly about general attacks on hardware, more from the theoretical perspective. I didn’t say anything bad hardware wallets that exist and I didn’t specify anything on the bad side.</description></item><item><title>Future Of Hardware Wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/future-of-hardware-wallets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/future-of-hardware-wallets/</guid><description>The future of hardware wallets
D419 C410 1E24 5B09 0D2C 46BF 8C3D 2C48 560E 81AC
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137663515957837826
Introduction We are making a secure hardware platform for developers so that they can build their own hardware wallets. Today I want to talk about certain challenges for hardware wallets, what we&amp;rsquo;re missing, and how we can get better.
Current capabilities of hardware wallets Normally, hardware wallets keep keys reasonably secret and are able to spend coins or sign transactions.</description></item><item><title>Hardware Wallet Design Best Practices</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/edgedevplusplus/hardware-wallet-design-best-practices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/edgedevplusplus/hardware-wallet-design-best-practices/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171322716303036417
Introduction We have 30 minutes. This was a talk by me and Jimmy but Jimmy talked for like 5 hours yesterday so I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking today.
Imagine you want to start working in bitcoin development. There&amp;rsquo;s a chance you will end up using a hardware wallet. In principle, it&amp;rsquo;s not any different from other software development. There&amp;rsquo;s still programming involved, like for firmware. Wallets have certain features and nuances compared to software wallets.</description></item></channel></rss>