<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mit Bitcoin Expo 2017 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/</link><description>Recent content in Mit Bitcoin Expo 2017 on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bitcoin Mining And Trustlessness</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/bitcoin-mining-and-trustlessness/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/bitcoin-mining-and-trustlessness/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/838500313212518404
Yes, something like that. As mentioned, I&amp;rsquo;ve been contributing to Bitcoin Core since 2011 and I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on various parts of bitcoin, such as the early payment channel work, some wallet stuff, and now I work for Chaincode Lab one of the sponsors&amp;ndash; we&amp;rsquo;re a bitcoin research lab. We all kind of hang out and work on various bitcoin projects we find interesting. I want to talk about reflections on trusting trust.</description></item><item><title>Exchange Security</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/exchange-security/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/exchange-security/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/838517545783148545
How often do you check your wallets? Have you ever looked in your wallet and found all your bitcoin gone or missing? Last summer, somebody, a friend of mine checked his wallet and found that 100,000 bitcoin was gone. What the hell, right? But that&amp;rsquo;s what happened at Bitfinex last summer. Some hacker got into their hot wallet and stole 100,000 bitcoin. This was $70 million bucks. Of which 1.</description></item><item><title>Ideal Number Of Full Bitcoin Nodes</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/ideal-number-of-full-bitcoin-nodes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/ideal-number-of-full-bitcoin-nodes/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/838481130944876544
Today I am going to be talking about bitcoin full nodes. Can everyone hear me? Okay, great. I don&amp;rsquo;t actually think there&amp;rsquo;s a specific number. I think a lot of people do. They look for a number. 5000 is about how many we have today, 6000. Some people ask whether it&amp;rsquo;s a good number. I think that&amp;rsquo;s the wrong way to look at the role of full nodes in the ecosystem.</description></item><item><title>Mimblewimble And Scriptless Scripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/mimblewimble-and-scriptless-scripts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/mimblewimble-and-scriptless-scripts/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/838480912396533760
Up next we have Andrew Poelstra and he is going to be talking about a really interesting new concept for a cryptocurrency. It&amp;rsquo;s called mimblewimble, after a spell from Harry Potter, because it prevents characters from speaking. Try speaking? Hello, test. We also have a&amp;hellip; hello? hello? Can you guys hear me?
I am going to talk about the concept of scriptless scripts. It&amp;rsquo;s a way of describing what mimblewimble does, in a way that shows the conceptual details, and maybe give the ability to take the lessons we learned from mimblewimble and apply to other projects.</description></item><item><title>Scaling and UTXO commitments</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/scaling-and-utxos/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/scaling-and-utxos/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/838481311992012800
Thank you. I&amp;rsquo;ll admit the last one was probably the most fun other than. On the schedule, it said scaling and UTXO and I threw something together. TXO commitments were a bold idea but recently there were some observations that make it more interesting. I thought I would start by going through what problem they are actually solving.
Like David was saying in the last presentation, running a full node is kind of a pain.</description></item></channel></rss>