<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ben Carman on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/ben-carman/</link><description>Recent content in Ben Carman on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/ben-carman/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vortex: ZeroLink for Lightning Opens</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/vortex-zerolink-for-lightning-opens/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/vortex-zerolink-for-lightning-opens/</guid><description>(The start of the talk is missing from the source media)
What is a blind signature All these people could come, and they all can then present their signatures. And Bob will know, &amp;ldquo;okay, all of these signatures are correct, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know who gave me which one. You&amp;rsquo;ll see how we use this in the protocol to get some privacy. This is kind of the structure (referring to slide#2).</description></item><item><title>OP_VAULT Round 2 &amp; OP_CTV</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/op_vault-round-2-op_ctv/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/op_vault-round-2-op_ctv/</guid><description>The podcast episode discusses the OP_VAULT proposal for enhancing Bitcoin self-custody and security. NVK hosts a panel with James O&amp;rsquo;Beirne, Rijndael, Greg Sanders, and Ben Carman, who delve into the technical aspects and benefits of OP_VAULT. The proposal aims to improve Bitcoin custody by introducing vaults, allowing users to lock their coins with predetermined spend conditions, enhancing security against theft and accidental loss. They compare OP_VAULT with other proposals like CTV and ANYPREVOUT, highlighting its simplicity and operational efficiency. The conversation also addresses potential concerns about covenants and the importance of community engagement and education to facilitate the proposal&amp;rsquo;s acceptance and activation. The episode emphasizes the need for better custody solutions to secure large amounts of Bitcoin, especially as the user base grows and the value of Bitcoin increases.</description></item><item><title>OP_VAULT for Bitcoin Covenants Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/op_vault-for-bitcoin-covenants-panel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/op_vault-for-bitcoin-covenants-panel/</guid><description>Speaker 0: 00:00:45
Today we have an absolute all-star panel here. We&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking about the Bitcoin Op Vault. It&amp;rsquo;s a new proposal by James. And you know, like any new proposals to Bitcoin, there is a lot to go over. And It&amp;rsquo;s a very big, interesting topic. So today we have Rindell.
Speaker 2: 00:01:05
Hey, good morning. Yeah, I&amp;rsquo;m here talking about vaults, Bitcoin developer, and I work a lot on multi-sig and vaults that don&amp;rsquo;t use covenants.</description></item><item><title>Discrete Log Contract Specification</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi-research-club/discrete-log-contract-specification/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi-research-club/discrete-log-contract-specification/</guid><description>Today&amp;rsquo;s WRC episode includes Nadav Kohen and Benthecarman discuss the use of Discrete Log Contracts (DLCs) and their potential benefits and challenges. They explain that DLCs can enable various applications such as betting, options contracts, insurance, and synthetic assets. They highlight the advantages of DLCs, including high liquidity and fast trading of futures, especially once implemented on the Lightning Network. However, they also acknowledge that there may still be a need for centralized solutions depending on the specific use case. The speakers delve into the technical aspects of DLCs, including the transition to Schnorr signatures and the privacy implications of using DLCs. They also discuss the role of oracles in DLCs and the potential for coin joints with DLCs. Overall, the speakers provide a detailed overview of DLCs and their potential applications in the cryptocurrency space.</description></item></channel></rss>