<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Soft fork activation on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/soft-fork-activation/</link><description>Recent content in Soft fork activation on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/soft-fork-activation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Covenants, Introspection, CTV and Activation Impasse</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/covenants-introspection-ctv-and-activation-impasse/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/covenants-introspection-ctv-and-activation-impasse/</guid><description>Introduction NVK: 00:01:10
As usual, nothing is happening in Bitcoin and we figured, what a great day to put people to sleep in a one to three hour podcast. We don&amp;rsquo;t know yet how it&amp;rsquo;s going to be. We actually don&amp;rsquo;t know how this is going to play out at all. I have here with me Mr. Rijndael. Hello, sir. Welcome back.
Rijndael: 00:01:30
Hello. Good morning.
NVK: 00:01:32
Good morning.</description></item><item><title>OP_VAULT Round 2 &amp; OP_CTV</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/op_vault-round-2-op_ctv/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/op_vault-round-2-op_ctv/</guid><description>The podcast episode discusses the OP_VAULT proposal for enhancing Bitcoin self-custody and security. NVK hosts a panel with James O&amp;rsquo;Beirne, Rijndael, Greg Sanders, and Ben Carman, who delve into the technical aspects and benefits of OP_VAULT. The proposal aims to improve Bitcoin custody by introducing vaults, allowing users to lock their coins with predetermined spend conditions, enhancing security against theft and accidental loss. They compare OP_VAULT with other proposals like CTV and ANYPREVOUT, highlighting its simplicity and operational efficiency. The conversation also addresses potential concerns about covenants and the importance of community engagement and education to facilitate the proposal&amp;rsquo;s acceptance and activation. The episode emphasizes the need for better custody solutions to secure large amounts of Bitcoin, especially as the user base grows and the value of Bitcoin increases.</description></item><item><title>Demystifying and Understanding Bitcoin Core Development</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/demystifying-and-understanding-bitcoin-core-development/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/demystifying-and-understanding-bitcoin-core-development/</guid><description>Intro NVK: 00:00:40
Today, we&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking about Bitcoin Core development and trying to demystify it, maybe sort of like shed some light. So, some of the FUD goes away and new FUD comes in maybe, who knows?
Guest introductions NVK: 00:00:51
I have this awesome panel with me. I have a James O&amp;rsquo;Beirne. Hi James.
James O&amp;rsquo;Beirne: 00:00:56
Hi, good to be here.
NVK: 00:00:58
Thanks for coming.</description></item><item><title>User Rejected Soft Forks (URSFs)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/are-users-rejecting-bitcoin-forks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/are-users-rejecting-bitcoin-forks/</guid><description>Intro Aaron: Live from Utrecht, this is Bitcoin, Explained. Hey Sjors.
Sjors: What&amp;rsquo;s up?
Aaron: Sjors Provoost, Bitcoin Core contributor and author.
Sjors: Oh yes.
Aaron: Congratulations!
Sjors: Thank you.
Aaron: Your new book, Bitcoin: A Work in Progress is now available on Amazon?
Sjors: On everywhere. You go to btcwip.com, which is Work in Progress. There&amp;rsquo;s links to various Amazons and other sites where you can hopefully buy the book.</description></item><item><title>Socratic Seminar - Taproot is locked in. What now?</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2021-07-20-socratic-seminar-taproot-rollout/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2021-07-20-socratic-seminar-taproot-rollout/</guid><description>Gist of resources discussed: https://gist.github.com/michaelfolkson/0803271754f851530fe8242087859254
This event was livestreamed on YouTube and so comments are attributed to specific individuals by the name or pseudonym that was visible on the livestream. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be anonymized please get in touch.
Intro Michael Folkson (MF): Welcome to everyone on the call, welcome to anybody on YouTube. This is a Socratic Seminar on Taproot rollout or Taproot support post activation in November.</description></item><item><title>Explaining Segregated Witness</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/explaining-segregated-witness/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/explaining-segregated-witness/</guid><description>Aaron: 00:01:46
Live from Utrecht. This is The Van Wirdum Sjorsnado. Hello. Sjors, we&amp;rsquo;re going to talk about a classic today.
Sjors: 00:01:52
Yeah. We&amp;rsquo;re going to party like it&amp;rsquo;s 2015.
Aaron: 00:01:55
SegWit.
Segregated Witness Sjors: 00:01:56
That&amp;rsquo;s right.
Aaron: 00:01:57
Segregated Witness, which was the previous soft fork, well, was the last soft fork. We&amp;rsquo;re working towards a Taproot soft fork now.
Sjors: 00:02:06
It&amp;rsquo;s the last soft fork we know of.</description></item><item><title>How Bitcoin UASF went down, Taproot LOT=true, Speedy Trial, Small Blocks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2021-03-17-luke-dashjr-taproot-activation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stephan-livera-podcast/2021-03-17-luke-dashjr-taproot-activation/</guid><description>Luke Dashjr arguments against LOT=false: https://gnusha.org/url/https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2021-February/018498.html
T1-T6 and F1-F6 arguments for LOT=true and LOT=false: https://gnusha.org/url/https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2021-February/018380.html
F7 argument for LOT=false: https://gnusha.org/url/https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2021-February/018415.html
Transcript by: Stephan Livera Edited by: Michael Folkson
Intro Stephan Livera (SL): Luke, welcome to the show.
Luke Dashjr (LD): Thanks.
SL: So, Luke for listeners who are unfamiliar, maybe you could take a minute and tell us a little bit about your background and how long you’ve been developing and contributing with Bitcoin Core.</description></item><item><title>Taproot Activation with Speedy Trial</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/taproot-activation-speedy-trial/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/taproot-activation-speedy-trial/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this episode of &amp;ldquo;The Van Wirdum Sjorsnado, &amp;quot; hosts Aaron van Wirdum and Sjors Provoost discussed Speedy Trial, the proposed Taproot activation mechanism that has been gaining traction in recent weeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They explained that Speedy Trial would give miners three months to signal support for the Taproot upgrade with their hash power. If a supermajority of miners signals support for the upgrade within these three months, Taproot will activate a couple of months later: six months since the release of the software client that includes the activation logic. If miners don&amp;rsquo;t signal support within three months, the upgrade will expire and a new upgrade path can be considered. (It is, as of yet, not defined what the potential alternative upgrade path would look like).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Van Wirdum explained that Speedy Trial was born out of a compromise between developers and users who preferred different upgrade mechanisms for the Taproot soft fork, while Provoost detailed what some of the more technical implementation considerations of Speedy Trial are, like the benefits of using block heights instead of timestamps, and the extended delay between signaling and enforcement. Finally, the hosts discussed some of the downsides and risks of Speedy Trial.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Taproot activation and LOT=true vs LOT=false</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/taproot-activation-lockinontimeout/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/taproot-activation-lockinontimeout/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this episode of &amp;ldquo;The Van Wirdum Sjorsnado, &amp;quot; hosts Aaron van Wirdum and Sjors Provoost discussed activation of the Taproot soft fork upgrade, and more specifically, the lock-in on timeout (LOT) parameter.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The LOT parameter can be set to either &amp;rsquo;true&amp;rsquo; (LOT=true) or &amp;lsquo;false&amp;rsquo; (LOT=false). LOT=false resembles how several previous soft forks were activated. Miners would have one year to coordinate Taproot activation through hash power; if and when a supermajority (probably 90 percent) of miners signal readiness for the upgrade, the soft fork will activate. But if this doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen within (probably) a year, the upgrade will expire. (After which it could be redeployed.) LOT=true also lets miners activate the soft fork through hash power, but if they fail to do this within that year, nodes will activate the soft fork regardless.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Van Wirdum and Provoost discussed the benefits and detriments of each option. This also includes possible scenarios of what could happen if some users set LOT to true, while other users set LOT to false, and the associated risks. Finally, the hosts discussed what they think is most likely going to happen with Taproot activation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sydney Socratic Seminar</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-02-23-socratic-seminar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sydney-bitcoin-meetup/2021-02-23-socratic-seminar/</guid><description>Topic: Agenda in Google Doc below
Video: No video posted online
Google Doc of the resources discussed: https://docs.google.com/document/d/1VAP4LNjHHVLy9RJwpQ8LqXEUw79z5TTZxr9du_Z0-9A/
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have expressed a preference for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
PoDLEs revisited (Lloyd Fournier) https://gnusha.org/url/https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/lightning-dev/2021-January/002929.html
We’ll start with me talking about my research into UTXO probing attacks on Lightning in the dual funding proposal.</description></item><item><title>Socratic Seminar - Signet</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-08-19-socratic-seminar-signet/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-08-19-socratic-seminar-signet/</guid><description>Pastebin of the resources discussed: https://pastebin.com/rAcXX9Tn
The conversation has been anonymized by default to protect the identities of the participants. Those who have given permission for their comments to be attributed are attributed. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be attributed please get in touch.
Intro Michael Folkson (MF): This is a Socratic Seminar organized by London BitDevs. We have a few in the past. We had a couple on BIP-Schnorr and BIP-Taproot that were really good with Pieter Wuille, Russell O’Connor and various other people joined those.</description></item><item><title>How to Activate a New Soft Fork</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-magazine/2020-08-03-eric-lombrozo-luke-dashjr-taproot-activation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-magazine/2020-08-03-eric-lombrozo-luke-dashjr-taproot-activation/</guid><description>Location: Bitcoin Magazine (online)
Aaron van Wirdum in Bitcoin Magazine on BIP 8, BIP 9 or Modern Soft Fork Activation: https://bitcoinmagazine.com/articles/bip-8-bip-9-or-modern-soft-fork-activation-how-bitcoin-could-upgrade-next
David Harding on Taproot activation proposals: https://gist.github.com/harding/dda66f5fd00611c0890bdfa70e28152d
Intro Aaron van Wirdum (AvW): Eric, Luke welcome. Happy Bitcoin Independence Day. How are you doing?
Eric Lombrozo (EL): We are doing great. How are you doing?
AvW: I am doing fine thanks. Luke how are you?
Luke Dashjr (LD): OK. How are you?</description></item><item><title>Breaking Down Taproot Activation Options</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/breaking-down-taproot-activation-options/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/breaking-down-taproot-activation-options/</guid><description>This podcast episode delves into the nuances of Bitcoin soft fork activation, with a particular focus on the upcoming Taproot activation. Hosts Aaron van Wirdum and Sjors Provoost discuss the history and mechanisms of soft fork activation, including the challenges faced during previous activations such as SegWit. They explore different proposals for activating Taproot, weighing the merits and drawbacks of methods like BIP 9, BIP 91, BIP 148 (UASF), and the newer BIP 8. The discussion highlights the importance of achieving consensus within the community and the complexities involved in coordinating upgrades across the decentralized Bitcoin network. The episode concludes with considerations for future soft fork activations, emphasizing patience, thorough review, and the potential for innovative solutions like &amp;ldquo;sporks&amp;rdquo; to address these challenges</description></item><item><title>Is Taproot development moving too fast or too slow?</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2020-07-20-greg-maxwell-taproot-pace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2020-07-20-greg-maxwell-taproot-pace/</guid><description>Taproot has been discussed for 2.5 years already and by the time it would activate it will certainly at this point be over three years.
The bulk of the Taproot proposal, other than Taproot itself and specific encoding details, is significantly older too. (Enough that earlier versions of our proposals have been copied and activated in other cryptocurrencies already)
Taproot&amp;rsquo;s implementation is also extremely simple, and will make common operations in simple wallets simpler.</description></item><item><title>Handling Reorgs &amp; Forks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/reorgs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/reorgs/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1052344700554960896
Introduction Good morning, my name is Bryan. I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking about reorganizations and forks in the bitcoin blockchain. First, I want to define what a reorganization is and what a fork is.
Definitions You might have heard that the bitcoin blockchain is a permanent data structure that records everything from all time and that is actually somewhat false. Instead, actually the bitcoin blockchain can be modified and changed, and some of these changes are called reorgs and some of these changes are called forks.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Full Nodes</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2018-07-23-john-light-bitcoin-full-nodes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2018-07-23-john-light-bitcoin-full-nodes/</guid><description>John Light blog post on soft forks and hard forks: https://medium.com/@lightcoin/the-differences-between-a-hard-fork-a-soft-fork-and-a-chain-split-and-what-they-mean-for-the-769273f358c9
Intro My presentation today is going to be about Bitcoin full nodes. Everything you wanted to know and more. There should perhaps be an asterisk because I’m not going to say literally everything but if anyone in the audience has any questions that want to go really deep down the rabbit hole then we’ll see just how far down we can go.</description></item><item><title>Changing Consensus Rules Without Breaking Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/changing-consensus-rules-without-breaking-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/changing-consensus-rules-without-breaking-bitcoin/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005822360321216512
Introduction I&amp;rsquo;d like to talk about &amp;hellip; we actually discovered we can replace the script completely with soft-forks.
It&amp;rsquo;s important to note this quote from satoshi, from summer 2010: &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t believe a second compatible implementation will ever&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;
Comparing open-source development to bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s blockchain &amp;hellip; a lot of the inspiration came from the development of open-source. All source code is public, analogous to all blockchain being public. All changes are logged, same as all ledger additions, and subject to audit.</description></item><item><title>Light Clients During 2017 Interfork Period</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/light-clients-during-2017-interfork-period/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/light-clients-during-2017-interfork-period/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005617123287289857
Next up is Thomas.
Introduction Alright. Hello everyone. Thank you for having me. I&amp;rsquo;m the developer of the Electrum wallet. I started this project in 2011. I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about lite clients and the implication of the 2017 hard-fork. We might be in the middle of two forks at the moment.
So we have segwit and we are very happy about that. ((applause)) This graph was taken from Pieter Wuille&amp;rsquo;s website.</description></item><item><title>Socialized Costs Of Hard Forks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/socialized-costs-of-hard-forks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/socialized-costs-of-hard-forks/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005518746260262912
KL: Can you hear me? Is it good? Okay. I hope you have practiced your French because.. no, the presentations are in English. Welcome and thank you very much for being here. This conference will very probably be the best we&amp;rsquo;ve had in the bitcoin sphere. The crowd is pretty crazy. I&amp;rsquo;ve had the ticket list and I can say the people in this room, not just the speakers, the attendees are all super amazing.</description></item><item><title>On Consensus and All Kinds of Forks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lets-talk-bitcoin-podcast/2017-06-04-consensus-uasf-and-forks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lets-talk-bitcoin-podcast/2017-06-04-consensus-uasf-and-forks/</guid><description>User activated soft forks vs hard forks Adam Levine (AL): I’m trying to look at the user activated soft fork thing and not see hypocrisy just steaming out of its ears. I’m really in need of you to help me understand why this is not the case Andreas. The argument to this point about scaling, one of the arguments, one of the larger arguments, has been that hard forks are the worst thing that can happen.</description></item><item><title>The Great Debate Whalepool</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2016-12-14-whalepool/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2016-12-14-whalepool/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/809174512105295872
Host: Mr. Ver, can you hear this?
RV: Yes, I can.
Host: Welcome to Whalepool.
Gavin: Hey Roger, it&amp;rsquo;s Gavin. I heard about this.
RV: Hey Eric. I see lots of familiar names in here.
RV: Who was that? I don&amp;rsquo;t know whose voice that was.
Hodl: Mr. Hodl
RV: Thanks for organizing this. Hello Mr. Hodl.
Host: Okay, ready to go. Here we have Eric Lombrozo who is a developer who has committed code to Bitcoin Core.</description></item><item><title>Lessons Learned with Segwit in Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/segwit-lessons-learned/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/segwit-lessons-learned/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785034301272420353
Hi. My name is Greg Sanders. I will be giving a talk about segwit in bitcoin lessons learned. I will also give some takeaways that I think are important. A little bit about myself. I work on Elements Project at Blockstream. I was a reviewer on segwit for Bitcoin Core. How do we scale protocol development? How do we scale review and keep things safe?
Segwit started as an element in elements alpha.</description></item><item><title>Cali 2016</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-developers-miners-meeting-2016/cali2016/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-developers-miners-meeting-2016/cali2016/</guid><description>California Gathering 2016
Transcription introduction Some Bitcoin developers and miners gathered together during the end of the July to socialize and become better acquainted with each other. The following discussions were live transcribed by an untrained volunteer with attribution removed as per Chatham House rules. In bitcoin, discussions can move very quickly, which can cause an increase in errors, including semantic errors, when typing in real time. This text was not produced from an audio recording.</description></item><item><title>A Flexible Limit Trading Subsidy For Larger Blocks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/a-flexible-limit-trading-subsidy-for-larger-blocks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/a-flexible-limit-trading-subsidy-for-larger-blocks/</guid><description>slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY2/3_tweaking_the_chain_2_friedenbach.pdf
I really want to thank jgarzik for that interesting talk. Who picks what block size? My talk is going to be about a category of dynamic block size proposals that attach the block size limit to the fee in such a way that as there is more demand for block size, through users that want to pay fees, the block size will increase or decrease as necessary. The need for a dynamic block size is so that the block size can increase.</description></item><item><title>Bip101 Block Propagation Data From Testnet</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/bip101-block-propagation-data-from-testnet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/bip101-block-propagation-data-from-testnet/</guid><description>I am a bitcoin miner. I am a C++ programmer and a scientist. I will be going pretty fast. I have a lot of stuff to cover. Bare with me.
My perspective on this is that scaling bitcoin is an engineer problem. My favorite proposal for how to scale bitcoin is bip101. It&amp;rsquo;s over a 20-year time span. This will give us time to implement fixes to get Bitcoin to a large level.</description></item><item><title>Bip99 And Uncontroversial Hard Forks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/bip99-and-uncontroversial-hard-forks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/bip99-and-uncontroversial-hard-forks/</guid><description>slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY1/1_overview_1_timon.pdf
bip99 https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/master/bip-0099.mediawiki
We are going to focus on consensus rules. I am going to give an introduction and then focus on controversial versus non-controversial hard-forks.
Why do we want to classify consensus changes in the first place? Well, for one, you often have long discussions many times in Bitcoin, we don&amp;rsquo;t always share the same terminology and the same definitions, and this could lead to disagreement. Another advantage of classifying consensus forks is to recommend strategies for them.</description></item><item><title>Changes Without Unanimous Consent</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/changes-without-unanimous-consent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/changes-without-unanimous-consent/</guid><description>I want to talk about dealing with consensus changes without so-called consensus. I am using consensus in terms of the social aspect, not in terms of the software algorithm consensus for databases. &amp;ldquo;Consensus changes without consensus&amp;rdquo;. If you don&amp;rsquo;t consensus on consensus, then some people are going to follow one chain and another another chain.
If you have unanimous consensus, then new upgrades work just fine. Developers write software, miners run the same stuff, and then there are no splits because PoW builds on other blocks and we&amp;rsquo;re all happy and the economy is all in agreement as well and everyone wins.</description></item><item><title>Spork: Probabilistic Bitcoin Soft Forks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/spork-probabilistic-bitcoin-soft-forks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/spork-probabilistic-bitcoin-soft-forks/</guid><description>Introduction Thank you for the introduction. I have a secret. I am not an economist, so you&amp;rsquo;ll have to forgive me if I don&amp;rsquo;t have your favorite annotations today. I have my own annotations. I originally gave a predecessor to this talk in Japan. You might notice my title here is a haiku: these are protocols used for changing the bitcoin netwokr protocols. People do highly value staying together for a chain, we&amp;rsquo;re doing coordinated activation of a new upgrade.</description></item><item><title>Taproot, Schnorr, and the next soft-fork</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/taproot-schnorr-soft-fork/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/taproot-schnorr-soft-fork/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1162839000811548672
Introduction I am going to speak about this potential next version of bitcoin. Who here has heard of these words? Taproot? Schnorr? Who has heard these buzzwords these days? Yeah, so, the proposed next soft-fork is going to involve both of these technologies sort of interplaying. We want to talk about what are these technologies and how do we use thse things and why is it important that a bitcoin user or holder understands these technologies?</description></item></channel></rss>