<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>zero-knowledge on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/zero-knowledge/</link><description>Recent content in zero-knowledge on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/zero-knowledge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Crypto In Cryptocurrency</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/crypto-in-cryptocurrency/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/crypto-in-cryptocurrency/</guid><description>The &amp;ldquo;crypto&amp;rdquo; in cryptocurrency: Why everything is weird and hard
I do not have any slides for you. This is my attempt to keep this non-technical, by depriving myself of any ability to write equations on screen. The topic of my talk is why everything is weird and hard in cryptocurrency. What is cryptography as a mathematics and field of science? And how does this work in practice?
Encryption Historically the purvue of cryptography is encryption, like trying to come up with something random looking.</description></item><item><title>Bulletproofs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2018-02-02-andrew-poelstra-bulletproofs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2018-02-02-andrew-poelstra-bulletproofs/</guid><description>49th Milan Bitcoin meetup
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/962326126969442304
https://www.reddit.com/r/Bitcoin/comments/7w72pq/bulletproofs_presentation_at_feb_2_milan_meetup/
Introduction Alright. Thank you for that introduction, Giacamo. I am here to talk about bulletproofs. This is different from proof-of-bullets, which is what fiat currencies use. In bulletproofs, we use a zero-knowledge proof which has nothing to do with consensus at all, but it has a lot of exciting applications. The original motivation to create bulletproofs was for range proofs which are used in confidential transactions.</description></item><item><title>Building Bulletproofs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/building-bulletproofs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/building-bulletproofs/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1090668746073563136
Introduction There are two parts to this talk. The first part of the talk will be building, like all the pieces we put into making the implementation of bulletproofs. We&amp;rsquo;ll talk about the group we used, the Ristretto group and ristretto255 group. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about parallel lelliptic curve arithmetic, and Merlin transcripts for zero-knowledge proofs, and how all these pieces fit together.
Cathie will talk in part two about constraint system proofs, cloak for a confidential assets protocol, ZkVM for zero-knowledge contracts, and aggregation multi-party computation with session types to aggregate proofs and have faster verification.</description></item><item><title>Bulletproofs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/bulletproofs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2018/bulletproofs/</guid><description>Bulletproofs
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/958881877896593410
http://web.stanford.edu/~buenz/pubs/bulletproofs.pdf
https://joinmarket.me/blog/blog/bulletpoints-on-bulletproofs/
https://crypto.stanford.edu/bulletproofs
Introduction Good morning everyone. I am Benedikt Bünz and I am going to talk about bulletproofs. This is joint work with myself, Jonathan Bootle, Dan Boneh, Andrew Poelstra, Pieter Wuille, and Greg Maxwell. Bulletproofs are short proofs that we designed originally with the goal of improving confidential transactions but I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about how they have many more applications and how they are short zero-knowledge proofs for arbitrary computations really.</description></item><item><title>Hardware Accelerated Rsa - VDFs, SNARKs, and Accumulators</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/hardware-accelerated-rsa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/hardware-accelerated-rsa/</guid><description>Hardware Accelerated RSA - VDFs, SNARKs, and Accumulators
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230551345700069377
Introduction I am going to talk about accelerating RSA operations in hardware. So let&amp;rsquo;s just get into it.
Outline I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about what acceleration is and why we&amp;rsquo;re interested in it, then we&amp;rsquo;ll get into RSA primitives, then we&amp;rsquo;ll get into algorithms, and then various platforms for hardware. Hardware is anything you&amp;rsquo;re going to run software on. We&amp;rsquo;ll look at what the tradeoffs are, and then some performance numbers and measurements we&amp;rsquo;ve taken.</description></item><item><title>Stark For Developers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/stark-for-developers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/stark-for-developers/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230279740570783744
Introduction It always seems like there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of different proof systems, but it turns out they really work well together and there&amp;rsquo;s great abstractions that are happening where we can take different tools and plug them together. We will see some of those in this session. I think STARKs were first announced 3 years ago back when this conference was BPASE, and now they are ready to use for developers and they are deployed in the wild and it&amp;rsquo;s exciting to see how far we&amp;rsquo;ve come in the past few years.</description></item><item><title>State Of Cryptography</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/state-of-cryptography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/state-of-cryptography/</guid><description>State of cryptography for blockchains beyond ECDSA and sha256
Signatures and zero-knowledge proofs
Benedikt Bunz, Stanford University
Am going to talk about cryptography relevant to blockchains. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about signatures and zero-knowledge proofs. It has a lot of applications to bitcoin. It turns out that bitcoin is pretty simple in terms of cryptography. It just uses a hash function (sha256) and,s eparately, ECDSA for signatures. I will be mentioning some other cryptography that bitcoin could use.</description></item><item><title>Survey Of Progress In Zero Knowledge Proofs Towards Trustless Snarks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/survey-of-progress-in-zero-knowledge-proofs-towards-trustless-snarks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/survey-of-progress-in-zero-knowledge-proofs-towards-trustless-snarks/</guid><description>Ben Fisch (Stanford University) (benafisch)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171683484382957568
Introduction I am going to be giving a survey of recent progress into succinct zero-knowledge proofs. I&amp;rsquo;ll survey recent developments, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to start with what zero-knowledge proofs are. This is towards SNARKs without trusted setup. I want to help you get up to date on what&amp;rsquo;s happening on with SNARKs. There&amp;rsquo;s an explosion of manuscripts and it&amp;rsquo;s hard to keep track.
One theme is the emergence of polynomial commitment schemes which is an efficient tool for building transparent SNARKs without trusted setup.</description></item><item><title>Zero Knowledge Proofs For Bitcoin Scalability And Beyond</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/zero-knowledge-proofs-for-bitcoin-scalability-and-beyond/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/zero-knowledge-proofs-for-bitcoin-scalability-and-beyond/</guid><description>I am going to tell you about zero-knowledge proofs for Bitcoin scalability. Even though this is an overview talk, many of the results I will be telling you about are based on work done by people in the slides and also here at the conference.
First I will give a brief introduction to zero knowledge proofs. Then I will try to convince you that if you care about Bitcoin scalability, then you should care about zero-knowledge proofs and you should keep them on your radar.</description></item><item><title>Zksharks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/zksharks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/cryptoeconomic-systems/2019/zksharks/</guid><description>zkSHARKs
Introduction Indeed I am Madars Virza. I am going to talk about SHARKs. I am going to be talking about zero-knowledge SHARKs. It&amp;rsquo;s actually something serious and it&amp;rsquo;s related to non-interactive zero-knowledge proofs.
Non-interactive zero knowledge proofs zkproofs are protocols between two parties, a prover and a verifier. Both prover and verifier know a public input, but only the prover knows a secret input as a witness. The prover wants to convince the verifier that some relationship holds between the public input and the secret witness.</description></item><item><title>Zkvm - zero-knowledge virtual machine for fast confidential smart contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/zkvm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/zkvm/</guid><description>Fats, private, flexible blockchain contracts
Oleg Andreev (Stellar) (oleganza)
https://medium.com/stellar-developers-blog/zkvm-a-new-design-for-fast-confidential-smart-contracts-d1122890d9ae and https://twitter.com/oleganza/status/1126612382728372224
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171711553512583169
Introduction Okay, welcome. What is zkvm? It&amp;rsquo;s a multi-asset blockchain architecture that combines smart contracts and confidentiality features. It&amp;rsquo;s written in pure rust from top to bottom.
https://github.com/stellar/slingshot
Agenda I&amp;rsquo;ll explain the good parts, and then I&amp;rsquo;ll explain away the bad parts. Sounds like a good time.
What does this have to do with bitcoin? zkvm is a unique combination of the best ideas in the blockchain space.</description></item></channel></rss>