<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Arvind Narayanan on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/arvind-narayanan/</link><description>Recent content in Arvind Narayanan on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/arvind-narayanan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Arvind Narayanan</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/arvind-narayanan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/arvind-narayanan/</guid><description>I would like to introduce Arvind. He is a professor at Princeton. He has talked about this in a number of different forums.
Hi everyone. My name is Arvind. This is turning out to be one of the more unusual and interesting events that I have been to. Someone at my table called the first session a quasi-religious experience. Not sure whether that was a good thing or not. Joking aside, my favorite thing about this is that the position statements were available on the website.</description></item><item><title>Lessons For Bitcoin From 150 Years Of Decentralization</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/lessons-for-bitcoin-from-150-years-of-decentralization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/lessons-for-bitcoin-from-150-years-of-decentralization/</guid><description>Arvind Narayanan (twitter- random_walker) - Princeton University
Another 30 seconds. Take your seats. We have Arvind Narayanan. Some of the research from Princeton has rivaled the work of MIT. Professor Narayanan is going to teach us some lessons for Bitcoin.
Thank you. Can you hear me? I think you can. What I want to do today is to look at lessons from history for the future of Bitcoin, the next 10 years for Bitcoin, the next 30 years for Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Security Of Diminishing Block Subsidy</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/security-of-diminishing-block-subsidy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/security-of-diminishing-block-subsidy/</guid><description>Miners no longer incentivized to mine all the time. The future of mining hardware. Impact on the bitcoin ecosystem. Implications and assumptions of the model.
Are minting rewards and transaction fees the same? Transaction fees are time-dependent. A miner can only claim transaction fees as transactions are added to their block. As transaction fees start to dominate the block reward, they become time-dependent. We are modeling this block reward as a linear function of time, we have this factor B which might be initial minting reward, and we have some scaling factor, the block reward is like &amp;ldquo;b + at&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Threshold signatures</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/arvind-narayanan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/arvind-narayanan/</guid><description>I want to tell you what threshold signatures are and I want to convince you that threshold signatures are a technology you need. This is collaborative work.
There are three things I want to tell you today. The first is that the banking security model has been very very refined and has sophisticated techniques and process and controls for ensuring security. It does not translate to Bitcoin. This may seem surprising.</description></item></channel></rss>