<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Peter Todd on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/peter-todd/</link><description>Recent content in Peter Todd on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/peter-todd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Single Use Seals</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/single-use-seals/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/single-use-seals/</guid><description>Single use seals
Building on Bitcoin 2018
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014168068447195136
I am going to talk about single use seals and ways to use them. They are a concept of building consensus applications and things that need consensus. I want to mention why that matters. What problem are we trying to solve? Imagine my cell phone and I open up my banking app or the banking app or lightning app&amp;hellip; I want to make sure that what I see on my screen is the same as what you see on your screen.</description></item><item><title>Solar Powered Space Pirates</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/solar-powered-space-pirates/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/solar-powered-space-pirates/</guid><description>Solar powered space pirates: A threat to bitcoin?
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005633917356007425
Let&amp;rsquo;s see. How do I make this fullscreen? Alright, anyone who can actually read French know how to make this fullscreen? My french teachers in high school would be very disappointed in me.
My name is Peter Todd. I do cryptography consulting. I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved in Bitcoin Core as well. I want to tell you about whether solar powered space pirates are a threat to bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Scaling and UTXO commitments</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/scaling-and-utxos/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/scaling-and-utxos/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/838481311992012800
Thank you. I&amp;rsquo;ll admit the last one was probably the most fun other than. On the schedule, it said scaling and UTXO and I threw something together. TXO commitments were a bold idea but recently there were some observations that make it more interesting. I thought I would start by going through what problem they are actually solving.
Like David was saying in the last presentation, running a full node is kind of a pain.</description></item><item><title>Scalable Smart Contracts Via Proofs And Single Use Seals</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/scalable-smart-contracts-via-proofs-and-single-use-seals/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/blockchain-protocol-analysis-security-engineering/2017/scalable-smart-contracts-via-proofs-and-single-use-seals/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/957660108137418752
slides: https://cyber.stanford.edu/sites/default/files/petertodd.pdf
https://petertodd.org/2016/commitments-and-single-use-seals
https://petertodd.org/2016/closed-seal-sets-and-truth-lists-for-privacy
Introduction I am petertodd and I am here to break your blockchain. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of interesting following a talk like that, in some ways I&amp;rsquo;m going in a more extreme direcion for consensus. Do we actually need consensus at all? Can we make a more robust system by eliminating it to the maximum extent possible? I think for some use case at least I have some techniques that will let you go do this.</description></item><item><title>Breaking The Chain</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/breaking-the-chain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/breaking-the-chain/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785144266683195392
http://dpaste.com/1ZYW028
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/milan/client-side-validation/
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong/braiding-the-blockchain/
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/milan/jute-braiding/
Inclusivitiy So it seems like we have two big topics here, one is braiding and one is proof-of-publication. I had a talk in Hong Kong about braiding. The major difference is the inclusive nature. The notion that every block gets a block reward as a way to solve selfish-mining. It&amp;rsquo;s a competition between the orphans that get a reward and the ones that don&amp;rsquo;t that causes a loss of security.</description></item><item><title>Client Side Validation</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/client-side-validation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/client-side-validation/</guid><description>Progress on scaling via client-side validation
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785121442602029056
http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/scalingbitcoin/milan/breaking-the-chain/
Let&amp;rsquo;s start with what isn&amp;rsquo;t client-side validation. I am going to call this the miner-side approach. Here&amp;rsquo;s some smart contract code. In this example, it&amp;rsquo;s Chronos which is a timestamping contract. What you have here is a contract that stores in ethereum state consensus some hashes as they are received, they are timestamped. And ultimately at some point in the future you could go and ask the ethereum state machine, you know, did you go and get this hash?</description></item><item><title>Cryptographic Hocus Pocus</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/cryptographic-hocus-pocus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/cryptographic-hocus-pocus/</guid><description>Cryptographic hocus-pocus meaning nothing: The zcash trusted setup MPC
or: &amp;ldquo;Peter Todd&amp;rsquo;s secret love letter to Zooko&amp;rdquo;
Background See http://web.archive.org/web/20170717025249/https://petertodd.org/2016/cypherpunk-desert-bus-zcash-trusted-setup-ceremony
and later it was then redacted: https://petertodd.org/2016/cypherpunk-desert-bus-zcash-trusted-setup-ceremony
Introduction Alright. Hopefully you guys are all awake ish or something. I am going to give a talk about the zcash trusted setup. As many of you know, I was involved in it. The way to start is to answer, what is it?</description></item><item><title>Day 1 Closing Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/day-1-closing-panel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/day-1-closing-panel/</guid><description>Closing panel
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043517333640241152
RS: Thanks guys for joining the panel. We just need to get one more chair. I am going to introduce Alex Petrov here because everyone else was on stage. The closing panel is going to be an overview of what&amp;rsquo;s happening in bitcoin. I want to start with the question I started with last year. What is the current state of bitcoin compared to last year? What has happened?</description></item><item><title>Fraud Proofs</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/fraud-proofs-petertodd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/fraud-proofs-petertodd/</guid><description>In Bitcoin we have made this tradeoff where we don&amp;rsquo;t have everyone running full nodes. Not everyone is participating equally. If you have a full node, you have lots of gigs of hard drive space, but if you do that, you only get a few transactions per second. Modularizing validation an argument for this is how to improve on this situation.
What&amp;rsquo;s the problem we are trying to solve? This is a real screenshot from one of the Android wallets.</description></item><item><title>In Adversarial Environments Blockchains Dont Scale</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/in-adversarial-environments-blockchains-dont-scale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/in-adversarial-environments-blockchains-dont-scale/</guid><description>slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY1/2_security_and_incentives_2_todd.pdf
That was a very useful talk (on security assumptions), thank you Andrew.
I am going to start by talking about nitty-gritty applications where adversarial thinking is useful for incentives for decentralization. In an environment where everyone has the data, we are kind of limited as to what we can do. When we talk about scale, I am talking about 5 or 10 orders of magnitude. Do we have a system that has fundamentally different scaling characteristics?</description></item><item><title>Overview Of Security Concerns</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/overview-of-security-concerns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/overview-of-security-concerns/</guid><description>Overview of Security Concerns
I am going to talk about scale-related security issues. Scale-related security issues. I said scale, not scalability. We are not talking about scalability. We&amp;rsquo;re talking about changing numbers, and what are the implications, what attacks are easier or harder by changing the block size number. What are we trying to accomplish? What is the system meant to be? Nobody really agrees of course. What&amp;rsquo;s interesting is that as much as we disagree about what was meant to be, there are a lot of key things about what bitcoin could be, these visions share some details.</description></item><item><title>Petertodd Dex</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/petertodd-dex/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/petertodd-dex/</guid><description>I have been working on deterministic expressions language called DEX. It looks like lambda calculus. But really we&amp;rsquo;re trying to create a way to specify expressions that would return true if a signature is valid. Something like this, which is really just check a signature against a pubkey for a message, is essentially something that would be baked into your software anyway. We&amp;rsquo;re trying to move into a layer of abstraction where you can specify the conditions you need for your particular use case.</description></item><item><title>Present And Future Tech Challenges In Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/present-and-future-tech-challenges-in-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/present-and-future-tech-challenges-in-bitcoin/</guid><description>1 on 1: Present and future tech challenges in bitcoin
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1043484879210668032
PR: Hi everybody. I think I have the great fortune to moderate this panel in the sense that we have really great questions thought by the organizers. Essentially we want to ask Adam and Peter what are their thoughts on the current and the future tech challenges for bitcoin. I&amp;rsquo;m just going to start with that question, starting with Peter.</description></item><item><title>Scalability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/peter-todd-scalability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2015/peter-todd-scalability/</guid><description>There we go. Yeah. Looks good. Thank you.
So I wanted to talk about scalability and I wanted to give two opposing views of it. The first is really, scaling Bitcoin up is really really easy. The underlying architecture of Bitcoin is designed in a way that makes it easy to scale. You have your blockchain, and you have your blocks at the top which are 80 bytes data structures. They form a massive long chain all the way back to the genesis block when Bitcoin was created.</description></item></channel></rss>