<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Joseph Poon on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/joseph-poon/</link><description>Recent content in Joseph Poon on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/joseph-poon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2015-05-26-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2015-05-26-lightning-network/</guid><description>Tadge Dryja Joseph Poon How Lightning Network can offer a solution for bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s scalability problems
http://lightning.network/
slides: https://lightning.network/lightning-network-presentation-sfbitcoinsocial-2015-05-26.pdf
Great to have you guys. They are going to talk about bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s scalability problems. There they are.
Okay, hi. So yeah, I titled it solutions because that sounds more positive than talking about problems. Joseph will go after that and talk about what needs to change and the economics and things like that.</description></item><item><title>Scaling Bitcoin To Billions Of Transactions Per Day</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2015-02-23-scaling-bitcoin-to-billions-of-transactions-per-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2015-02-23-scaling-bitcoin-to-billions-of-transactions-per-day/</guid><description>Scaling Bitcoin To Billions Of Transactions Per Day
http://lightning.network/
Joseph Poon joseph@lightning.network Thaddeus Dryja rx@awsomnet.org We&amp;rsquo;re doing a presentation on the lightning network and micropayments. Right now bitcoin faces some interesting problems, like transactions aren&amp;rsquo;t instant, and micropayments don&amp;rsquo;t work. The transaction fees are 1/10th of a cent or higher depending on the exchange rate. And, &amp;ldquo;bitcoin doesn&amp;rsquo;t scale&amp;rdquo; especially if you have a lot of micropayments. One megabyte blocks? Well, let&amp;rsquo;s increase them.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Failure Modes And The Role Of The Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/bitcoin-failure-modes-and-the-role-of-the-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/bitcoin-failure-modes-and-the-role-of-the-lightning-network/</guid><description>I am going to be talking about bitcoin failure modes, and Joseph will talk about how the lightning network can help. I&amp;rsquo;ll start. We&amp;rsquo;ll start off by saying that bitcoin is working, which is really cool. Blocks starts with lots of zeroes, coins stay put, they move when you tell them to. That&amp;rsquo;s really cool and it works. That&amp;rsquo;s great. This is a good starting place. We should acknowledge that bitcoin can fail.</description></item><item><title>Improvements to Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/maaku-panel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/maaku-panel/</guid><description>This can be a broad range of topics for improvements. I am Mark Friedenbach, I have worked on Bitcoin protocol research, but I also do Core tech engineering at Blockstream. We also have Jonas, an independent Bitcoin Core developer. We also have Andrew Poelstra, who has been core to the crypto work which has been incoporated into Bitcoin, such as libsecp256k1 which we recently integrated in the 0.12 release. It speeds up Bitcoin validation by 7-8x.</description></item><item><title>Network Topologies And Their Scalability Implications On Decentralized Off Chain Networks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/network-topologies-and-their-scalability-implications-on-decentralized-off-chain-networks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/network-topologies-and-their-scalability-implications-on-decentralized-off-chain-networks/</guid><description>slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY2/1_layer2_3_poon.pdf
LN transactions are real Bitcoin transactions. These are real zero-confirmation transactions. What&amp;rsquo;s interesting is that the original idea behind Bitcoin was solving the double-spending problem. When you move off-chain and off-block, you sort of have this opposite situation where you use double-spends to your advantage, spending from the same output, except you have this global consensus of block but you have this local ordering that you use through this lightning system of penalties through which you can update the balances between two people.</description></item></channel></rss>