<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Partially signed bitcoin transactions on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/psbt/</link><description>Recent content in Partially signed bitcoin transactions on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/psbt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Newsletter #292 Recap</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinops/newsletter-292-recap/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinops/newsletter-292-recap/</guid><description>Mark Erhardt: 00:03:57
We are complete. Maybe we can start. So good morning. This is Optech Newsletter #292 Recap. And as you can hear, Mike is not here today and I&amp;rsquo;m filling in as the main host. Today we have four news items, two releases and release candidates, and four PRs to talk about in our notable code and documentation changes. I&amp;rsquo;m Merch and I work at Chaincode Labs and bring you weekly this OpTec newsletter recap.</description></item><item><title>The Bitcoin Core Wallet</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/the-bitcoin-core-wallet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/the-bitcoin-core-wallet/</guid><description>The discussion with Andrew Chow explores the evolution of the Bitcoin Core wallet, emphasizing significant developments like descriptor wallets and PSBT for enhancing functionality and interoperability. The conversation highlights the continuous efforts to refactor and improve the wallet&amp;rsquo;s codebase, addressing challenges and introducing innovations in coin selection and transaction management. The importance of maintaining high security and review standards is underscored, reflecting the wallet&amp;rsquo;s role in supporting Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s core principles. Future directions include improving the wallet&amp;rsquo;s performance, user experience, and GUI.</description></item><item><title>Miniscript</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/miniscript/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-labs/chaincode-podcast/miniscript/</guid><description>Sanket describes to Murch his work on Miniscript. We explore uses for Miniscript, learn about intersections with PSBTs, Output Descriptors, and Taproot, and suss out the difference between Miniscript and Miniscript Policy.</description></item><item><title>Segwit, PSBT Vulnerability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/la-bitdevs/2020-06-18-luke-dashjr-segwit-psbt-vulnerability/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/la-bitdevs/2020-06-18-luke-dashjr-segwit-psbt-vulnerability/</guid><description>SegWit/PSBT vulnerability (CVE-2020-14199)
Location: LA BitDevs (online)
CVE: https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2020-14199
Trezor blog post on the vulnerability: https://blog.trezor.io/latest-firmware-updates-correct-possible-segwit-transaction-vulnerability-266df0d2860
Greg Sanders Bitcoin dev mailing list post in April 2017: https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2017-August/014843.html
The vulnerability The way Bitcoin transactions are encoded in the software is there is a list of coins essentially and then there is a list of destinations and the amount being sent to each destination. The destinations do not include the fee. Nothing in the transaction tells you what the fee of the transaction is.</description></item><item><title>Magical Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/la-bitdevs/2020-05-21-alekos-filini-magical-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/la-bitdevs/2020-05-21-alekos-filini-magical-bitcoin/</guid><description>Magical Bitcoin site: https://magicalbitcoin.org/
Magical Bitcoin wallet GitHub: https://github.com/MagicalBitcoin/magical-bitcoin-wallet
sipa’s Miniscript site: http://bitcoin.sipa.be/miniscript/
Andrew Poelstra Miniscript presentation at London Bitcoin Devs: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-02-04-andrew-poelstra-miniscript/
Andrew Poelstra Miniscript workshop at Advancing Bitcoin: https://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/advancing-bitcoin/2020/2020-02-07-andrew-poelstra-miniscript/
Intro I am a developer, I work on Bitcoin. I came to Bitcoin pretty late compared to the people I work with. I started a couple of years ago working with Giacomo Zucco at BHB Network. I worked for a while at Blockstream and then I left.</description></item><item><title>Hardware Wallets in Bitcoin Core</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-02-05-andrew-chow-hardware-wallets/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2020-02-05-andrew-chow-hardware-wallets/</guid><description>Slides: https://www.dropbox.com/s/k02o32d0pagac4r/Andrew%20Chow%20slides.pdf
BIP174 (PSBT): https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/master/bip-0174.mediawiki
PSBT Howto for Bitcoin Core: https://github.com/bitcoin/bitcoin/blob/master/doc/psbt.md
Introduction Hey everyone. As you may have guessed I’m Andrew Chow. I’m Engineer at Blockstream and I also work on Bitcoin Core a lot, mostly in the wallet. I am going to be talking about hardware wallets and a bit history with them in Core and also how to integrate them in Core and how we are integrating them into Core.</description></item><item><title>Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2019-03-15-partially-signed-bitcoin-transactions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/sf-bitcoin-meetup/2019-03-15-partially-signed-bitcoin-transactions/</guid><description>Topic: PSBT
Location: SF Bitcoin Devs
Introduction Andrew: So as Mark said I&amp;rsquo;m Andrew Chow and today I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking about BIP 174, partially signed Bitcoin transactions, also known as PSBT. Today I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking a bit about why we need PSBTs, or Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions, what they are, and the actual format of the transaction itself and how to use a PSBT and the workflows around that.</description></item><item><title>Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions (BIP174)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/partially-signed-bitcoin-transactions-bip174/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/partially-signed-bitcoin-transactions-bip174/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1047730297242935296
Introduction Bryan briefly mentioned partially-signed bitcoin transactions (PSBT). I can give more depth on this. There&amp;rsquo;s history and motivation, a background of why this is important, what these things are doing. What is the software doing?
History and motivation Historically, there was no standard for this. Armory had its own format. Bitcoin Core had network-serialized transactions. This ensures fragmentation and it&amp;rsquo;s incomplete and bad that there was no standard. For segwit, a transaction to a legacy node looks like a zero-input transaction, which is a way to flag it as a segwit transaction.</description></item><item><title>Current And Future State Of Wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/current-and-future-state-of-wallets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/current-and-future-state-of-wallets/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014127893495021568
Introduction I started to contribute to Bitcoin Core about 5 years ago. Since then, I have managed to get 450 commits merged. I am also the co-founder of a wallet hardware company based in Switzerland called Shift+ Cryptocurrency.
Wallets is not rocket science. It&amp;rsquo;s mostly about pointing the figure to things that we can do better. I prepared a lot of content.
Privacy, security and trust When I look at existing wallets, I see the triangle of privacy, security and trust.</description></item><item><title>State Of Multisig</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/state-of-multisig/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bit-block-boom/2019/state-of-multisig/</guid><description>State of multisig for bitcoin hodlers: Better wallets with PSBT
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1162769521993834496
Introduction I am going to be talking about the state of multisig. It&amp;rsquo;s a way of creating a transaction output that requires multiple keys to sign. This is a focus for people holding bitcoin. I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about some of the benefits and some of the issues. I am not a security expert, though.
Perspective Multisig is an emphasis on saving and not spending a lot.</description></item></channel></rss>