<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>build systems on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/build-systems/</link><description>Recent content in build systems on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/build-systems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CMake Update</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2023-09/cmake/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2023-09/cmake/</guid><description>Update Hebasto has a branch he has been PRing into his own repo. Opened a huge CMake PR for Bitcoin core.
Introducing it chunk by chunk on his own repo
QT and GUIX is after that
Next steps How to get this into Core?
We don’t have something clean. Still have something wonky and how and what to do with autotools.
Ideally introduce CMake for a full cycle. It might still be a little too rough to ship on day 1 of the v27 cycle.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Toolchain, Unit Testing And Deterministic Builds</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/bitcoin-toolchain-unit-testing-and-deterministic-builds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/bitcoin-toolchain-unit-testing-and-deterministic-builds/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048103693885759489
Introduction Just to continue on what James said about the build system on Bitcoin Core&amp;hellip; I am going to talk about deterministic builds. I am MarcoFalke and I also work at Chaincode Labs in NYC.
Bitcoin Core Build System The build system is based on autotools, so it should just work anywhere where autotools runs. Just run ./autogen.sh ./configure and then make, that&amp;rsquo;s it.
We recently added support for MSVC builds mostly for Windows developers to do native builds not having to switch between Linux and Windows all the time.</description></item><item><title>Protecting Yourself And Your Business</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/protecting-yourself-and-your-business/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/protecting-yourself-and-your-business/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048087226742071296
Introduction Hello. My name is Warren Togami and I will be talking about exchange security. Not only protecting the people but also the business. This has been a topic of interest recently.
Warren&amp;rsquo;s security background I have some credibility when it comes to security due to my previous career in open-source software. I have been working on the Linux operating system first with Fedora then with Red Hat for many years.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Build System</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/bitcoin-build-system/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/bitcoin-build-system/</guid><description>Bitcoin build systems and bitcoin build system security
Carl Dong, Chaincode Labs
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137347937426661376
I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it to Amsterdam this year, but I hope the graphics I have prepared for this talk can make up for my absence. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you want to be a good bitcoin citizen and start to run your own bitcoin node. Say you go to bitcoincore.org, you click the download button, and you open the disk image and you double click on Bitcoin Core.</description></item></channel></rss>