<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security Problems on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/security-problems/</link><description>Recent content in Security Problems on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/security-problems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Block 1, 983, 702 Problem</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/the-block-1-983-702-problem/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/the-block-1-983-702-problem/</guid><description>&lt;p>The episode from &amp;ldquo;Bitcoin Explained&amp;rdquo; podcast, hosted by Aaron van Wirdum and Sjors Provoost, discusses a complex issue in the Bitcoin protocol known as the &amp;ldquo;Block 1, 983, 702 Problem.&amp;rdquo; The dialogue delves into the historical bug in Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s protocol that allowed for the existence of duplicate transactions, leading to potential consensus failure and the loss of Bitcoin for miners. This problem, stemming from an &amp;ldquo;OG Satoshi bug, &amp;quot; has been partially addressed over time through various Bitcoin Improvement Proposals (BIPs), specifically BIP30 and BIP34, which aimed to prevent duplicate transactions by ensuring unique coinbase transactions in each block.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, a subsequent realization highlighted a loophole: early blocks (pre-BIP34) could contain numerical sequences in their coinbase transactions that might accidentally be replicated in future blocks, posing a potential risk of creating duplicate transactions again. This issue, dubbed the &amp;ldquo;Block 1, 983, 702 Problem, &amp;quot; could theoretically allow an attacker to exploit this loophole, though it would require significant resources and specific conditions to be feasible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To mitigate this risk, a temporary fix was implemented in 2018, deciding to reinstate BIP30 checks from block 1, 983, 702 onwards, giving the Bitcoin community time to find a more permanent solution. Several potential fixes are discussed, including making SegWit mandatory for all blocks, which would inherently prevent the duplication issue by ensuring a unique identifier in each block that was not present in pre-BIP34 blocks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Throughout the conversation, Provoost and van Wirdum explore the technical nuances of the problem, the historical context of its discovery, and the implications for Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s security and consensus mechanism. They emphasize the importance of proactive problem-solving in the Bitcoin community while acknowledging the complexities involved in implementing changes to the protocol.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Was Under ATTACK!</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/bitcoin-was-under-attack/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/bitcoin-was-under-attack/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hosts Aaron van Wirdum and Sjors Provoost finally met in Utrecht again to record Bitcoin, Explained. In this episode, they discuss a recent attack on the Bitcoin network, where some nodes were flooding peers with fake IP-addresses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As previously discussed in episode 13, Bitcoin nodes connect to peers on the network through IP-addresses, which they learn from their existing peers. Nodes on the network essentially share the IP-addresses of other nodes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Recently, however, some Bitcoin nodes shared large amounts of IP-addresses that weren’t associated with real Bitcoin nodes at all. While this attack did not do very much damage, it did waste resources from nodes on the network. On top of that, Aaron and Sjors explain, the attack could offer the attacker insight into Bitcoin’s network topology by analyzing how the fake IP-addresses spread through the network.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, Aaron and Sjors discuss how the attack was solved by rate limiting the amount of IP-addresses than any node will allow its peers to be shared. Further, they consider how in free and open source software development, fixing problems is not always as straightforward as it may seem…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Erebus Attacks And How To Stop Them With ASMAP</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/erebus-attacks-and-how-to-stop-them-with-asmap/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-explained/erebus-attacks-and-how-to-stop-them-with-asmap/</guid><description>Aaron van Wirdum: 00:00:07
Live from Utrecht, this is The Van Wirdum Sjorsnado.
Sjors Provoost: 00:00:10
Hello!
Aaron van Wirdum: 00:00:10
Hey Sjors. What&amp;rsquo;s up? We got a market cap all time high, did you celebrate?
Sjors Provoost: 00:00:14
No, I did not because it&amp;rsquo;s just dilution.
Aaron van Wirdum: 00:00:16
What do you mean?
Sjors Provoost: 00:00:17
I mean somebody&amp;rsquo;s making more Bitcoin. So it&amp;rsquo;s fun that the market cap goes up, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter unless you&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>A Quantitative Analysis of Security, Anonymity and Scalability for the Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2020-05-09-sergei-tikhomirov-lightning-privacy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lightning-hack-day/2020-05-09-sergei-tikhomirov-lightning-privacy/</guid><description>Location: Lightning Hacksprint (Fulmo)
Slides: https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1H9EdrhjQ9x3q0qfsei7iFYINVf2lwPyjUKHd3CScy4k/edit#slide=id.g7774542944_0_0
Paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2020/303
Intro Hello everyone. I am Sergei, I am a PhD student at the University of Luxembourg. I am going to present our joint work with Pedro Moreno-Sanchez and Matteo Maffei from TU Wien on certain aspects of the privacy and scalability of the Lightning Network. The full paper can be found here.
LN intro (for completeness) Let me give some context on what Lightning Network is.</description></item><item><title>Why is seed splitting a bad idea?</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/andreas-antonopoulos/2020-04-08-andreas-antonopoulos-seed-splitting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/andreas-antonopoulos/2020-04-08-andreas-antonopoulos-seed-splitting/</guid><description>This is something that is being discussed all the time especially on newbie forums. It really needs to be careful very carefully. A friend had the idea to achieve 2 out of 3 protection from my wallet seed by storing the seed in the following way:
Location 1: seed words 1-8 and 9-16 Location 2: seed words 1-8 and 17-24 Location 3: seed words 9-16 and 17-24
It sounds a lot like Shamir’s Secret Sharing scheme but easier.</description></item><item><title>Beyond 51% attacks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/beyond-hashrate-majority-attacks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/beyond-hashrate-majority-attacks/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230624835996250112
Introduction Alright let&amp;rsquo;s get started with the next session. Vitalik is from Canada. He is a former writer for Bitcoin Magazine and can often be seen wearing unicorn shirts. He will be telling us about &amp;ldquo;Beyond 51% attacks&amp;rdquo;. Take it away.
Okay, so hello everyone. Hi. Okay. I will start by reminding everyone that 51% attacks are in fact bad. Bear with me for a few minutes. Is this better?</description></item><item><title>Stress Testing Decentralized Finance</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/stress-testing-decentralized-finance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/coordination-of-decentralized-finance-workshop/2020-stanford/stress-testing-decentralized-finance/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1229844754990370816
Introduction More quantitatively, I think coming up with stress tests is akin to Bryan&amp;rsquo;s question&amp;hellip;. stress testing is something that people in this space kind of do, and I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about what that looks like and what an actuarial analysis should look like.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to go through three examples of where an actuarial analysis shows certain weaknesses that need to be monitored and understood. They are going to be more on the scifi end of cryptocurrency.</description></item><item><title>Hardware Wallet Design Best Practices</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/hardware-wallet-design-best-practices/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/hardware-wallet-design-best-practices/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171322716303036417
Introduction We have 30 minutes. This was a talk by me and Jimmy but Jimmy talked for like 5 hours yesterday so I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking today.
Imagine you want to start working in bitcoin development. There&amp;rsquo;s a chance you will end up using a hardware wallet. In principle, it&amp;rsquo;s not any different from other software development. There&amp;rsquo;s still programming involved, like for firmware. Wallets have certain features and nuances compared to software wallets.</description></item><item><title>Hardware Wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/austin-bitcoin-developers/2019-06-29-hardware-wallets/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/austin-bitcoin-developers/2019-06-29-hardware-wallets/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1145019634547978240
see also:
Extracting seeds from hardware wallets The future of hardware wallets coredev.tech 2019 hardware wallets discussion Background A bit more than a year ago, I went through Jimmy Song&amp;rsquo;s Programming Blockchain class. That&amp;rsquo;s where I met M where he was the teaching assistant. Basically, you write a python bitcoin library from scratch. The API for this library and the classes and fnuctions that Jimmy uses is very easy to read and understand.</description></item><item><title>Attack Vectors of Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-fabrice-drouin-attack-vectors-of-lightning-network/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/chaincode-residency/2019-06-25-fabrice-drouin-attack-vectors-of-lightning-network/</guid><description>Location: Chaincode Residency – Summer 2019
Introduction All right so I&amp;rsquo;m going to introduce really quickly attack vectors on Lightning. I focus on first what you can do with the Lightning protocol, but I will mostly speak about how attacks will probably happen in real life. It&amp;rsquo;s probably not going to be direct attacks on the protocol itself.
Denial of Service So the basic attacks you can have when you&amp;rsquo;re running lightning nodes are denial of service attacks basically.</description></item><item><title>Hardware Wallets (History of Attacks)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2019-05-01-stepan-snigirev-hardware-wallet-attacks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2019-05-01-stepan-snigirev-hardware-wallet-attacks/</guid><description>Slides: https://www.dropbox.com/s/64s3mtmt3efijxo/Stepan%20Snigirev%20on%20hardware%20wallet%20attacks.pdf
Pieter Wuille on anti covert channel signing techniques: https://gnusha.org/url/https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2020-March/017667.html
Introduction This talk is the second in the series after my previous talk in London a few months ago at the Advancing Bitcoin conference. There I was talking mostly about general attacks on hardware, more from the theoretical perspective. I didn’t say anything bad hardware wallets that exist and I didn’t specify anything on the bad side. Here I feel a bit more free as it is a meetup not a conference so I can say bad things about everyone.</description></item><item><title>Topological Analysis of the Lightning Network</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-topological-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/lightning-network-topological-analysis/</guid><description>paper: https://arxiv.org/abs/1901.04972
https://github.com/seresistvanandras/LNTopology
Introduction Knowing the topology is not necessarily a vulnerability, but it gives you a lot of information. If I know Bryan&amp;rsquo;s full node is connected to some other nodes, I will have an easier time to cut Bryan out of the network or launch attacks against him. Knowing the topology is not necessarily a vulnerability, but it&amp;rsquo;s really strong information.
Recent research There were some recent papers published on this topic:</description></item><item><title>Wallet Security, Key Management &amp; Hardware Security Modules (HSMs)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/wallet-security/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/wallet-security/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1049813559750746112
Intro Alright, I’m now going to talk about bitcoin wallet security. And I was asked to talk about key management and hardware security modules and a bunch of other topics all in one talk. This will be a bit broader than some of the other talks because this is an important subject about how do you actually store bitcoin and then some of the developments around the actual storage of bitcoin in a secure way.</description></item><item><title>Breaking Hardware Wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/breaking-hardware-wallets/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/breaking-hardware-wallets/</guid><description>Breaking hardware wallets: Tales from the trenches and glimpses into the future
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005627960160849920
Hello. Nobody cares? Ah. So next up is Nicolas. And he will talk about hardware attacks. Thank you.
Introduction Hi everybody. Thanks for making a great conference so far. I am Nicolas from Ledger hardware wallet. Today I am going to be talking about breaking hardware wallets. I don&amp;rsquo;t mean physically breaking them. If you expected to come steal a hardware wallet and be able to break it, then you will be disappointed.</description></item><item><title>Hunting Moby Dick, an Analysis of 2015-2016 Spam Attacks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/spam-attacks-analysis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/spam-attacks-analysis/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005525351517360129
Introduction Hi. Thanks for Breaking Bitcoin to invite me to speak and to present this research on Moby Dick.
Moby Dick and spam attacks&amp;ndash; let me explain, Moby Dick is an entity that spammed or sent a lot of transactions in bitcoin in 2015. We did some analysis on who this person is or what they were doing. This is bitcoin archaeology, where we analyze past activities and try to analyze what happened and get insight into what could happen.</description></item><item><title>Exchange Security</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/exchange-security/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2017/exchange-security/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/838517545783148545
How often do you check your wallets? Have you ever looked in your wallet and found all your bitcoin gone or missing? Last summer, somebody, a friend of mine checked his wallet and found that 100,000 bitcoin was gone. What the hell, right? But that&amp;rsquo;s what happened at Bitfinex last summer. Some hacker got into their hot wallet and stole 100,000 bitcoin. This was $70 million bucks. Of which 1.</description></item><item><title>On the Security and Performance of Proof of Work Blockchains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/on-the-security-and-performance-of-proof-of-work-blockchains/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/on-the-security-and-performance-of-proof-of-work-blockchains/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785066988532068352
As most of you might know, in bitcoin and blockchains, the information is very important. Every node should receive the blocks in the network. Increase latency and risk network partition. If individual peers do not get the information, they could be victims of selfish mining and so on. Multiple blockchains has been proposed, multiple reparameterizations like litecoin, dogecoin, ethereum and others. One of the key changes they did was the block interval time.</description></item><item><title>Overview of Security Concerns</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/overview-of-security-concerns/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/overview-of-security-concerns/</guid><description>I am going to talk about scale-related security issues. Scale-related security issues. I said scale, not scalability. We are not talking about scalability. We&amp;rsquo;re talking about changing numbers, and what are the implications, what attacks are easier or harder by changing the block size number. What are we trying to accomplish? What is the system meant to be? Nobody really agrees of course. What&amp;rsquo;s interesting is that as much as we disagree about what was meant to be, there are a lot of key things about what bitcoin could be, these visions share some details.</description></item><item><title>Extracting Seeds From Hardware Wallets</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/extracting-seeds-from-hardware-wallets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/extracting-seeds-from-hardware-wallets/</guid><description>7DC5A359D0D5B5AB6728&amp;hellip;
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137672946435198976
Introduction My talk is about extracting seeds from hardware wallets. I am chief security officer at Ledger. I joined Ledger a bit more than one year ago. I built the Ledger Donjon which is an independent red team. Our mission is to help secure Ledger&amp;rsquo;s products. So what we do day to do is try to break all the hardware wallets. We continuously challenge the security of our products.</description></item><item><title>Failures Of Secret Key Cryptography (2013)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/failures-of-secret-key-cryptography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/failures-of-secret-key-cryptography/</guid><description>FSE 2013
Welcome to the second invited talk, to be given by Dan Bernstein. Dan is one of the few members of our community who does not need an introduction. It&amp;rsquo;s a great honor and pleasure that he has agreed to give a talk here. Dan comes from UC Berkeley and from Chicago. Just a few things you might know Dan from&amp;ndash; he sued the U.S. government about export controls. In 2004, .</description></item><item><title>Security and Attacks on Decentralized Mining Pools</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/security-attacks-decentralized-mining-pools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/security-attacks-decentralized-mining-pools/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137373752038240262
Introduction Hi, I am Alexei. I am a research student at Imperial College London and I will be talking about the security of decentralized mining pools.
Motivation The motivation behind this talk is straightforward. I think we can all agree that to some extent the hashrate in bitcoin has seen some centralization around large mining pools, which undermines the base properties of censorship resistance in bitcoin which I think bitcoin solves in a nice matter.</description></item><item><title>Transparent Dishonesty: front-running attacks on Blockchain</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/transparent-dishonesty/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/transparent-dishonesty/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1231005309310627841
Introduction The last two talks are going to be about frontrunning. One of the features of blockchain is that they are slow but this also opens them up to vulnerabilities such that I can insert my transactions before other people and this could have bad consequences and Shayan is going to explore this a little bit.
My talk will not be as intense as the previous talk, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to have more pictures.</description></item></channel></rss>