<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>vaults on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/vaults/</link><description>Recent content in vaults on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/vaults/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Covenants, Introspection, CTV and Activation Impasse</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/covenants-introspection-ctv-and-activation-impasse/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/covenants-introspection-ctv-and-activation-impasse/</guid><description>Introduction NVK: 00:01:10
As usual, nothing is happening in Bitcoin and we figured, what a great day to put people to sleep in a one to three hour podcast. We don&amp;rsquo;t know yet how it&amp;rsquo;s going to be. We actually don&amp;rsquo;t know how this is going to play out at all. I have here with me Mr. Rijndael. Hello, sir. Welcome back.
Rijndael: 00:01:30
Hello. Good morning.
NVK: 00:01:32
Good morning.</description></item><item><title>OP_Vault - A New Way to HODL?</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcointranscripts/stephan-livera-podcast/opvault-a-new-way-to-hodl/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcointranscripts/stephan-livera-podcast/opvault-a-new-way-to-hodl/</guid><description>Stephan:
James, welcome back to the show.
James 00:02:46:
Hey, Stephan, it&amp;rsquo;s great to be back. I think it&amp;rsquo;s been almost four years.
Stephan 00:02:50:
Damn. Yeah, well, in terms of on the show, yeah, actually in person, you know, a couple of times, some of the conferences and things. But I know you&amp;rsquo;ve got this awesome proposal out, and it looks pretty interesting to me, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure SLP listeners will be very interested to hear more about it.</description></item><item><title>Revault Bitcoin vaults</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/honey-badger-diaries/2020-04-24-kevin-loaec-antoine-poinsot-revault/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/honey-badger-diaries/2020-04-24-kevin-loaec-antoine-poinsot-revault/</guid><description>Aaron: So you guys built something. First tell me are you a company? Is this a startup? What is the story here?
Kevin: My personal interest in vaults started last year when Bryan Bishop published his email on the mailing list. I was like “That is an interesting concept.” After that I started engaging with him on Twitter proposing a few different ideas. There were some limitations and some attacks around it.</description></item><item><title>On-Chain Defense in Depth</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2019-02-09-mcelrath-on-chain-defense-in-depth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/2019-02-09-mcelrath-on-chain-defense-in-depth/</guid><description>On-chain defense in depth (UCL CBT seminar)
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1159542209584218113
Introduction It seems strange to come to a university and put PhD on my slides because in the finance world that&amp;rsquo;s weird. I put it up there.
Okay, so. I work for Fidelity Digital Assets. Just a couple words about this. Our lawyers make us say this: &amp;ldquo;This presentation is intended to be educational in nature and is not representative of existing products and services from Fidelity Investments or Fidelity Digital Assets.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Covenants: Opportunities and Challenges</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/covenants/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/covenants/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785071789705728000
We published this last February at an academic workshop. The work itself has interesting ramifications. My real goal here is to start a conversation and then do a follow-up blog post where we collate feedback from the community. We would like to add this to Bitcoin Core. Covenants.
This all started from a very basic and simple observation about the current status of our computing infrastructure. The observation is that the state of our computing infrastructure is no where near safe enough to store assets like bitcoin.</description></item></channel></rss>