<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CVEs (various) on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/cves/</link><description>Recent content in CVEs (various) on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/cves/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Replace-by-Fee Bug (CVE-2021-31876)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-magazine/bitcoin-explained/replace-by-fee-bug-cve-2021-31876/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-magazine/bitcoin-explained/replace-by-fee-bug-cve-2021-31876/</guid><description>Intro Aaron van Wirdum: 00:00:08
Live from Utrecht, Aruba and Utrecht, the Netherlands, this is The Van Wirdum Sjorsnado.
Sjors Provoost: 00:00:15
Hello, welcome, and listeners, sorry for the maybe not perfect sound quality, because we have to make do with the remote recording.
Aaron van Wirdum: 00:00:24
Yeah, for the second time since we&amp;rsquo;re making our show my laptop broke, so here I am on my phone.
Sjors Provoost: 00:00:32</description></item><item><title>libsecp256k1 testing</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2015-01-08-libsecp256k1-testing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2015-01-08-libsecp256k1-testing/</guid><description>Today OpenSSL de-embargoed CVE-2014-3570 &amp;ldquo;Bignum squaring may produce incorrect results&amp;rdquo;. That particular security advisory is not a concern for Bitcoin users, but it allows me to explain some of the context behind a slightly cryptic statement I made in the release notes for the upcoming Bitcoin Core 0.10: “we have reason to believe that libsecp256k1 is better tested and more thoroughly reviewed than the implementation in OpenSSL”. Part of that “reason to believe” was our discovery of this OpenSSL flaw.</description></item><item><title>OpenSSL bug discovery</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2015-01-08-openssl-bug/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2015-01-08-openssl-bug/</guid><description>I contributed to the discovery and analysis of CVE-2014-3570 &amp;ldquo;Bignum squaring may produce incorrect results&amp;rdquo;. In this case, the issue was that one of the carry propagation conditions was missed. The bug was discovered as part of the development of libsecp256k1, a high performance (and hopefully high quality: correct, complete, side-channel resistant) implementation of the cryptographic operators used by Bitcoin, developed primarily by Bitcoin Core developer Pieter Wuille along with a number of other people.</description></item></channel></rss>