<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>forks on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/forks/</link><description>Recent content in forks on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/forks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Are Users Rejecting Bitcoin Forks???</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-magazine/bitcoin-explained/are-users-rejecting-bitcoin-forks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-magazine/bitcoin-explained/are-users-rejecting-bitcoin-forks/</guid><description>Intro Aaron: Live from Utrecht, this is Bitcoin, Explained. Hey Sjors.
Sjors: What&amp;rsquo;s up?
Aaron: Sjors Provoost, Bitcoin Core contributor and author.
Sjors: Oh yes.
Aaron: Congratulations!
Sjors: Thank you.
Aaron: Your new book, Bitcoin: A Work in Progress is now available on Amazon?
Sjors: On everywhere. You go to btcwip.com, which is Work in Progress. There&amp;rsquo;s links to various Amazons and other sites where you can hopefully buy the book.</description></item><item><title>Great Consensus Cleanup</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06/2019-06-06-great-consensus-cleanup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2019-06/2019-06-06-great-consensus-cleanup/</guid><description>https://lists.linuxfoundation.org/pipermail/bitcoin-dev/2019-March/016714.html
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1136591286012698626
Introduction There&amp;rsquo;s not much new to talk about. Unclear about CODESEPARATOR. You want to make it a consensus rule that transactions can&amp;rsquo;t be larger than 100 kb. No reactions to that? Alright. Fine, we&amp;rsquo;re doing it. Let&amp;rsquo;s do it. Does everyone know what this proposal is?
Validation time for any block&amp;ndash; we were lazy about fixing this. Segwit was a first step to fixing this, by giving people a way to do this in a more efficient way.</description></item><item><title>Handling Reorgs &amp; Forks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/reorgs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/reorgs/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1052344700554960896
Introduction Good morning, my name is Bryan. I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking about reorganizations and forks in the bitcoin blockchain. First, I want to define what a reorganization is and what a fork is.
Definitions You might have heard that the bitcoin blockchain is a permanent data structure that records everything from all time and that is actually somewhat false. Instead, actually the bitcoin blockchain can be modified and changed, and some of these changes are called reorgs and some of these changes are called forks.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Full Nodes</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2018-07-23-john-light-bitcoin-full-nodes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2018-07-23-john-light-bitcoin-full-nodes/</guid><description>Location: London Bitcoin Devs
John Light blog post on soft forks and hard forks: https://medium.com/@lightcoin/the-differences-between-a-hard-fork-a-soft-fork-and-a-chain-split-and-what-they-mean-for-the-769273f358c9
Intro My presentation today is going to be about Bitcoin full nodes. Everything you wanted to know and more. There should perhaps be an asterisk because I’m not going to say literally everything but if anyone in the audience has any questions that want to go really deep down the rabbit hole then we’ll see just how far down we can go.</description></item><item><title>Changing Consensus Rules Without Breaking Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/changing-consensus-rules-without-breaking-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/changing-consensus-rules-without-breaking-bitcoin/</guid><description>Changing consensus rules without breaking bitcoin
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005822360321216512
Introduction I&amp;rsquo;d like to talk about &amp;hellip; we actually discovered we can replace the script completely with soft-forks.
It&amp;rsquo;s important to note this quote from satoshi, from summer 2010: &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t believe a second compatible implementation will ever&amp;rdquo; &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;
Comparing open-source development to bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s blockchain &amp;hellip; a lot of the inspiration came from the development of open-source. All source code is public, analogous to all blockchain being public.</description></item><item><title>Light Clients During 2017 Interfork Period</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/light-clients-during-2017-interfork-period/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/light-clients-during-2017-interfork-period/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005617123287289857
Next up is Thomas.
Introduction Alright. Hello everyone. Thank you for having me. I&amp;rsquo;m the developer of the Electrum wallet. I started this project in 2011. I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about lite clients and the implication of the 2017 hard-fork. We might be in the middle of two forks at the moment.
So we have segwit and we are very happy about that. ((applause)) This graph was taken from Pieter Wuille&amp;rsquo;s website.</description></item><item><title>Socialized Costs Of Hard Forks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/socialized-costs-of-hard-forks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2017/socialized-costs-of-hard-forks/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1005518746260262912
KL: Can you hear me? Is it good? Okay. I hope you have practiced your French because.. no, the presentations are in English. Welcome and thank you very much for being here. This conference will very probably be the best we&amp;rsquo;ve had in the bitcoin sphere. The crowd is pretty crazy. I&amp;rsquo;ve had the ticket list and I can say the people in this room, not just the speakers, the attendees are all super amazing.</description></item><item><title>Consensus Uasf And Forks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/lets-talk-bitcoin-podcast/2017-06-04-consensus-uasf-and-forks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/lets-talk-bitcoin-podcast/2017-06-04-consensus-uasf-and-forks/</guid><description>On Consensus and All Kinds of Forks
Location: Let’s Talk Bitcoin podcast (Episode 333)
User activated soft forks vs hard forks Adam Levine (AL): I’m trying to look at the user activated soft fork thing and not see hypocrisy just steaming out of its ears. I’m really in need of you to help me understand why this is not the case Andreas. The argument to this point about scaling, one of the arguments, one of the larger arguments, has been that hard forks are the worst thing that can happen.</description></item><item><title>Bip101 Block Propagation Data From Testnet</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/bip101-block-propagation-data-from-testnet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/bip101-block-propagation-data-from-testnet/</guid><description>I am a bitcoin miner. I am a C++ programmer and a scientist. I will be going pretty fast. I have a lot of stuff to cover. Bare with me.
My perspective on this is that scaling bitcoin is an engineer problem. My favorite proposal for how to scale bitcoin is bip101. It&amp;rsquo;s over a 20-year time span. This will give us time to implement fixes to get Bitcoin to a large level.</description></item><item><title>Bip99 And Uncontroversial Hard Forks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/bip99-and-uncontroversial-hard-forks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/bip99-and-uncontroversial-hard-forks/</guid><description>slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY1/1_overview_1_timon.pdf
bip99 https://github.com/bitcoin/bips/blob/master/bip-0099.mediawiki
We are going to focus on consensus rules. I am going to give an introduction and then focus on controversial versus non-controversial hard-forks.
Why do we want to classify consensus changes in the first place? Well, for one, you often have long discussions many times in Bitcoin, we don&amp;rsquo;t always share the same terminology and the same definitions, and this could lead to disagreement. Another advantage of classifying consensus forks is to recommend strategies for them.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin Script</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/bitcoin-script/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/bitcoin-script/</guid><description>Featuring roasbeef
Agenda opcodes OP_CHECKSIGFROMSTACK sighash flags keytree sigs MAST graftroot, taproot covenants, reverse covenants (input restrictions: this input has to be spent with tihs other input, or can only be spent if this other one doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist) stack manipulation script languages (simplicity) tx formats, serialization? what would we change with hard-fork changes to the transaction format? Segwit transaction encoding format sucks; the witnesses are at the end and inline with all the scriptsigs and that should be changed.</description></item><item><title>Blockchain Testbed</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/blockchain-testbed/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/blockchain-testbed/</guid><description>A testbed for bitcoin scaling
I want to talk today about how to scale bitcoin. We want lower latency, we want higher throughput, more bandwidth and more transactions per second, and we want security. We can try to tune the parameters. In all of the plots, I have time going from left to right and these are blocks in rectangles. We have larger blocks which might give us more throughput. We could have shorter block length, and transactions would come faster on the chain and we have better throughput but we get forks and orphans when that happens.</description></item><item><title>Ethcore</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/ethcore/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/w3-blockchain-workshop-2016/ethcore/</guid><description>ethcore
At ethcore, we are building the infrastructure for the future of the decentralized web. Unless we get distracted by TheDAO and soft-forks and hard-forks. Maybe decentralization is not the most important thing. We want to build a p2p secure serverless web. Why is decentralization such an important notion? There&amp;rsquo;s no intrinsic value in being decentralized. There&amp;rsquo;s intrinsic value in being utilized and secure by people.
This is a bit of how we see the architecture.</description></item><item><title>Segwit Lessons Learned</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/segwit-lessons-learned/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/segwit-lessons-learned/</guid><description>Lessons learned with segwit in Bitcoin
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/785034301272420353
Hi. My name is Greg Sanders. I will be giving a talk about segwit in bitcoin lessons learned. I will also give some takeaways that I think are important. A little bit about myself. I work on Elements Project at Blockstream. I was a reviewer on segwit for Bitcoin Core. How do we scale protocol development? How do we scale review and keep things safe?</description></item><item><title>Spork Probabilistic Bitcoin Soft Forks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/spork-probabilistic-bitcoin-soft-forks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2019/spork-probabilistic-bitcoin-soft-forks/</guid><description>Spork: Probabilistic bitcoin soft-forks
Introduction Thank you for the introduction. I have a secret. I am not an economist, so you&amp;rsquo;ll have to forgive me if I don&amp;rsquo;t have your favorite annotations today. I have my own annotations. I originally gave a predecessor to this talk in Japan. You might notice my title here is a haiku: these are protocols used for changing the bitcoin netwokr protocols. People do highly value staying together for a chain, we&amp;rsquo;re doing coordinated activation of a new upgrade.</description></item><item><title>What Internet governance can learn from Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/pindar-wong/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2016/pindar-wong/</guid><description>Pindar Wong
Forked to Death: What Internet governance can learn from Bitcoin
So, the last talk today is going to be from Pindar Wong. He&amp;rsquo;s been involved with Internet in Hong Kong. He also helped organize the Scaling Bitcoin workshops. It&amp;rsquo;s my pleasure to have him speaking today.
Okay. Thank you very much for staying until the bitter end. My topic today is forked to death, what Internet governance can learn from Bitcoin.</description></item></channel></rss>