<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Adam Ficsor on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/adam-ficsor/</link><description>Recent content in Adam Ficsor on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/speakers/adam-ficsor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CoinShuffle++ (Part 1)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/coinshuffle-plusplus-part-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/coinshuffle-plusplus-part-1/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s episode Tim Ruffing introduces the CoinShuffle++ protocol and explains its key components. He describes how the protocol uses power sums and polynomial roots to ensure secure messaging between participants. The protocol consists of four stages: Dimi Hellman key exchange, commitment, DC net, and confirmation. The protocol handles malicious peers by revealing secret keys and excluding them in the next round. Ruffing also highlights the scalability of the CoinShuffle++ protocol, as it can accommodate a large number of participants and complete the process in a relatively short time. The use of dice mix enhances the efficiency of the protocol compared to its predecessor, CoinShuffle. Futher Tim dives into the challenges of implementing CoinShuffle++, a decentralized protocol for coinjoining cryptocurrencies. He highlights the issues caused by varying internet connection speeds and round communication, leading to slower performance. Ruffing also discusses concerns about the negotiation process and cryptography affecting communication speed. Additionally, he acknowledges the complexity of the topic and expresses a desire to simplify it for wider understanding and implementation. Overall, Ruffing emphasizes the importance of maintaining privacy in peer-to-peer transactions and the potential of cryptography in various applications.</description></item><item><title>Anonymous Bitcoin</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/anonymous-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/anonymous-bitcoin/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014128850765303808
https://github.com/zkSNACKs/WalletWasabi
One year ago I was standing here at this conference and Igave a talk. Today I am standing here and I titled my talk &amp;ldquo;Anonymous bitcoin&amp;rdquo;. One year ago at this conference, the conference was named &amp;ldquo;breaking bitcoin&amp;rdquo;. I did not break bitcoin. Someone else did, you might remember.
Today I want to present how I build on bitcoin. I have two goals with this presentation. I want to provide a case study of the bitcoin developer and his mistakes and successes.</description></item></channel></rss>