<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Privacy Enhancements on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/privacy-enhancements/</link><description>Recent content in Privacy Enhancements on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/privacy-enhancements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Monero and the Privacy Doom Principle</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/monero-and-the-privacy-doom-principle/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoinplusplus/onchain-privacy/monero-and-the-privacy-doom-principle/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a blockchain researcher and developer. I&amp;rsquo;ve built the Sia blockchain ecosystem and I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the space for a while and today I&amp;rsquo;m talking about Monero and privacy models that ended up being explained in analytical techniques that we can use to beat error in privacy.
The Concept of Privacy in Cryptocurrencies So my name is David Vork. I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the blockchain space for about a decade. I&amp;rsquo;ve been between researching and launching blockchains, doing a lot of engineering, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been in the space for a while and studying things.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Metrics for Coin Selection</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2023-09/privacy-metrics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-core-dev-tech/2023-09/privacy-metrics/</guid><description>Goal: Get privacy consciousness into coin selection Configurability Privacy vs cost (waste) Privacy: weighted on a 0-5 scale Cost: weighted on a 0-5 scale Convert privacy preference (0-5) into satoshis to make it compatible with the waste score Combined score = PrivacyScoreWeight x PrivacyScore + CostWeight x WasteMetric 20-30 sats per privacy point as a gut feeling Privacy score example: sending to different script type than inputs of transaction We already match the change type to the recipient type, but that can still mean that we have differently typed inputs than outputs If we have two input sets, where one has the same type and the other has a different type, the one with the same type inputs should be preferred by the privacy metric Privacy score example: Preferring spending UTXOs of similar age E.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Privacy &amp; Splice Panel</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/lightning-privacy-splice-panel/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/bitcoin-review-podcast/lightning-privacy-splice-panel/</guid><description>Housekeeping Speaker 0: 00:01:17
Today we&amp;rsquo;re going to be talking about Lightning privacy, splicing and other very cool things with an absolute amazing panel here. Just before that, I have a couple of things that I want to set out some updates. So OpenSats is now taking grants for a Bitcoin application, sorry, taking grant applications for Bitcoin projects and Nostra projects and Lightning projects. And there is about five mil for an OSTER, five mil for Bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Silent Payments and Alternatives</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-15-silent-payments/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/tabconf/2022/2022-10-15-silent-payments/</guid><description>Introduction I will talk about silent payments but also in general the design space around what kind of constructs you can have to pay people in a non-interactive way. In the bitcoin world, there are a couple common ways of paying someone. Making a payment is such a basic thing. &amp;hellip; The alternative we have is that you can generate a single address and put it in your twitter profile and everyone can pay you, but that&amp;rsquo;s not private.</description></item><item><title>Checking Bitcoin balances privately</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/checking-bitcoin-balances-privately/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/checking-bitcoin-balances-privately/</guid><description>In this video, the Wasabi Research Club delves into the topic of checking Bitcoin balances privately. They discuss the use of homomorphic encryption and private information retrieval to protect users&amp;rsquo; privacy when querying data from a server. They explore different solutions and strategies to address challenges such as address linkability, block retrieval, and the scalability and cost of checking balances. The team also emphasizes the need for an open standard for private information retrieval to ensure decentralization. They discuss the use of Tor and homomorphic encryption together, as well as the possibility of batching requests to improve efficiency. The video concludes by highlighting the ongoing research and exploration of potential solutions to ensure private querying of Bitcoin balances and more&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Anonymous Credentials</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/anonymous-credentials/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/anonymous-credentials/</guid><description>Jonas Nick discusses anonymous credentials and their applications in this section. Anonymous credentials involve getting a blinded token signed by a server, where the server does not see the message being signed. These tokens contain attributes that can be selectively revealed, and range proofs can be used to verify attributes without revealing additional information. The speaker highlights the flexibility and security of anonymous credentials and how they improve on traditional signatures. They also discuss advancements in these credentials, such as mercurial signatures and delegateable anonymous credentials. The speaker mentions the work of Del Tauri and their solution for creating a divisible e-cash system using homomorphic cryptographic commitments, range proofs, and blind signature schemes. They also discuss the merging and breaking of anonymous credentials, as well as reissuing tokens without exposing the individual values. The implementation and linkability of credentials are also explored in the conversation. Overall, the participants express the need for further study and propose focusing on the cryptography part of the scheme in the next session.</description></item><item><title>Coinshuffle++ (Part 2)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/coinshuffle-plusplus-part-2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/coinshuffle-plusplus-part-2/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s episode Tim Ruffing explores the concept of disruption in the Coinshuffle++ protocol and how it can be detected. He explains that the protocol passively observes messages and their outcomes, without knowing which message belongs to each participant. The speaker also discusses the practicality of blocking someone from the protocol, mentioning the role of network setting and the potential power of an attacker. Additionally, Ruffing highlights the importance of multiple communication rounds, protocols for key exchange, and the need for peers to verify if the protocol has been disrupted. Further Tim explains the concept of introducing another broadcast round in Coinshuffle++ to avoid disruption. By replacing one broadcast with another, the protocol ensures that if one message is disrupted, all messages are disrupted. This eliminates the need for a broadcast round to check for disruption, as participants can simply look at the list of messages and determine if their own message is there or not. This approach provides a guarantee of message integrity without additional broadcasts. Ruffing also addresses the limitations of Coinshuffle++, such as the lack of privacy in transactions with unequal inputs and the inability to pay while mixing. He discusses potential solutions for the anonymity of payments and emphasizes the benefits of Coinshuffle++ for coin shuffling. The timing and trust aspects of the protocol are also discussed, with a mention of potential delays and the need to trust other peers. Overall, Coinshuffle++ offers improvements in message integrity and coin mixing, but there is room for further development in addressing certain limitations and ensuring robust anonymity.</description></item><item><title>CoinShuffle++ (Part 1)</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/coinshuffle-plusplus-part-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/coinshuffle-plusplus-part-1/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s episode Tim Ruffing introduces the CoinShuffle++ protocol and explains its key components. He describes how the protocol uses power sums and polynomial roots to ensure secure messaging between participants. The protocol consists of four stages: Dimi Hellman key exchange, commitment, DC net, and confirmation. The protocol handles malicious peers by revealing secret keys and excluding them in the next round. Ruffing also highlights the scalability of the CoinShuffle++ protocol, as it can accommodate a large number of participants and complete the process in a relatively short time. The use of dice mix enhances the efficiency of the protocol compared to its predecessor, CoinShuffle. Futher Tim dives into the challenges of implementing CoinShuffle++, a decentralized protocol for coinjoining cryptocurrencies. He highlights the issues caused by varying internet connection speeds and round communication, leading to slower performance. Ruffing also discusses concerns about the negotiation process and cryptography affecting communication speed. Additionally, he acknowledges the complexity of the topic and expresses a desire to simplify it for wider understanding and implementation. Overall, Ruffing emphasizes the importance of maintaining privacy in peer-to-peer transactions and the potential of cryptography in various applications.</description></item><item><title>Applying Private Information Retrieval to Lightweight Bitcoin Clients</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/private-information-retrieval/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/private-information-retrieval/</guid><description>SPV overview I have to thank the prior speaker. This is basically the same, except this time we&amp;rsquo;re not using SGX. We&amp;rsquo;re looking at bitcoin lightweight clients. You have a lite client with not much space not much computing power, can&amp;rsquo;t store the bitcoin blockchain. All it knows about is the header information. We assume it has the blockheader history. In the header, we can find the merkle tree, and given the merkle tree we can make a merkle proof that a given transaction is included in a block.</description></item><item><title>Privacy Concepts for Bitcoin application developers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/privacy-concepts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2019/privacy-concepts/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1171036497044267008
Introduction You&amp;rsquo;re not going to walk out of here as a privacy protocol developer. I am going to mention and talk about some ideas in some protocols that exist. What I find myself is that of really smart people working on a lot of pretty cool stuff that can make privacy easier and better to use. A lot of times, application developers or exchanges aren&amp;rsquo;t even aware of those things and as a result the end result is that people just sometimes use bitcoin in very non-private ways because they&amp;rsquo;re not aware of how to do privacy.</description></item><item><title>Future Of Privacy Coins</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/future-of-privacy-coins/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/future-of-privacy-coins/</guid><description>AM: That&amp;rsquo;s not good. Hi everyone. Thanks for coming to the future of privacy coins panel. I want to spend a minute talking ablout backgrounds and interest in this area.
BG: I have a PhD in something. I got into monero a couple of years ago. I needed to pay rent, so I did some work in math in exchange for money.
AP: I work on confidential transactions and scriptless scripts and I do not have a PhD.</description></item><item><title>Multi-Hop Locks for Secure, Privacy-Preserving and Interoperable Payment-Channel Networks</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-hop-locks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tokyo-2018/multi-hop-locks/</guid><description>Giulio Malavolta (Friedrich-Alexander-University Erlangen-Nuernberg), Pedro Moreno-Sanchez (Purdue University), Clara Schneidewind (Vienna University of Technology), Aniket Kate (Purdue University) and Matteo Maffei (Vienna University of Technology)
https://eprint.iacr.org/2018/472.pdf
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1048476273259900928
This is joint work with my colleagues. I promise I will talk slower than the last talk. In a multi-hop network, the security tool is a hash-time lock contract (HTLC) where the payment is conditioned on revealing the pre-image of a hash function. This is pretty much the main setup for the lightning network today.</description></item><item><title>Cross-Chain Swaps: Atomically Swapping Coins for Privacy or Cross-Blockchain Trades</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/cross-chain-swaps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/edgedevplusplus/2018/cross-chain-swaps/</guid><description>Ethan and Nicolas describe atomic cross-chain swaps - a protocol where two parties can exchange coins as a single operation. The exchange does not require any trusted third party and neither of the parties involved can cheat each other. They describe how this can be used on a single blockchain as a privacy protocol or “cross-chain” as a trading protocol.</description></item><item><title>CoinjoinXT and other techniques for deniable transfers</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/coinjoinxt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/building-on-bitcoin/2018/coinjoinxt/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1014197088979226625
https://joinmarket.me/blog/blog/coinjoinxt/
Introduction My talk today is about what I&amp;rsquo;m calling CoinjoinXT which is kind of a new proposal. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t say it&amp;rsquo;s a new technology, but perhaps a new combination of technologies. My name is Adam Gibson. Yes, another Adam, sorry about that. I have been working on privacy tech for the last number of years, mostly on joinmarket. Today&amp;rsquo;s talk is not about joinmarket, but it is about coinjoin.</description></item><item><title>BOLT Anonymous Payment Channels for Decentralized Currencies</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/bolt-anonymous-payment-channels-for-decentralized-currencies/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/bolt-anonymous-payment-channels-for-decentralized-currencies/</guid><description>paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2016/701.pdf
To make questions easier, we are going to have a mic on the isle. Please line up so that we can have questions quickly. Okay, now we have Ian Miers.
My name is Ian Miers. Just got my PhD at Hpkins&amp;hellip; authors of zcash, zerocash, &amp;hellip; My interest in bitcoin was, first getting involved, was dealing with the privacy aspect. There is also a scaling problem. I assume you are aware of that.</description></item><item><title>ValueShuffle: Mixing Confidential Transactions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/valueshuffle-mixing-confidential-transactions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/valueshuffle-mixing-confidential-transactions/</guid><description>paper: https://eprint.iacr.org/2017/238.pdf
Thank you.
We have seen two talks now about putting privacy in layer two. But let&amp;rsquo;s talk about layer one. We still don&amp;rsquo;t have great privacy there. So the title of this talk is valueshuffle - mixing confidential transactions. I don&amp;rsquo;t have to convince you that bitcoin at the moment is not really private. There are a lot of possibilities to link&amp;hellip; to deal them as, to link addresses together.</description></item><item><title>Confidential Transactions</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2017-04-28-gmaxwell-confidential-transactions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/greg-maxwell/2017-04-28-gmaxwell-confidential-transactions/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/859604355917414400
Introduction Thank you.
So as mentioned, I am going to be talking about confidential transactions today. And I look at confidential transactions as a building block fundamental piece of technology, it&amp;rsquo;s not like altcoin or something like that. It&amp;rsquo;s not a turnkey system, it&amp;rsquo;s some fundamental tech, and there are many different ways to use it and deploy it.
My interest in this technology is primarily driven by bitcoin, but the technology here could be applied to many other things, including things outside of the cryptocurrency space.</description></item><item><title>Fungibility Overview</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/fungibility-overview/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/fungibility-overview/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784676022318952448
Introduction Alright. So let&amp;rsquo;s get started. Okay. Why fungibility? Let&amp;rsquo;s start. What does fungibility mean? Bitcoin is like cash. The hope is that it&amp;rsquo;s for immediate and final payments. To add some nuiance there, you might have to wait for some confirmations. Once you receive a bitcoin, you have a bitcoin and that&amp;rsquo;s final. So even with banks and PayPal, who sometimes shutdown accounts for trivial reasons or sometimes no reason at all, it&amp;rsquo;s typically not the case that it&amp;rsquo;s someone who sent you money&amp;hellip; if you were selling something on ebay, and someone bought an item from you, and that person had an account shutdown, the money you received will not be removed from your account.</description></item><item><title>TumbleBit: An Untrusted Bitcoin-Compatible Anonymous Payment Hub</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/tumblebit/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/tumblebit/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/784686167052709888
Hi. So I&amp;rsquo;m going to be talking about tumblebit. It&amp;rsquo;s our untrusted private bitcoin payment system. Tumblebit provides payments which are private. They provide set anonymity when used as a classic tumbler. They are untrusted. The tumbler can&amp;rsquo;t violate your privacy, and can&amp;rsquo;t steal your coins. It&amp;rsquo;s also scalable. It&amp;rsquo;s compatible and works with today&amp;rsquo;s bitcoin. There are no malleability concerns. We&amp;rsquo;re going to rely on the constrained opcodes that currently exist in bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Fungibility And Scalability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/fungibility-and-scalability/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/hong-kong-2015/fungibility-and-scalability/</guid><description>slides: https://scalingbitcoin.org/hongkong2015/presentations/DAY1/1_overviews_2_back.pdf
I think everyone knows what fungibility is, it&amp;rsquo;s when coins are equal and interchangeable. It&amp;rsquo;s an important property for an electronic cash system. All bitcoin users would have a problem if fungability goes away.
Bitcoin has fungibility without privacy. Previous electronic cash systems had fungibility and cryptographic blinding. In Bitcoin, there&amp;rsquo;s decentralized mining that somebody will process your transaction even if a given miner may not. But there is some privacy, because it&amp;rsquo;s based on pseudonyms.</description></item><item><title>Privacy-Preserving Smart Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/privacy-preserving-smart-contracts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/privacy-preserving-smart-contracts/</guid><description>ranjit@csail.mit.edu
http://people.csail.mit.edu/ranjit/
We have been looking at how much we can support or what limitations we might encounter. There are also efficiency issues and privacy guarantees. And then there are some potential relaxations that will help with removing the fundamental limitations and express the power and make smart contracts more useful.
The point of this talk is off-chain transactions and secure computation. I will also highlight the relationship of secure computation and bitcoin.</description></item><item><title>Fungibility and Privacy</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/bitcoin-adam3us-fungibility-privacy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/misc/bitcoin-adam3us-fungibility-privacy/</guid><description>First of all I was going to explain what we mean by fungibility before bitcoin and ecash. It&amp;rsquo;s an old legal concept in fact, about paper currency. It&amp;rsquo;s the idea that a one ten dollar note is the same as any other ten dollar note. If you receive a note that was involved in a theft, 10 transactions ago, and the police investigate the theft, they have no right to remove the ten dollar note from your pocket.</description></item><item><title>A Tale of Two Trees: One Writes, and Other Reads, Scaling Oblivious Accesses to Large-Scale Blockchains</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/scaling-oblivious-read-write/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/tel-aviv-2019/scaling-oblivious-read-write/</guid><description>Introduction We are trying to get optimized oblivious accesses to large-scale blockchains. This is collaborative work with our colleagues.
Motivation As we all know, bitfcoin data has become too large to store in resource-constrained devices. It&amp;rsquo;s like 240 GB. The current solution today is bip37 + Nakamoto&amp;rsquo;s idea for simplified payment verification (SPV) clients which don&amp;rsquo;t run the bitcoin network rules. Resource-constrained clients (thin clients) have to rely on other potentially malicious full clients to obtain transaction information.</description></item><item><title>Breaking Bitcoin Privacy</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/breaking-bitcoin-privacy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/breaking-bitcoin/2019/breaking-bitcoin-privacy/</guid><description>0A8B 038F 5E10 CC27 89BF CFFF EF73 4EA6 77F3 1129
https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1137304437024862208
Introduction Hello everybody. I invented and created joinmarket, the first really popular coinjoin implementation. A couple months ago I wrote a big literature review on privacy. It has everything about anything in privacy in bitcoin, published on the bitcoin wiki. This talk is about privacy and what we can do to improve it.
Why privacy? Privacy is essential for fungibility, a necessary property of money where one unit is always equal to any other unit.</description></item><item><title>Cryptographic Hocus-Pocus Meaning Nothing: The Zcash Trusted Setup MPC</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/cryptographic-hocus-pocus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/magicalcryptoconference/2019/cryptographic-hocus-pocus/</guid><description>or: &amp;ldquo;Peter Todd&amp;rsquo;s secret love letter to Zooko&amp;rdquo;
Background See http://web.archive.org/web/20170717025249/https://petertodd.org/2016/cypherpunk-desert-bus-zcash-trusted-setup-ceremony
and later it was then redacted: https://petertodd.org/2016/cypherpunk-desert-bus-zcash-trusted-setup-ceremony
Introduction Alright. Hopefully you guys are all awake ish or something. I am going to give a talk about the zcash trusted setup. As many of you know, I was involved in it. The way to start is to answer, what is it?
What is the zcash trusted setup? It&amp;rsquo;s a bunch of toxic waste, basically.</description></item><item><title>Day 1 Group Summaries</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/day-1-group-summaries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/milan-2016/day-1-group-summaries/</guid><description>We need two to three minute report backs from each session. Also, note takers. Please email your notes to contact@scalingbitcoin.org so that we can add notes to the wiki. Come join us. Okay, so.
Lightning We discussed routing and several aspects of routing algorithms in the lightning network. We talked about the tradeoff between privacy aspects and reliability in routing. We quickly discovered that after some of the things were already resolved by the papers&amp;ndash; the way how we deal with a general separation and channel transaction fees, is actually quite an interesting discussion topic.</description></item><item><title>DECO: Liberating Web Data Using Decentralized Oracles for TLS</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/decentralized-oracles-tls/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/stanford-blockchain-conference/2020/decentralized-oracles-tls/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/1230657639740108806
Introduction I am Fan from Cornell. I am going to be talking about DECO, a privacy-preserving oracle for TLS. This is joint work with some other people.
Decentralized identity What is identity? To use any system, the first thing that the user needs to do is to prove her identity and that she is a user to the system. The identity can be descriptive. You can think of digital identity as a set of descriptions about a user.</description></item><item><title>Extreme Opsec For The Modern Cypherpunk</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/extreme-opsec-for-the-modern-cypherpunk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/baltic-honeybadger/2018/extreme-opsec-for-the-modern-cypherpunk/</guid><description>Jameson is the infrastructure engineer at Casa. Please welcome Jameson Lopp.
Introduction Hi fellow cypherpunks. We&amp;rsquo;re under attack. Corporations and nation states in their quest for omniscience have slowly stripped away our privacy. We are the frog being boiled in the pot called progress. We can&amp;rsquo;t trust that corporations will grant us privacy out of their beneficience. Our failures here are our own. After being swatted a year ago, I set out to restart my life with a new focus on privacy.</description></item><item><title>Privacy and Scalability</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/privacy-and-fungibility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/montreal-2015/privacy-and-fungibility/</guid><description>Even though Bitcoin is the worst privacy system ever, everyone in the community very strongly values privacy.
There are at least three things: privacy censorship resistance fungibility
The easiest way to censor things is to punish communication, not prevent communication. Privacy is the weakest link in censorship resistance. Fungibility is an absolute necessity for any medium of exchange. The properties of money include fungibility. Without privacy you may not be able to have fungibility.</description></item></channel></rss>