<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Discreet Log Contracts (DLCs) on ₿itcoin Transcripts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/tags/dlc/</link><description>Recent content in Discreet Log Contracts (DLCs) on ₿itcoin Transcripts</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://btctranscripts.com/tags/dlc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Socratic Seminar - Discreet Log Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2021-08-10-socratic-seminar-dlcs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/london-bitcoin-devs/2021-08-10-socratic-seminar-dlcs/</guid><description>Gist of resources discussed: https://gist.github.com/michaelfolkson/f5da6774c24f99dba5c6c16ec8d499e9
This event was livestreamed on YouTube and so comments are attributed to specific individuals by the name or pseudonym that was visible on the livestream. If you were a participant and would like your comments to be anonymized please get in touch.
Intro Michael Folkson (MF): Welcome to everyone on the call, welcome to people watching on YouTube. This is a Socratic Seminar, we’ve got a Zoom call and it is being livestreamed on YouTube.</description></item><item><title>Discrete Log Contract Specification</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/discrete-log-contract-specification/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/wasabi/research-club/discrete-log-contract-specification/</guid><description>Today&amp;rsquo;s WRC episode includes Nadav Kohen and Benthecarman discuss the use of Discrete Log Contracts (DLCs) and their potential benefits and challenges. They explain that DLCs can enable various applications such as betting, options contracts, insurance, and synthetic assets. They highlight the advantages of DLCs, including high liquidity and fast trading of futures, especially once implemented on the Lightning Network. However, they also acknowledge that there may still be a need for centralized solutions depending on the specific use case. The speakers delve into the technical aspects of DLCs, including the transition to Schnorr signatures and the privacy implications of using DLCs. They also discuss the role of oracles in DLCs and the potential for coin joints with DLCs. Overall, the speakers provide a detailed overview of DLCs and their potential applications in the cryptocurrency space.</description></item><item><title>Discreet Log Contracts</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/discreet-log-contracts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/scalingbitcoin/stanford-2017/discreet-log-contracts/</guid><description>http://diyhpl.us/wiki/transcripts/discreet-log-contracts/
paper: https://adiabat.github.io/dlc.pdf
Hello everyone. I am going to give a talk about discreet log contracts. I am from MIT DCI. I work on lightning network software and discreet log contracts. A quick intro: these are pretty new. I am not sure if they work. This presentation is part of the peer review process. Maybe the math doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. Please let me know. It might also work, though.
It&amp;rsquo;s a system of smart contracts using bitcoin which is similar to lightning network.</description></item><item><title>Improving Bitcoin Smart Contract Efficiency</title><link>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2018/improving-bitcoin-smart-contract-efficiency/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://btctranscripts.com/mit-bitcoin-expo/mit-bitcoin-expo-2018/improving-bitcoin-smart-contract-efficiency/</guid><description>https://twitter.com/kanzure/status/980545280973201410
Introduction I will be talking about discreet log contracts, taproot, and graftroot. Not in that order, the order will actually be taproot, graftroot, and then discreet log contracts.
Quick intro: I&amp;rsquo;m Tadge Dryja. I work here at MIT down the street at Digital Currency Initiative. I was coauthor on the lightning network paper, and I worked on lightning. I also was the author of a paper introducing discreet log contracts.</description></item></channel></rss>